COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS
EXPRESSLY PROHIBITED BY THE
U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
HOUSE WILL BE IN ORDER.
THE CHAIR LAYS BEFORE THE HOUSE
A COMMUNICATION FROM
THE
SPEAKER.
THE CLERK: THE
SPEAKER'S ROOMS,
WASHINGTON, D.C.
NOVEMBER
29, 2011.
I HEREBY
APPOINT THE HONORABLE
ANDY HARRIS TO
ACT AS
SPEAKER
PRO TEMPORE ON THIS DAY.
SIGNED,
JOHN A. BOEHNER,
SPEAKER OF THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
PRAYER WILL BE OFFERED BY OUR
CHAPLAIN, FATHER CONROY.
CHAPLAIN CONROY:
LET US PRAY.
GRACIOUS GOD,
WE GIVE YOU
THANKS FOR G
IVING US ANOTHER
DAY.
YOU HAVE BLESSED US
WITH ALL
GOOD
GIFTS
AND THIS PAST WEEK
WITH
THANKFUL HEARTS WE
GATHERED WITH FAMILY
AND
LOVED
ONES
THROUGHOUT THIS GREAT LAND
TO
CELEBRATE OUR BLESSINGS
TOGETHER.
BLESS THE MEMBERS
OF THE
PEOPLE'S HOUSE WHO HAVE BEEN
ENTRUSTED WITH
THE PRIVILEGE TO
SERVE OUR NATION
AND ALL
AMERICANS IN THEIR NEED.
GRANT THEM
TO WORK TOGETHER IN
RESPECT
AND AFFECTION AND TO BE
FAITHFUL IN THE
RESPONSIBILITIES THEY HAVE BEEN
GIVEN.
AS THE
END
OF THE FIRST SESSION
APPROACHES, AND MUCH
IS
LEFT
TO
BE DONE,
BESTOW UPON THEM THE
GIFTS
OF WISDOM AND DISCERNMENT
THAT IN THEIR WORDS
AND
ACTIONS
THEY WILL
DO JUSTICE, LOVE WITH
MERCY, AND
WALK HUMBLY WITH
YOU.
MAY ALL THAT
IS
DONE THIS DAY
BE FOR YOUR
GREATER HONOR AND
GLORY.
AMEN.
.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR HAS EXAMINED THE JOURNAL
OF THE LAST DAY'S PROCEEDINGS
AND ANNOUNCES TO THE HOUSE HIS
APPROVAL THEREOF.
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 1 OF RULE 1
THE JOURNAL STANDS APPROVED.
&gt;&gt; MR. SPEAKER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE GENTLEMAN
RISE?
&gt;&gt;
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 1 OF RULE
1, THE JOURNAL STANDS APPROVED.
, I DEMAND A VOTE ON THE
SPEAKER'S
APPROVAL OF THE
JOURNAL.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
QUESTION IS ON AGREEING TO THE
SPEAKER'S APPROVAL OF THE
JOURNAL.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
THE AYES
HAVE
IT.
THE JOURNAL
STANDS
APPROVED.
MR. KUCINICH:
MR. SPEAKER, I
OBJECT TO THE VOTE ON THE
GROUNDS THAT A QUORUM IS NOT
PRESENT
AND I MAKE A POINT OF
ORDER THAT A QUORUM IS NOT
PRESENT.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 8 OF RULE
20, FURTHER PROCEEDINGS ON THIS
QUESTION ARE MOST PONED.
--
ARE POSTPONED.
THE PLEDGE OF ALLEGIANCE
WILL
BE LED
BY THE GENTLEMAN FROM
OHIO, MR.
KUCINICH.
MR. KUCINICH: THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
I ASK THAT OUR COLLEAGUES AND
THOSE IN THE
AUDIENCE PLEASE
RISE AND JOIN
US
AS
WE
CELEBRATE OUR NATION.
I PLEDGE ALLEGIANCE TO THE FLAG
OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
AND TO THE REPUBLIC FOR WHICH
IT STANDS, ONE NATION UNDER
GOD, INDIVISIBLE, WITH LIBERTY
AND JUSTICE FOR ALL.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR WILL ENTERTAIN
REQUESTS
FOR ONE-MINUTE
SPEECHES.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM TEXAS RISE?
MR. POE:
I ASK PERMISSION TO
ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR ONE
MINUTE.
MR. POE:
MR. SPEAKER,
THOSE
WHO
SAY THAT THE
BORDER IS SECURE
AND THE
VIOLENCE IS
CONTAINED
IN MEXICO
ARE LIVING IN A
BLISSFUL STATE
OF IGNORANCE.
CASE IN
POINT, LAST WEEK,
ACCORDING
TO
&quot;THE
HOUSTON
CHRONICLE,&quot; THREE
S.U.V.'S
CARRYING
MEXICAN ZETA CARTEL
SOLDIERS TRIED TO
HIJACK A
TRACTOR TRUCK RIG
LOADED WITH
DRUGS ON A ROAD
IN
NORTH
HOUSTON.
THEY UNLEASHED
BLAZING
GUNFIRE,
A
SHOOTOUT OCCURRED WITH POLICE
WHO WERE
TRACKING THE TRUCK
FROM
MEXICO.
THE TRUCK
DRIVER WAS
KILLED, A
PEACE OFFICER WAS
WOUNDED.
THREE MEXICAN
NATIONALS AND
ANOTHER OF
UNKNOWN CITIZENSHIP
WERE
CHARGED WITH
CAPITAL
MURDER.
THE LOCAL HEAD OF THE
D.E.A.,
JAVIER
PENA, SAID
WE'RE NOT
GOING TO
TOLERATE THESE THUGS
USING THEIR WEAPONS LIKE THE
WILD, WILD
WEST.
SADLY, THIS
BRAZEON CASE OF
VIOLENCE
IS FAMILIAR, SEEN ON
THE STREETS OF
MEXICO.
AND NOW IT'S
BECOME A REALITY
IN THE
UNITED STATES.
UNTIL WASHINGTON
REALIZES WHAT
HAPPENS IN
MEXICO DOESN'T STAY
IN
MEXICO, MORE CARTEL
SHOOTOUTS ON AMERICAN
STREETS
ARE COMING
OUR WAY.
AND THAT'S JUST THE
WAY
IT IS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM OHIO RISE?
MR. KUCINICH: GOOD AFTERNOON,
MR. SPEAKER.
I ASK PERMISSION TO ADDRESS THE
HOUSE FOR ONE MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. KUCINICH: WELL, CONGRESS IS
IN A DEAD LOCK OVER TAX AND
SPENDING CUTS.
WE LEARN
THE
FED
SECRETLY GAVE
WALL STREET BANKS OVER
$7.7
TRILLION.
WHERE DID THE FED GET THAT
$7.7
TRILLION?
THEY CREATED MOST OF IT
FROM
NOTHING.
WELL, OUR GOVERNMENT SLID
INTO
MASSIVE
DEBT, THE FED PICKED
WINNERS AND
LOSERS AND SECRETLY
HELD BIG
BANKS
RECORD
PROFITS.
REMEMBER THE
GREAT DEBATE WE
HAD HERE, OVER
$700 BILLION IN
TARP
FUNDS?
THERE WAS NO
DEBATE OVER THE
$7.7 TRILLION THE
FED
GAVE THE
BANKS.
DID CONGRESS HAVE
A
CLUE?
THERE'S ANOTHER GAME
GOING ON
WAY OVER OUR
HEADS AND OUR
CONSTITUENTS ARE
STRUGGLING.
WELL, THE BANKS
WITH THE HELP
OF THE
FED CAPTURED CONTROLLED
CONTROL OF
OUR GOVERNMENT.
-- CAPTURED CONTROL OF
OUR
GOVERNMENT.
COULD THE THREAT OF
OUR
NATIONAL
SOVEREIGNTY BE
ANY
CLEARER?
RENEED TO
RECLAIM THE
CONSTITUTIONAL
PRIMACY.
LET'S TAKE OUR
FREEDOM BACK
FROM THE FED.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM SOUTH CAROLINA RISE?
MR. WILSON:
MR. SPEAKER, I ASK
PERMISSION TO ADDRESS THE HOUSE
FOR ONE MINUTE AND TO REVISE
AND EXTEND MY REMARKS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. WILSON:
MR. SPEAKER,
LAST
MONDAY THE JOINT
SELECT
COMMITTEE ON
DEFICIT
REDUCTION
ANNOUNCED THAT THE
BIPARTISAN
GROUP HAD
FAILED
TO REACH AN
AGREEMENT.
IN AN
OP-ED TO THE &quot;WALL STREET
JOURNAL,&quot; CONGRESSMAN
JEB
HENSARLING, CO-CHAIR OF THE
SUPERCOMMITTEE, STATED THAT THE
GROUP, QUOTE,
MISSED AN
HISTORIC OPPORTUNITY TO LIFT
THE
BURDEN OF DEBT AND HELPS
FOR ECONOMIC GROWTH AND JOB
CREATION.
END OF
QUOTE.
LAST WEEK I
ATTENDED A TOWN
HALL
MEETING IN FOREST ACRES,
SOUTH CAROLINA,
HOSTED BY MAYOR
FRANK BRUNSON
WHERE WE
DISCUSSED WAYS
TO PROMOTE
SMALL
BUSINESSES AND
ENCOURAGE JOB
GROWTH WITHIN THE
PRIVATE
SECTOR.
THE MESSAGE FROM THE
CONSTITUENTS WAS
VERY CLEAR.
CONGRESS
MUST REDUCE
WASHINGTON'S OUT-OF-CONTROL
SPENDING BEFORE IT'S TOO
LATE.
AS CONGRESS RETURNS FROM THE
THANKSGIVING DAY
RECESS,
I
ENCOURAGE MY COLLEAGUES IN THE
SENATE TO BEGIN
FOCUSING ON JOB
CREATION BY
CONSIDERING
ANY
OF
THE 20 JOB BILLS THE
HOUSE HAS
PASSED WITH
BIPARTISAN SUPPORT
THIS YEAR.
IN
CONCLUSION, GOD BLESS OUR
TROOPS SAND WE WILL
NEVER
FORGET SEPTEMBER 11 AND THE
GLOBAL WAR ON TERRORISM.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM TEXAS RISE?
MR.
BURGESS: I ASK PERMISSION
TO ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE AND TO REVISE AND EXTEND
MY REMARKS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. BURGESS: THANK YOU, MR.
SPEAKER.
IT WAS ABOUT A WEEK AGO THAT
THE JOINT SELECT
COMMITTEE
ANNOUNCED THAT THEY WERE
UNABLE
TO REACH AN
AGREEMENT
IN
FINDING
$1.2
TRILLION IN
CUTS
BEFORE THEIR
DEADLINE.
NOW, COULD
THEY HAVE DONE THIS
WITHOUT REALLY
BREAKING A
SWEAT?
THE ANSWER IS
YES,
THEY
COULD.
THE ENTIRE
TARGET FOR WHICH
THEY WERE
REACHING,
$1.2
TRILLION TO
$1.5 TRILLION COULD
HAVE BEEN CUT WITH
A SINGLE
ACT,
REPEALING THE AFFORDABLE
CARE ACT.
$1.5 TRILLION IN NEW
SPENDING
THAT THIS COUNTRY
CANNOT AFFORD
IS CONTAINED
WITHIN THE
CONFINES OF THE
AFFORDABLE CARE
ACT.
LOOK, WASHINGTON
NEEDS
TO QUIT
POINTING
FINGERS AND GET BACK
TO WORK IF
WE EXPECT TO PUT
AMERICA BACK TO
PROSPERITY.
WASHINGTON SHOULD CUT.
FAMILIES DO NOT
THE LUXURY OF
MISSING THEIR
DEADLINES AND
NEITHER
SHOULD WASHINGTON.
AMERICANS MUST
REDUCE THEIR
DEFICIT AND WE
NEED TO PUT
PEOPLE BACK TO
WORK.
THE HOUSE HAS
PASSED MORE
THAN
25 BILLS
THAT
WOULD AFFECT
EMPLOYMENT.
25 OF THESE
HOUSE-PASSED BILLS
ARE STALLED IN THE
SENATE.
YOU CAN FIND
OUT MORE ABOUT
THEM BY
GOING TO JOBS.GOP.GOV.
LET'S FOCUS ON WAYS TO
REDUCE
THE
DEFICIT.
THAT MEANS CREATING
MORE
TAXPAYERS, NOT MORE
TAXES.
I
YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM ILLINOIS RISE?
MRS. BIGGERT:
I ASK PERMISSION
TO ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE AND TO REVISE AND EXTEND
MY REMARKS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLEWOMAN
IS RECOGNIZED.
MRS. BIGGERT:
MR. SPEAKER, I
RISE
TODAY TO CONGRATULATE THE
ILLINOIS
BOWLING BROOK HIGH
SCHOOL FOOTBALL TEAM
ON WINNING
THE CLASS
8-A CHAMPIONSHIP ON
NOVEMBER
25.
THE COACH LED
THE
TEAM TO A
RECORD BREAKING
SEASON
OF 13
WINS AND
ONE
LOSS.
THIS
ACCOMPLISHMENT BY THE
RAIDERS MARKS THE
FIRST STATE
FOOTBALL
CHAMPIONSHIP FOR
BOWLING BROOK HIGH SCHOOL.
DESPITE THE ABSENCE
OF THEIR
STAR
LINEBACKER, THE
RAIDERS
OVERCAME FIVE
TURNOVERS AND WON
THE CHAMPIONSHIP GAME BY A
SCORE OF
21-17 AGAINST THE
TOP-RATED LOYOLA
ACADEMY.
EACH PLAYER
DEMONSTRATED A
TREMENDOUS LEVEL
OF
DEDICATION
AND HARD
WORK,
INCLUDING
SENIORS
ANTONIO
MORRISON AND
ROBBY
BAIN.
OTHER STARS WAS
JUNIOR AARON
BAILEY WHO SCORED
THE
GAME-WINNING TOUCHDOWN AND
SENIOR DARRYON
RHODES WHO
SEALED THE GAME WITH
AN
INTERCEPTION.
MR. SPEAKER, OUR COMMUNITY IS
VERY
PROUD
OF NIECE
ACCOMPLISHED YOUNG ATHLETES.
ONCE AGAIN,
I'D
LIKE TO
CONGRATULATE THE
BOWLING BROOK
HIGH SCHOOL RAIDERS ON THEIR
WIN
AND WISH THEM CONTINUED
SUCCESS IN ALL OF
THEIR FUTURE
ENDEAVORS.
I
YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM NORTH CAROLINA
RISE?
MS. FOXX:
I ASK PERMISSION TO
ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE,
MR. SPEAKER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEWOMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MS. FOXX: THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
THE SO-CALLED SUPERCOMMITTEE
ANNOUNCED LAST WEEK THAT
IT WAS
UNABLE TO COME UP WITH A
PLAN
TO
REDUCE THE
DEFICIT BY
$1.2
TRILLION OVER
THE EXCOURSE OF
YEARS.
THAT IS A
SAD COMMENTARY ON
WASHINGTON, D.C.'S ADDICTION TO
SPENDING.
$1.2
TRILLION IS ONE YEAR LESS
OF
OVERSPENDING AT THE GOING
RATE.
JUST CONTINUE THE
MESS
IN
EUROPE.
THE BAILOUT FUND IS
TRYING TO
KEEP DEBTOR
NATIONS LIKE
GREECE,
PORTUGAL AFLOAT WHILE
ITALY
TEETERS ON
THE BRINK OF
INSOLVENCY.
EUROPE'S SOVEREIGN DEBT
CRISIS
IS NOT
AN ABSTRACT ECONOMIC
LESSON.
IT'S DEBT
FINANCE, GOVERNMENT
PROFLIGACY.
SOME THESE
NATIONS
BATTERED BY
THE CONSEQUENCE OF
HIGH DEBT
LEVELS
HAVE DEBT TO G.D.P.
RATIOS THAT ARE CLOSE TO OUR
OWN.
IF CONGRESS DOESN'T GET SERIOUS
ABOUT
REDUCING SPENDING AND
ENDING THE FEDERAL
DEBT
ADDICTION, WE'RE GOING TO
FIND
OURSELVES IN THE SAME
BOAT AS
OUR FRIENDS
IN THE EURO ZONE.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM ILLINOIS RISE?
&gt;&gt;
I ASK PERMISSION TO ADDRESS
THE HOUSE FOR ONE MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
&gt;&gt; THANK YOU,
MR. SPEAKER.
THIS THANKSGIVING MANY OF US
HAD THE
OPPORTUNITY TO
SPEND
TIME WITH OUR
FAMILIES
AND
LOVED ONES SO
I THINK IT'S
FITTING THAT NOVEMBER IS
NATIONAL
ADOPTION MONTH.
I
ALSO THINK IT'S
APPROPRIATE
TO TAKE TIME DURING
THIS
HOLIDAY SEASON
TO RECOGNIZE THE
TENS OF
THOUSANDS
OF FAMILIES
NATIONWIDE WHO ARE FOSTER
FAMILIES.
UNFORTUNATELY IN MY HOME
STATE
OF ILLINOIS
A POTENTIAL TRAGIC
SITUATION
UNFOLDED.
FAITH-BASED ADOPTION
REAGS
ACROSS THE STATE ARE BEING
SHUT
DOWN BECAUSE OF THEIR
BELIEF
IN
TRADITIONAL
MARRIAGE.
THE ILLINOIS DEPARTMENT OF
CHILD
AND FAMILY
SERVICES HAS
DECLINED TO
RENEW
CONTRACTS
WITH SEVERAL
ORGANIZATIONS.
THEY HAVE
DECIMATED THESE
AGENCIES, SOME OF WHOSE
WORK
WAS
70% FOSTER CARE.
MR. HULTGREN:
IT'S AN
UNFORTUNATE SITUATION
AND I AM
WATCHING IT.
THE RIGHT
TO
ADOPTION IS ONE
THING
WE
REALLY MUST DEFEND.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM PENNSYLVANIA RISE?
&gt;&gt;
I ASK PERMISSION TO ADDRESS
THE HOUSE FOR ONE MINUTE AND TO
REVISE AND EXTEND.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. PITTS:
MR. SPEAKER,
LET'S
BE PERFECTLY
CLEAR, OUR TAX
POLICY AFFECTS JOB
GROWTH.
WHEN THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
RAISES
TAXES, RAISES RATES, OR
CREATES NEW
TAXES, BUSINESSES
MAKE DECISIONS
REGARDING THEIR
WORK FORCE.
WHEN THE GOVERNMENT
TAKES MORE,
BUSINESSES HAVE
TO
MAKE DUE
WITH
LESS.
ALL
TOLD,
LAST YEAR'S HEALTH
CARE
REFORM LAW WILL RAISE
TAXES BY
$800 BILLION OVER THE
NEXT 10
YEARS.
ONE OF THE NEW
TAXES IS A 2.3%
TAX ON MEDICAL
DEVICES.
MICHIGAN-BASED
MANUFACTURE
STRYKER ANNOUNCED
THAT
THEY
WILL
REDORS THEIR WORK FORCE BY
5% SO THEY WILL BE
PREPARED TO
PAY THIS NEW
TAX BEGINNING IN
2013.
STRYKER IS JUST ONE
OF THE
FIRST TO
ANNOUNCE REDUCTIONS
AND
LAYOFFS.
MEDICAL DEVICE
COMPANIES WILL
BE FACED
WITH
DIFFICULT
DECISIONS
ABOUT WHERE THEY WILL
CUT IN ORDER
TO PAY THIS
MASSIVE NEW TAX
BILL.
MANY WILL HAVE
NO
CHOICE BUT TO
REDUCE THE WORK
FORCE.
WE DON'T NEED
A HEALTH REFORM
LAW THAT
DESTROYS
A PLUS.
WE NEED ONE
THAT
ENCOURAGES THE
CREATION OF GOOD JOBS
WITH GOOD
BENEFITS.
WE MUST
REPEAL THE
SO-CALLED
AFFORDABLE CARE ACT.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 12-A OF RULE
1, THE CHAIR DECLARES THE HOUSE
IN RECESS
UNTIL APPROXIMATELY
4:00 P.M. TODAY.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
HOUSE WILL BE IN ORDER.
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 8 OF RULE
20, THE CHAIR WILL POSTPONE
FURTHER PROCEEDINGS TODAY ON
MOTIONS TO SUSPEND THE
RULES
ON
WHICH A
RECORDED
VOTE OR THE
YEAS AND NAYS ARE
ORDERED.
OR
ON WHICH THE VOTE INCURS AN
OBJECTION UNDER CLAUSE 6 OF
RULE
20.
RECORD VOTES
ON POSTPONED
QUESTIONS WILL BE TAKEN AFTER
6:30 P.M.
TODAY.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM UTAH SEEK
RECOGNITION?
MR. CHAFFETZ: MR. SPEAKER, I
MOVE THAT THE HOUSE
SUSPEND THE
RULES AND PASS H.R.
3012, THE
FAIRNESS FOR HIGH
SKILLED
IMMIGRANTS ACT OF
2012 AS
AMENDED.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CLERK WILL REPORT THE TITLE OF
THE BILL.
THE CLERK: UNION CALENDAR
NUMBER 193, H.R.
3012, A
BILL
TO AMEND THE IMMIGRATION AND
NATIONALITY ACT TO ELIMINATE
THE PER COUNTRY NUMERICAL
LIMITATION FOR EMPLOYMENT-BASED
IMMIGRANTS, TO INCREASE THE PER
COUNTRY NUMERICAL LIMITATION
FOR FAMILY-SPONSORED
IMMIGRANTS, AND FOR OTHER
PURPOSES.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
PURSUANT TO THE RULE, THE
GENTLEMAN FROM UTAH, MR.
CHAFFETZ, AND THE GENTLEMAN
FROM TENNESSEE, MR.
COHEN, EACH
WILL CONTROL 20 MINUTES.
THE CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM UTAH.
MR. CHAFFETZ: MR. SPEAKER, I
ASK
UNANIMOUS CONSENT THAT ALL
MEMBERS MAY HAVE FIVE
LEGISLATIVE DAYS TO REVISE AND
EXTEND THEIR REMARKS
AND
INCLUDE
EXTRANEOUS MATERIALS ON
H.R.
3012, AS
AMENDED,
CURRENTLY UNDER
CONSIDERATION.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION.
MR. CHAFFETZ: THANK YOU.
I YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME AS I
MAY CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. CHAFFETZ: I RISE IN SUPPORT
OF H.R.
3012, THE
FAIRNESS FOR
HIGH SKILLED
IMMIGRANTS ACT.
I'D FIRST LIKE
TO THANK
CHAIRMAN SMITH FOR
HIS
WORK AND
DILIGENCE AND COMMITMENT ON
THIS ISSUE.
WE WOULDN'T BE HERE
TODAY
WITHOUT HIS EFFORTS
AND HIS
COMMITMENT TO
THIS.
I WANT
TO THANK
RANKING MEMBER
CONYERS AND
THE IMMIGRATION
SUBCOMMITTEE RANKING MEMBER
ZOE
LOFGREN.
SHE HAS BEEN INSTRUMENTAL IN
PUTTING THIS BILL
TOGETHER
TO
MAKE IT SOMETHING
THAT WE
HOPE
WOULD PASS
TODAY.
AND HER
WORK ON
THE JUDICIARY
COMMITTEE.
THE
IMMIGRATION
AND NATIONALITY
ACT PROVIDES
THAT THE TOTAL
NUMBER OF
VISAS MADE AVAILABLE
TO NATIVES
CANNOT EXCEED 7% OF
THE TOTAL NUMBER
OF
SUCH VISAS
MADE
AVAILABLE IN THAT YEAR.
THE BILL
COMPLETELY
ELIMINATES
THE
PER-COUNTRY CAPS FROM
EMPLOYMENT VISAS AND
RAISES THE
PER-COUNTRY CAP FROM
7% TO 15%
FOR
FAMILY-BASED VISAS ALL
WITHOUT ADDING
A SINGLE
ADDITIONAL VISA.
IN OTHER WORDS, THERE IS NO
NET
INCREASE IN THE TOTAL NUMBER OF
VISAS.
AND WHAT I WANT
MEMBERS ON
BOTH
SIDES OF THE
AISLE TO
UNDERSTAND OR RECOGNIZE IS
THERE IS NOT A
NET
INCREASE IN
THE
TOTAL
NUMBER OF
VISAS.
BUT IT
DOES MAKE IMPORTANT
ADJUSTMENTS THAT
WILL ALLOW US
TO
BETTER SERVICE AND FIX LEGAL
IMMIGRATION WHICH IS ONE OF THE
COMMITMENTS I HAVE IN
WORKING
IN THIS
CONGRESS.
WHILE PER COUNTRY
LIMITS MAKES
SOME
LIMITED SENSE IN THE AREA
OF FAMILY
IMMIGRATION, THEY
MAKE NO
SENSE IN
EMPLOYMENT-BASED
IMMIGRATION.
AMERICAN COMPANIES TREAT ALL
HIGH-SKILLED IMMIGRANTS EQUALLY
REGARDLESS OF WHERE THEY COME
FROM.
OUR IMMIGRATION POLICY SHOULD
DO THE SAME
THING.
H.R.
3012 CREATES A FAIR AND
EQUITYIBLE FIRST
COME FIRST
SERVE
SYSTEM.
AMERICAN COMPANIES
WILL DO WHAT
THEY DO BEST,
HIRING SMART
PEOPLE TO CREATE
JOBS FOR
AMERICANS.
PER COUNTRY CAPS
ARE THE AN TIT
CISOF THE FREE
SH -- AN THEICIS
OF THE FREE
COUNTRY.
IT IS THE
PRIMARY
OBJECTIVE OF
AMERICAN
COMPANIES.
THIS BILL WILL
MAKE SURE THAT
EMPLOYERS MEET THAT
OBJECTIVE.
FEARS THAT THIS WILL
LEAD
TO
CHEAP LABOR IS
UNFOUNDED.
IT
RELIES ON THE FALSE
ASSUMPTION THAT THE
REMOVAL
OF
THESE CAPS WILL HAVE A
NEGATIVE
IMPACT ON
AMERICAN
WORKERS.
FIRST, IT
REMOVES THE
EMPLOYMENT-BASED
VISAS.
SOME ARGUE
THAT THIS WILL
REPLACE IT
WITH CHEAP FOREIGN
LABOR WHICH CANNOT AND
WILL NOT
HAPPEN.
CURRENT LAW
PROHIBITS U.S.
EMPLOYERS FROM HIRING
FOREIGN
WORKERS TO
FILL THESE JOBS
UNLESS THERE
IS
INSUFFICIENT
U.S.
WORKERS WHO ARE WILLING,
ABLED,
QUALIFIED AND AVAILABLE.
THIS BILL DOES NOT
CHANGE THIS
REQUIREMENT BUT IT
DOES
ENCOURAGE
HIGH-SKILLED
IMMIGRANTS TO STAY
AND HELP
BUILD OUR ECONOMY
RATHER THAN
USING THE
SKILLS THEY USE HERE.
THE SECOND
CRITICISM
I HEAR
APPLIES
TO THE PROVISION THAT
RAISES
THE FAMILY-BASED PER
COUNTRY BASE FROM
7% TO 15%.
THEY FEAR IT
WILL BE A BURDEN
TO OUR SYSTEM.
TO THE CONTRARY.
THOSE WHO
BENEFIT MOST
UNDER
THE FAMILY
CAP ADJUSTMENT ARE
LAW-ABIDING WORKERS
WHO
DEMONSTRATED THEIR RESPECT FOR
THE RULE
OF
LAW BY
WAITING IN
LINE FOR MANY YEARS
IF NOT
DECADES.
AN
UNMARRIED MINOR CHILD IN
MEXICO WHOSE SON OR
DAUGHTER OF
A U.S. CITIZEN
WILL RECEIVE
A
GREEN CARD IN NOVEMBER OF
THIS
YEAR HAS BEEN
WAITING
IN LINE
SINCE APRIL,
1993.
THAT'S AN
18 1/2-YEAR WAIT.
REGARDLESS -- REWARDING
THOSE
WHO
ARE
PATIENTLY
WAITING TO
COME TO THIS COUNTRY LEGALLY
WILL
INCENTIVIZE MORE PEOPLE
TO
ENTER OUR
COUNTRY LEGALLY
THROUGH THE MEANS
THAT WE HAVE
SET
FORTH.
THIS BILL DOES NOT
ADD
A SINGLE
NEW GREEN
CARD
TO THE SYSTEM.
THERE'S
NO TRICK OR COMPROMISE
INVOLVED.
WE ARE SENDING A
MESSAGE
THAT
WE WANT
PEOPLE TO
COME TO
AMERICA LEGALLY AND
WE ARE
SENDING THAT MESSAGE WITHOUT
MASSIVE COMPREHENSIVE
REFORMS.
THIS IS A
SIMPLE,
STRAIGHTFORWARD AND CONSISTENT
WITH WHAT I
THINK MOST MEMBERS
FROM BOTH
SIDES OF THE AISLE
STAND ON THE ISSUE
OF
IMMIGRATION.
THIS LEGISLATION IS PRO-GROWTH,
IT'S
PRO-JOBS, AND IT'S
PRO-FAMILY.
I'D LIKE TO
THANK THE COMPETE
AMERICA AND
IMMIGRATION VOICE
FOR THEIR FIRELESS
EFFORTS IN
HELPING TO GET THIS BILL
PASSED
AND I THANK
CHAIRMAN SMITH,
RANKING MEMBER
CONYERS, AND MS.
LOFGREN FOR THEIR WORK IN
HELPING TO BRING THIS BILL
FORWARD.
AT THIS
TIME
I'D ALSO -- I'D
ASK UNANIMOUS CONSENT
-- I'LL
WITHDRAW THAT FOR A
SECOND.
I RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN RESERVES THE BALANCE
OF HIS TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM TENNESSEE.
MR.
COHEN: THANK YOU.
I ALSO RISE IN
SUPPORT OF THIS
BIPARTISAN
PROPOSAL
THAT
PROVIDES
TWO SMALL TECHNICAL
FIXES TO OUR
COUNTRY'S
IMMIGRATION LAWS.
I TAKE THE BALANCE
OF THE TIME
THAT I HAVE
ALLOTTED TO ME TO
MAKE THIS STATEMENT.
THE BILL
REMOVES THE SO-CALLED
PER COUNTRY LIMITS
FROM
APPLYING TO
EMPLOYMENT-BASED
GREEN CARDS.
CURRENT IMMIGRATION
LAW
PROVIDES
140,000 GREEN CARDS
ANNUALLY TO EMPLOY
-BASED
IMMIGRANTS.
THEY
DO NOT PERMIT 7% OF THE
140,000 VEES RAYS.
BECAUSE OF THIS
PER COUNTRY
LIMIT A COUNTRY
LIKE INDIA WITH
A POPULATION
OF
1.2 BILLION IS
LIMITED TO THE SAME NUMBER
OF
VISAS TO A
COUNTRY LIKE ICELAND
WITH THE POPULATION OF
300,000
AND A LOT
OF
ICE.
THIS MAKES
NO SENSE.
AND HAS
RESULTED IN A DECADES'
LONG BACKLOG FROM NATIONALS
OF
INDIA AND CHINA
AND
MAKES IT
IMPOSSIBLE FOR CERTAIN U.S.
EMPLOYERS
TO
RETRACT AND RETAIN
CERTAIN ESSENTIAL
WORKERS THAT
HELPS TO KEEP
AMERICA
COMPETITIVE INDEED
FROM CHINA
AND INDIA.
THERE ARE MANY PEOPLE
TRAINED
IN STEM
AREAS THAT WE
NEED
TO
KEEP OUR
COUNTRY
COMPETITIVE.
ELIMINATING
THE PER COUNTRY
BASE WOULD TREAT EVERYONE ON
A
FIRST
COME FIRST SERVE BASIS.
BECAUSE THE BILL DOES
NOT
PROVIDE ADDITIONAL GREEN
CARDS
IT DOES
NOT
ADDRESS THE OVERALL
BACKLOG.
IT TREATS THOSE
PEOPLE
MORE
EQUITABLELY.
AND
THERE IS
NO
UNINTENDED
CONSEQUENCE, THIS SFAZED IN
SLOWLY OVER THREE YEARS.
THE BILL ALSO
RAISES THE
COUNTRY LIMIT FOR
FAMILY-BASED
IMMIGRANTS FROM
7% TO 15%.
THIS WOULD HAVE A
SIMILAR
EFFECT OF
MAKING THE TREATMENT
SUCH IMMIGRANTS
MORE
EQUITABLE.
THESE FIXES ARE
SMALL
BUT THEY
MEAN A GREAT DEAL
TO THE PEOPLE
THAT THEY
DO HELP.
H.R.
3012 IS SUPPORTED BY QUITE
A
FEW BUSINESS GROUPS
INCLUDING
THE UNITED STATES CHAMBER OF
COMMERCE, COMPETE AMERICA
AND
THE AMERICAN COUNCIL
ON
INTERNATIONAL
PERSONNEL.
AND THE
SUPPORTER
FOR ADVOCATES
OF
AMERICAN AND
IMMIGRANT
FAMILIES INCLUDING THE
ASIAN
AMERICAN
JUSTICE CENTER
AND
NATIONAL
IMMIGRATION LAW
CENTER.
I, LIKE MY
COLLEAGUE ON THE
OTHER SIDE,
WANT TO THANK THE
PEOPLE WHO WERE ABOVE
ME ON THE
COMMITTEE LEVEL, THE
CHAIRMAN
IN
PARTICULAR,
CHAIRMAN
SMITH,
AND RANKING MEMBER OF OUR
SUBCOMMITTEE,
ZOE LOFGREN, WHO
HAS
WORKED WITH CONGRESSMAN
CHAFFETZ WHO WORKED SO
HARD ON
THIS BILL AND
COMMARME SMITH TO
GET THIS
BIPARTISAN BILL --
CHAIRMAN SMITH TO GET THIS
BIPARTISAN BILL THROUGH THE
COMMITTEE AND TO THE FLOOR.
IT'S
IMPORTANT WE GET
BIPARTISAN BILLS THROUGH.
AND BECAUSE OF OUR
CHAIRMAN WE
HAVE THAT OPPORTUNITY TO DO
IT
ON OCCASION TO DO
SUCH A
THING.
I ASK MY COLLEAGUES TO
SUPPORT
THIS IMPORTANT LEGISLATION AND
I
RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN RESERVES THE BALANCE
OF HIS TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM UTAH IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. CHAFFETZ: I NOW WANT TO
RECOGNIZE THE
CHAIRMAN OF OUR
COMMITTEE, CHAIRMAN LAMAR
SMITH
OF
TEXAS,
AND YIELD TO HIM SUCH
TIME AS HE
MAY
CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM TEXAS IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. SMITH: I THANK
THE
GENTLEMAN FOR YIELDING ME TIME
AND THANK HIM FOR
THE
SPONSORSHIP OF THIS
LEGISLATION.
.
THIS BILL
INTRODUCED BY
CONGRESSMAN CHAFFETZ DOES
JUST
THAT AND I AM
HAPPY
TO BE A
CO-SPONSOR.
THE
IMMIGRATION NATIONALITY ACT
GENERALLY PROVIDES THE TOTAL
NUMBER OF FAMILIES
SPONSORED IN
EMPLOYER
SPONSORED GREEN CARDS
NATIVE TO
ANY ONE COUNTRY
CANNOT EXCEED
7% OF THE TOTAL
NUMBER OF
GREEN CARDS AVAILABLE
EACH YEAR.
.
BECAUSE OF
THESE CAPS ON GREEN
CARDS AND
BECAUSE SOME
COUNTRIES HAVE MORE
SKILLED
WORKERS THAT AMERICAN
EMPLOYERS
WANT,
NATIVES OF THESE
COUNTRIES MUST
WAIT YEARS
LONGER THAN OTHER
COUNTRIES.
FOR FOREIGN
PROFESSIONALS OF
ADVANCED
DEGREES, GREEN
CARDS
ARE IMMEDIATELY
AVAILABLE TO
APPROVED APLY CAPTS FROM MOST
CUPRIES.
BECAUSE EMPLOYERS
SEEK SO MANY
EMPLOYEES FROM INDIA AND
CHINA,
THE PER
COUNTRY CAPS RESULT IN
GREEN
CARDS ONLY BEING
AVAILABLE TO THESE THESE
INDIVIDUALS WHO
APPLIED BEFORE
NOVEMBER OF
2007, FOUR YEARS
AGO.
GREEN
CARDS ARE NOW
AVAILABLE
TOOPLY CANTS
FROM MOST
COUNTRIES WHO
APPLIED ON OR
BEFORE SEPTEMBER OF
2005.
BUT BECAUSE
EMPLOYERS SEEK TO
MANY -- SO
MANY WORKERS, THE
PER
COUNTRY CAP RESULT IN GREEN
CARDS ONLY BEING
AVAILABLE TO
THOSE FROM
CHINA WHO APPLIED
BEFORE 2004 AND
FROM INDIA
BEFORE
2002.
SIMILAR
PROBLEMS EXIST IN THE
FAMILY
GREEN CARDS.
THAT'S WHY
NATIVES ONLY GET
GREEN
CARDS IF THEY FIRST
APPLIED
BEFORE JUNE, 2000, 11
YEARS
AGO.
PEOPLE FROM
THE PHILIPPINES
HAVE HAD
TO WAIT UNTIL -- WAIT
SINCE 1998.
THIS BILL WILL
DO AWAY WITH THE
CAP
ENTIRELY BY 2015 AND RAISES
THE
FAMILY-SPONSORED PER
COUNTRY CAP FROM
7% TO 15% THIS
LEGISLATION MAKES
SENSE.
WHY SHOULD MERP
EMPLOYERS WHO
SEEK GREEN
CARDS FOR SKILLED
FOREIGN
WORKERS HAVE TO WAIT
LONGER BECAUSE THE
WORKERS ARE
FROM INDIA OR
CHINA.
AMERICAN BUSINESS
EMPLOYERS
HAVE ALREADY
PROVED TO THE U.S.
GOVERNMENT THEY NEED
THESE
WORKERS THAT
QUALIFIED
AMERICANS ARE NOT
AVAILABLE AND
THAT
AMERICAN WORKERS WILL NOT
BE
HARMED.
IT MAKES
SENSE TO REPEAL THE
EMPLOYMENT-BASED PER
COUNTRY
CAPS.
I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO SUPPORT
H.R. 3012 AND
BEFORE I YIELD
BACK THE
BALANCE OF MY
TIME
AGAIN,
I WANT TO THANK THE
GENTLEMAN FROM UTAH
FOR
SPONSORING THIS LEGISLATION.
MR. CHAFFETZ:
I RESERVE.
SPERO: THE GENTLEMAN
FROM
TENNESSEE.
MR.
CO---
&gt;&gt; I YIELD TWO
MINUTES TO THE
GENTLEMAN, MR. MORAN.
MR. MORAN: THANK YOU.
MR. SPEAKER,
I'M A CO-SPONSOR
OF THIS BIPARTISAN
LEGISLATION
AND I WANT TO
SPEAK ON ITS
BEHALF.
I WAS
-- I HEARD ABOUT A
CONVERSATION THAT
BILL CLINTON
HAD
WITH STEVE JOBS.
THE APPLE
COMPUTER HAS ABOUT
200,000 EMPLOYEES
OUTSIDE OF
THE
BORDERS OF THE UNITED
STATES.
--
OF THE UNITED STATES, I
UNDERSTAND.
AND I BELIEVE
IT'S WALTER
ISAACSON IN HIS
BIOGRAPHY OF
STEVE
JOBS TALKS ABOUT A
CONVERSATION HE HAD
WITH
PRESIDENT
CLINTON WHO ASKED,
WHAT WOULD IT
TAKE TO GOAT
THESE
EMPLOYEES BACK IN THE
UNITED STATES.
STEVE JOBS SAID, GIVE
ME 30,000
HIGHLY SKILLED
WORKERS IN THE
UNITED STATES AND
WE'LL GET
THOSE
JOBS BACK.
THAT'S WHAT
THIS IS ABOUT.
IT'S
HAVING ACCESS WITHIN THE
UNITED STATES TO THE
MOST
HIGHLY
SKILLED ENGINEERS,
SCIENTISTS,
MATHEMATICIANS THAT
WILL IN TURN GENERATE
THE KIND
OF
ECONOMIC ACTIVITY THAT WE
ALL WANT
IN TERMS OF JOB
CREATION AND NATIONAL ECONOMIC
GROWTH.
NOW, IN THE
NORTHERN VIRGINIA
AREA, WE'RE VERY FORTUNATE.
WE HAVE A STRONG
HIGH TECH
SECTOR.
BUT FOR THAT TECH
SECTOR TO
CONTINUE TO
GROW AND
EXPAND, WE
HAVE GOT TO HAVE
A WORK FORCE
NOT ONLY ADEQUATE
IN TERMS OF
QUANTITY BUT
PARTICULARLY IN
TERMS OF
QUANTITY -- IN TERMS
OF
QUALITYITY.
WE KNOW -- QUALITY.
WE
KNOW HOW IMPORTANT TECH
FIRMS WILL BE IN THE
GLOBAL
ECONOMY
OF THE 21ST CENTURY BUT
I DON'T THINK WE
FULLY TAKE
INTO ACCOUNT HOW IMPORTANT
THIS
KIND OF
LEGISLATION IS WHERE WE
CAN
CONTINUE TO ATTRACT THE
BEST AND
BRIGHTEST FROM AROUND
THE WORLD.
WHO,
IN FACT, DO WANT TO GO TO
GRADUATE
SCHOOL HERE AND DO
WANT
TO CONTINUE RESIDING IN
THE UNITED STATES
AND TO WORK
HERE,
APPLYING THEIR TALENTS
AND SKILLS.
NOW,
UNDER CURRENT LAW,
EMPLOYMENT-BASED AND
FAMILY
SPONSORED
IMMIGRANT VISAS CAN'T
EXCEED 7%
OF THE TOTAL OF THOSE
VISAS MADE AVAILABLE THAT
YEAR.
THAT CAP
HINDERS THE ABILITY TO
HAVE HIGH TECH
FIRMS IN THE
UNITED STATES
TO HIRE
THE TOP
TALENT
FROM COUNTRIES LIKE
INDIA AND
CHINA, WHO HAVE A
DISPROPORTIONATELY LARGE NUMBER
OF INDIVIDUALS WITH THE
EDUCATION AND EXPERIENCE SOUGHT
AFTER BY MANY OF
THESE
TECHNOLOGY
COMPANIES.
IT DOESN'T
MAKE SENSE TO
CONTINUE ENFORCING
OUTDATED,
ARBITRARY
CAPS THAT MAKE IT
HARDER FOR
COUNTRIES TO HIRE
EMPLOYEES THAT THEY NEED
AND WE
NEED TO
GROW AND PROSPER WITHIN
THE UNITED STATES.
THIS LEGISLATION ELIMINATES
PER
COUNTRY
LIMITS ON THE ALLOTMENT
OF
HIGH-SKILLED GREEN CARDS
WITHOUT ADDING A
SINGLE
ADDITIONAL
GREEN CARD TO THE
SYSTEM
AND INCREASES PER
COUNTRY LIMITS FROM
7% TO 15%,
MORE THAN
DOUBLES, IN THE
FAMILY-BASED
IMMIGRATION
SYSTEM,
REDUCING SUBSTANTIAL
BACK
LOGS IN THE
FAMILY-BASED
SYSTEM AS WELL.
IT DOESN'T
ADD ANY VISAS BUT
MORE RATIONALLY
DISTRIBUTES THE
ALLOTMENT READILY
AVAILABLE.
MR. COHEN: I YIELD
THE
GENTLEMAN SUCH TIME
HEAS
MAY
CONSUME AN NEEDS.
MR. MORAN:
I'LL TRY TO BE
JUDICIOUS IN USING THAT
TIME.
I THANK MY
GOOD FRIEND FROM
MEMPHIS FOR
YIELDING ME THE
TIME.
THIS LEGISLATION
IS MODEST IN
SCOPE.
BUT IT IS VERY
IMPORTANT
BECAUSE IT
-- IT PUT THIS IS
COUNTRY IN THE RIGHT
DIRECTION
OF ECONOMIC GROWTH.
NOW, I WANT TO
SAY, I WISH WE
WOULD SET OUT
AMBITIONS HIRING
-- AMBITIOUS
HIRING IN THE
WHOLE AREA
OF IMMIGRATION, OUR
IMMIGRATION
SYSTEM IS
BROKEN
AND NEEDS
A COMPLETE OVERHAUL.
WE NEED IT
TO ESTABLISH A PATH
TO
LEGALIZATION FOR THOSE
CURRENTLY IN THE
COUNTRY AND
ADDRESS OTHER PROBLEMS BUT
MAYBE WE
CAN USE THIS TO
ADDRESS
THE BROAD BENEFITS TO
THE
COUNTRY THAT WOULD ACCRUE
BY
IMPROVING THE IMMIGRATION
SYSTEM.
REGARDLESS OF WHETHER
WE CAN
GET THE
MORE AMBITIOUS
LEGISLATION,
THE BILL BEFORE US
TODAY FIXES A REAL
PROBLEM THAT
HARMS
OUR NATION'S
COMPETITIVENESS.
THAT'S WHY IT HAS BIPARTISAN
SUPPORT.
THAT'S WHY IT'S THE RIGHT THING
TO
DO.
I THINK
IT'S TERRIBLY IMPORTANT
FOR THE AREA
OF OUR ECONOMY
WHICH IS
GOING TO PRODUCE THE
MOST JOBS
IN THE FUTURE, THE
MOST
COMPETITIVE JOB WITH THE
HIGHEST
PROFIT MARGINS, THIS
THAT
WE CAN THEN SELL TO THE
REST OF THE WORLD.
SO
MR. SPEAKER, I CONGRATULATE
THE
SPONSORS OF THIS
LEGISLATION AND WOULD HOPE THAT
WE
WOULD GET UNANIMOUS SUPPORT
FOR IT.
THANK YOU, MR. SPEAKER.
MY
TIME IS UNDER THE CONTROL OF
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM TENNESSEE.
MR. COHEN: I YIELD
BACK
THE
BALANCE OF OUR TILE.
SPERO: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
UTAH.
MR. CHAFFETZ: WE HAVE
NO
ADDITIONAL
SPEAKERS.
I THANK CHAIRMAN SMITH AND
I
WANT TO RECOGNIZE
THE GOOD WORK
AND
WORKING RELATIONSHIP I HAVE
WITH MS. LOFGREN OF
CALIFORNIA
AND LUIS
GUTIERREZ, I THINK IT
DOES DEMONSTRATE
THAT WE CAN
WORK IN A
BIPARTISAN WAY TO
PASS
LEGISLATION THAT WILL HAVE
AN
IMPORTANT EFFECT ON
BUSINESSES, JOBS, THE
ECONOMY
AND A LOT OF
FAMILIES.
I
URGE SUPPORT OF 3012 AND
YIELD BACK
THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
SPERO: THE QUESTION
IS, WILL
THE HOUSE SUSPEND THE RULES AND
PASS 46R789 R.
3012 AS AMENDED?
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
IN THE OPINION
OF THE CHAIR --
&gt;&gt; I OBJECT TO THE VOTE
ON THE
GROUNDS THAT A
QUORUM IS NOT
PRESENT AND RAISE A
POINT OF
ORDER THAT A
QUORUM IS NOT
PRESENT.
SPERO: PURSUANT
TO CLAUSE 8 OF
RULE 20,
FURTHER PROCEEDINGS ON
THIS QUESTION WILL BE
POSTPONED.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE
GENTLEMAN SEEK
RECOGNITION?
MR. CHAFFETZ: I
MOVE HAT HOUSE
SUSPEND THE RULES.
SPERO:
-- THE SPEAKER
PRO
TEMPORE: THE CLERK
WILL REPORT
THE BILL.
THE CLERK:
QUALIFYING MEMBERS
OF
THE RESERVE COMPONENTS OF
THE ARMED
FORCES AND MEMBERS OF
THE NATIONAL GUARD
WHO, AFTER
SEVENTH,
2001, ARE CALLED TO
ACTIVE DUTY OR TO
PERFORM A
HOMELAND DEFENSE
ACTIVITY FOR
NOT LESS
THAN 90 DAYS.
THE
SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
UTAH, MR.
CHAFFETZ,
AND THE GENTLEMAN
FROM
TENNESSEE, MR.
COHEN, EACH
WILL
CONTROL 20 MINUTES.
THE CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
UTAH.
MR. CHAFFETZ: I ASK UNANIMOUS
CONSENT THAT ALL
MEMBERS HAVE
FIVE
LEGISLATIVE DAYS TO REVISE
AND EXTEND THEIR
REMARKS AND
INCLUDE
EXTRANEOUS MATERIAL ON
H.R. 2192.
THE SPEAKER
PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION.
THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. CHAFFETZ: BEFORE
US TODAY
IS AN
IMPORTANT BILL SPONSORED
BY MY COLLEAGUE, MR.
COHEN, AN
MR. FORBES OF
VIRGINIA.
ON
SEPTEMBER 11, 2001,
ANNIVERSARIES, WE PAUSE
TO
HONOR THE VIMS
WHO PERISHED
THAT
2R57B8GIC DAY AND WE ARE
REMINDED OF THE BRAVERY
OF
MILITARY
PERSONNEL AND THANK
MILL FAIR ALMOST I
-- FAMILIES
FOR
THEIR SACRIFICE.
THE LAST
10 YEARS HAVE BEEN
HARD OF
-- ON OUR MEMBERS OF
THE MILITARY AND NATIONAL
GUARD.
ABOUT ONE MILLION
GUARDSMEN
HAVE BEEN
DEPLOYED OVER THE
LAST 10 YEARS,
AND WE ARE
GRATEFUL.
THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT HAS
RESPONSIBILITY TO EASE THEIR
RETURN TO
CIVILIAN LIFE FROM
WAR.
MANY RETURN HOME WITH PHYSICAL
HANDICAPS, FOR MANY
OTHERS,
PSYCHOLOGICAL
CHALLENGES FACE
THEM
AND THEIR FAMILIES.
SOME
HAVE SUFFERED FINANCIAL
HARDSHIPS
AND FREQUENTLY
BANKRUPTCY
IS UNFORTUNATELY THE
LAST RESORT.
IN
A CHAPTER 7
BANKRUPTCY A
DEBTOR SURRENDERS
VIRTUALLY ALL
THEIR ASSETS
AND RECEIVES A
DISCHARGE AT THE
END OF THE
SHORT CASE.
IN CONTRAST IN
A CHAPTER 13
CASE, A
DEBTOR RETAIN THEIRS
ASSETS
BUT MUST COMMIT THEIR
DISPOSABLE INCOME TO
REPAYMENT
OF
THEIR CREDITORS BEFORE
RECEIVING A DISCHARGE IF
THEIR
DEBTS.
IN 2005, CONGRESS
ENACTED THE
BANKRUPTCY
ABUSE PROTECTION AND
CONSUMER
PROTECTION ACT, OFTEN
REFERRED TO
AS BAPCPA.
BAPCPA
TO -- THROUGH THIS LAW,
CONGRESS
INSERTED INTO THE CODE
A WAY
TO DETERMINE IF A
DEBTOR
HAS
DISPOSABLE INCOME TO BE
USED TO PAY THEIR
DEBTS.
IT'S
COMMONLY REFERRED TO AS
THE
MEANS TEST.
IF
A DEBTOR IS ABLE TO PAY SOME
PORTION OF
THEIR DEBTS, THEN
THEIR FILING OF A
CHAPTER 7
BANKRUPTCY
IS PRESUMED TO BE AN
ABUSE OF THE
SYSTEM.
THE
DEBTOR REMAINS ELIGIBLE FOR
RELIEF UNDER OTHER
BANKRUPTCY
CHAPTERS,
INCLUDING CHAPTER 13,
WHERE THEY CAN
RESTRUCTURE HOW
THEY PAY THEIR
DEBTS.
IN
2008, CONGRESS RECOGNIZED
THAT
MILITARY RESERVISTS AND
NATIONAL
GUARDSMEN SUFFER
UNIQUE
FINANCIAL PROBLEMS AND
ENACTED THE MILITARY
DEBT
RELIEF ACT,
SIGNED INTO LAW IN
2008.
THAT ALLOWS
SERVICE AND
NATIONAL
GUARDSMEN TO BYPASS
THE MEANS
TEST.
WHEN THEY
RETURN FROM THE FRONT
LINES OF WAR,
THEY HAVE ENDURED
ENOUGH.
THEY DO NOT NEED TO ALSO
SUFFER
A
PRESUMPTION OF BANKRUPTCY
ABUSE IF THEY ARE IN
NEED OF A
QUICK,
FRESH START IN
BANKRUPTCY
THAT ACT
EXPIRES IN
DECEMBER OF THIS YEAR.
H.R.
2192, WHICH MR. COHEN AND
MR.
FORBES INTRODUCED, EXTENDS
THE
SUNSET DATE OF THE ACT THAT
WAS PASSED IN 2008.
AMERICA IS STILL A NATION
AT
WAR AND WE
CONTINUE TO CALL ON
OUR GUARDSMEN
AND RESERVISTS TO
PERFORM
HEROIC TASKS.
WE SHOULD NOT MAKE LIFE
MORE
DIFFICULT
BY ALLOWING MEANS
TEST
EXEMPTIONS TO LAPSE.
THE BILL
EXTENDS THE
SUNSET
DATE BY FOUR
YEARS, AT WHICH
TIME, CONGRESS WILL HAVE THE
OPPORTUNITY
TO RE-EXAMINE
WHETHER THIS
MEANS
TEST
CARVEOUT HAS
SERVED ITS PURPOSE
AND
WHETHER IT IS NEEDED ANY
LONGER.
I WANT TO THANK
AGAIN MR. COHEN
AND MR.
FORBES FOR INTRODUCING
THIS
LEGISLATION.
I
ENCOURAGE MY COLLEAGUES TO
VOTE YES ON THE
BILL.
AT THIS
TIME, I RESERVE THE
BALANCE OF
MY TIME.
SPERO:
THE GENTLEMAN -- THE
SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THANK YOU,
MR. SPEAKER.
I YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME
AS I
MAY CONSUME.
MR. COHEN:
I YIELD MYSELF
SUCH
TIME AS
I MAY CONSUME.
24 BIPARTISAN
LEGISLATION I
INTRODUCED IN JUNE OF
THIS YEAR
WITH MR.
FORBES, MR.
ROHRABACHER
AND
OTHERS, ENSURES
THAT MEMBERS OF THE
NATIONAL
GUARD AND SERVICE --
ARMED
FORCES
WILL BE ABLE TO OBTAIN
BANKRUPTCY
RELIEF WITHOUT FILL
OUGHT
THE SUBSTANTIAL PAPERWORK
REQUIRED BY THE
MEANS TEST.
H.R.
2192 EXTENDS THE EXISTING
MEANS TEST
EXCEPTION WHICH WILL
EXPIRE
IN A
FEW WEEKS IF
CONGRESS FAILS TO
ACT, AND ACT
WE SHOULD FOR
OUR SERVICE AND
NATIONAL
GUARDS PEOPLE WHO HAVE
RISKED THEIR LIFE
FOR OUR
SAFETY.
FILING
CHAPTER SEVEN BANKRUPTCY
IS CONSIDERED
AN ABUSE OF THE
BANKRUPTCY LAW
.
THIS WILL
APPLY TO THOSE WHO
SERVE
ON ACTIVE DUTY FOR 90
TAIS AND
REMAINS IN EFFECT FOR
DAYS AFTER THEY LEAVE THE
MILITARY.
THE DEBT
RELIEF EXTENSION ACT
WOULD
EXTEND THE EXCEPTION
UNTIL
DECEMBER, 2015.
THIS MODEST BUT
IMPORTANT
EXCEPTION
ALLOWS QUALIFYING
MEMBERS OF THE DWARD
AND
RESERVES TO OBTAIN BANKRUPTCY
RELIEF WITHOUT
FULFILLING THE
MEANS
TEST PAPERWORK
REQUIREMENTS.
.
MORE
THAN MANY
SERVING MULTLE
TOURS OF
DUTY, THEY MADE UP 43%
OF U.S.
FORCES SERVING IN IRAQ
AND
AFGHANISTAN AND
REPRESENT
MORE THAN
20% OF THOSE KILLED
IN ACTION AND
20% OF THOSE
WOUNDED IN ACTION.
MANY OF
THESE CITIZEN WARRIORS
HAVE BEEN
ASKED
TO DISRUPT
THEIR LIVES IN
ACTIVE WAR
ZONES.
LIKE OTHER
VETERANS,
THEY OFTEN
HAVE DIFFICULTY ADJUSTING TO
CIVILIAN LIFE.
IT'S ESTIMATED
APPROXIMATELY
40% OF
ALL GUARD MEMBERS WILL
EXPERIENCE SOME SORT OF
FINANCIAL HARDSHIP AND THE
26%
OF GUARD
MEMBERS HAVE MONEY
PROBLEMS
REPLATED TO THEIR
DEPLOYMENT IN THE WAR
ZONES.
H.R.
2192 IS A WAY FOR US TO
RECOGNIZE
THE SACRIFICE OF
NATIONAL
GUARD AND RESERVE
MEMBERS WHO
HAVE SUFFERED
FINANCIAL
HARDSHIP SINCE
SEPTEMBER 11.
THE SERVICE MEMBERS CIVIL
RELIEF ACT AND OTHER
LAWS
TO
BENEFIT MILITARY VETERANS WILL
HELP THEM.
I
THANK REPRESENTATIVE FORBES,
ROHRABACHER, TWO
MEMBERS
OF THE
REPUBLICAN PARTY WHO WORKED
WITH
ME ON
THIS
AND
CO-SPONSORED IT AND
SCHAKOWSKY
AND
NADLER OF MY PARTY FOR
COAST
SPONSORING 2192.
I THANK YOU
THE JUDICIARY
CHAIRMAN SMITH AND
RANKING
MEMBER
CONIERS ON COURTS,
ADMINISTRATIVE LAW CHAIRMAN
COBLE FOR THEIR
ASSISTANCE IN
MOVING THIS BILL.
THIS BILL DOES
INDEED HELP
RESERVISTS AND NATIONAL
GUARDSMEN IN A SPECIAL
WAY.
IT SHOWS US
THE PREVIOUS BILL
THAT MR.
CHAFFETZ SPONSORED
SHOWS THAT
WE
IN THE JUDICIARY
COMMITTEE CAN WORK IN A
BIPARTISAN MANNER AND
THAT
CONGRESS CAN WORK AND WE
SHOULD
BE AT
LEAST IN DOUBLE DIGITS.
I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO SUPPORT
H.R.
2192, AND I RESERVE THE
BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN RESERVES THE BALANCE
OF HIS TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM UTAH.
MR. CHAFFETZ: MR. SPEAKER, I
HAVE NO ADDITIONAL SPEAKERS AT
THIS TIME.
I WOULD ENCOURAGE MY
COLLEAGUES
TO VOTE FOR
IT.
IT'S A GOOD DAY
WHEN
WE COME
TO
THE FLOOR
OF THE
HOUSE
AND
SUPPORT OUR
GUARDSMEN AND THOSE
SERVING IN THE MILITARY.
I
APPRECIATE THE GOOD
BIPARTISAN SUPPORT AND
WORK
THAT MR. COHEN
AND MR.
FORBES
AND
OTHERS.
WITH THAT I WILL
RESERVE THE
BALANCE OF OUR
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN RESERVES THE BALANCE
OF HIS TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM TENNESSEE.
MR. COHEN: I YIELD THE
REMAINDER OF MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM TENNESSEE YIELDS
THE BALANCE OF HIS
TIME.
MR. CHAFFETZ: I
YIELD BACK THE
BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
QUESTION IS WILL THE HOUSE PASS
H.R.
-- HOUSE SPULLS AND PASS
2192.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
IN THE OPINION OF THE CHAIR
,
2/3 HAVING RESPONDED IN THE
AFFIRMATIVE --
MR. COHEN:
MR. SPEAKER,
I
OBJECT TO THE VOTE ON THE
GROUNDS THAT A QUORUM IS NOT
PRESENT -- I ASK FOR A RECORDED
VOTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: DO YOU
ASK FOR THE
YEAS AND NAYS?
MR. COHEN:
THAT
TOO.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
ALL
THOSE IN FAVOR OF TAKING THIS
VOTE BY THE YEAS AND NAYS WILL
RISE AND REMAIN STANDING UNTIL
COUNTED.
A SUFFICIENT NUMBER HAVING
ARISEN, THE YEAS AND NAYS ARE
ORDERED.
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 8 OF RULE 20
AND THE CHAIR'S PRIOR
ANNOUNCEMENT, FURTHER
PROCEEDINGS ON THIS MOTION WILL
BE POSTPONED.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA SEEK
RECOGNITION?
&gt;&gt; MR. SPEAKER, I MOVE THE
HOUSE SUSPEND THE RULES
AND
PASS H.R.
1801 AS REPORTED BY
THE COMMITTEE OF
HOMELAND
SECURITY.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CLERK WILL REPORT THE TITLE OF
THE BILL.
THE CLERK:
--
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: DOES
THE GENTLEMAN SEEK TO CALL THE
BILL AS AMENDED?
&gt;&gt;
YES, MR. SPEAKER, I DO.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CLERK WILL REPORT THE TITLE OF
THE BILL.
THE CLERK:
UNION CALENDAR
NUMBER
182,
H.R. 1801, A BILL
TO AMEND TITLE 49, UNITED
STATES CODE, TO PROVIDE FOR
EXPEDITED SECURITY SCREENINGS
FOR MEMBERS OF THE ARMED FORCES
.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
PURSUANT TO THE RULE, THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA, MR.
CRAFF
HE CAN, AND
THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM CALIFORNIA,
MS.
RICHARDSON, EACH
WILL
CONTROL
20 MINUTES.
THE CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA.
MR. CRAVAACK
: MR. SPEAKER, I
ASK
ALL MEMBERS MAY HAVE FIVE
LEGISLATIVE DAYS TO REVISE AND
EXTEND THEIR REMARKS AND TO
INCLUDE ANY EXTRANEOUS MATERIAL
ON THE BILL UNDER
CONSIDERATION.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION.
MR. CRAVAACK: THANK YOU, MR.
SPEAKER.
I YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME AS I
MAY CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. CRAVAACK: MR. SPEAKER, THE
BILL UNDER CONSIDERATION TODAY,
H.R. 1801, THE RISK-BASED
SECURITY SCREENING FOR MEMBERS
OF THE ARMED FORCES
ACT, IS A
BIPARTISAN
EFFORT WHICH DIRECTS
T.S.A. TO ESTABLISH AN
EXPEDITED SCREENING PROCESS FOR
MEMBERS OF THE
ARMED FORCES
AND
THEIR
FAMILIES AND ARE
TRAVELING THROUGHOUT
OUR
NATION'S
AIRPORTS.
CURRENTLY MILITARY SERVICE
MEMBERS
MUST REFORM THEIR BELT
BUCKLES AND OTHER
THINGS BEFORE
GOING THROUGH
CHECKPOINT.
IT MAKES ABSOLUTELY
NO
SENSE
TO
REQUIRE AN AMERICAN SERVICE
MEMBER TO TAKE
OFF THEIR
JACKETS AND MEDALS FOR
T.S.A.
SCREENING BEFORE
BOARDING THEIR
FLIGHT
HOME.
UNLESS
INTELLIGENCE IDENTIFIES
SPECIFIC
THREAT, WE
SHOULD
HONOR OUR SERVICE
MEMBERS,
WILLINGNESS TO
SACRIFICE
THEMSELVES FOR OUR COUNTRY BY
TREATING THEM AS
PATRIOTS, NOT
OPERATING UNDER THE
ASSUMPTION
THAT EVERYONE INTENDS
TO
HARM
OUR COUNTRY'S
TRANSPORTATION
SYSTEM.
IMPORTANTLY, THIS
COMMONSENSE
BILL WILL
STREAMLINE THE
SCREENING
PROCESS FOR OUR
SERVICE MEMBERS
AND
LEAD
TO
DECREASED CHECKPOINT WAIT
TIMES
FOR OTHER AMERICAN
TRAVELERS.
MOREOVER, THIS
LEGISLATION WILL
COMPLEMENT THE
T.S.A.
ADMINISTRATOR'S MOVE
TO A
RISK-BASED CHECKPOINT
SCREENING
SYSTEM
FOR
PASSENGERS AND
I AM
PLEASED TO
REPORT THAT AFTER
H.R.
1801 WAS PASSED
UNANIMOUSLY WITH BIPARTISAN
SUPPORT IN
COMMITTEE, T.S.A.
HAS NOW
BEGUN
TESTING A
MILITARY I.D.
READING PILOT
PROGRAM FOR
U.S. ARMED SERVICE
MEMBERS
AT
MONTERREY PENINSULA
AIRPORT IN
KOREA.
WHILE THIS BILL WILL
NOT LET A
MEMBER
OF THE ARMED FORCES
BYPASS
SECURITY, IT
WILL
REQUIRE
T.S.A. TO DEVELOP AN
EXPEDITED
SCREENING
PROCESS
DISIGNED TO
REDUCE OUR SERVICE
MEMBER CHECKPOINT
WAITING TIMES
.
TO BE
CLEAR,
THIS PROGRAM DOES
NOT
IMPACT THE
T.S.A.'S
EXISTING LAYERED
AVIATION
SECURITY APPROACH
THAT
INCLUDES
FEDERAL AIR
MARSHALS, THE LAST
LINE
OF DEFENSE, SECURE FLIGHT
VETTING,
A.I.T.
MACHINES,
T.S.A. INTELLIGENT
ANALYSTS,
EXPLOSIVE TRACE
DETECTIONS, K-9
TEAMS, BOARDING
SYSTEMS.
IT'S
PART OF THE HIGHLY
INTEGRATED INTELLIGENCE SYSTEM
THAT
ALLOWS
FURTHER
CONCENTRATION OF LIMITED
RESOURCES ON
POTENTIALLY HIGHER
RISK PASSENGERS.
IN
CLOSE,
I'D LIKE TO THANK
TRANSPORTATION
SECURITY
COMMITTEE CHAIRMAN MIKE
ROGERS
AND
HOMELAND SECURITY COMMITTEE
CHAIRMAN
PETER
KING FOR MOVING
THIS
LEGISLATION AND ALL OF MY
COLLEAGUES IN
COMMITTEE,
PARTICULARLY
RANKING MEMBER
BENNIE THOMPSON AND
SUBCOMMITTEE RANKING MEMBER
SHEILA JACKSON LEE FOR THEIR
SUPPORT.
THANK YOU, MR. SPEAKER,
AND
I
RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN RESERVES THE BALANCE
OF HIS TIME.
THE GENTLEWOMAN FROM
CALIFORNIA.
MS. RICHARDSON: MR. SPEAKER, I
RISE IN SUPPORT OF H.R.
AND
I YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME AS
I MAY CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEWOMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MS. RICHARDSON: THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
FIRST OF ALL, I'D
LIKE
TO
ACKNOWLEDGE THE WORK OF
CHAIRMAN KING AND
RANKING
MEMBER THOMPSON.
AS A MEMBER
OF THE COMMITTEE ON
HOMELAND SECURITY, I'M PLEASED
THAT FOR THE FIRST
TIME IN THIS
112TH CONGRESS THE
HOUSE IS
CONSIDERING
IMPORTANT
TRANSPORTATION SECURITY
LEGISLATION.
H.R.
1801, THE RISK-BASED
SECURITY SCREENING FOR
MEMBERS
OF THE
ARMED FORCES ACT
REQUIRES THAT
TRANSPORTATION
SECURITY ADMINISTRATION TO
DEVELOP A PLAN FOR
PROVIDING
EXPEDITED
SCREENING
FOR OUR
MILITARY
PERSONNEL
AT AIRPORT
SECURITY
CHECKPOINTS.
SINCE 2001, THERE
HAVE BEEN
MORE THAN TWO MILLION
TROOPS
THAT HAVE BEEN
DEPLOYED TO IRAQ
AND
AFGHANISTAN.
LAST CONGRESS
AN EARLIER
VERSION OF THIS
LEGISLATION WAS
ACCEPTED
AS AN AMENDMENT ON A
BIPARTISAN BASIS
AS MY
COLLEAGUE MENTIONED
EARLIER.
DURING
CONSIDERATION OF THE
TRANSPORTATION SECURITY
ADMINISTRATION
AUTHORIZATION
ACT, WHICH PASSED
THIS HOUSE BY
VOTES IN THE YE -- AYES,
AND 25
IN THE
NAY, BUT IT WAS
NOT ACTED UPON
BY THE SENATE
UNFORTUNATELY.
H.R.
1801 PROPERLY RECOGNIZES
THE
PRECIOUSNESS OF TIME TO OUR
PATRIOTIC MEN AND
WOMEN
SERVING
IN OUR ARMED
SERVICES
WITHOUT
COMPROMISING
AVIATION SECURITY.
THIS LEGISLATION
WILL ENSURE
THAT OUR
TROOPS AND
THEIR
FAMILIES, INCLUDING
236,963
DEFENSE PERSONNEL
IN
MY OWN
HOME STATE
IN
CALIFORNIA, ARE
GIVEN
THE
OPPORTUNITY TO BOARD
AN AIRCRAFT IN
A
SECURITY
APPROVED
EXPEDITED MANNER.
OUR TROOPS
HELP
KEEP OUR
COUNTRY SAFE.
THE LEAST
WE CAN
DO IS DEVISE
METHODS THAT HELP
SPEED UP THE
SCREENING
PROCESS FOR OUR
TROOPS THAT ARE
IN
UNIFORM AND
ARE
TRAVELING ON AIRPLANES
WHILE
ON OFFICIAL DUTY.
AS OUR MILITARY
PRESENCE IN
IRAQ
WINDS
DOWN, IT IS
IMPORTANT THAT
WE REMAIN
COGNIZANT OF THE
BURDENS THAT
DEPLOYMENTS BEAR AND
THEIR
TRAVEL ON SERVICE MEMBERS AND
THEIR FAMILIES IN
TIMES
OF WAR
AND PEACE.
IN
ADDITION TO TRAVEL SERVICES,
I SUPPORT
AND URGE THIS
CONGRESS, THE ADMINISTRATION
AND
THE DEPARTMENT OF
HOMELAND
SECURITY TO
STRENGTHEN ALL
MILITARY
SERVICES AND PROGRAMS
FOR OUR
TROOPS,
INCLUDING
INCREASING
VETERAN RECRUITMENT
EFFORTS.
SOME OF THE ADDITIONAL
MILITARY
SUPPORT THAT THIS
CONGRESS
SHOULD CONSIDER WOULD BE,
ONE,
PROVIDING TAX CREDITS FOR
HIRING VETERANS
LOOKING
FOR
WORK,
TWO, STRENGTHENING
MUCH-NEEDED TRAINING
PROGRAMS
FOR
SEPARATING SERVICE MEMBERS,
THREE,
ENCOURAGING BUSINESSES
AND GOVERNMENT
CONTRACTORS TO
HIRE THE BRAVE
MEN AND WOMEN
WHO
HAVE BEEN DEPLOYED AND HAVE
NOW
RETURNED WITH DEVELOPED
VALUABLE
SKILLS AND
PROFESSIONALISM WHILE
IN THE
ARMED FORCES.
FOUR,
ENSURING
THAT THE SERVICE
MEMBERS LEAVE THE
MILITARY
CAREER READY.
H.R.
IS ONE OF MANY
OPPORTUNITIES FOR
THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC AND THIS CONGRESS
TO
DEMONSTRATE THEIR SUPPORT TO
THOSE WHO ARE
SERVING BRAVELY.
FURTHER, IT IS
IMPORTANT TO
NOTE THAT
CONSIDERATION OF
H.R.
1801 MARKS
THE FIRST TIME IN
THIS CONGRESS
THAT
THE HOUSE IS
CONSIDERING A BILL
REPORTED BY
THE COMMITTEE
ON HOMELAND
SECURITY.
I AND OTHER
MEMBERS OF THIS
COMMITTEE LOOK
FORWARD
TO THIS
LEGISLATION NOT BEING
OUR
LAST.
A NUMBER
OF --
A NUMBER OF
COMMONSENSE HOMELAND SECURITY
BILLS ARE ON THE FLOOR OF THE
HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES'
CALENDAR AND WARRANT
TIMELY
CONSIDERATION.
WITH THAT,
MR. SPEAKER, I
RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEWOMAN RESERVES THE
BALANCE OF HER
TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA.
MR. CRAVAACK:
MR. SPEAKER, I
YIELD TWO
MINUTES TO THE
DISTINGUISHED GENTLEMAN FROM
TEXAS, MR.
FARENTHOLD.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM TEXAS IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. FARENTHOLD: THANK YOU.
I RISE
IN
SUPPORT OF
H.R.
1801.
AS WE COME
OFF
A HOLIDAY
WEEKEND, THE MOST
BUSY TRAVEL
TIME IN
THIS
COUNTRY, MANY
AMERICANS HAVE GONE THROUGH THE
SCREENING AT OUR
NUMEROUS
AIRPORTS.
THE
T.S.S. WORKS HARD
SCREENING
EVERYBODY -- THE
T.S.A. WORKS
HARD
SCREENING EVERYBODY MAKING
EVERYBODY SAFE.
MEMBERS
OF
OUR
MILITARY, WHOM
WE KNOW
WHO HAVE SERVED AND PUT
THEIR LIFE ON THE
LINE FOR THIS
COUNTRY,
SHOULD BE AMONG THOSE
WHO FIRST
IN A PROGRAM WHERE
WHERE HE TRUST OUR
TRAVELERS.
WE MUST CONTINUE
TO LOOK FOR
EFFICIENCIES TO SPEED AIR
TRAVEL.
WE MUST CONTINUE TO LOOK
FOR
WAYS TO
COME
WITH LESS INVASIVE
WAYS TO
SCREEN PASSENGERS.
WE
MUST LOOK
FOR WAYS TO MAKE
TRAVELING A
MORE PLEASANT
EXPERIENCE
AND A MORE
PROFITABLE EXPERIENCE FOR THE
BUSINESS MEN AND WOMEN
WHO
TRAVEL.
I URGE SUPPORT
OF THIS BILL
WHERE WE START
WHERE
WHERE HE
SHOULD START, WITH
MEMBERS
OF
OUR ARMED
SERVICES, BUT
THERE
ARE OTHER PLACES WE
NEED
TO
LOOK TO --
TRUSTED TRAVELER
PROGRAM, FLIGHT CREWS
RECEIVING
EXPEDITED
SCREENING, THE
T.S.A.
MUST CONTINUE TO
WORK TO
IMPROVE THIS
PROCESS TO MAKE IT
SAFER AND
MORE EFFICIENT
AND
THIS BILL GIVES THE
T.S.A. THE
ENCOURAGEMENT THAT
THEY NEED
AND IS A GREAT STEP
ALONG THE
WAY
TO MORE EFFICIENT AND
PRIVATE AND
BETTER SCREENING
FOR OUR SARPTE
SECURITY.
AND WITH
THAT
I'LL
YIELD BACK.
--
FOR OUR
AIRPORT SECURITY.
AND WITH
THAT I WILL YIELD
BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM CALIFORNIA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MS. RICHARDSON: MR. SPEAKER,
I
HAVE NO MORE
SPEAKERS.
IF THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
IS PREPARED TO CLOSE
I AM
PREPARED TO CLOSE.
MR.
CRAVAACK: I AM
PREPARED TO
CLOSE AFTER
THE GENTLEWOMAN HAS
CLOSED.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM CALIFORNIA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MS. RICHARDSON:
MR. SPEAKER,
I
YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME AS I MAY
CONSUME.
MR. SPEAKER, H.R. 1801 IS
NEEDED, IT'S
COMMON SENSE AND
IT'S A
PIECE OF LEGISLATION
WITH A HISTORY OF
BIPARTISAN
SUPPORT.
I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES
TO
SUPPORT
THIS MEASURE AND OUR
TROOPS.
THEIR TIME IS LIMITED
AND IT
CERTAINLY SHOULD SHUNTE BE
WASTED IN LONG LINES
AT THE
AIRPORT.
AIRPORT -- SHOULDN'T BE WASTED
IN LONG LINES
AT THE
AIRPORT.
AIRPORTS HAVE CHECKPOINTS
THAT
EXPEDITE THE SECURITY SCREENING
PROCESS AND OUR
SERVICEPERSON
ELL HAVE
EARNED THIS PRIVILEGE
-- SERVICE
PERSONNEL HAVE
EARNED THIS PRIVILEGE
AS WELL.
WE NEED TO
PUT
ON HOMELAND
SECURITY BILLS AND BILLS
AIMED
AT
EASING OUR VETERANS FROM
MILITARY SERVICE
TO
CIVILIAN
CAREERS.
IT'S LATE
NOVEMBER IN THE FIRST
SESSION OF
THIS 112TH CONGRESS
AND IT'S
COMING TO
AN END AND
THE PUBLIC IS
HURTING AND
CONGRESS
MUST
ACT.
WITH
THAT, MR. SPEAKER, ON H.R.
1801, I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO
UNANIMOUSLY SUPPORT THIS
BILL
AND I
YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF
MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEWOMAN YIELDS BACK THE
BALANCE OF HER TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA.
MR. CRAVAACK:
MR. SPEAKER,
I'D
LIKE TO THANK
MY COLLEAGUE
FROM
CALIFORNIA FOR HER
SUPPORT ON
THIS VERY
IMPORTANT BILL AND
OUR
TRUST WE PLACE ON OUR
MILITARY
PERSONNEL.
MR. SPEAKER, I URGE SUPPORT OF
H.R.
1801 AND
YIELD BACK THE
BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN YIELDS BACK THE
BALANCE OF HIS TIME.
THE QUESTION IS WILL THE HOUSE
SUSPEND THE RULES AND PASS H.R.
1801 AS
AMENDED.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
.
THOSE
OPPOSED, NO
IN
FAVOR OF
TAKING THIS VOTE BY
THE
YEAS AND NAYS WILL RISE AND
REMAIN STANDING UNTIL
COUNTED.
A
SUFFICIENT NUMBER HAVING
RISEN, THE YEAS AND NAYS
ARE
ORDERED.
FURTHER PROCEED OPTION
THIS
QUESTION WILL BE POSTPONED.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM MICHIGAN SEEK
RECOGNITION?
&gt;&gt; I MOVE
THE HOUSE SUSPEND THE
RULES AND PASS THE BILL
H.R.
2465.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
DOES
THE GENTLEMAN SEEK
TO CALL THE
BILL
UP AS AMENDED?
&gt;&gt; YES.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CLERK WILL REPORT THE TITLE OF
THE BILL.
THE CLERK:
H.R. 2465, A BILL TO
AMEND THE FEDERAL
EMPLOYEES
COMPENSATION ACT.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
PURSUANT TO THE RULE, THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MICHIGAN, MR.
WALBERG, AND THE
GENTLEWOMAN
FROM
CALIFORNIA, MS. WOOLSEY,
EACH WILL CONTROL 20
MINUTES.
THE CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE
GENTLEMAN
FROM MICHIGAN.
MR. WALBERG: I ASK UNANIMOUS
CONSENT THAT ALL
MEMBERS HAVE
FIVE
MINUTES TO REVISE AND
EXTEND
THEIR REMARKS ON
H.R.
2465.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION.
MR. WALBERG: I YIELD MYSELF
SUCH TIME AS I MAY CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. WALBERG: THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
I RISE IN SUPPORT OF H R.
2465.
THE FEDERAL
WORKERS
COMPENSATION
MODERNIZATION AND
IMPROVEMENT ACT.
THE LEGISLATION WAS APPROVED
UNANIMOUSLY BY
THE HOUSE
EDUCATION
AND WORK FORCE
COMMITTEE, A
TESTAMENT TO ITS
COMMON SENSE, BIPARTISAN
POLICIES.
I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO SUPPORT
IT.
FOR MORE THAN 90 YEARS A
WORKERS
COMPENSATION PROGRAM
HAS
PROVIDED ASSISTANCE TO
FEDERAL EMPLOYEES WHO
BECOME
INJURED OR ILL THROUGH
A
WORK-REALED ACTIVITY.
THE PROGRAM
REFLECTS OUR
COMMITMENT TO THE MEN
AND WOMEN
WHO SERVE
OUR COUNTRY IN THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT.
ESTABLISHED BY THE
FEDERAL
EMPLOYEES
COMPENSATION ACT, THE
PROGRAM IS
ADMINISTERED BY THE
DEPARTMENT OF LABOR
AND IN
RECREN
YEARS, IT HAS GROWN
SIGNIFICANTLY IN
SIZE AND IN
COST.
AN
ESTIMATED $3 -- AN ESTIMATED
THREE MILLION
EMPLOYEES ARE
COVERED BY
THE PROGRAM.
DURING
FISCAL YEAR 2010,
BENEFICIARIES
RECEIVE NEARLY $3
BILLION IN
WORKERS'
COMPENSATION.
UNFORTUNATELY, THIS FEDERAL
PROGRAM HAS NOT BEEN
SIGNIFICANTLY REFORMED OR
UPDATED IN
ALMOST 40 YEARS.
AND
AS IS TOO OFTEN THE CASE
WITH GOVERNMENT PROGRAMS
LEFT
UNCHECKED FOR
DECADES, WASTE,
AND -- WASTE AND
INEFFICIENCIES
HAVE
CREPT INTO THE SYSTEM,
LEADING TO
POOR USE OF TAXPAYER
RESOURCES AND
DIMINISHED
SUPPORT FOR THE
INDIVIDUALS THE
PROGRAM IS
INTENDED TO SERVE.
THROUGH THE
OVERSIGHT EFFORTS
OF THE EDUCATION
AN WORK FORCE
COMMITTEE, WE HAVE
LEARNED
ABOUT A
NUMBER OF CHALLENGES
CONFRONTING THE PROGRAM.
FOR EXAMPLE, WORKERS IN
RURAL
AREAS
LIKE MY OWN MAY HAVE
LIMITED ACCESS TO
MEDICAL CARE.
ADDITIONALLY,
MR. SPEAKER, SOME
COMPENSATION
LEVELS REMAIN SET
TO
FORMULAS THAT MADE SENSE IN
THE DAYS OF THE
SECOND WORLD
WAR
BUT ARE INAPPROPRIATE
TODAY.
CLEARLY
REFORM IS LONG OVERDUE.
FEDERAL
EMPLOYEES SHOULD HAVE
ACCESS
TO A PROGRAM
THAT
REFLECTS THE
REALITIES OF
TODAY'S ECONOMY
AND TAKES INTO
ACCOUNT THE BEST
PRACTICES OF
MEDICAL
CARE.
TAXPAYERS DESERVE
A PROGRAM
THAT
OPERATES EFFICIENCY --
EFFICIENTLY AND
EFFECTIVELY.
THAT'S
WHY I ALONG WITH THE
OTHER LEADERS
ON THE EDUCATION
AND
WORK FORCE
COMMITTEE
INTRODUCED THE
FEDERAL WORK
FORCE
COMPENSATION
MODERNIZATION AND IMPROVEMENT
ACT.
AN INITIAL STEP IN OUR EFFORT
TO STRENGTHEN THE PROGRAM AN
BRING IT INTO
THE 21ST CENTURY.
THE BILL
BEFORE US TODAY
ADVANCE THIS IS
GOAL IN THREE
IMPORTANT
WAYS.
FIRST,
MR. SPEAKER, H R. 2465
ENHANCES THE
EFFICIENCY OF THE
FEDERAL
WORKERS COMPENSATION
PROGRAM.
THE
LEGISLATION
ALLOWS
PHYSICIAN
ASSISTANTS AND
ADVANCED PRACTICE
NURSES,
HIGHLY
TRAINED INDIVIDUALS IN
MEDICAL
PROFESSION, TO CERTIFY
A
WORKER'S DISABILITY AND
ENSURE
THESE PROFESSIONALS ARE
REIMBURSED FOR THEIR SERVICES.
THE BILL ALSO
STREAMLINES THE
CLAIMS PROCESS
FOR WORKERS WHO
SUSTAIN
A TRAUMATIC INJURY IN
AN
AREA OF ARMED CONFLICT.
THESE INDIVIDUAL CANS
WORK IN
HOSTILE AN EVEN DEADLY
ENVIRONMENTS AND THE
NOT HAVE
TO
WAIT MONTHS FOR BENEFITS
THEY ARE
ENTITLED TO AND THE
TAXPAYER
WISHES TO AFFORD THEM.
SECONDLY, THE LEGISLATION,
MR.
SPEAKER,
IMPROVES THE INTEGRITY
OF THE WORKERS
COMPENSATION
PROGRAM.
THE
LABOR DEPARTMENT WOULD BE
ALLOWED TO CROSS
CHECK AN
EMPLOYEE'S EARNINGS WITH
INFORMATION HELD AT THE
SOCIAL
SECURITY
ADMINISTRATION,
HELPING TO PROVIDE WORKERS THE
BENEFITS
THEY DESERVE, NO MORE,
AND NO LESS.
THE DEPARTMENT
WOULD ALSO BE
EMPOWERED TO
COLLECT
ADMINISTRATIVE
COSTS AND
OTHER
EXPENSES FROM
AGENCIES
EMPLOYING THE
WORKERS,
PROMOTING
GREATER
ACCOUNTABILITY WITHIN
THE
PROGRAM FOR ALL
FEDERAL
AGENCIES.
FINALLY,
MR. SPEAKER, THE
LEGISLATION
MODERNIZES BENEFITS
TO
BETTER MEET THE NEEDS OF
TODAY'S
WORKERS, PROVIDING THE
LEVEL OF
SUPPORT EMPLOYEES NEED
AND GUARANTEING THAT
INJURIES
OR ILLNESSES
RESULTING
FROM AN
ACT OF
TERRORISM ARE TREATED
LIKE OTHER WAR RISK
HAZARDS.
THE
FEDERAL WORKERS
COMPENSATION MODERNIZATION AND
IMPROVEMENT ACT
REPRESENTS
COMMON SENSE REFORM
FOR FEDERAL
-- REFORM FEDERAL WORKERS
AND
TAXPAYERS DESERVE.
I ENCOURAGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO
SUPPORT THE LEGISLATION AND
RESERVE THE
BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN RESERVES THIS CHAIR
RECOGNIZES THE GENTLEWOMAN FROM
CALIFORNIA.
MS. WOOLSEY: I ASK UNANIMOUS
CONSENT TO REVISE AND EXTEND MY
REMARKS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION.
MS. WOOLSEY: I
YIELD MYSELF
SUCH TIME AS
I MAY CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEWOMAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
MS. WOOLSEY:
MR. SPEAKER, I
RISE IN
SUPPORT OF H.R. 2465,
THE FEDERAL
WORKERS
COMPENSATION
MODERNIZATION AND
IMPROVEMENT ACT.
THIS LEGISLATION
IS A PRODUCT
OF
BIPARTISAN COOPERATION AND
CONSENSUS AND I
THANK THE
CHAIRMAN OF THE
WORK FORCE
PROTECTION
COMMITTEE FOR
BEING
HERE
AND BEING THE LEADER ON
THIS TODAY.
THIS
LEGISLATION UPDATES AND
IMPROVES THE FEDERAL
EMPLOYEES'
COMPENSATION ACT OR
FECA,
WHICH
PROVIDES
LEGISLATION TO ENSURE
THEY CAN
CONTINUE TO SUPPORT
THEIR FAMILIES
AND PAY THEIR
BILLS IF
THEY'RE INJURED ON THE
JOB.
A
CORE PRINCIPLE
EMBEDDED IN
THE
LAW IS THAT WORKERS SHOULD
BE NO
BETTER OFF OR NO WORSE
OFF FOR HAVING
SUFFERED A
WORK-RELATED INJURY.
THE REFORMS IN THIS BILL
ARE AN
INITIAL STEP TOWARD
MAKING FECA
FAIRER AND
MORE EFFICIENT FOR
TAXPAYERS AND
FEDERAL EMPLOYEES
WHO DEPEND ON THE PROGRAM.
H.R.
2465 UPDATES BENEFITS FOR
FUNERAL
EXPENSES AND FACIAL
DISFIGUREMENTS BETH
OF WHICH
HAVE NOT
BEEN UPDATED SINCE
1949.
IT
ENSURES THAT ACTS OF TERROR
ARE COVERED
TO INCLUDE ADVANCE
PRACTICE
NURSES AND PHYSICAL
ASSISTANCE.
IT ALSO
EXPANDS THE
CONTINUATION OF PAY
PERIOD FROM
DAYS TO 135 DAYS FOR THOSE
WHO
ARE INJURED OVERSEAS IN A
ZONE OF
ARMED CONFLICT.
TO
MAKE IT EASIER TO FILE FOR
BENEFITS.
THIS LEGISLATION
WILL IMPROVE
PROGRAM
INTEGRITY BY ALLOWING
THE DEPARTMENT
OF LABOR TO
MATCH ITS
RECORDS AGAINST
SOCIAL SECURITY EARNINGS
INFORMATION,
ENSURING THAT
BENEFICIARIES ARE NOT
RECEIVING
PROHIBITED
SALARY FOR OUTSIDE
INCOME
AT THE SAME TIME THEY'RE
RECEIVING
BENEFITS.
CONSISTENT
WITH THE GOVERNMENT
ACCOUNTABILITY
RECOMMENDATION,
THE
BILL ALLOWS THE GOVERNMENT
TO RECOVER A PORTION OF
PAYMENTS
SECURED FROM THIRD
PARTIES.
MR. SPEAKER, THESE
COMMON
SENSE, BIPARTISAN
CHANGES WILL
MAKE
IT MORE EFFICIENT AND
ACCORDING TO THE CONGRESSIONAL
BUDGET OFFICE
WILL PRODUCE
SAVINGS FOR
TAXPAYERS AND THE
POSTAL SERVICE.
THE COMMITTEE IS AWARE
OF
DEPARTMENT OF LABOR
PROPOSALS
TO SLASH
BENEFITS FOR WORKERS
WHILE
-- WITH DEPENDENTS,
REDUCE
BENEFITS FOR PERMANENTLY
DISABLED
WORKERS WHEN THEY
REACH
RETIME AGE AND SHRINK
SURVIVOR
BENEFITS.
WHILE
THE DEPARTMENT CONTENDS
THEIR PROPOSAL
ADDRESSES
INEQUITIES, THEY HAVE NOT
PRESENTED EVIDENCE THAT THESE
CHANGES
WILL NOT CREATE
UNINTENDED
CONSEQUENCES.
FOR THAT
REASON, I WAS PLEASED
TO CHAIR
CHAIRMAN KLEIN,
SUBCOMMITTEE CHAIRMAN
WALBERG
AND
RANKING MEMBER MILNER
SPONSORING A JULY 8 REQUEST
TO
THE G.A.O.
ASKING THAT IT
ASSESS THE
IMPACTS OF THE LABOR
DEPARTMENT'S PROPOSED CHANGES.
THE
G.A.O. REPORT WILL BE
VITAL.
IT WILL BE SO
IMPORTANT AS WE
LOOK
FOR WAYS TO FURTHER
IMPROVE THE
BILL WITHOUT
UNDERMINING ITS CORE
VALUES.
BEFORE WE
CONSIDER WHAT WE'RE
GOING TO BE DOING,
WE HAVE TO
CONSIDER
WHO IS IMPACTED BY
CHANGES WHEN WE
MODIFY THIS
LAW.
AND WE DO --
AND WHEN WE DO, WE
HAVE TO
KEEP IN MIND THAT THIS
LAW IS
THESE WORK -- THAT THIS
IS THE
WORKERS' EXCLUSIVE
REMEDY.
THEY CANNOT SUE THE GOVERNMENT
FOR THEIR
LOSSES.
LESLIE BLACK
WAS A CORRECTIONAL
OFFICER
AT THE FEDERAL CRECKAL
INSTITUTE IN SOUTH CAROLINA.
WHEN SHE WAS
ATTACKED BY AN
INMATE
ON MAY 7, NO, MAY 2,
2007, SHE
WROTE THIS.
I
QUOTE HER.
SHE WROTE, THE
INMATE WHO
ATTACKED ME HAD
EMBEDDED TWO
RAZORS INTO
A PLASTIC SPOON BY
MELTING THE SPOON
AROUND THE
RAZOR, CREATING A
LETHAL
WEAPON.
WITH THIS WEAPON HE
SLASHED MY
THROAT AND
RIGHT ARM, CAUSE SEG
VEER
BLEEDING, BLOOD LOSS AND
LACERATIONS.
SINCE THIS ATTACK, MY FAMILY
AND I HAVE
SURVIVED ON A
REDUCED INCOME OF MY
WORKERS'
COMPENSATION
BENEFITS AND MY
HUSBAND'S INCOME,
INCLUDING HIS
WAGES AS
A MEMBER OF THE ARMY
NATIONAL GUARD.
WE HAVE THREE CHILDREN
AT HOME
AND MY
WORKERS' COMPENSATION
BENEFITS
HAVE BEEN THE
DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN FINANCIAL
SURVIVAL AND FINANCIAL RUIN.
WE HUARDLY
LIVE IN THE LAP OF
LUXURY.
THAT'S THE END OF HER QUOTE.
SHE HOPES TO RETURN
TO WORK AT
THE PRISON
IN
A SUITABLE
POSITION IN THE
NEAR FUTURE,
MR. SPEAKER.
SHE
ASKS, WHY WOULD ANYONE WANT
TO CUT
BENEFITS FOR SOMEONE WHO
WAS HURT
TRYING TO KEEP THE
COMMUNITY SAFE?
GIVEN THE
PUBLIC SERVICE
PROVIDED BY LESLIE
AND OTHER
FEDERAL WORKERS,
I WAS
DISAPPOINTED TO SEE
THAT THE
SENATE COMMITTEE
ON HOME AND
SECURITY -- ON
HOMELAND AND
SECURITY GOVERNMENT
AFFAIRS HAS
REPORTED OUT
POSTAL REFORM
LEGISLATION THAT ADOPTED
MANY
OF THE DEPARTMENT
OF LABOR'S
PROPOSALS TO CUT
FECA AND THEN
WENT A STEP
FURTHER AND CUT
THEM EVEN MORE
DEEPLY WITHOUT
HAVING FIRST
UNDERTAKEN AN
ANALYSIS OF
THOSE IMPACTS.
THE SENATE COMMITTEE
EVEN
IMPOSED SOME OF THESE
CUTS
RETROACTIVELY,
FRANKLY, TAKING
A
MEAT AX TO THE PROGRAM
WITHOUT FIRST
DOING YOUR
HOMEWORK
IS IRRESPONSIBLE.
IT IS MY HOPE THAT THE
LEGISLATION BEFORE US
TODAY,
COUPLED
WITH A BIPARTISAN
COMMITMENT TO
STUDY THE MATTER
WITH
CARE,
CONSERVE -- CAN
SERVE AS AN
X. FOR THE CORRECT
PATH FORWARD,
IMPROVING FECA.
THESE
ARE NOT JUST NUMBERS,
THEY ARE NOT JUST
PERCENTAGES
WE ARE DEALING
WITH.
THESE
CHANGES COULD MEAN UNJUST
IMPOVERISHMENT
FOR A FEDERAL
FIREFIGHTER
INJURED WHILE
BATTLING A FOREST FIRE
OR THE
WIDOW OF A
FIRE WORKER.
REPRESENTATIVE
GIFFORDS AND HER
STAFF WERE
COVERED UNDER THE
LAW FOLLOW HANDGUN THE
ASSAULT
THAT
KILLED SIX EARLIER THIS
YEAR.
AS WE MOVE FORWARD, IT IS
IMPORTANT THAT
ANY FURTHER
REFORMS ARE
FAIR TO BOTH
TAXPAYERS AND INJURED
WORKERS.
WHILE I
APPRECIATE THE DESIRE
OF SOME
COLLEAGUES TO MOVE
QUICKLY TO
ADRESS THEIR
CONCERNS
ABOUT THESE BENEFITS,
IT IS PRUDENT TO
ALLOW A FEW
MONTHS FOR THE
G.A.O. TO
COMPLETE
ITS WORK BEFORE
REDESIPING THE BENEFIT
STRUCTURE.
MR. SPEAKER, I'M ALSO TROUBLED
TO
LEARN
THAT THE HOUSE
COMMITTEE
ON GOVERNMENT
AND --
ON
OVERSIGHT AND GOVERNMENT
REFORM
DECIDED TO INCLUDE
CHANGES IN THE
POSTAL REFORM
BILL
TO CREATE A SEPARATE
POSTAL WORKERS
COMPENSATION
OUTSIDE
OF FECA.
ALL
FEDERAL WORKERS SHOULD BE
COVERED UNDER THE
SAME WORKERS
COMPENSATION SYSTEM,
REGARDLESS
OF WHICH
AGENCY EMPLOYEES THEM.
SO
PURSUANT TO HOUSE RULES,
WORKERS COMPENSATION
PROGRAMS,
INCLUDING THIS ONE,
HAVE BEEN
WITHIN
THE PRIMARY JURISDICTION
OF THE HOUSE
COMMITTEE ON
EDUCATION
AND WORK FORCE AND I
EXPECT THAT MEMBERS OF OUR
COMMITTEE WILL HAVE AN
OPPORTUNITY TO WEIGH
IN ON THAT
BILL
BEFORE IT MOVES FORWARD.
MR. SPEAKER
,
THIS IS
ENDORSED
BY
A LARGE COALITION OF LABOR
UNIONS
AND RETIREE GROUPS.
I ASK
UNANIMOUS CONSENT TO
INSERT IN THE
RECORD LETTERS
FROM
THE AMERICAN ACADEMY OF
PHYSICIANS
ASSISTANCES, THE
AMERICAN ASSOCIATION
OF NURSE
ANS THE THE
TISTS, THE AMERICAN
NURSE ASSOCIATION, AND THE
NATIONAL
ASSOCIATION OF
CLINICAL NURSE
SPECIALISTS AND
FIVE
OTHER AMAZING GROUPS.
IN
CLOSING, I'D LIKE TO THANK
--
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION.
MS. WOOLSEY:
THANK YOU.
I'D LIKE TO THANK
CHAIRMAN
KLEIN,
RANKING MEMBER WALBERG,
I MEAN
CHAIRMAN WALBERG,
RANKING MEMBER
MILLER, AND --
FOR
THEIR WORK ON THIS
LEGISLATION.
IT
HAS BEEN TRULY A
GIFT TO
WORK
IN A BIPARTISAN MANNER.
THANK YOU, MR. WALBERG.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: DOES
THE GENTLEWOMAN YIELD BACK THE
BALANCE OF HER TIME?
MS. WOOLSEY: I ASK UNANIMOUS
CONSENT
AT THIS TIME THAT ALL
MEMBERS HAVE
FIVE LEGISLATIVE
DAYS
TO
INSERT EXTRANEOUS
MATERIALS
.
I BELIEVE WE HAVE
MEMBERS OF OUR
--
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: WITHOUT
OBJECTION.
DOES THE GENTLEWOMAN WISH TO
RESERVE THE BALANCE OF HER TIME?
MS. WOOLSEY: I WILL
RESERVE THE
BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEWOMAN RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MICHIGAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
&gt;&gt; THANK YOU, MR. SPEAKER.
I ASK FOR
UNANIMOUS CONSENT TO
SUBMIT
FOR THE RECORD
A
MANAGER'S
JOINT STATEMENT
OF
LEGISLATIVE
INTENT.
THIS STATEMENT
REFLECTS THE
VIEWS
OF CHAIRMAN KLEIN, MR.
MILLER, MS. WOOLSEY,
AND MYSELF,
REGARDING KEY
ASPECTS OF THE
BILL.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: WITHOUT
OBJECTION.
WALWAL I HAVE NO ADDITIONAL
SPEAKERS
AT THIS TIME I
CONTINUE
TO RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN RESERVES THE BALANCE
OF HIS TIME.
THE GENTLEWOMAN FROM CALIFORNIA.
MS. WOOLSEY: I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO
SUPPORT H.R.
AND I
YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF
MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEWOMAN YIELDS BACK HER
TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MICHIGAN.
MR.
WALBURG: THANK YOU,
SPEAKER.
LET ME
CLOSE BY ACKNOWLEDGING
THE
BIPARTISAN EFFORT THAT WENT
INTO
CRAFTING THE LEGISLATE --
LEGISLATION AS MY
RANKING MEMBER
OF THE SUBCOMMITTEE,
MS.
WOOLSEY, HAS ALREADY
STATED.
IT WAS A
BIPARTISAN EFFORT THAT
WORKED
TOWARD A VERY
SATISFACTORY
, EVEN MORE SO, A
NECESSARY
CONCLUSION.
AS WELL AS
BRINGING THE BILL
BEFORE THE HOUSE TODAY.
I'D LIKE TO
EXPRESS MY GRATITUDE
TO
THE CHAIRMAN, RANKING MEMBER
OF THE EDUCATION AND WORK FORCE
COMMITTEE,
CONGRESSMAN JOHN
KLEIN, AND
GEORGE MILLER,
FOR
THEIR WORK AND THE
WORK OF THEIR
STAFF ON THIS
IMPORTANT
LEGISLATION.
I'D ALSO
RECOGNIZE THE HARD WORK
OF THE STAFFS
OF OUR WORK FORCE
PROTECTION SUBCOMMITTEE
, BOTH
CONGRESSWOMAN
WOOLSEY'S AND
MINE, IN THIS EFFORT
AS WELL.
THE COMMITTEE
ON WHICH WE ARE
PRIVILEGED TO SERVE BRINGS
TOGETHER
INDIVIDUALS FROM VERY
DIFFICULT WALKS OF LIFE
AND WITH
VERY
DIFFICULT VIEWS ON HOW TO
FIX THE PROBLEMS
FACING THIS
GREAT NATION.
BUT I'M ENCOURAGED THAT WE'VE
BEEN ABLE TO WORK
TOGETHER ON
THIS LEGISLATION
, DEMONSTRATING
OUR
SHARED COMMITMENT TO SERVE
AMERICAN
WORKERS
AND TAXPAYERS.
I
URGE MY COLLEAGUES TO SUPPORT
THE FEDERAL
WORKERS COMPENSATION
MODERNIZATION AND
IMPROVEMENT
ACT AND I
YIELD BACK THE BALANCE
OF MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN YIELDS BACK THE
BALANCE OF HIS TIME.
THE QUESTION IS WILL THE HOUSE
SUSPEND THE RULES AND
PASS H.R.
2465 AS
AMENDED.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
IN THE OPINION OF THE
CHAIR, 2/3
OF THOSE VOTING HAVING RESPONDED
IN THE AFFIRMATIVE, THE RULES
ARE SUSPENDED, THE
BILL IS
PASSED AND WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
MOTION TO RECONSIDER IS LAID
ON
THE
TABLE.
PURSUANT
TO CLAUSE 12-A OF RULE
1, THE
CHAIR DECLARES THE HOUSE
IN RECESS
UNTIL APPROXIMATELY
6:30
P.M. TODAY.
AND FOR OTHER PURPOSES.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
QUESTION
IS WILL THE HOUSE
SUSPEND THE RULES AND PASS THE
BILL AS AMENDED.
&gt;&gt; MR. SPEAKER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE
DOES THE GENTLEMAN
RISE?
&gt;&gt; I ASK FOR A ROLL
CALL VOTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: DOES
THE GENTLEMAN ASK FOR THE
YEAS
AND NAYS.
&gt;&gt; THE YEAS
-- YES.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
YEAS AN NAYS ARE REQUESTED.
THOSE
FAVORING A VOTE BY THE
YEAS AND NAYS
WILL RISE.
A SUFFICIENT NUMBER
HAVING
RISEN, THE YEAS AND NAYS
ARE
ORDER.
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE.
THIS IS A 15-MINUTE VOTE.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC., IN COOPERATION
WITH THE UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
ANY USE OF THE CLOSED-CAPTIONED
COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS
EXPRESSLY PROHIBITED BY THE
U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: ON
THIS
VOTE, THE YEAS ARE 389,
THE
NAYS ARE 15.
2/3
BEING IN THE AFFIRMATIVE,
THE
RULES ARE SUSPENDED, THE
BILL IS
PASSED AND WITHOUT
OBJECTION, THE MOTION
TO
RECONSIDER IS
LAID ON THE
TABLE.
THE
UNFINISHED BUSINESS IS THE
VOTE ON
THE MOTION OF THE
GENTLEMAN
FROM UTAH, MR.
CHAFFETZ, TO
SUSPEND THE RULES
AND
PASS
H.R. 2192 ON WHICH
THE
YEAS AND NAYS
ARE ORDERED.
THE
CLERK WILL REPORT THE TITLE
OF
THE BILL.
THE CLERK:
UNION CALENDAR
NUMBER
172, H.R. 21 2, A BILL
TO
EXEMPT FOR AN ADDITIONAL
FOUR-YEAR
PERIOD FROM AN
APPLICATION OF THE
MEANS TEST
ASSUMPTION
OF ABUSE QUALIFYING
MEMBERS OF
THE ARMED FORCES AND
NATIONAL GUARD
WHO, AFTER
SEPTEMBER 11, 2001, ARE
CALLED
TO
ACTIVE DUTY OR TO PERFORM A
HOMELAND DEFENSE
ACTIVITY FOR
NOT LESS
THAN 90 DAYS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
QUESTION IS, WILL
THE HOUSE
SUSPEND THE RULES AND PASS THE
BILL?
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE.
THIS IS A FIFE-MINUTE VOTE.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC., IN COOPERATION
WITH THE UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
ANY USE OF THE CLOSED-CAPTIONED
COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS
EXPRESSLY PROHIBITED BY THE
U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: ON THIS
VOTE THE YEAS ARE
406, THE NAYS
ARE
ONE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: ON THIS
VOTE THE YEAS ARE
407, THE NAYS
ARE
ONE.
2/3 OF THOSE VOTING HAVING
RESPONDED IN THE AFFIRMATIVE,
THE RULES ARE SUSPENDED
, THE
BILL
IS PASSED AND WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE MOTION TO
RECONSIDER IS
LAID ON THE TABLE.
THE
UNFINISHED BUSINESS IS THE
VOTE ON THE
MOTION OF THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA,
MR.
CRAVAACK, TO SUSPEND THE
RULES
AND
PASS H.R. 1801 AS AMENDED ON
WHICH THE
YEAS AND NAYS ARE
ORDERED.
THE CLERK WILL REPORT THE
TITLE
OF THE BILL.
THE CLERK: UNION CALENDAR
NUMBER
182,
H.R. 1801, A BILL TO AMEND
TITLE 49
, UNITED STATES CODE, TO
PROVIDE
FOR EXPEDITED SECURITY
SCREENINGS FOR MEMBERS OF THE
ARMED FORCES
.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
QUESTION IS WILL THE HOUSE
SUSPEND THE RULES AND
PASS THE
BILL AS
AMENDED.
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE.
THIS IS A FIVE-MINUTE VOTE.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
INC., IN COOPERATION WITH THE
UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
ANY USE OF THE CLOSED-CAPTIONED
COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS EXPRESSLY
PROHIBITED BY THE U.S. HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: ON THIS
VOTE THE YEAS ARE
404, THE
NAYS
ARE
ZERO.
2/3 OF THOSE VOTING HAVING
RESPONDED IN THE AFFIRMATIVE,
THE RULES ARE
SUSPENDED, THE
BILL
IS PASSED AND WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE MOTION TO
RECONSIDER IS LAID ON THE
TABLE.
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE
8 OF RULE 20,
THE
UNFINISH THED BUSINESS IS
THE QUESTION
ON AGREEING -- THE
UNFINISHED BUSINESS IS THE
QUESTION ON AGREEING TO THE
SPEAKER AS I 'PROLVE OF THE
JOURNAL WHICH THE CHAIR
SHOULD
PUT DE NOVO.
THE QUESTION IS ON AGREEING
TO
THE SPEAKER'S
APPROVAL OF THE
JOURNAL.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
IN THE OPINION OF THE CHAIR,
THE
AYES HAVE
IT.
THE JOURNAL STANDS
APPROVED.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
HOUSE WILL BE IN ORDER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
HOUSE
WILL BE IN ORDER, PLEASE
MOVE YOUR CONVERSATIONS OFF
THE
FLOOR.
THE HOUSE
WILL BE IN ORDER.
PLEASE MOVE YOUR CONVERSATIONS
OFF
OF THE FLOOR.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
HOUSE WILL BE IN ORDER.
THE HOUSE
WILL BE IN ORDER.
THE CHAIR
IS READY TO ENTERTAIN
ONE-MINUTES.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM COLORADO RISE?
&gt;&gt; REVISE AND EXTEND MY
REMARKS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: WITHOUT
OBJECTION.
THE HOUSE
WILL BE IN ORDER.
&gt;&gt; THANK YOU,
MR. SPEAKER.
I RISE TODAY
TO HONOR NAVY
INTELLIGENCE SPECIALIST
SEAMAN
ANTHONY
WHO SERVES OUR COUNTRY
WITH
GREAT ONER -- HONOR AND
PROUD.
HE'S
BEEN
AWARDED THE JOINT
ACHIEVEMENT MEDAL
FOR HIS
ACHIEVEMENTS
DURING OPERATION
AWEDSY DAWN.
HE
SERVES AS UNITED STATES
AFRICA COMMAND TARGET
BRANCH
ANALYST
FROM
FEBRUARY OF APRIL,
2011,
PROVIDING INDEPTH ANALYSIS
OF
LIBYAN TARGETS.
DURING
THIS TIME HE PROVIDED
OVER
25% OF THE ELECTRONIC
TARGET
FOLDERS WRIT BIN THE
UNITED STATES AFRICAN COMMAND
AND
EXPERTLY MANAGED
CLASSIFICATION
DOWN GRADING
DISSEMINATION OF OVER 248
TARGETS.
MR. TIPTON: ADDITIONALLY
AS A
REMOTE
TERMINAL SECURITY
OFFICER,
HE MANAGED NEW ACCOUNTS
FOR 15
TEMPORARILY ASSIGNED DUTY
PERSONNEL,
ALLOWING THEM TO
PROVIDE IMMEDIATE SUPPORT FOR
THE MISSION.
THE SEAMAN
GRADUATED FROM MOUNT
ROSE HIGH SCHOOL
IN MOUNT ROSE,
COLORADO, IN
2009.
BEFORE
ENLISTING IN THE UNITED
STATES NAVY.
FOR HIS CRITICAL
CONTRIBUTIONS
TO
THE SUCCESS OF OPERATION
AWEDSY DAWN, HE'S
BEEN PRESENTED
WITH THE JOINT
SERVICE
ACHIEVEMENT MEDAL
AND IS AN
EXAMPLE TO THE
CITIZENS OF
COLORADO AND TO THE UNITED
STATES OF AMERICA.
MR. SPEAKER,
IT IS AN HONOR TO
RECOGNIZE
INTELLIGENCE
SPECIALIST
SEAMAN ANTHONY T.
SHMAT
LS.
I
YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE
GENTLELADY FROM
TEXAS RISE?
MS. JACKSON LEE: THE HOUSE
IS
NOT IN ORDER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLELADY IS
CORRECT, THE
HOUSE
IS NOT IN ORDER.
PLEASE TAKE YOUR
CONVERSATIONS
OFF THE FLOOR OF THE HOUSE.
WOULD MEMBERS
AT THE REAR OF
THE
CHAMBER TAKE YOUR
CONVERSATIONS OFF THE FLOOR OF
THE HOUSE.
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM TEXAS IS
RECOGNIZED FOR ONE
MINUTE.
MS. JACKSON LEE: I
THANK THE
SPEAKER
VERY MUCH.
WHAT I LIKE
ABOUT
THE
UNIVERSITY OF
HOUSTON IS ONE,
MANY OF THEIR
CAMPUSES ARE IN
THE
18TH CONGRESSIONAL DISTRICT
BUT THEY BELIEVE A
UNIVERSITY,
AS THEY SEEK TYRE
ONE STATUS,
IS
BEST WHEN THEY SUPPORT
ACADEMIC
EXCELLENCE AND OF
COURSE
ATHLETIC EXCELLENCE.
I'M PLEASED TODAY TO
SHOW THIS
PICTURE
OF U-H STUDENTS
STANDING IN
LINE -- U OF H
STUDENTS
STANDING IN LINE FOR
THE CHAMPIONSHIP GAME
THAT THE
COUGARS HAVE MANAGED
TO HAVE A
12-0
SEASON AND NOW ARE THE
CONFERENCE
U.S.A. WEST DIVISION
CHAMPIONS
AND WILL PLAY THEIR
CHAMPIONSHIP GAME
AT ROBERTSON
STADIUM WITH ONE OF
THEIR
OPPONENTS.
WE'RE EXCITED ABOUT
COUGARS,
WE'RE
COUGAR RED, WE THINK
THE
COACH FOR NOT BEING
INTERESTED
IN WHERE HE GOS
NEXT YEAR BUT
FOCUSED ON THE
KIDS AND THE
CHAMPIONSHIP.
COACH
KEVIN -- YOU ARE THE
BEST.
TO THE LEADERSHIP
OF THE
UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON AND
THE
STUDENTS, I WANT
TO STAY ON
--
TO SAY ON THE FLOOR
OF THE
HOUSE,
WE'RE ALL RED ABOUT
THIS,
AND THANK YOU FOR BEING A
FINE
INSTITUTION THAT CARES
ABOUT THE STUDENT
IS READY TO
HAVE OUTREACH TO
YOUNG PEOPLE.
THEY ARE
GOING TO PLAY ON
SATURDAY.
GO, CUE GARS, IT'S
GOING TO BE
A GREAT
DAY.
ER YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
PLEASE
DIRECT ALL COMMENTS
TO THE
CHAIR, NOT TO THE
VIEWING
AUDIENCE.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
RISE?
&gt;&gt; TO
ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE AND REVISE AND EXTEND.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR ONE
MINUTE.
&gt;&gt; THANK YOU, MR. SPEAKER.
NOVEMBER IS
NATIONAL
ALZHEIMER'S
DISEASE
AWARENESS
MONTH.
AS THIS MONTH
COMING TO A --
COMES TO A CLOSE,
I WANT TO
DRAW
ATTENTION TO THE
ALZHEIMER'S
BREAKTHROUGH ACT.
WITH OVER FIVE MILLION
AMERICANS
SUFFERING FROM THIS
DEGENERATIVE DISEASE OF
THE
BRAIN,
ALZHEIMER'S IS THE SIXTH
LEADING CAUSE OF
DEATH IN THE
UNITED STATES.
IT'S PRNT TO
WORK TO FIND A
CURE TO EASE THE
SUFFERING OF
THOSE
WHO ARE AFFECTED AS WELL
AS THEIR
FAMILIES.
MR. PAULSEN:
THE ALZHEIMER'S
BREAKTHROUGH ACT
WOULD
ENCOURAGE
PUBLIC-PRIVATE
PARTNERSHIPS AND HELP THEM
PURSUE THE DEVELOPMENT
OF
ALZHEIMER'S
TREATMENTS.
AS
A CO-SPONSOR OF THIS
LEGISLATION, I DO
ASK MY
COLLEAGUES WHETHER
YOU HAVE A
LOVED ONE
AFFECTED BY THIS
DISEASE OR NOT TO
SIGN ON AS A
CO-SPONSOR OF THIS
LEGISLATION
SO WE CAN FIND
A CURE TO
THIS
TERRIBLE
DISEASE.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM GEORGIA
RISE?
&gt;&gt; TO
ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR
ONE
MINUTE.
&gt;&gt; MR. SPEAKER,
I THANK YOU FOR
THE TIME.
WE'VE JUST
GOTTEN BACK FROM
THANKSGIVING, A
UNIQUELY
AMERICAN
HOLIDAY.
WE ARE GRATEFUL
FOR THE
BLESSINGS
WE HAVE, BLESSINGS
THAT COME BOTH FROM
GOD THE
FATHER
AND BLESSINGS THAT COME
FROM
HAVING WON THE BIRTH
LOTTERY AND
BEING BORN AN
AMERICAN.
AS I WATCH THE CHALLENGES GOING
ON
AROUND THE GLOBE, I LOOK
AT
THE CHALLENGES IN
EUROPE, I
LOOK AT THE
CHALLENGES IN
AFRICA, I LOOK
AT THE
CHALLENGES IN
ASIA, WE NEED TO
BE PROUD.
MR. WOODALL:
WE NEED TO BE
PROUD
OF AMERICAN
EXCEPTIONALISM.
WE NEED
TO FOCUS ON THOSE
THINGS THAT EXIST HERE AND
HERE
ALONE,
MR. SPEAKER, IN THE
COMING WEEKS
WITH THE
CHALLENGES WE ARE
GOING TO
FACE.
LET US NOT LOOK
TO NATIONS
AROUND
THE WORLD AND SEE HOW
THEY ARE
DOING IT.
LET'S LOOK TO THE VALUES
AND
PRINCIPLES THAT HAVE
MADE THIS
COUNTRY
GREAT FOR OVER 200
YEARS AND LET'S
DOUBLE DOWN ON
THOSE.
I
YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: ARE
THERE
ANY FURTHER REQUESTS FOR
ONE
MINUTES?
THE CHAIR
LAYS BEFORE THE HOUSE
THE
FOLLOWING PERSONAL
REQUESTS.
THE CLERK: LEAVE
OF ABSENCE
REQUESTED
FOR MS. SUTTON OF
OHIO
FOR TODAY.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE REQUEST
IS GRANTED.
UNDER THE
SPEAKER'S ANNOUNCED
SPOIL
OF JANUARY 5, 2011, THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
CALIFORNIA, MR.
GARAMENDI
IS RECOGNIZED
FOR 60
MINUTES
AS THE DESIGNEE OF THE
MINORITY LEADER.
MR. GARAMENDI: MR. SPEAKER,
IT'S GOOD TO BE
BACK AND I HOPE
ALONG WITH ALL
MY COLLEAGUES, I
HOPE
ALL MY COLLEAGUES HAD AS
ENJOYABLE A THANKSGIVING AS I
DID WITH MY
FAMILY AND WITH OUR
CONSTITUENTS BACK
IN OUR
DISTRICT.
WE HAVE MUCH TO BE THANKFUL
FOR.
AFTER
ALL, THIS IS
AMERICA.
THIS HAS ALWAYS
BEEN THE PLACE
OF DREAMS.
THIS IS AMERICA, IT'S ALWAYS
BEEN THE PLACE
WHERE PEOPLE
FOUND OPPORTUNITY.
WHERE
WHATEVER THEY WANTED TO
DO,
THEY COULD ACHIEVE IT.
AND IT'S
STILL THAT AMERICA
TODAY.
BUT IT'S
UP TO US IN THE THIRD
YEAR OF
THIS RECESSION TO
RESTORE THE AMERICAN DREAM.
AND
THERE ARE WAYS WE CAN DO
IT.
AND TONIGHT, TOGETHER
WITH MY
COLLEAGUES
WHO WILL SOON BE
JOINING
ME, WE'LL TALK ABOUT
VARIOUS WAYS IN
WHICH THE
DEMOCRATS IN THIS HOUSE
WILL,
AND
HAVE, MADE NUMEROUS PROPOSE
OLS
-- PROPOSALS TO RESTORE THE
AMERICAN DREAM.
I WAS
OUT IN THE DISTRICT FOR
FIVE
OF THE DAYS WE WERE GONE,
TALKING TO
PEOPLE, AND MANY OF
THEM,
IN FACT, ONE FELLOW WHO
HAS
A BOOK BINDING COMPANY, 85
YEARS OLD, ABOUT
TO RETIRE AND
TURN THAT
COMPANY
OVER TO HIS
EMPLOYEES, WAS
TALKING ABOUT
THE
ENORMOUS STRENGTH OF THIS
NATION.
HE WAS SHARING THE STORY OF
HIMSELF AN HIS
EMPLOYEES AND
THE
WAY IN WHICH THEY CAME
HERE,
MANY STRUGGLED FROM VERY
BAD
SITUATIONS IN OTHER
COUNTRIES.
BUT THEY CAME HERE WITH
OPTIMISM.
THEY CAME HERE
WITH A TRUE
BELIEF
THAT IN AMERICA YOU CAN
MAKE IT IF
YOU FOLLOW THE
RULES, IF YOU
WORK HARD, YOU
CAN
MAKE IT.
YOU CAN
HAVE A GOOD LIFE.
YOU CAN TAKE CARE
OF YOUR
FAMILY.
UNFORTUNATELY FOR ALL TOO MANY
AMERICANS, THAT'S NOT THE
CASE
TODAY.
SO
RESTORING THE AMERICAN DREAM
IS OUR TASK.
WE
CAN DO IT.
THE PRESIDENT
MORE THAN TWO
MONTHS
AGO PROPOSED THE
AMERICAN JOBS
ACT.
A
PROPOSAL THAT WOULD PUT TWO
MILLION OR THREE
MILLION
AMERICANS BACK TO
WORK
IMMEDIATELY.
TONIGHT ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF
THIS
NATION'S CAPITAL, THE U.S.
SENATE
IS DEBATING A PORTION OF
THAT AMERICAN
JOBS ACT.
A PORTION OF IT
THAT IS A VERY,
VERY
SIGNIFICANT TAX CUT FOR
MEN AND WOMEN THAT ARE
WORKING.
THEIR SOCIAL SECURITY PAYMENTS
WOULD BE
REDUCED BY 50%.
NO LONGER
WOULD THEY PAY 6.2%
OF THEIR WAGE
INTO THE SOCIAL
SECURITY
FUND,
THEY WOULD PAY
3.1%.
AND FOR
THEIR EMPLOYERS, THE
SAME REDUCTION.
PROVIDING A VERY
POWERFUL
INCENTIVE
FOR INDIVIDUALS TO
HAVE MONEY IN THEIR
POCKETS
ABOUT
$1,500 A YEAR.
MONEY IN
THEIR POCKETS SO THAT
THEY
COULD PARTICIPATE IN
BUYING
GIFTS FOR THEIR
CHILDREN.
AS WE
LOOK TO CHRISTMAS, WE
KNOW THERE ARE
MANY, MANY
AMERICANS
THAT ARE NOT GOING TO
BE ABLE TO
DO THAT.
MR. SPEAKER,
IT'S TIME FOR
US
IN THIS HOUSE
TO FOLLOW THE
LEAD OF
THE PRESIDENT.
AND TO
GIVE EVERY AMERICAN
WORKER,
98% OF AMERICANS, A
VERY SIGNIFICANT TAX
REDUCTION.
$1,500
BY REDUCING THAT SOCIAL
SECURITY TAX.
AND FOR THEIR
EMPLOYERS, THE
SAME.
UP
TO, IF THEIR EMPLOYERS ARE
UP TO
$50 MILLION OF PAYROLL
THEY
CAN REDUCE BY 50% THEIR
SOCIAL SECURITY
TAX.
SO THAT THAT
EMPLOYER HAS MORE
MONEY TO HIRE PEOPLE
THAT
DEBATE IS
GOING ON IN THE U.S.
SENATE TODAY.
UNFORTUNATELY, HERE
IN THIS
HOUSE,
WE HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO
EVEN TAKE UP
THAT ISSUE.
WE SHOULD.
BECAUSE IT'S PART OF WHAT WE
MUST DO TO PUT
AMERICANS BACK
TO WORK.
TO
GIVE THEM A BREAK.
NOW JOINING ME
IN THIS
DISCUSSION
TONIGHT AS WE TALK
ABOUT
RESTORING THE AMERICAN
DREAM AND ABOUT THE
THINGS WE
CAN DO TO
MAKE THAT HAPPEN IS
MY
COLLEAGUE
FROM THE GREAT
STATE OF
NEW YORK, WE HAVE
OFTEN BEEN
HERE, WE CALL
OURSELVESES THE
EAST-WEST TEAM.
AND MR.
TONKO, GOOD TO SEE YOU
BACK.
I HOPE YOU HAD AS
GOOD A
THANKSGIVING
AS I DID.
I'M
SURE YOU WORKED AS HARD IN
YOUR DISTRICT
AS I DID DURING
THOSE DAYS SYSTEM OF
PLEASE
SHARE WITH US AND
WELCOME BACK.
MR. TONKO:
THANK YOU,
REPRESENTATIVE
GARAMENDI, AND
THANK YOU
FOR LEADING US IN
AN
HOUR OF
DISCUSSION A DIALOGUE
THAT'S MOST
CRITICAL TO THE
ECONOMIC
VIABILITY, THE
COMEBACK OF AMERICA'S
MIDDLE CLASS.
YOU TALK ABOUT SOME OF
THESE
INCENTIVES THAT WOULD BE
ADDRESSED THROUGH A
PAYROLL TAX
DEDUCTION.
IT'S ALL ABOUT
EMPOWERING OUR
MIDDLE CLASS.
ENHANCING
THEIR PURCHASING
POWER.
ENABLING US TO
ENHANCE THAT
DEMAND OUT THERE FOR
PRODUCTS
THAT
THEN OBVIOUSLY TRANSLATES
INTO JOB
GROWTH BECAUSE WITH
MORE DEMAND UPON
MANUFACTURERS
IN THIS
COUNTRY, WITH MORE
CONSUMER
CONFIDENCE, WITH
ABSOLUTE
INCREASE IN PURCHASING
POWER, THERE WILL BE
A POSITIVE
OUTCOME.
THERE'S NO DENYING THAT
UNEMPLOYMENT IS
DRIVING THE
DEFICIT.
AND
IF WE CAN TURN THAT AROUND
IF WE CAN
INVEST IN WAYS THAT
ENHANCE
THE MIDDLE CLASS,
THAT'S
GOOD FOR ALL STRATA, ALL
INCOME
STRATA IN THIS NATION.
WHAT'S BEEN LOST IN THE
LONLIC
HERE FOR
THE MAJORITY IS THAT
THE
EMPOWERMENT OF THE MIDDLE
CLASS STANDS TO
PRODUCE GAINS
FOR EVERYBODY.
AND WITH WE SAW
WHAT HAPPENED
IN THE
BUILDUP BEFORE OUR ENTRY
HERE INTO
THE HOUSE.
IN THE PERIOD
OF THE RECESSION.
IT WAS ALL
ABOUT BORROWING,
TOTALLY, THE MONEY
THAT WAS
NECESSARY TO SPEND
ON
A TAX CUT
FOR MILLIONAIRES
AND
BILLIONAIRES.
SOME WOULD SUGGEST THOSE ARE
THE
JOB
CREATORS.
BUT WHAT HAPPENED WAS, WE
REALIZED
8.2 MILLION JOBS LOST.
SO THAT
DIDN'T WORK.
WE
OUGHT NOT GO BACK AN REVISIT
THAT FORMULA BECAUSE IT WAS
NOT
A
FORMULA FOR SUCCESS.
WHAT WE NEED HERE
IS TO BRING
ABOUT THE
LONG OVERDUE
EMPOWERMENT
OF THE MIDDLE CLASS
AND IT IS WORKING
FAMILIES
ACROSS
THIS COUNTRY THAT NEED
THAT
ASSISTANCE TODAY AND BY
THE WAY, IT
WORKS FOR EVERY --
IN
EVERYBODY'S FAVOR.
SO
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE PROMOTING.
IT'S GOOD TO START OFF
WITH
THAT
DISCUSSION.
BECAUSE
AS WE MOVE FORWARD,
INVESTMENTS ARE WHAT IT'S
ABOUT.
INVESTING OUR WAY TO
PROSPERITY,
INVESTING OUR WAY
TO OPPORTUNITY,
INVESTING OUR
WAY TO
A STRONGER TOMORROW, FOR
ALL HERS.
IT'S NOT GOING
TO COME BY
CUTTING
INTO SITUATIONS THAT
RELIEVE THE LIABILITY.
THE RESPONSIBILITY
OF THOSE WHO
HAVE
BEEN MOST PROFITABLE HERE.
THAT
DIDN'T WORK.
THAT IS NOT GOING
TO BE THE
FORMULA
FOR A COMEBACK FOR MOST
AMERICANS.
WHAT WE NEED
IS TO BE
SENSIVETIVE TO THE
INVESTMENT
IN
EDUCATION, HIGHER EDUCATION
IN SOUNDER TAX
POLICY, REFORMS
OF TAX
POLICY, AND CERTAINLY
INVESTMENT AND RESEARCH.
AS WE INVEST IN
RESEARCH, THAT
EQUALS
JOBS.
AND
THAT'S STILL THE HIGHEST
PRIORITY OF
AMERICA'S GENERAL
PUBLIC OUT
THERE.
WE NEED JOBS AND
THE DIGNITY OF
WORK IS WHAT
OUGHT TO BE FRONT
AN CENTER FOR
THE WORK WE DO
HERE IN
PUBLIC POLICY FORMAT
AND
RESOURCE ADVOCACY, TO GO
FORWARD AND
HERALD THE NEED OF
THE
MIDDLE
CLASS.
MR. GARAMENDI:
THANK YOU SO
MUCH.
THE EXPERIENCES WE HAVE
AS WE
RETURN TO
OUR DISTRICT AND TALK
TO
OUR CONSTITUENTS AND SHARE
WITH OUR FAMILY,
THESE ARE THE
STORIES OF LIFE, THESE
ARE THE
STORIES
OF REAL AMERICANS, NOT
THAT WE'RE NOT
REAL, WE'VE GOT
A SPECIAL
TASK AS THEIR
REPRESENTATIVES, TO REPRESENT
THEM HERE.
AND THEY DO
WANT JOBS, THEY
WANT TO GO BACK
TO WORK.
WE KNOW MANY
OF THEM ARE UNABLE
TO FIND
JOBS.
THE AMERICAN
JOBS ACT DID HAVE
IN ADDITION TO THE TAX
ISSUES I
JUST
TALKED ABOUT, THERE WAS
ANOTHER PROVISION
THAT I MUST
SAY, WE
ACTUALLY GOT SOMETHING
DONE JUST BEFORE THE
THANKSGIVING RECESS AND
THAT
WAS FOR THE
VETERANS.
THIS
WAS PART OF THE
PRESIDENT'S
PROPOSAL THAT
ACTUALLY DID
BECOME LAW AND
WHAT HE WANTED TO
DO AND WE
AGREED WITH HIM
WAS TO GIVE
VETERANS THOSE MEN
AND WOMEN
THAT ARE
OUT THERE FIGHTING FOR
THIS COUNTRY
IN
IRAQ AN
AFGHANISTAN AND EVEN
WAY BACK
INTO
THE VIETNAM WAR AND THE
FIRST
GULF WAR, GIVE THOSE
VETERANS A CHANCE
FOR A JOB.
AND THERE'S
A VERY SPECIAL TAX
PROVISION
THAT'S TOTALLY PAID
FOR,
NOT BORROWED, THAT WE
VOTED OUT OF HERE SO
EMPLOYERS
GOT A TAX CREDIT,
A REDUCTION
IN
THEIR TACKS FOR EVERY
VETERAN
THEY HIRED, $5,600 FOR
AN
UNEMPLOYED VETERAN OR $9,600
FOR A
DISABLED VETERAN.
I'M VERY, VERY
PLEASED WE WERE
ABLE TO
DO THAT FOR THE
VETERANS.
THAT'S ONE VERY IMPORTANT
SLICE
OF THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC THAT IS
FACING
UNEMPLOYMENT, BUT THERE
ARE MANY, MANY
MORE.
IF
I COULD JUST PICK UP FOR A
SECOND ON
A COUPLE OF WORDS YOU
SAID YOU
TALKED ABOUT
INVESTMENT.
IN THE AMERICAN JOBS ACT,
THERE'S
A VERY, VERY
IMPORTANT
INVESTMENT, AND
YOU MENTIONED
IT.
IT'S
THE EDUCATION INVESTMENT.
THE PRESIDENT
OPROPOSED THAT WE
SPEND ABOUT
$30 BILLION TO KEEP
TEACHERS
IN THE CLASSROOM NOW
SO THAT OUR
KIDS WOULD BE ABLE
TO CONTINUE TO
LEARN.
THAT'S
THE FUTURE AND IF THEY
MISS A YEAR OF
LEARNING,
THEY'RE
GOING TO BE BEHIND THE
REST OF THEIR
LIVES AND SO HE
PROPOSED THAT, IT'S STILL
OUT
THERE, STILL
OPEN, HASN'T HAD A
CHANCE TO COME FORWARD
YET BUT
WE'LL
SEE.
MAYBE WE CAN
GET THAT ONE DONE.
A
CRITICAL INVESTMENT IN YOUR
CHILDREN.
WHAT'S MORE IMPORTANT
THAN OUR
CHILDREN?
MR.
TONKO: REPRESENTATIVE
GARAMENDI,
AS YOU TALK ABOUT
THAT, THE LOSS IN ANY
GIVEN
YEAR, WHERE
A STUDENT MAY LOSE
THE
OPPORTUNITY IN THE
CLASSROOM BECAUSE OF THESE
CUTS
THAT ARE SIGNIFICANT TO
EDUCATION, THAT IS
ONE
MEASUREMENT, BUT
LET ME SUGGEST
ANOTHER.
WE SEE
AN AGGRESSIVE
INVESTMENT
GOING ON
AROUND THE WORLD IN
EMERGING
POWERS OUT THERE THAT
ARE NATIONS
COMPETING WITH US
IN THAT GLOBAL
MARKETPLACE,
CLEAN
ENERGY, INNOVATION, AND
IDEAS
ECONOMY.
AN IDEAS ECONOMY
IS A
ROBUST
OPPORTUNITY FOR
A
SOPHISTICATED
NATION LIKE
HOURS, BUT IT
REQUIRES
COMMITMENT, COMMITMENT
TO
INVESTMENT.
INVESTMENT IN EDUCATION.
WE TAKE THAT INTELLECTUAL
CAPACITY AND WE MAKE IT
WORK.
WE DID
THAT IN THE SPACE RACE OF
THE
1960'S.
PRESIDENT KENNEDY, RATHER
YOUTHFUL PRESIDENT IN HIS
TIME,
OFFERED A
CHALLENGE TO AMERICA,
OFFERED A CHALLENGE IN
A WAY
THAT
ENABLED US TO INVEST IN
RESEARCH
THAT ENABLED US TO WIN
THE GLOBAL RACE
ON SPACE.
THAT WAS AN UNLEASHING
OF
TECHNOLOGY
, AN ALL -- IN ALL
TOLD SECTORS OF THE
ECONOMY AND
FROM EVERY
PERSPECTIVE OF
QUALITY OF LIFE
THAT WAS
ENHANCED BY THE INVESTMENTS THAT
WERE MADE.
MR. GARAMENDI: MR.
TONKO, WE'RE
GOING TO INTERRUPT
OUR DIALOGUE
HERE FOR
A FEW MOMENTS.
I RECOGNIZE OUR
COLLEAGUE FROM
THE RULES
COMMITTEE HAS SOME
WORK THAT NEEDS TO BE
CARRIED
OUT.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM GEORGIA RISE?
&gt;&gt; MR. SPEAKER, I SEND TO THE
DESK A PRIVILEGED REPORT FROM
THE COMMITTEE ON RULES
FOR
FILING UNDER THE RULE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CLERK WILL REPORT THE
TITLE.
THE CLERK: REPUBLICAN TO
ACCOMPANY HOUSE RESOLUTION
477,
RESOLUTION
PROVIDING FOR
CONSIDERATION OF THE
BILL H.R.
3463,
TO REDUCE FEDERAL SPENDING
AND THE
DEFICIT BY TERMINATING
TAXPAYER
FINANCING OF
PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION
CAMPAIGNS
AND PARTY
CONVENTIONS AND BY
TERMINATING
THE ELECTION
ASSISTANCE COMMISSION,
PROVIDING
FOR CONSIDERATION
OF THE BILL
H.R.
527, TO AMEND THE CHAPTER 6
OF TITLE
5, UNITED STATES CODE,
COMMONLY
KNOWN AS THE REGULATORY
FLEXIBILITY ACT, TO
ASSURE
COMPLETE
ANALYSIS OF POTENTIAL
IMPACTS ON
SMALL ENTITIES OF
RULES AND
FOR OTHER PURPOSES.
AND
PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION
OF THE BILL H.R.
3010, TO REFORM
THE PROCESS
BY WHICH FEDERAL
AGENCIES
ANALYZE AND FORMULATE
NEW REGULATIONS
AND GUIDANCE
DOCUMENTS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
REFERRED TO THE HOUSE CALENDAR
AND ORDERED
PRINTED.
MR. WOODALL: I THANK MY FRIEND
FOR YIELDING.
MR. GARAMENDI:
I THANK OUR
COLLEAGUE FROM GEORGIA FOR
BRINGING FORTH THESE
PIECES OF
LEGISLATION.
I WON'T COMMENT ON THEM NOW BUT
I WILL A LITTLE LATER
AS TO
WHETHER
-- WE'LL JUST LET IT GO.
TALK
ABOUT IT TOMORROW.
THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
MR. TONKO, YOU WERE
TALKING
ABOUT
THE NEED FOR INVESTMENT
AND
INDEED IN THE AREA OF
EDUCATION AND RESEARCH
, CRITICAL
FUNCTIONS,
I
DO WANT TO STAY
WITH THAT
SUBJECT FOR A WHILE
BUT I
NOTICED OUR COLLEAGUE
FROM
THE
GREAT STATE OF OHIO HAS
JOINED US
, MRS. BETTY SUTTON.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR BEING
WITH US THIS
EVENING.
I
KNOW THAT YOU, TOO, HAD A
FAMILY AND A
CONSTITUENCY TO
WORK
WITH THIS LAST WEEK.
SO PLEASE SHARE
WITH US YOUR
THOUGHTS.
MS. SUTTON: WELL, I THANK
THE
GENTLEMAN, REPRESENTATIVE
GARAMENDI, YOU'VE
JUST DONE A
TREMENDOUS JOB IN LEADING
THE
WAY,
SHOWING THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE, BECAUSE WE ALL KNOW THAT
THINGS
DON'T HAVE TO BE THE WAY
THAT THEY ARE.
WE ALL KNOW THAT WE
CAN INVEST
IN THE
THINGS THAT HAVE ALWAYS
MADE
OUR COUNTRY STRONG, THINGS
LIKE EDUCATION, THAT
WE KNOW NOT
HOME
STRENGTHENS THE INDIVIDUAL
BUT
IS KEY TO THE SUCCESS OF
OUR
FUTURE.
INVESTING IN POLICIES THAT WILL
ENABLE US TO MAKE
IT IN AMERICA,
AND WHEN WE
TALK ABOUT AMERICA
IT
IN AMERICA, REPRESENTATIVE
GARAMENDI,
AND, REPRESENTATIVE
TONKO,
I KNOW THAT WE'RE OFTEN
TALKING ABOUT
MANUFACTURING AND
COMING FROM OHIO
, MANUFACTURING
OF COURSE IS NOT
JUST A PART OF
OUR PAST AND OUR
HISTORY, IT'S A
STRONG PART OF WHAT IS GOING
TO
MAKE US
SUCCESSFUL IN THE
FUTURE.
AND I WILL TELL YOU
, I'M EXCITED
BECAUSE
IN THE COMING DAYS I'LL
BE INTRODUCING
A NUMBER OF BILLS
THAT ARE ALL
RELATED TO HOW WE
CAN
STRENGTHEN U.S.
MANUFACTURING
AND BOLSTER U.S.
MANUFACTURING FOR
OUR WORKERS
AND
OUR PRODUCTIVITY RIGHT HERE
IN THE
UNITED STATES.
SO, I'M GRATEFUL TO BE DOWN
HERE
WITH YOU AND
I CAN JUST TELL
YOU,
I WENT OUT AND I TALKED TO
OUR
FOLKS AND THERE IS A GROWING
BELIEF THAT
THERE IS A BETTER
WAY,
THERE'S A COMPREHENSIVE
UNDERSTANDING THAT
THINGS HAVE
NOT
BEEN FAIR.
THAT THE DECK HAS
BEEN STACKED.
AND THAT THERE'S
STILL THOSE
HERE WHO ARE TRYING
TO PROTECT
THE WEALTHIEST
AND THE
MOST
PRIVILEGED
AT THE EXPENSE OF THE
OTHERS.
AND THAT'S WHY I'M SO GRATEFUL
TO HAVE THE CHANCE
TO BE HERE
AND FIGHT
ALONGSIDE YOU AND
REPRESENTATIVE TONKO
AND OTHERS
AND REPRESENTATIVE
JACKSON LEE
HAS JOINED
US
HERE FROM TEXAS.
BECAUSE IN THE LAST
ELECTION WE
HEARD OVER AND OVER
AGAIN,
OFTENTIMES THAT
REFRAIN
OF,
PEOPLE DON'T
WANT A GOVERNMENT
ON
THEIR BACK.
AND
I AGREE AND I KNOW YOU DO
TOO THAT
PEOPLE DON'T WANT A
GOVERNMENT ON THEIR BACK.
BUT
THEY DO WANT A
GOVERNMENT ON
THEIR
SIDE.
AND THAT'S
WHAT WE'RE HERE TO
MAKE SURE THAT
THEY GET, BECAUSE
THAT IS
NOT WHAT THEY'RE GETTING
WITH THE
REPUBLICAN LEGISLATOR
AS IT
EXISTS TODAY
--
LEGISLATURE AS IT
EXISTS TODAY.
SO, CARRY
ON, REPRESENTATIVE
GARAMENDI, AND COUNT
ME IN AS
SOMEBODY WHO
SUPPORTS IN THOSE
INVESTMENTS IN
EDUCATION AND IN
MAKING
IT
IN AMERICA.
MR. GARAMENDI: INDEED
YOU
CARRIED MANY
PIECES OF
LEGISLATION.
I LIKED YOUR
ONE, WHAT IS IT,
DON'T FLUSH AMERICA DOWN THE
DRAIN?
HAVING TO DO WITH REBUILDING OUR
SANITATION SYSTEMS
HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES.
MS. SUTTON: REPRESENTATIVE
GARAMENDI,
IF YOU'LL YIELD JUST
A
MOMENT.
THE NAME OF THE BILL, JUST TO
SET THE RECORD VERY
CLEAR IS,
STOP AMERICAN
JOBS FROM GOING
DOWN THE
DRAIN ACT.
AND
THE WHOLE POINT OF THAT BILL
IS
THAT WHEN WE ARE BUILDING OUR
INFRASTRUCTURE,
OUR WATER AND
SEWER SYSTEMS, AS YOU
POINT OUT,
THAT
REALLY NEED TO BE BUILT IN
THIS COUNTRY AND OF COURSE IT
WOULD PUT PEOPLE TO
WORK, IT
WOULD HELP
OUR COMMUNITIES, SPUR
OUR ECONOMY
AND IF WE DO IT
USING U.S.
-MANUFACTURED GOODS
AND
IRON AND STEEL WHICH IS WHAT
THE BILL WOULD REQUIRE,
THEN WE
PUT EVEN
MORE PEOPLE TO WORK
WHILE WE'RE
STRENGTHENING OUR
COMMUNITIES.
SO, YES, STOP AMERICAN JOBS FROM
GOING DOWN THE DRAIN ACT.
MR. GARAMENDI: I
APPRECIATE YOUR
CORRECTION
OF MY
CHARACTERIZATION OF THE
BILL.
BUT IT NONETHELESS
WAS A GREAT
PIECE
OF LEGISLATION AND IT'S
PART
OF THE MAKE IT IN AMERICA
AGENDA.
USING OUR TAX MONEY, IN THIS
CASE TO BUILD THE
SANITATION
SYSTEMS,
THE WATER SYSTEMS, AND
REQUIRING THAT
THAT MONEY BE
USED TO
BUY AMERICAN-MADE
EQUIPMENT.
I HAVE A BILL THAT WOULD DO THE
SAME THING FOR
SOLAR, WIND
PROGRAMS, WIND
TURBINES, SOLAR,
AS
WELL AS FOR TRAINS, BUSES AND
THE
LIKE.
IT'S
OUR TAX MONEY, USE IT TO
BUY AMERICAN-MADE EQUIPMENT.
THAT'S PART OF THE DEMOCRATIC
AGENDA.
AND
IT WORKS.
I
CAN GIVE SOME EXAMPLES A
LITTLE LATER.
I DON'T WANT TO TAKE UP
TOO MUCH
TIME
BUT I DO WANT TO THANK YOU
BECAUSE THERE'S
NOBODY WORKING
HARDER
IN THIS
ENTIRE CAPITOL
BUILDING,
DEMOCRAT, REPUBLICAN
OR THE
SENATE, THAN YOU ARE IN
REBUILDING
THE MANUFACTURING
CENTER
OF AMERICA.
THE
GREAT STATE OF OHIO.
NOW, TEXAS
IS A LITTLE FAR FROM
OHIO, BUT YOU'VE
GOT A FEW
THINGS GOING FOR YOU IN TEXAS,
TOO, DON'T
YOU?
LET ME INTRODUCE AND
BRING TO
OUR
COLLOQUY HERE SHEILA JACKSON
LEE.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US ONCE
AGAIN.
IT'S GOOD TO BE BACK FROM
THANKSGIVING, WHERE
WE WERE WITH
OUR CONSTITUENTS
AND OUR
FAMILIES.
MS. JACKSON LEE: IT'S A DELIGHT
TO HAVE BEEN HERE WITH THE
GENTLELADY FROM OHIO.
WE WORKED TOGETHER
CLOSELY.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM NEW YORK.
I ALWAYS WANT TO ASK
HIM
HOW HIS
FAIR
CONSTITUENTS ARE DEALING,
THEY HAD SOME SERIOUS MOUNTAINS
TO CLIMB, IF YOU WILL, WITH
THEIR RECENT HURRICANE, A VERY
UNUSUAL SET OF CIRCUMSTANCES.
WE JOIN TOGETHER TO ALLOW THOSE
COMMUNITIES TO COME BACK,
WOULDN'T THAT
BE A PERFECT
INVESTMENT OF
REBUILDING
INFRASTRUCTURE
?
MR.
GARAMENDI, LET ME THANK YOU
FOR YOUR
LONGSTANDING HISTORY OF
PUTTING THINGS BACK
TOGETHER.
I'M NOT GOING TO
CALL YOU THE
HUMP
TY DUMTY MAN
.
LET
ME SHARE SOME ANECDOTAL
UNIQUENESS TO THIS QUESTION OF
MAKE IT IN AMERICA.
I HOPE EVERYBODY HAD
A WONDERFUL
THANKSGIVING.
IT'S A SPECIAL HOLIDAY WHERE WE
FIND TIME TO SAY
THANKS.
I HEARD
THAT THE GENTLEMAN FROM
NEW YORK MIGHT HAVE BEEN
GIVEN A
HAM, MADE
IN AMERICA.
AND
I KNOW THAT THE PEOPLE WHO
RECEIVE THE HAM
WERE GRATEFUL
FOR IT.
I
HAD THE OPPORTUNITY TO WORK
WITH THOSE, WE
HAD OVER 800
TURKEYS
MADE IN AMERICA, TO BE
ABLE TO GIVE TO TO
SENIORS AND
FAMILY
-- TO BE ABLE TO GIVE TO
SENIORS AND
FAMILY.
THE JOY OF COURSE WAS
IN THE
GIVING BUT
MORE IMPORTANTLY IT
WAS
A PRODUCT THAT WE
MADE FROM
START TO
FINISH.
YES, IT'S
FOOD.
AS WE WENT DOWN
THE AISLES
OF
THE MANY GROCERY
STORES, SINCE
THOSE WERE THE
HIGHLIGHTS
OF
THAT SEASON
, EATING, PEOPLE WERE
BUYING GOODS
IN MOST INSTANCES
THAT WERE MADE IN
AMERICA.
AND THEY BOUGHT THEM.
AND
THEN OF COURSE THAT FAMOUS
FRIDAY
THAT WE CAN NOW
TUOT TO
BE THE
BEST FRIDAY --
TOUT TO BE
THE BEST FRIDAY OVER A NUMBER OF
YEARS.
$52 BILLION WAS
SPENT BY
AMERICANS
IN MANY INSTANCES ON
THE ELECTRONIC GOODS THAT WERE
MADE
IN AMERICA.
STEVE JOBS IS
NO LONGER
WITH US,
BUT HE
CREATED THAT
INFRASTRUCTURE
OF TECHNOLOGY AND
SOFTWARE AND THE
SOPHISTICATION
OF PRETTY THINGS THAT
MANY
AMERICANS
WENT TO BUY.
SOME
$7 BILLION OVER 2010 AND
THE STUDIES
INDICATED THAT
AMERICANS
WERE BUYING FIRST FOR
THEMSELVES,
THOSE ELECTRONIC
ITEMS THAT THEY
WANTED TO HAVE
FOR THIS
HOLIDAY SEASON.
AS
I BEGIN TO LOOK AT
LEGISLATION, TO
TALK ABOUT JOBS,
I'M GOING
TO TRY TO MAKE
THE
ENERGY INDUSTRY A LITTLE BIT
MORE
FRIENDLY AND WE'LL BE
INTRODUCING
LEGISLATION THAT
TALKS ABOUT CREATING
JOBS IN
THAT INDUSTRY BUT
WORKING IN THE
ENVIRONMENTAL ASPECT OF IT.
FIXING THE COAST
LINE, FOR
EXAMPLE,
AS YOU WELL KNOW WE
HAVE
SUFFERED THROUGH HURRICANE
RITA, KATRINA,
IKE AND THE
DETERIORATION OF THE COAST
LINE.
SO SOMEBODY
WANTS TO STOP US
FROM GOING
DOWN THE DRAIN, I
WANT TO STOP
US FROM A
DISAPPEARING COAST LINE.
I WANT YOU
TO HAVE THE BEAUTIFUL
BEACHES, WHETHER IT IS IN
THE
ALABAMAS AND
LOUISIANA AND
TEXAS, THE
FLORIDAS OF THE
WORLD, THOSE COAST LINES HAVE
BEEN
DETERIORATING.
WE
CAN FIND WORK OR INDIVIDUALS
CAN HAVE
WORK IN FIXING THE
BEAUTIFUL COAST
LINES, EVEN IN
SOUTH CAROLINA
, I KNOW THAT THE
GENTLEMAN
WANTS THE COAST LINE
TO BE FIXED.
SO
THERE IS NOT A
LACK OF
OPPORTUNITY TO FIX
WORK.
JUST
HEARD MY GOOD FRIEND FROM
MASSACHUSETTS IN THE RULES
COMMITTEE INDICATE THAT
THERE
ARE BRIDGES
IN THE STATE OF
MASSACHUSETTS
, MY GOOD FRIEND,
MR. MCGOVERN, THAT ARE
OLDER IN
SOME STATES
AND THAT THEY NEED
TO BE FIXED
AND THAT WOULD BE A
SHARING OF THE
WEALTH, TO MANY,
MANY DIFFERENT DISTRICTS AND
STATES, IF
WE WERE TO ENGAGE AS
THE PRESIDENT WANTED US
TO DO TO
LOOK AT HOW
WE DO THE
INFRASTRUCTURE.
BUT MAKE IT IN AMERICA
IS
HAPPENING, RIGHT NOW
IN THE
CAROLINAS,
A YOUNG LADY IS
BRINGING HER
COMPANY BACK FROM
SRI LANKA AND SHE
IS USING THE
TEXTILE INDUSTRY,
I DON'T HAVE
ITS FULL NAME BUT IT
BEGINS WITH
MITT,
USING THE TEXTILE INDUSTRY
TO NOW
MAKE HER PRODUCT.
SO
I CAME TODAY TO SAY THAT I
HAVE HOPE,
I'M AN OPTIMIST, AND
MANY OF THE
ECONOMISTS THAT
WE'VE BEEN
LISTENING
TO, JESSE
SACHS,
FOR EXAMPLE, HAVE
INDICATED THAT
WE WORRY TOO MUCH
ABOUT THE DEFICIT AND THE DEBT.
NOT TO
IGNORE IT.
BUT WE REALLY SHOULD BE
WORRYING
ABOUT
INVESTING IN AMERICA,
REBUILDING
MAKE IT IN AMERICA,
INVESTING IN
INFRASTRUCTURE,
CREATING JOBS.
AND AMERICANS WILL DO WHAT THEY
DID ON LAST
FRIDAY, THE DATE WAS
NOVEMBER
26, I BELIEVE, IT MIGHT
HAVE
BEEN, LAST FRIDAY, 25, LAST
FRIDAY AND THEY WENT OUT AND
BOUGHT
GOODS, BY AND LARGE, MADE
IN
AMERICA.
LET'S DO
MORE OF THAT, LET'S
HAVE THE
INCENTIVES THAT THEY
NEED AND
BY THE WAY LET'S
ADD
THE SMALL BUSINESS
COMPONENT TO
IT.
WE HAD THE
BUY A SMALL BUSINESS
ON
SATURDAY, THESE SMALL
BUSINESSES ARE IN
AMERICA.
AND IF YOU
SUPPORT A SMALL
BUSINESS YOU SUPPORT ONE
OR TWO
OR
THREE OR FOUR EMPLOYEES.
SO, I AM
GRATEFUL, AS I SAID,
I'M GOING TO DO THIS COAST
LINE
BILL, I
CAN SEE JUST EONS OF
PERSON
BEING PUT TO WORK, I CAN
SEE MONEYS GOING
INTO REDUCE THE
DEFICIT, WE'LL JOIN THAT
WITH
THE DRAIN
, IF YOU WILL, THE
INFRASTRUCTURE FOR OUR
SEWAGE
AND
WASTEWATER, COMES UNDER
HOMELAND SECURITY, BY THE
WAY,
AND WE HAVE TO
PROTECT THAT.
SECURITY
ISSUES ARE ALSO THE
INFRASTRUCTURE OF
SECURITY,
PROVIDES JOBS AS
WELL.
I WANT TO
CLOSE ON THIS NOTE
WHICH IT
SOUNDS AS IF IT'S NOT
TIED IN BUT
IT IS.
IT REALLY IS
TIED IN.
WE HAVE
IN THE THANKSGIVING
BACKDROP WAS
THE ACKNOWLEDGMENT,
I'M NOT GOING
TO CALL IT
FAILURE, OF THE SUPERCOMMITTEE
THAT THEY COULD NOT COMPLETE
THEIR TASK.
LET ME -- ON THE RECORD, IVERB
SAID IT IN PUBLIC SETTINGS,
THANK THE COLLEAGUE THAT
ACCEPTED THE CHALLENGE.
BUT I WANT TO SAY TO MY
COLLEAGUES, LET US NOT BE
NONOPTIMISTIC.
LET US NOT BE
UNHAPPY OR
DISAPPOINTED
OR SAD.
FRANKLY
THE JOB OF THE CONGRESS
IS
TO FORMULATE THE VISION GOING
FORWARD ON THE BEHALF
OF THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE.
LET ME TELL YOU
WHY I SEE WE
HAVE
BEEN GIVEN AN OPPORTUNITY.
SOME PEOPLE
ONLY TALK ABOUT
DEFENSE.
I TALK ABOUT 46 MILLION
AMERICANS THAT ARE
ON SNAP.
HERE'S OUR CHANCE.
WE CAN TAKE THE WORKS
OF A
JEFFREY
SACHS, WE CAN TAKE THE
WORK
OF A MR. SPENS WHO TALKS
ABOUT INFRASTRUCTURE
INVESTMENT,
WE
CAN FIND THIS LONG-TERM CUTS
OF
$1 TRILLION LEAVING OUT
MEDICARE
AND SOCIAL SECURITY AND
MEDICAID AND WE CAN FIND
THEM IN
A WAY THAT
TALKS ABOUT BUSH TAX
CUTS BUT HAS
A THOUGHTFUL WAY OF
LOOKING AT TAX
REFORM AND THEN
WE CAN PUT OUR
VISION FORWARD
THAT INCLUDES MAKING IT
IN
AMERICA.
MY FRIENDS, WE MAKE
DEFENSE
PRODUCTS IN
AMERICA.
I DON'T WANT TO BE
A WAR
PROMOTER, I WANT OUR TROOPS
HOME, BUT I BELIEVE IN
MILITARY
PREPAREDNESS.
THOSE ARE JOBS.
WE HAVE A YEAR TO DO
IT.
WE CAN
THROW OFF THE SHACKLES OF
PARTISANSHIP
AND THOUGHTFULLY
PUT
FORWARD A LEGISLATIVE
INITIATIVE WHICH THE PRESIDENT
WILL NOT
VETO IF THERE IS A PLAN
THAT INCLUDES
REVENUE -- EXCUSE
ME, DEFICIT
REDUCTION.
DON'T
BE AFRAID OF DOING OUR
JOB.
SO, I'M
WILLING TO SAY WE HAVE
BEEN
GIVEN AN OPPORTUNITY, JUST
LIKE MY
CUGERS ARE BEING
GIVEN
AN OPPORTUNITY FOR A
CHAMPIONSHIP THIS COMING WEEKEND
AT THE UNIVERSITY
OF HOUSTON,
WHICH WILL BY THE
WAY CREATE A
LOT
OF REVENUE WITH FOLKS COMING
FROM ALL OVER.
BUT WE HAVE BEEN
GIVEN AN
OPPORTUNITY AND I AM GLAD WE'RE
HERE ON THE FLOOR
TO
POINT OUT
THAT IT IS
NOT THE END BUT IT IS
THE BEGINNING,
I SIMPLY ASK THAT
THERE
BE FRIENDS ON THE OTHER
SIDE OF THE AISLE
THAT WILL JOIN
US
IN REVENUE, JOB CREATION,
DEFICIT
REDUCTION, REVENUE, JOB
CREATION, WE
CAN PASS THESE
BILLS, WE
CAN JOIN THE SENATE,
WE CAN
DO THE
PAYROLL TAX RELIEF
FOR
A LITTLE BIT AND THE
UNEMPLOYMENT, BUT WE
CAN CREATE
JOBS AND THANK
THE GENTLEMAN FOR
ALLOWING ME TO
PARTICIPATE WITH
HIM,
EXCITED ABOUT THE
LEGISLATION
THAT MY COLLEAGUES
HAVE, KNOW
I'VE WORKED WITH
TONKO FOR ALL THAT
HE HAS DONE
IN
THE LEGISLATIVE INITIATIVE
AND ALSO
YOU, SO THANK YOU SO
VERY MUCH AND WITH THAT
I YIELD
BACK
TO THE GENTLEMAN WITH GREAT
OPTIMISM.
MR. GARAMENDI:
THANK YOU VERY
MUCH, YOU ARE ALWAYS ON
TOP OF
THE
ISSUES AND YOU ARE ALWAYS
VERY, VERY
CORRECT, SHEILA
JACKSON LEE, THANK YOU FOR
THE
ENORMOUS
AMOUNT OF WORK YOU'VE
DONE
FOR
YOUR CONSTITUENTS
.
YOU
MENTIONED YOUR -- THE SUPER
COMMITTEE, EVERYBODY SAID
IT
WAS A FAILURE AND
THEY DID NOT
ACHIEVE THE GOAL SET OUT.
HOWEVER THE PUBLIC
NEEDS TO
KNOW THAT THE
LEGISLATION THAT
SET
UP THE SUPER COMMITTEE,
REDUCED THE
DEFICIT OF THE
UNITED STATES
BY
$2.1
TRILLION.
A
$2.1 TRILLION REDUCTION IN
THE
DEFICIT AND IN THE
LEGISLATION THAT
ESTABLISHED
THE SUPER
COMMITTEE, $1
TRILLION IS
ALREADY GOING INTO
PLACE.
THE OTHER $1.2 TRILLION
WAS THE
SPECIFIC
TASK OF THE SUPER
COMMITTEE TO TRY
TO FIGURE OUT
IF THERE WAS
A BETTER WAY TO
MAKE THE CUTS.
OR
ADDING REVENUE.
THEY WERE
UP ABLE TO PUT THE
REVENUE TOGETHER BUT
THE CUTS
REMAIN.
THOSE ARE GOING
TO GO FORWARD.
YOU'RE QUITE
CORRECT, MS. LEE,
IT -- MS. JOHNSON
LEE, EXCUSE
ME.
THAT IT WILL --
WE DO HAVE THE
NEXT 13
MONTHS TO FIGURE OUT,
ALMOST
14 MONTHS, TO FIGURE OUT
A BETTER
WAY, MAYBE IT'S
REVENUE, LESS
CUTS, MAYBE IT'S
A LITTLE
DIFFERENT CUTS THAT
ARE
CURRENTLY
ACROSS THE BOARD
IN THE
DEFENSE DEPARTMENT AS
WELL AS THE
DISCRETIONARY
FUNDING, BUT WE HAVE A CHANCE
TO DO THAT.
WE HAVE TIME TO DO
THAT.
SO IT'S
NOT ALL ROST.
THE DEFICIT
HAS BEEN REDUCED.
NOW
WE NEED TO DO IT IN A
SMARTER WAY,
ONE THAT PROMOTES
AMERICAN JOBS,
PUTS PEOPLE TO
WORK
AND CREATES MORE JOBS AND
MANUFACTURING IN AMERICA.
MR. TONKO, YOU COME
FROM A
STATE
THAT REALLY STARTED THE
GREAT
AMERICAN INDUSTRIAL
REVOLUTION AND
AN AREA IN WHICH
IT ACTUALLY
BEGAN, THE UPPER
HUDSON
RIVER VALLEY.
WHY DON'T
WE CARRY ON OUR
CONVERSATION HERE.
YOU WERE TALKING ABOUT
RESEARCH, TAKE IT WHEREVER
YOU'D LIKE TO
GO.
MR.
TONKO: SURE.
ABSOLUTELY.
LET
ME RESPOND TO THE ABSOLUTE
CLEAR FOCUS
THAT OUR FRIEND,
THE GENTLEWOMAN FROM
TEXAS,
REPRESENTATIVE
FOR
THE STRENGTH
OF TEXAS,
REPRESENTATIVE
JACKSON LEE IS
CONSTANTLY
TALKING ABOUT
THE OPPORTUNITIES
TO MAKE
IT IN
AMERICA.
BUT SHE
CITED ALSO THE FLOOD
DAMAGE
IN MY DISTRICT, THE
MOHAWK
VALLEY OF UPSTATE NO.
SOMETIMES WE
-- OF UPSTATE NEW
YORK.
SOMETIMES WE SIT AROUND AND TRY
TO
COUNT THE EFFECT OF
INFRASTRUCTURE
FUR OUR JOB
GROWTH AND THERE ARE DIFFERENT
WAYS TO
EXPRESS THE ECONOMIC
DEVELOPMENT QUOTIENT RELATED
TO
INFRASTRUCTURE.
THE TRADITIONAL ROADS
AND
BRIDGES BUT THEN
BROADBAND AND
OUR GRID
SYSTEM FOR
OUR
ELECTRIC
UTILITIES.
WHAT ROLE
DOES IT PLAY?
SOMETIMES THE
BEST EXPRESSION
IS TONE WHEN THAT IS
TAKEN FROM
YOU.
AND
WHEN ROADS AND BRIDGES WERE
WASHED
AWAY.
WE SAW
IMMEDIATELY WHAT THE
EFFECT WAS ON
THE REGIONAL
ECONOMY.
AND THEREFORE THE
STATE ECONOMY
AND THEN WE'RE ALL
CONNECTED,
ONE TO
ANOTHER, THAT THE
NATIONAL
ECONOMY HURTS THROUGH
THE RAH
VADGES OF FLOOD WATERS
THAT IMPACTED THIS
DISTRICT,
SOME
WOULD SAY WITH 500-YEAR
STORM IMPACT.
WHAT DID THAT
MEAN?
IT MEANT
YOU COULDN'T HAUL MILK
THAT WAS
PROCESSED, PRODUCED ON
THESE FARMS.
YOU COULDN'T SHIP PRODUCTS
BEING MANUFACTURED.
IT
STOPPED THE ECONOMIC
VIABILITY OF
A DISTRICT.
OF
A REGION.
SO
IT'S IMPORTANT FOR US TO
LOOK AT THOSE
BRIDGES THAT
MEASURE
IN DEFICIENT FORM.
WE NEED
TO MAKE CERTAIN WE HAVE
STATE
OF THE ART
INFRASTRUCTURE.
BROADBAND.
WE BEGAN TO TALK ABOUT THIS
WITH THE SPACE RACE
OF THE
1960'S.
WE
UNLEASHED UNTOLD
AMOUNTS OF
INVESTMENT
IN TECHNOLOGY THAT
ENABLED
US TO STRETCH
OPPORTUNITY
HERE, THINK OF THE
ROTARY
PHONE AND NOW MOVED ALL
THE WAY UP
TO WHAT IS A
CHANGING TELEPHONE BY
THE WEEK.
AND THAT
ALL HAPPENED BECAUSE
OF AN
INVESTMENT IN THE
INTELLECT OF THIS NATION
SYSTEM
OF
THE INTELLECTUAL CAPACITY OF
THIS
NATION HAS BEEN AN
INSPIRATION
TO NOT ONLY THIS
COUNTRY, BUT TO
FOLKS AROUND
THE WORLD
WHERE THE QUALITY OF
LIFE
WAS
RAISED SIMPLY BY THE
INVENTIVE
QUALITIES OF AMERICAN
WORKERS.
AND SO
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE
CALLING FOR
HERE.
THE
DEMOCRATS OF THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES BELIEVE
IN
INVESTING
IN THE WORKER, IN
RESEARCH,
RESEARCH EQUALS JOBS.
RESEARCH
EQUALS OPPORTUNITIES.
THE
INTELLECTUAL CAPACITY THAT
WAS DEVELOPED
HERE, I'M TOLD BY
THE
MOST RECENT FORMER ENERGY
MINISTER OF
DENMARK, INFLUENCED
THE TURN
AROUND OF
THINKING IN
DENMARK, WHERE THEY
CHANGED
THEIR ECONOMY,
INNOVATIVE
OUTCOMES, INSPIRED
BY
PATENTS FROM THE UNITED
STATES OF AMERICA.
WE HAVE THAT
INTELLECT.
WE TALK ABOUT
MANUFACTURING
AS
A BASE.
WE
LOST -- SAW THE
EXODUS OF
MANUFACTURING JOBS TO THE
MILLIONS,
TO THE MILLIONS.
STILL PERMINGED
HIGHEST ON THE
LIST FOR
MANUFACTURING JOB BUS
IF WE
ALLOWED THAT TREND WHERE
WE WERE
DISINTERESTED, PAID NO
ATTENTION TO MANUFACTURING
AND
AGRICULTURE
IF WE ALLOWED THAT
TO
CONTINUE, WE KILL SINK AS AN
ECONOMY.
WHAT WE NEED TO DO IS
BRING THE
FOCUS
BACK TO MANUFACTURING TO
AGRICULTURE.
THE FOCUS WAS TOTALLY ON THE
SERVICE ECONOMY AND
MORE
NARROWLY TO THE
FINANCIAL
SERVICES.
WE KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
MR. GARAMENDI:
WOULD THE
GENTLEMAN PAUSE
FOR A MOMENT.
MR.
TONKO: ABSOLUTELY.
MS. JACKSON LEE:
YOU ARE SAYING
SOMETHING
SO
INSPIRATIONAL.
I WANT TO
SAY, ONE,
WE ARE
STILL THE GREATEST
AND LARGEST
ECONOMIC ENGINE IN THE
WORLD,
IN SPITE OF
CHINA, IN SPITE OF
RUSSIA,
IN SPITE OF INDIA, OUR
GOOD FRIENDS.
STILL
PERCOLATING ALONG.
SECOND, WHEN
WE'VE HAD OUR
DIFFICULTIES IN THE PAST, THERE
HAVE BEEN
RECESSIONS IN THE
1950'S,
POST-WORLD WAR II, ON
INTO
OUR GOOD FRIEND BOTH
FORMER PRESIDENT FORD AND
CARTER, AS YOU WELL KNOW, FOR
THOSE
WHO READ HISTORY
BOOKS,
WE HAD SOME
MOMENTS.
THE
REASON WE ARE IN TROUBLED
WATERS, THAT PEOPLE
CAN'T SEEM
TO
COMPREHEND, WE NEVER HAD A
EWE
ROE.
WE NEVER HAD EUROPE
IN THE
STATE THAT
IT IS PRESENTLY IN.
WHEN THE
MARKETS WERE TROUBLED
ON MONDAY,
WAS IT MONDAY?
EVEN
POST, I THINK MONDAY THEY
PERCOLATED BUT WHEN THEY WERE
TROUBLED,
THEY WERE LOOKING AT
EUROPE.
SO IF WE
GET OBSESSED WITH
OTHER
THAN WHAT YOU'RE
SAYING
ABOUT HOW
WE CAN GET BACK IN
THE GAME
AT THE PEAK WE WANT TO
BE, WE DON'T
TAKE IN THE GREAT
PICTURE.
THAT GREAT PICTURE IS OUR
MARKETS ARE NOT
NECESSARILY
TROUBLED, WE NEED TO
DO BETTER,
WE
NEED TO CREATE JOBS, BUT
THEY ARE
INTERNATIONAL MARKETS
AND THEY ARE TROUBLED BY
THE
EWE ROE.
WHAT I WAS
SAYING, LET'S
UNDERSTAND THAT SO WE CAN DO
OUR BUSINESS HERE IN THE
UNITED
STATES AN FOCUS ON
THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
TEND TO THE
MARKETS, BUT GO
AHEAD AND INVEST
AND REALIZE
THAT THE
MARKETS ARE
INTERRELATED.
WE CAN OVERCOME
THAT BY DOING
EXACTLY WHAT
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
NEW YORK HAS SAID, MAKE IT IN
AMERICA.
MR. GARAMENDI: MS. JACKSON LEE,
YOU TALKED ABOUT
INVESTMENTS
AND ABOUT THE
INTERNATIONAL
ASPECTS OF OUR
ECONOMY, AND MR.
TONKO,
YOU WERE SO CORRECT WHEN
YOU TALK
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN THOSE
INFRASTRUCTURES ARE
NOT THERE.
NOW IN THE AMERICAN
JOBS ACT,
WHICH WE OUGHT TO BE
WORKING ON
AND
PASSING, THERE IS $50
BILLION
OVER AND ABOVE THE
ONGOING MONEY,
THIS IS NEW
MONEY, ADDITIONAL
MONEY, THAT
WOULD BE IMMEDIATELY AVAILABLE
TO RESTORE THE
COASTAL AREAS
THEY HAVE
UNITED STATES,
REBUILD
THE INFRASTRUCTURE IN
THOSE AREAS THAT HAVE
BEEN HARD
HIT BY THE
FLOODS OF THIS
YEAR,
TO
IMPROVE THE 100-YEAR-OLD
PLUS
BRIDGES IN AMERICA, THOSE
ARE
ALL
THINGS THAT WE NEED TO
MOVE OUR ECONOMY.
WE
TALKED EARLIER, MS. SUTTON
FROM OHIO,
ABOUT THE SANITATION
AND WATER
SYSTEMS, EACH AND
EVERY ONE OF
THESE SHOULD BE
FRAMED IN
SUCH A WAY AS TO
CREATE AMERICAN JOBS.
NOT JUST THE CONSTRUCTION JOBS,
BUT THE REST OF
THE
STORY,
WHICH IS
THE
CONCRETE, THE
STEEL, THE BOLT
THE BUMPS, ALL
THOSE
THINGS THAT GO INTO THE
INFRASTRUCTURE
CAN AND SHOULD
BE AMERICAN
MADE.
IF WE HAVE
A POLICY.
NOW ON THE
FLOOR HERE, THREE
WEEKS AGO, WE WERE
TALKING
ABOUT
THIS, AND OUR COLLEAGUE
FROM ILLINOIS,
MS. JANIKOWSKI
-- MS. SCHAKOWSKY,
BROUGHT
SOMETHING
TO THE FLOOR THAT
BLEW ME
AWAY.
SHE BROUGHT A
DOCUMENT
PREPEARED IN
1788, BY GEORGE
WASHINGTON.
IT WAS A MANUFACTURING
POLICY
FOR
AMERICA.
HE TOLD HAMILTON, WHO WAS THEN
THE SECRETARY OF THE
TREASURY,
TO
GO OUT AND DEVELOP EIGHT
STEPS FOR
AN AMERICAN
MANUFACTURING
POLICY.
SO THIS IS NOT
NEW IN AMERICA,
FOLKS.
WE NEED A
MANUFACTURING POLICY
IN
AMERICA, WE CALL
IT MAKE IT
IN AMERICA.
IT'S A
TAX POLICY.
EDUCATIONAL
POLICY.
AN
INFRASTRUCTURE POLICY.
IT IS AN
INTERNATIONAL TRADE
POLICY WHERE
WE DON'T GIVE IT
AWAY
BUT WE REQUIRE FAIR TRADE,
NOT FREE TRADE,
FAIR TRADE.
THESE ARE AMERICAN
MANUFACTURING POLICIES
OF
TODAY.
THANK YOU, GEORGE WASHINGTON,
FOR SETTING US
ON THE COURSE WE
NEED
TO CONTINUE WITH.
MR.
TONKO: ABSOLUTELY.
I
HEAR IN YOUR
STATEMENT THE
WISDOM
OF SOUND PLANNING.
WE NEED THAT.
FOR GOVERNMENT TO BE
SMART AND
EFFICIENT,
WHICH IS THE CALL
BY
THE GENERAL
PUBLIC, WE WANT
SMART INVESTMENT
FROM OUR
GOVERNMENT.
ASK ANY
COMPETITOR OUT THERE IN
THE GLOBAL ECONOMY, THEY ARE
COMPETING
AGAINST INDUSTRIES
THAT ARE BEING
CO-INVESTED IN
BY
THEIR NATIVE LANDS.
THERE ARE
CO-INVESTMENTS IN
GOVERNMENT AND THE PRIVATE
SECTOR AND
WE ARE MOVING IN THE
OTHER
DIRECTION.
A
COUPLE OF THINGS COME TO MINE
HERE.
I
PARTICIPATED THIS PAST
WEEKEND IN SMALL
BUSINESS
SATURDAY.
AND THE
SPIRIT I DETECTED WAS
THE
LEAP OF FAITH.
SOUND LEAP OF
FAITH BY
MANY
SMALL BUSINESS LEADERS.
WHO SAID,
I WANT TO OFFER A
SERVICE, I'M GOING
TO PUT
MY
CREATIVE GENIUS
TO WORK.
I'M
GOING TO MAKE MY COMMITMENT
TO
COMMUNITY A RESPONSE HERE
THAT'S
TANGIBLE.
I SAW
A LOT OF BELIEF IN THE
AMERICAN PUBLIC,
BELIEF IN THE
AMERICAN
SYSTEM, AND IT OFFERS
A WARM
AND FUZZY, COZY,
PERSONALIZED
RELATIONSHIP.
PEOPLE COME IN, THEY ARE
KNOWN
WHEN THEY WALK
INTO A SHOP.
THEY
SEE THE
CREATIVE FLAIR
INTRODUCED INTO THAT SMALL
BUSINESS.
I ALSO SEE
MORE TECHNICAL SAVVY
QUALITIES THAT
TECHNICALLY
SAVVY
QUALITIES, THAT ARE
ENGAGED IN
IN THE DISTRICT I
REPRESENT WITH A LOT OF
STARTUPS, INCUBATORS.
AGAIN, ANOTHER
LEAP OF GOOD
FAITH BUT
NEEDING AN
INVESTMENT, A
CO-PARTNERING, A
PARTNERING WITH
GOVERNMENT,
ESPECIALLY IN
A VERY TENUOUS
ECONOMY, WHERE
THERE'S STILL
A
LOT OF
GUESSWORK AND WE NEED TO
BE THERE
TO REMOVE SOME OF THAT
RISK.
THAT IS SO
CRITICALLY
IMPORTANT.
YOU
KNOW, REPRESENTATIVE GARE
MEN
TEE, YOU MENTIONED EARLIER,
THAT
MY DISTRICT IS THE DONOR
DISTRICT TO THE
ERIE CANAL,
BARGE
CANAL, TRIGGERED AN
INDUSTRIAL REVOLUTION.
THESE MILLTOWNS
GIVEN BIRTH TO
BY
THE CANAL BECAME THE
EPICENTERS OF INDUSTRY
AND
INNOVATION.
MILLTOWNS THAT
HAD BLUE COLLAR
WORKERS COMING UP
WITH
TREMENDOUSLY CLEVER
IDEAS.
FOR PEOPLE TO
THROW UP THEIR
ARMS
AND SAY,
MANUFACTURING
THEN IS WHAT IT WAS,
IT WAS OUR
GREATNESS,
IT'S GONE TODAY.
NOTHING
COULD BE FURTHER FROM
THE
TRUTH.
WHAT
IS THE CHALLENGE TODAY TO
A
SOPHISTICATED SOCIETY LIKE
THE AMERICAN
SOCIETY IS THAT
WHILE
WE HAVE A NUMBER OF
PRODUCT LINES WE
DEVELOPED
THROUGH OUR DECADES OF
MANUFACTURING, THE
CHALLENGE TO
A
SOPHISTICATED SOCIETY IS
BUILD THE PRODUCTS
THAT ARE IN
DEMAND TODAY AND
IF WE
BELIEVE
THAT EVERY PRODUCT
THAT'S EVER
REQUIRED BY SOCIETY
HAS BEEN
CONCEIVED AND ENGINEERED AND
DESIGNED AND
MANUFACTURED THEN
THE STORY
IS OVER.
BUT,
WE BELIEVE LIKE SO MANY OF
US
DO BELIEVE, THAT WE CAN BE
THE BY WI
SARDS OF THOSE NEW
PRODUCTS, AND
WE DEVELOP IT BY
INVESTING IN
IDEAS, INVESTING
IN
RESEARCH.
THEN WE BUILD
THOSE PRODUCTS
THAT ARE
NOW THE STEP UP, IN
YOU WILL.
THAT'S WHERE WE ARE WITH
OUR
POLICY
INITIATIVES AS A
DEMOCRATIC
CAUCUS IN THE HOUSE
OF REPRESENTATIVES.
MAKE IT
IN AMERICA.
BY
EMBRACING THE INTELLECTUAL
CAPACITY OF THIS
NATION.
AND
HOLDING FAST TO INNOVATION,
ENTREPRENEURS AND THE
MANUFACTURING OF TODAY, SPUN UP
TO
A NEW LEVEL.
THAT'S AMERICA AT OUR
GREATEST
MOMENT.
MR. GARAMENDI:
IF I MIGHT
INTERRUPT
YOU FOR JUST A
MOMENT, EVERY HOUR WE ARE
HERE,
WE ARE
JOINED BY MEN AND WOMEN
WHO ARE WORKING
HARD ON BEHALF
OF THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE.
THE
STENOGRAPHERS TAKING DOWN
OUR WORDS HERE
DESERVE A PRAISE
OF
THANKSGIVING, NOT THAT OUR
WORDS
ARE SO WORTHWHILE TO PUT
INTO THE
AMERICAN RECORD BUT
THEY DO IT
NONETHELESS AND I
WANT TO
THANK THEM FOR THEIR
GOOD WORK AND
THE STAFF BEHIND
US AS
WE GO THROUGH THIS
HOUR.
MR.
TONKO: IF YOU'LL SUFFER --
SUFFER AN
INTERRUPT, YIELD,
PLEASE, MR.
-- REPRESENTATIVE
GARAMENDI.
I ABSOLUTELY
ENDORSE WHAT YOU
JUST
SAID.
THEY ARE
DEVOTED, THEY ARE AN
ESSENTIAL PART OF
THIS BODY TO
INTRODUCE ALL OF THE
STATEMENTS
INTO THE ANALS OF
HISTORY,
MAKING --
ANNALS OF HISTORY,
MAKING CERTAIN THAT
THE
PROGRESS
REQUIRED BY THIS
NATION RIGHT NOW,
THEY PROVIDE
AN
AWESOME, AWESOME TASK.
.
MR. GARAMENDI: IF I
MIGHT
INTERRUPT YOU SOME OF THE
THINGS
YOU WERE TALKING
ABOUT, DOWN
THROUGH THE
EARLIEST YEARS OF
THIS
COUNTRY, THERE HAS BEEN A
JOINING OF THE
GOVERNMENT AND
PRIVATE
SECTOR TO ACCOMPLISH
REALLY THE
BUILDING OF AMERICA
AND IT HAS BEEN DONE IN
MANY,
MANY
WAYS.
I WAS
STARTLED AND SURPRISED AND
VERY HAPPY
WHEN MS. SCHAKOWSKY
BROUGHT THAT
DOCUMENT IN FROM
THE GENTLEWOMAN IS RECOGNIZED
WASHINGTON'S ADMINISTRATION
ABOUT THE
ESTABLISHMENT OF
INDUSTRIAL POLICY THAT
PLACED
THE
AMERICAN GOVERNMENT IN SYNC
WITH THE NEW
NEW MANUFACTURING
PROGRAMS IN
AMERICA.
YOU TALK
ABOUT THE
MILL TOWNS,
THEY JUST DIDN'T
HAPPEN.
IT HAPPENED
BECAUSE IT WAS A
GOVERNMENT POLICY WORKING
WITH
THEM, THOSE
ENTREPRENEURS, TO
CREATE THESE NEW
BUSINESSES,
THESE NEW
JOBS.
AND DOWN
THROUGH THE CENTURIES,
WE HAVE BEEN ABLE
TO USE THIS
THIS GOVERNMENT
WORKING WITH THE
GOVERNMENT WITH THE
PRIVATE
SECTOR
AND CREATE THE AMERICAN
DREAM THAT ALL
OF US POSSESS OR
HAVE
PARTICIPATED IN.
TODAY
, WE ARE IN A DISCUSSION,
IF YOU
WILL, WITH THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC ABOUT
WHETHER TO CONTINUE
THAT
COORDINATION OF THE PUBLIC
GOVERNMENTS,
STATE,
LOCAL,
FEDERAL GOVERNMENTS, WORKING
TO
ACHIEVE A GOAL IN THE
PRIVATE
SECTOR.
THERE IS A
DIFFERENT VERSION
OUT
THERE THAT
SAYS GET
GOVERNMENT
AWAY AND THINGS
WILL
GO WELL,
ELIMINATE ALL
REGULATION AND
ELIMINATE ALL OF THE PROGRAMS
AND
LET THE FREE MARKET DO IT.
IT'S NEVER WORKED.
AND THE PROOF
OF IT IS IS FOUND
IN
THE FIRST DECADE OF THIS
CENTURY.
THAT
PHILOSOPHY OF PUSH
GOVERNMENT
ASIDE, DEREGULATE,
REDUCE
TAXES AND GET GOVERNMENT
OUT
OF THE WAY
ACTUALLY CREATED
A SITUATION OF THE
GREAT
RECESSION
AND NO JOBS.
IN
FACT,
EIGHT MILLION AMERICAN
JOBS
LOST.
WE NEED TO
GO BACK
TO
THE
POLICIES THAT
ACTUALLY CREATED
GROWTH IN
AMERICA, THE POLICIES
OF FRANKLIN
ROOSEVELT, CARRIED
OUT BY
TRUMAN, EISENHOWER, EVEN
RONALD REAGAN AND
LYNDON JOHNSON
CARRIED OUT THE
BASIC
POLICIES
THAT WORKING
TOGETHER, WE CAN
BUILD A GREAT
COUNTRY.
MR. TONKO: YOU ARE
ABSOLUTELY
RIGHT, AND I BELIEVE AS
YOU
JUST
INDICATED, OUR
HISTORY, OUR
AMERICAN HISTORY
IS
REPLETE WITH
THE
SOUNDNESS OF GOVERNMENT
PLANNING AND
POLICIES THAT
INCORPORATED INVESTMENTS FROM
THE PUBLIC
SECTOR.
AND IT
MADE US
STRONG.
IT
RETAINED OUR STRENGTH.
IT WAS
A SUSTAINABLE OUTCOME AND
THE WAY OF THE WORLD
TODAY IS
OTHER
NATIONS ARE CO-INVESTING
WITH THE PRIVATE SECTOR AND
WHEN
YOU LOOK AT THE
SCENARIO OF
THREATS TO
CUT
SOME VERY
VALUABLE
PROGRAMS, YOU KNOW YOU
ARE
GOING TO
PLACE OUR
BUSINESSES AT
RISK.
AND IF
THERE'S
ANYTHING I HEAR
FROM
MY MIDDLE CLASS THAT IS
DISGRUNTLED WITH
WASHINGTON,
THEY AREN'T AGAINST
PEOPLE
MAKING MONEY,
THEY'RE NOT
AGAINST THAT.
THEIR CONCERN AND
THEY
ARE
DEEPLY
UPSET
BY THE UNDUE
INFLUENCE THAT A
GROWING FEW,
MOST POWERFUL
HAVE
ON THE
PROCESS.
THEY SEE IT AS
GREED, A
REJECTION OF WHAT
WORKED IN THE
PAST, WHERE PEOPLE SHARED
THE
WEALTH, SHARED
BY INVESTING IN
AMERICA'S MIDDLE
CLASS, WHICH IS
THAT INTELLECTUAL
CAPACITY, IS
THAT
INNOVATIVE
SPIRIT, IS THAT
POTENTIAL FOR THE NEXT
GENERATION OF JOBS.
AND THAT'S
WHERE
OUR STRENGTH
LIES.
AND THAT'S WHY
THEY'RE
UPSET,
UNDUE INFLUENCE HAS
CAUSED THIS
GREED THAT
PRODUCES A DRAIN ON
THE MIDDLE CLASS OF
THIS
COUNTRY
AND REDUCES
THE
NUMBER OF JOBS
THAT WE
COULD
POSSIBLY HAVE IN
THIS NATION.
MR. GARAMENDI: I NOTICED
TWO OF
OUR
COLLEAGUES
VR JOINED US.
IF YOU
HAD
THIS NEXT VIEW WHILE
YOU MADE THIS STATEMENT
ABOUT
THE
CHANGE IN
THE NATURE OF
AMERICA'S WEALTH
.
THIS CHART HAS
BECOME, I THINK,
BECOME
RATHER FAMOUS OR
INFAMOUS.
THE BLUE LINE
HERE
IS A CHART
THAT SHOWS THE
GROWTH IN THE
WEALTH
-- THE INCOME OF THE TOP
1%
OF
AMERICANS.
AND DOWN HERE
IS WHAT THE REST
OF
AMERICANS HAVE HAD
OVER THE
LAST 20 YEARS OR
SO.
WHAT WE HAVE
SEEN IS BASICALLY
FLATLINING FOR
THE
MIDDLE CLASS
AND CERTAINLY FOR
THE
POOR.
NO IMPROVEMENT OR
VERY, VERY
LITTLE
IMPROVEMENT IN
THEIR
SITUATION
WHILE THE VERY SMALL
1% --
THIS IS
THE 99% HERE --
THIS IS THE
1%.
AND THIS IS THE
ANGER THAT YOU
NOW
SEE IN THE
STREETS OF
AMERICA AND IT'S
EXACTLY WHAT
YOU WER
E TALKING
ABOUT, MR.
TONKO
WITH A
FEW 1% OF THE
AMERICAN
PUBLIC, GETING AN
INCREASING SHARE
OF THE AMERICAN
INCOME
AND WEALTH, CREATING A
BIFURCATING
SOCIETY, A FEW THAT
ARE WEALTHY AND
THE
REST THAT
ARE GROWING
POORER.
WITH THAT,
I WOULD LIKE TO TURN
TO A WOMAN
FROM THE GREAT
MIDWEST,
THE STATE OF OHIO, THAT
IS
ENDURING THIS EXACT HALLOWING
OUT
OF THE AMERICAN MIDDLE
CLASS.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US AND
THANK YOU FOR YOUR YEARS
OF WORK
REPRESENTING
YOUR PART OF THE --
WHAT WAS
ONCE THE GREATEST
INDUSTRIAL STRENGTH OF
AMERICA.
AND YOU
WANT TO SHARE SOME
THOUGHTS
THAT YOU SHARED WITH ME
AS YOU
WENT HOME AND TALKED TO
THE MEN AND
WOMEN OF CLEVELAND.
MS. KAPTUR:
THANK YOU FOR YOU
ARE
-- FOR YOUR
LEADERSHIP.
YOU ARE
UNRELENTING AND WE THANK
YOU
FOR YOUR TIME TONIGHT AND
CONGRESSMAN TONKO OF
NEW YORK,
YOUR
STEADFAST SERVICE HERE
REPRESENTING A
STATE
THAT HAS
SOME SIMILAR
SITUATIONS TO
HIGH'S IN THE
INDUSTRIAL AND
AGRICULTURAL
HEARTLAND OF OUR
COUNTRY.
IT'S
REALLY A SPECIAL PRIVILEGE
TO BE HERE WITH BOTH OF
YOU.
THIS MORNING,
ONE
OF MY FIRST
VISITS
WAS
WITH A COMPANY IN
OHIO, POLLY ONE.
TCH IS A
COMPANY THAT MAKES
PRODUCTS IN AMERICA
AND IT IS A
PLAYER AND
HUNDREDS AND
HUNDREDS
AND HUNDREDS OF
JOBS ARE
ASSOCIATED WITH
ITS PLASTICS
PRODUCTS, MATE
BOTH
OUT OF
TRADITIONAL
PETROLEUM-BASED
INPUTS AND
THE HYDRO ECONOMY AND
IT WAS QUITE
EXCITING.
WE
KNOW
THAT REAL WEALTH IS
CREATED IN OUR
COUNTRY
WHEN WE
MAKE GOODS
IN
AMERICA, WHEN WE
MAKE IT IN
AMERICA.
AND I
THINK THE PROBLEM OVER THE
LAST
SEVERAL
YEARS HAS BEEN THAT
IF YOU
TRAVEL TO ANY CITY IN
AMERICA AND YOU
LOOK AT THE
TALLEST
BUILDING,
WHAT
ARE THEY?
ARE THEY
THE FIRMS MAKING THINGS
OR ARE THEY
MERELY, AS I SAW IN
MICHIGAN
RGSLY -- RECENTLY,
A
GIGANTIC BANK WHOSE
HEADQUARTERS
IS
ON WALL STREET THAT JUST GOT
BAILED OUT BY
THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
I STOPPED MY
CAR AND
LOOKED AT
THAT
BUILDING AND LOOKED AT THE
DEVASTATION OF THE COMMUNITIES
AROUND THAT
PARTICULAR PART OF
MICHIGAN, AND I
THOUGHT,
WHAT'S
WRONG WITH THIS PICTURE.
BASICALLY, THIS
INSTITUTION HAS
SUCKED UP
THE WEALTH OF
NEIGHBORHOODS AFTER
NEIGHBORHOODS AND LEFT
RUBBLE IN
ITS WAY.
THEY'RE NOT BEING
HELD
ACCOUNTABLE.
AND YET,
I SEE
COMPANIES LIKE
POL ONE TRYING TO
MAKE IT IN A
GLOBAL
ECONOMY
WITH A VERY
UNFAIR SET OF TRADE
PRACTICES,
CLOSED
MARKETS AROUND THE WORLD,
CURRENCY
MANIPULATION,
INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY
THEFT.
YOU LOOK AT
WHAT IS HAPPENING
WITH
COMPETITORS, COMPETITION TO
U.S. INDUSTRY, AND
YOU HAVE TO
SAY TO THOSE PATRIOTS WHO
ARE
MAKING GOODS
IN
AMERICA, WE
STAND WITH
YOU.
WE
SHOULD BE REWARDING THOSE
COMPANIES.
WE SHOULD BE
MAKING MORE
GOODS
IN
OUR
COUNTRY.
AND I WANTED
TO ADD A WORD ABOUT
THE AUTO
INDUSTRY.
THERE WERE
THOSE IN
THIS CHAMBER
THAT VOTED
AGAINST THE
REFINANCING OF THE AUTO
INDUSTRY.
WITHOUT THAT INDUSTRY, THIS
COUNTRY WOULD
NOT HAVE A DEFENSE
BASE AND WE
WOULD NOT BE A GREAT
INDUSTRIAL
POWER.
AND NOW I
SEE
IN OUR REGION OF
THE
COUNTRY, I WAS JUST ATLANTA
CHRYSLER-FIAT AND
ANNOUNCED
BILLIONS OF
DOLLARS OF
INVESTMENTS AND
1,000
MORE
PEOPLE HIRED AT
THEIR MAIN
PRODUCTION FACILITY IN
TOLEDO,
OHIO.
CHRYSLER-JEEP THAT
MAKES
THE
WRANGLER AND
LIBERTY, THE
FEELING INSIDE THAT PLANT
OF
PEOPLE WHO HAVE
GIVEN THEIR
LIVES TO
KEEPING AMERICA
COMPETITIVE
AND TO MANUFACTURING
A LABEL
THAT IS KNOWN THROUGHOUT
THE
WORLD, IT WAS A WONDERFUL
DAY TO BE
THERE.
AND I WAS
REMINDED AND I SAID
VERY
FRANKLY, THERE WERE 170
MEMBERS OF CONGRESS WHO DIDN'T
THINK YOU SHOULD BE
HERE
AND
DIDN'T
THINK
THAT THIS COMPANY
SHOULD BE HERE AND THE
COMPANY
HAS PAID BACK
THE
LOAN THAT
WAS
MADE AND NOW
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
GOOD JOBS
BY MAKING GOODS IN
AMERICA.
SO I
WANTED
TO SHARE THOSE
EXPERIENCES.
AND I FEEL BAD THAT WE HAVE
A
COUNTRY WHERE
CERTAIN FINANCIAL
FIRMS THAT ARE
TOTALLY
SPECULATIVE HAVE BROUGHT US TO
THIS POINT.
BUT I
STAND WITH THOSE WHO HAVE
WEATHERED THE STORM AND
WHO ARE
NOW
HIRING AND
TRYING TO MOVE
THIS ECONOMY BACK
WHERE WE KNOW
IT CAN
BE.
AND I WAS VERY PROUD
TO
BE A
MEMBER AS WERE
THOSE THAT WERE
WITH
US HERE
TONIGHT TO VOTE FOR
THAT
REFINANCING OF THE AUTO
INDUSTRY AND WHETHER
IT'S
PLASTICS, GLASS,
WHETHER IT'S
FIBER, TEXTILES,
WHATEVER, IS
HELPING TO
LIFT THIS ECONOMY TO
WHERE
LAST WEEK ON THE DAY OF
AFTER
THANKSGIVING, RETAIL SALES
WENT
UP.
THAT'S WHAT WE
SHOULD BE DOING.
WE SHOULD BE
USING OUR POWER
HERE TO LIFT THOSE INDUSTRIES
THAT CAN
REALLY MAKE GOODS IN
OUR
COUNTRY AND HELP RECREATE A
STRENGTHENED MIDDLE
CLASS.
MR. GARAMENDI: WE HAVE EIGHT
MORE MINUTES
HERE, AND I WANT TO
-- WE TALKED
ABOUT THE
PURCHASING POWER OF
AMERICANS.
JANUARY 1
, UNLESS WE ACT,
AMERICAN WORKERS
WILL LOSE ABOUT
$1,500 OF PURCHASING
POWER.
WE
MUST RENEW THE -- AND
CONTINUE THE
REDUCTION IN THE
SOCIAL SECURITY TAX
THAT
AMERICAN WORKERS ARE PAYING
AND
BUSINESSES ARE
PAYING.
THAT PUTS -- AND
BY
THE WAY,
IT'S TOTALLY
PAID FOR BY THOSE
SUPERWEALTHY,
3.5% INCREASE ON
THEIR
TAXES OVER
$1 MILLION A
YEAR.
IT IS TOTALLY PAID FOR
AND
PART
OF THE AMERICAN JOBS
ACT.
I WAS
JUST
TALKING TO MR. TONKO
AND CAME ABOUT WHAT
YOU SAID
ABOUT
THOSE
MEN AND WOMEN
WORKING
HERE IN
AMERICA.
AND I WANT TO
END ON THIS
BETWEEN THE THREE OF
US.
WE DEMOCRATS HAVE
MADE
A PROMISE
TO AMERICA
.
IT'S NOT
A
CONTRACT.
IT
IS A PROMISE.
IT'S A
PLEDGE, AND THAT PLEDGE
IS TO PROTECT
SOCIAL SECURITY
AND
MEDICARE,
TWO OF THE MOST
FUNDAMENTAL AMERICAN
PROGRAMS,
BOTH OF
WHICH ARE AT RISK OF
BEING
SIGNIFICANTLY MODIFIED OR,
IN THE CASE
OF MEDICARE,
DESTROYED, BY
OUR REPUBLICAN
COLLEAGUES.
AND I WANT TO MAKE IT
VERY, VERY
CLEAR AND GET THE
COMMENTS FROM
MY TWO
COLLEAGUES HERE ABOUT OUR
COMMITMENT TO THESE
PROGRAMS,
SOCIAL SECURITY
IS THE BEDROCK
FOUNDATION
FOR EVERY AMERICAN'S
RETIREMENT AND
GIVEN THE WAY THE
STOCK
MARKET GYR
ATES, CAN'T
COUNT ON YOUR
401K.
HERE'S
THE
PROMISE TO
AMERICA
FROM THE
DEMOCRATS, YOU WILL
ALWAYS BE ABLE
TO COUNT ON
SOCIAL SECURITY.
THIS, IF
THEY WANT
TO FIGHT
ABOUT
IT,
THIS IS
THE FIGHT WE
WILL HAVE AND WE WILL WIN.
AND ON MEDICARE, MILLIONS OF
SENIORS ARE NOT IN POVERTY TODAY
AND ALIVE
TODAY
BECAUSE THEY
HAVE MEDICARE
INSURANCE.
FUNDAMENTAL, AMERICAN PROGRAM.
MR.ON
TONKO.
MR. TONKO:
YOU HIGHLIGHT SOME OF
THE MAJOR
DIFFERENCES AND
DISAGREEMENTS THAT HAVE
HIGHLIGHTED THE DEBATE
ON THE
HILL
HERE IN WASHINGTON
BETWEEN
THE TWO
PARTIES, AND I WOULD
SUGGEST IT'S
PROBABLY SOME OF
THE
REASONS THAT THE
SUPERCOMMITTEE COULD NOT
COME TO
CONSENSUS, BECAUSE
WE HAVE
CALLED UPON AN
OUTCOME THAT
IS
FAIR, BALANCED
AND BOLD, THAT WE
WILL NOT
ALLOW
FOR THE PAYMENT
OF THE PRICE
TAG ON FURTHER
COVENTING TAX CUTS
FOR
MILLIONAIRES
AND
BILLIONAIRES TO
BE PAID FOR BY
CUTS TO MEDICARE.
THERE WERE
THOSE WHO FOUGHT
SOCIAL SECURITY AT ITS
INCEPTION
AND FOUGHT IT
FOR 76 YEARS AND
WANT TO DENY
IT.
AND IT'S
ABOUT MAKING CERTAIN
THAT
THERE'S AN UNDERPINNING OF
SUPPORT FOR
OUR
ELDERLY AS THEY
GROW INTO
WHAT IS A LONGER LIFE
SPAN.
WE HAVE TO HAVE MEASURES IN
PLACE THAT
ENABLE
THERE TO BE A
QUALITY OF LIFE
THAT PROVIDES
ECONOMIC
VITALITY, ECONOMIC
BALANCE FOR
THOSE WHO MOVE INTO
THEIR RETIREMENT
YEARS.
AND I THINK THAT
WHEN WE LOOK AT
THE
MERMINGTS OF MEDICARE AND --
MEASUREMENTS OF
5% OF G.D.P. AND
HERE IS A
PROGRAM THAT HAS
WORKED
TREMENDOUSLY WELL.
CAN IT BE
BETTER?
ABSOLUTELY.
MAKE IT MORE
SECURE, MORE
SUSTAINABLE,
BUT DO
NOT DENY THE
MASSES OF
THIS COUNTRY WHO HAVE
PROSPERED, WHO HAVE BEEN
STHENGTHEND AND LIFTED BY
PROGRAMS LIKE
MEDICARE AND
SOCIAL SECURITY.
AND I'M PROUD TO
SAY
WE
STAND
FOR KEEPING THESE
PROGRAMS
IN
PLACE,
STRENGTHENING AND
NOT
DENYING THEM WHICH I
THINK IS A
MAJOR DISAGREEMENT
ON THE HILL.
.
MR. GARAMENDI: YOU'RE RIGHT,
THIS IS WHERE
WE STAND,
THIS IS
WHERE WE
FIGHT.
MS.
KAPTUR?
MS. KAPTUR: I JUST
WANT
TO SAY
I AM PROUD
TO STAND WITH MY
DEMOCRATIC
COLLEAGUES.
SOCIAL SECURITY IS AN EARNED
BENEFIT AND IT
BELONGS TO THE
AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
WE KNOW
ITS POWER NOT JUST TO
LET
SEEPOR, ALLOW THEM TO LIVE
A
DECENT LIFE IN THEIR
RETIREMENT
YEARS BUT POWER TO
LIFT THE ECONOMY
BECAUSE
SENIORS
SPEND, MAINLY ON THEIR
GRANDCHILDREN, AND
THEY MOVE
THOSE
DOLLARS INTO
THE ECONOMY.
YOU WATCH
WITH THAT COST OF
LIVING
INCREASE, WHICH I'M VERY
HAPPY ABOUT NEXT
YEAR, AND THE
FACT
THAT THE
MEDICARE OFFSET
WILL
NOT BE SO
GREAT THAT
SENIORS WILL HAVE EXTRA
BUYING
POWER
AND THEY WILL WATCH EVERY
PENNY.
I AM JUST SO PROUD
TO BE PART
OF A TRADITION OF
THE
DEMOCRATIC PARTY
THAT HAS
FOUGHT FOR
SOCIAL SECURITY AND
FOR
MEDICARE NOT JUST
FOR THE
FEW BUT
FOR ALL.
BUT FOR
ALL.
AND WE HAVE MADE
THE COUNTRY A
BETTER COUNTRY AS A RESULT.
SO I THINK IT'S
FAIR TO SAY
THAT YES, IT IS
TRUE THE
REPUBLICAN
PARTY HAS FOUGHT
SOCIAL SECURITY, YOU KNOW,
CAN'T THEY FIND
SOMETHING
ELSE?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE PROBLEM
IS WHEN THE VAST,
VAST, VAST
MAJORITY OF THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE, I THINK
99.99% OF THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE ADEPREE WITH
THIS.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THEIR PROBLEM
IS.
MAYBE THEY'RE NOT
LIVING IN
REALITY MOST OF THE TIME.
BUT I AM
JUST VERY PROUD TO BE
PART OF
THIS TRADITION ALONG
WITH MY
COLLEAGUES AND TO SAY
TO OUR
SENIOR CITIZENS THAT
NEXT YEAR WILL BE A BETTER
YEAR
THAN
THIS YEAR.
AND MY
HAT'S OFF TO FRANKLIN
ROOSEVELT AND
FRANCIS PERKINS
AND
ALL THE PEOPLE WHO FOUGHT
BACK IN THE
1930'S TO MAKE THIS
PROGRAM PART OF THE
AMERICAN
WAY OF
LIFE.
MR. GARAMENDI: AND THEN
CARRIED
ON
IN THE 1960'S WITH MEDICARE.
WE HAVE MUCH TO BE
THANKFUL FOR
AS
AMERICANS, DON'T WE?
MR.
TONKO: WE DO.
MR. GARAMENDI: WE ARE
THANKFUL
FOR THE MEN
AND WOMEN THAT
SERVED IN THE HOUSE
OVER THE
YEARS THAT BROUGHT US TO
WHERE
WE ARE,
THE WORLD'S
STROLINGENINGEST,
GREATEST
COUNTRY WITH
THE GREATEST
OPPORTUNITIES.
EVEN WITH ALL THE TROUBLE
WE
HAVE TODAY, WE HAVE
THE
GREATEST OPPORTUNITY.
IT'S A
COUNTRY IN WHICH THE
AMERICAN CREAM
LIVES AND WE
HAVE THE
OBLIGATION TO MAKE
SURE IT'S THERE FOR FUTURE
GENERATIONS.
MR. TONKO, WE ARE GOING
TO DO A
RAPID 30 SECONDS AROUND.
MR.
TONKO: WE HAD A WONDERFUL
HOUR OF
DISCUSSION AND I GIVE
THANKS FOR
THE WONDERFUL
INVESTMENTS THAT HAVE
MADE US
THIS
STRONG NATION.
IN CONCLUSION IF
WE INVEST IN
THE
MIDDLE CLASS OF THIS
NATION, OUR
GREATEST DAYS LIE
AHEAD OF US.
WE HAVE ARE A
-- WE HAVE A
CHANCE TO BE
CONTINUALLY
INVESTING
IN A WAY
THAT ALLOWS
US TO
MAKE IT IN AMERICA AND
ALLOW
FOR INTELLECTUAL CAPACITY
TO
REIGN SUPREME.
IT'S BEEN OUR
HISTORY, IT'S OUR
D.N.A., LET'S MAKE IT
HAPPEN.
I'M OPTIMISTIC ABOUT THE
TOMORROWS FOR THIS COUNTRY
WITH
THE APPROPRIATE
INVESTMENTS.
MR. GARAMENDI: MS.
KAPTUR?
MS. KAPTUR: AMERICAN AMERICA
HAS
BEEN A COUNTRY OF GREAT
HOPE
AND GREAT PROGRESS, AND AS
I LIKE
TO SAY, THE
LAST FOUR
LETTERS IN THE
WORD AMERICAN
ARE
I CAN.
IT'S A
TIME OF GREAT HOPE AND
PROMISE FOR THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE
AND WHAT A GREAT PLEASURE TO
JOIN MY
COLLEAGUES HERE THIS
EVENING.
MR. GARAMENDI: I YIELD BACK
WITH
GREAT THANKS TO MY
COLLEAGUES.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
CHAIR WOULD
ENTERTAIN
A MOTION
FOR
ADJOURNMENT.
MR.
TONKO: I MOVE THAT THE
HOUSE ADJOURN.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
QUESTION IS ON THE MOTION TO
ADJOURN.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO
THE AYES HAVE
IT.
THE MOTION IS ADOPTED.
ACCORDINGLY, THE HOUSE
STANDS
ADJOURNED UNTIL 10:00 A.M.
TOMORROW FOR MORNING
HOUR
DEBATE.