THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
HOUSE WILL BE IN ORDER.
THE CHAIR LAYS BEFORE THE HOUSE
A COMMUNICATION FROM THE
SPEAKER.
THE CLERK: THE
SPEAKER'S ROOM,
WASHINGTON, D.C., NOVEMBER 30,
2011.
I HEREBY APPOINT THE HONORABLE
MO BROOKS
TO ACT AS SPEAKER PRO
TEMPORE ON THIS DAY.
SIGNED,
JOHN
A. BOEHNER,
SPEAKER OF THE
HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
PURSUANT TO THE ORDER OF THE
HOUSE OF JANUARY 5, 2011, THE
CHAIR WILL NOW RECOGNIZE
MEMBERS FROM LISTS SUBMITTED BY
THE MAJORITY AND MINORITY
LEADERS FOR MORNING HOUR
DEBATE.
THE CHAIR WILL ALTERNATE
RECOGNITION BETWEEN THE PARTIES
WITH EACH PARTY LIMITED TO ONE
HOUR AND EACH MEMBER OTHER THAN
THE MAJORITY AND MINORITY
LEADERS AND THE MINORITY WHIP
LIMITED TO FIVE MINUTES
EACH
BUT
IN NO EVENT SHALL DEBATE
CONTINUE BEYOND
11:50 A.M.
THE CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
SOUTH CAROLINA,
MR.
DUNCAN, FOR FIVE MINUTES.
DUNCAN: THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
THIS PAST
WEEKEND I JOINED
MILLIONS OF AMERICANS IN
CELEBRATING THANKSGIVING WITH
FRIENDS AND
FAMILY.
AS AMERICANS
EACH OF US HAS SO
MUCH TO BE
THANKFUL FOR THIS
HOLIDAY SEASON.
AMERICA IS THE
GREATEST, MOST
FREE COUNTRY IN THE
HISTORY OF
THE WORLD.
AS A NATION WE CAN
DO ANYTHING
WE SET
OUT TO ACCOMPLISH.
WE BUILT THE
WORLD'S MOST FREE
AND
SUCCESSFUL
REPUBLIC RIGHT
HERE IN
AMERICA.
WE'VE
USED INNOVATION TO CURE
DISEASE, FIGHT
HUNGER AND
SPREAD THE
MESSAGE OF FREEDOM
ALL
ACROSS THE GLOBE.
WE'VE CHANGED
THE WAY SOCIETIES
INTERACT
BY INVENTING THINGS
LIKE THE
TELEPHONE, THE
AUTOMOBILE
AND THE
AIRPLANE.
WE'VE BUILT SOME
OF THE FINEST
SCHOOLS, UNIVERSITIES IN THE
HISTORY OF THE PLANET.
WE CHANGED OUR WORLD FOR
THE
BETTER BUT NONE
OF IT WOULD
HAVE BEEN POSSIBLE WITHOUT THE
GRACE AND BLESSING
OF OUR
ALMIGHTY GOD.
THAT'S WHY I WAS
BOTH SURPRISED
AND
DISAPPOINTED THAT PRESIDENT
OBAMA FAILED TO MAKE
A SINGLE
REFERENCES
TO GOD DURING HIS
THST ADDRESS
TO THE NATION.
-- THANKSGIVING
ADDRESS TO THE
NATION.
SINCE THE PRESIDENT HAS A
HISTORY OF DOING THIS
SORT OF
THING, I
DON'T THINK IT'S AN
OVERSIGHT.
PERHAPS IT'S HIS ATTEMPT TO
BEING
POLITICALLY CORRECT.
THERE'S
NO
EXCUSE FOR ONCE
AGAIN LEAVING OUT
THE ONE WHOM
OUR
FOUNDATIONS REST.
WHAT DID THE
FOUNDING FATHERS
SAY
IN THE DECLARATION OF
INDEPENDENCE?
OUR RIGHTS COME DIRECTLY FROM
GOD.
AS
THE APOSTLE PAUL
SAID, IN
EVERYTHING
GIVE THANKS FOR THIS
IS THE
WILL
OF GOD IN CHRIST
JESUS
FOR YOU.
WE SHOULD NEVER PASS UP
AN
OPPORTUNITY TO
THANK THE LORD
FOR THE
BLESSINGS HE'S BESTOWED
ON THIS GREAT
NATION.
I KNOW
POLITICAL CORRECTNESS
LOOMS OVER
THIS COUNTRY MORE
THAN
EVER BEFORE.
THERE'S A LOT
OF PRESSURE
WITHIN
ELEMENTS WITHIN OUR
SOCIETY WHO
CENSORS GOD.
LEAVING GOD OUT OF OUR
SCHOOLS,
CLASSROOMS.
NO PRAYING
BEFORE GRADUATION
AND ATHLETIC
EVENTS AND SOME
SHOPPING
MALLS WOULD RATHER
PLAY MUSIC
ABOUT SANTA CLAUS.
PRAYING AND
GIVING THANKS TO
GOD WAS THE EXAMPLE
SET FOR US
BY
THE FIRST SETTLERS WHO CAME
TO
AMERICA FOR RELIGIOUS
FREEDOM.
TIMES WERE TOUGH FOR
THEM.
THEY
ENDURED BITTERLY COLD
WINTERS, FOOD
SHORTAGES AND
PLAGUES.
THE
EARLY
SETTLERS FACED
INSURMOUNTABLE
ODDS, BUT THEY
THRIVED LEADING
TO THE
FORMATION OF THIS
GREAT NATION.
GENERAL GEORGE WASHINGTON, WHO
WENT ON TO BECOME
OUR FIRST
PRESIDENT, WAS
KNOWN
FOR
FREQUENTLY
STOPPING WHATEVER HE
WAS DOING AND
GETTING DOWN ON
ONE KNEE TO SEEK
GUIDANCE FROM
THE LORD AND
TO PRAISE HIM FOR
THE BLESSINGS
THAT WERE GIVEN
HIS
TROOPS.
HERE IN THIS
BUILDING THERE IS
A
CHAPEL WHERE MEMBERS OF
CONGRESS CAN GO TO
PRAY FOR
THIS
COUNTRY.
IN THAT
CHAPEL THERE IS A
BEAUTIFUL STAINED
GLASS WINDOW
DEPICTING OUR FIRST
PRESIDENT,
GEORGE WASHINGTON, IN HIS
COLONIAL
UNIFORM FROZEN
KNEELING IN
PRAYER.
THAT CHAPEL SHOULD
BE A
REMINDER
FOR ALL OF US THAT OUR
COUNTRY'S FAITH
SHOULD BE
NOTHING
TO HIDE BUT RATHER
SOMETHING TO EMBRACE
AND
PROTECT
AND THAT IMAGE OF
GEORGE WASHINGTON IN PRAYER
SHOULD BE A
REMINDER THAT OUR
LEADERS NEED TO SEEK
WISDOM OF
THE
LORD WHENEVER POSSIBLE.
FOR THE PAST SEVERAL
WEEKS,
FORMER
HEISMAN TROPHY WINNER
TIM TEBOW
HAS COME UNDER FIRE,
FACING
CRITICISM FROM SPORTS
COMMENTATORS AND EVEN
SOME OF
HIS
OWN TEAMMATES.
TIM TEBOW GAVE THE
FOLLOWING
RESPONSE TO
REPORTERS, A
RESPONSE
I BELIEVE PERFECTLY
EXPLAINS HOW
OUR COUNTRY SHOULD
RECOGNIZE GOD.
QUARTERBACK TEBOW SAID
THIS, IF
YOU'RE
MARRIED AND YOU REALLY
LOVE YOUR WIFE,
IS IT GOOD
ENOUGH
ONLY TO SAY TO YOUR
WIFE, I
LOVE HER, THE DAY YOU
GET MARRIED
OR SHOULD YOU TELL
HER EVERY
SINGLE DAY WHEN YOU
WAKE
UP AND EVERY
OPPORTUNITY?
MY
RELATIONSHIP WITH JESUS
CHRIST IS THE MOST IMPORTANT
THING IN MY LIFE
SO EVERY TIME
I
GET THE OPPORTUNITY TO TELL
HIM I LOVE HIM OR GIVE
HIM THE
OPPORTUNITY TO
SHOUT HIM
OUT ON
NATIONAL TV I AM GOING
TO TAKE
THAT OPPORTUNITY.
SO
AS I LOOK -- AND SO I LOOK
THE
RELATIONSHIP I HAVE WITH
HIM THAT I WANT TO GIVE
HIM THE
HONOR AND
TPWHRORY ANYTIME I
HAVE THE
OPPORTUNITY.
TIM
TEBOW'S BRAVE COMMENTS ARE
AN EXCELLENT
REMINDER THAT WE
NEED
TO LOOK FOR EVERY
OPPORTUNITY TO
THANK THE LORD
FOR
OUR BLESSINGS OF LIBERTIES
THAT
HE'S BESTOWED ON THIS
GREAT
COUNTRY.
MAY
GOD FORGIVE THIS NATION OF
ITS
SINCE, MAY HE OVERLOOK THE
TIMES WE
FORGET TO THANK HIM
FOR HIS
GIFTS AND
MAY PEOPLE
TURN TO HIM
FOR GUIDANCE AND
SALVATION AND MAY
HE CONTINUE
TO BLESS
THE UNITED STATES OF
AMERICA.
MR. SPEAKER, I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM OREGON, MR. BLUMENAUER,
FOR FIVE MINUTES.
MR. BLUMENAUER: THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
IT'S
A SIGN OF MATURITY TO BE
ABLE TO
RETAIN TWO DIFFERENT
BUT RELATED
CONCEPTS
IN YOUR
HEAD
AT THE SAME TIME.
FOR INSTANCE,
TAXES SHOULD NOT
BE
RAISED ON THE MAJORITY OF
WORKING
AMERICANS WHILE THE
ECONOMY IS IN
THIS VERY
DIFFICULT SITUATION
, BUT
A
LITTLE MORE CAN
REASONABLY BE
PAID BY
THOSE WHO ARE EXTREMELY
WELL-OFF.
THE SIMPLE FACT
IS THAT OUR
ECONOMY
AND OUR FAMILIES CANNOT
AFFORD TO
TAKE THE ECONOMIC HIT
THAT
IS POISED TO PULL TO PULL
$100 BILLION
OUT OF THE
ECONOMY
WITH THE
EXPIRATION OF THE 2%
PAYROLL
TAX HOLIDAY
THAT'S
SCHEDULED TO EXPIRE THIS
YEAR.
THERE IS
CURRENTLY A PROPOSAL
THAT'S
BEING DEBATED
IN THE
OTHER BODY THAT
I HOPE WILL
HAVE
THE OPPORTUNITY TO VOTE ON
HERE
TO BE ABLE TO EXTEND AND
EXPAND THE
PAYROLL TAX CUT AND
PAY FOR
IT.
UNDER THIS
PROPOSAL EMPLOYEES
WOULD RECEIVE A
50% ADDITIONAL
CUT
IN THE PAYROLL TAX, CUTTING
IT
ESSENTIALLY IN HALF, AND
EMPLOYERS
WOULD HAVE A SLIGHT
REDUCTION
IN THE PAYROLL TAX
THAT THEY
PAY ON THEIR
EMPLOYEES
UP TO THE FIRST 3.1%
OF PAYROLL
-- EXCUSE ME -- $5
MILLION OF
PAYROLL.
THIS WOULD HELP
98% OF
BUSINESSES BUT
NOT GIVE
UNNECESSARY
GIVEAWAYS TO LARGE
AND
PROFITABLE ORGANIZATIONS.
AND MOST
IMPORTANT, IT WOULD
PREVENT THE
TYPICAL FAMILY FROM
SUFFERING
A SIGNIFICANT
INCREASE
IN THEIR TAXES WHILE
THE
ECONOMY IS STILL FRAGILE.
THIS PROPOSAL
WOULD GIVE THE
AVERAGE FAMILY
$1,500 A YEAR
EXTRA
TO SPEND.
YOU WOULD THINK
THAT PEOPLE
OUGHT
TO BE ABLE TO CORRELATE
THOSE
TWO CONCEPTS.
THE
WAY THAT THIS WOULD BE
FINANCED IS A
SMALL SURTAX ON
NOT
JUST RICH BUT SUPERRICH
PEOPLE.
THESE ARE FOLKS WHO
MAKE OVER
$1
MILLION A YEAR AND THEY
WOULD JUST
PAY THE SURTAX ON
THAT AMOUNT THAT
THEY EARN OVER
THE
$1 MILLION THRESHOLD.
IT'S FAR LESS
THAN THE 1% THAT
WE ARE
HEARING ARGUED ABOUT.
THEY WOULD
STILL PAY LOWER BUSH
TAX-ERA
RATES ON THE FIRST $1
MILLION AND
THOSE THAT HAVE
EXTENSIVE
INVESTMENT INCOME
WHICH
MOST OF
THEM DO WOULD
STILL
BENEFIT FROM THOSE
LOWER
RATES.
UNFORTUNATELY WE HAVE PEOPLE
HERE THAT ARE CAUGHT UP
IN AN
IDEOLOGY THAT TRUMPS
CONCERN
FOR THE ECONOMY
AND THE
TYPICAL
AMERICAN FAMILY.
IT WAS
THIS REFUSAL TO CONSIDER
A
BALANCED APPROACH THAT IS
SUPPORTED
BY THE VAST MAJORITY
OF THE PUBLIC
THAT LED TO THE
COLLAPSE OF THE
SO-CALLED
SUPERCOMMITTEE.
AMERICANS WERE AND
ARE READY
FOR ACTION
THAT IS BOLD, BIG
AND BALANCED
AND FAIR.
NOW, WE
ACTUALLY CAN START ON
THE ROAD TO
RECOVERY BY JUST
GOING
ON AUTOPILOT.
THE
DEFAULT THAT IS SET UP THAT
WILL
LET THE BUSH-ERA TAX CUTS
EXPIRE, UNLESS
CONGRESS DONE
SOMETHING, AND MOVING
TOWARDS
AUTOMATIC SEQUESTRATION WILL
ACTUALLY SOLVE
MOST OF THE
DEFICIT PROBLEM THAT
WE FACE
JUST BY DOING
NOTHING.
BUT WE CAN
DO BETTER.
WE CAN
ADJUST, WE CAN CRAFT, WE
CAN
FOCUS IT TO GET THE MOST
BENEFIT
AND WE CAN START WITH A
MODEST
ADJUSTMENT.
I'D HOPE MY COLLEAGUES
WILL NOT
LET
THE WORSHIP OF THE TOP .1
OF THE ECONOMIC
PYRAMID TRUMP
CONCERNS
FOR THE
REST OF THE
WORKING
FAMILIES AND THE
AMERICAN
ECONOMY.
THANK YOU
AND I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM ALABAMA, MR. BROOKS, FOR
FIVE MINUTES.
MR. BROOKS: THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
OSLAM LIVES
IN ALABAMA'S FIFTH
CONGRESSIONAL
DISTRICT.
HE IS A
FATHER WHO LOVES AND
CARES VERY MUCH
ABOUT HIS SON.
AT HIS
REQUEST, LET ME SHARE
WITH YOU AND THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE THE
PLIGHT OF HIS SON,
HAMASH
KAHN.
MR.
KAHN IS AN AMERICAN CITIZEN
WHO, THANKS TO THE
OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION AND
THE UNITED
STATES
GOVERNMENT, HAS BEEN
WRONGFULLY
HELD FOR OVER A YEAR
AND A HALF
IN PAKISTAN PRISONS
WITHOUT
INDICTMENT FOR A
SPECIFIC CRIME OR
TRIAL.
THIS IS
HAMASH KAHN'S STORY.
HE'S
LIVED IN AMERICA SINCE HE
WAS 10 YEARS
OLD.
HE EARNED
A BACHELOR'S AND TWO
MASTERS DEGREE
FROM GEORGIA
SOUTHERN
UNIVERSITY, FOLLOWING
GRADUATION,
MR. KAHN WORKED FOR
CITIBANK IN
PAKISTAN.
IN
2003 THE MUSHARRAF
GOVERNMENT
HAD HIM LEAD
THE
BANK.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THE MUSHARRAF
GOVERNMENT FELL IN
2008.
AS IS OFTEN
IS THE CASE IN THE
WORLD, A NEW
GOVERNMENT REGIME
MEANS
THAT
APPOINTEES OF THE
LAST REGIME
HAS TROUBLE.
IN
KAHN'S CASE, THE NEW
GOVERNMENT
ISSUED AN ARREST
WARRANT ON
SUSPICION OF
CORRUPTION AND CORRUPT
PRACTICES.
LET ME
EMPHASIZE THAT POINT.
.
ON
SUSPICION OF CORRUPTION AND
CORRUPT PRACTICES.
FEARING REPRISALS,
HE FEARED
PAKISTAN FOR HIS
HOME, AMERICA.
THEREAFTER, PAKISTAN SOUGHT
EXTRADITION OF MR.
KAHN PURSUANT
TO THE ARREST
WARRANT FOR
SUSPICION OF
CORRUPTION AND
CORRUPT
PRACTICES.
LET ME BE
CLEAR ON THIS POINT.
THREE
PARTIES ARE INVOLVED
IN
THIS
TRAGEDY.
A NEW
PAKISTANI REGIME,
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND
THE UNITED
STATES
GOVERNMENT, AND KAHN, AN
AMERICAN
CITIZEN.
THE UNITED STATES
HAD TO DECIDE
WHOM TO
SUPPORT.
PAKISTAN
OR AN AMERICAN CITIZEN.
THE
OBAMA ADMINISTRATION CHOSE
PAKISTAN
OVER ITS OWN AMERICAN
CITIZEN.
MR. SPEAKER,
IT WOULD BE
WONDERFUL
TO KNOW
WHY THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION
MADE THAT
DECISION.
IN ANY
EVENT, ON DECEMBER 10,
2009, MR.
KAHN WAS ARRESTED BY
UNITED STATES
MARSHALS IN HIS
OFFICE IN
WASHINGTON,
D.C., AND
HELD
WITHOUT BOND FOR FIVE
MONTHS.
REMARKABLY, PERSONS IN MR.
KAHN'S
POSITION ARE BARRED FROM
FULLY DEFENDING
THEMSELVES AT
EXTRADITION HEARINGS.
FOR EXAMPLE, MR.
KAHN WAS BARRED
FROM
PRESENTING EVIDENCE TO
IMPEACH
THE ALLEGATIONS AGAINST
HIM.
MR.
KAHN
FOUGHT EXTRADITION
UNTIL IT BECAME
CLEAR THAT THE
SEVERE
EVIDENTIARY LIMITATIONS
MAY IT IMPOSSIBLE FOR
HIM TO
DEFEND HIMSELF.
ON MAY 13,
2010, THE UNITED
STATES GOVERNMENT
FORCEFULLY
HANDED MR.
KAHN OVER
TO
PAKISTANI
AUTHORITIES AT JOHN F.
KENNEDY AIRPORT IN
NEW YORK.
HE WAS
BOUND IN HANDCUFFS AND
LEG
CHAINS.
WITH THE
OBAMA ADMINISTRATION'S
ADMINISTRATION'S HISTORIC
ACT,
HE BECAME THE FIRST
AMERICAN
CITIZEN EVERY
EXTRADITED TO
PAKISTAN.
THE ONE
CONCESSION THE UNITED
STATES STATE DEPARTMENT RECEIVED
FROM THE
NEW PAKISTANI REGIME
WAS A PROMISE MR.
KAHN WOULD BE
FAIRLY TREATED
UNDER PAKISTANI
LAW.
WHILE ANYONE
HEARING THE STORY
CAN SUSPECT POLITICAL
MOTIVATIONS FOR THE PROSECUTION
OF MR.
KAHN BY PAKISTANI
AUTHORITIES, I
AM NOT IN A
POSITION
TO MAKE A JUDGMENT ON
THAT
ISSUE.
BUT I AM
IN A POSITION TO MAKE A
JUDGMENT
ABOUT OUR UNITED STATES
GOVERNMENT AND
ITS
RESPONSIBILITY TO PROTECT
AMERICAN CITIZENS.
WHETHER HE
IS INNOCENT OR GUILTY
OF THE CHARGES
BY PAKISTANI
AUTHORITIES, KAHN
HAS NOT BEEN
SERVED
JUSTICE.
UNDER PAKISTANI
LAW, AFTER
ARREST FOR
SUSPICION, PAKISTAN'S
NATIONAL
ACCOUNTABILITY BUREAU
CAN
HOLD A PERSON FOR
UP TO
THREE MONTHS,
THREE MONTHS
WITHOUT BRAILLE.
WITHIN
THAT -- WITHOUT BAIL.
WITHIN THAT THREE
MONTHS
PAKISTAN'S NATIONAL
ACCOUNTABILITY
BUREAU MUST
EITHER
INDICT A HELD PERSON FOR
SPECIFIC CRIMES FOR
TRIAL OR
ORDER HIS
RELEASE.
YET
IT IS NOW OVER 18 MONTHS
SINCE
KAHN BECAME THE FIRST
AMERICAN
CITIZEN EXTRADITED TO
PAKISTAN.
FOR THOSE 18 MONTHS MR.
KAHN HAS
BEEN
HELD WITHOUT BAIL, WITHOUT
INDICTMENT, AND
WITHOUT TRIAL.
MR.
KAHN LIVES IN A SIX FOOT BY
SIX FOOT PRISON CELL
IN PAKISTAN
I.
-- PAKISTAN.
I PRAY THE AMERICAN
STATE
DEPARTMENT DID NOT
ANTICIPATE HE
WOULD BE
HELD INDEFINITELY
WITHOUT INDICTMENT OR
TRIAL WHEN
THEY FORCEFULLY
BOUNDED AND
SHACKLED AND
AMERICAN CITIZEN
AND
GAVE HIM TO PAKISTAN.
THEREFORE,
MR. SPEAKER, I ENTER
THIS
STATEMENT ON THE
CONGRESSIONAL RECORD.
IT IS TIME
FOR AMERICA'S STATE
DEPARTMENT TO USE WHATEVER
INFLUENCE IS NECESSARY
AND
PROPER
TO CAUSE PAKISTAN TO
TREAT MR. KAHN
IN ACCORDANCE
WITH
PAKISTAN'S OWN LAW AND WITH
INTERNATIONAL
TREATY
OBLIGATIONS.
JUSTICE CANNOT BE SERVED
AN
AMERICAN
CITIZEN IN ANY OTHER
WAY.
MR. SPEAKER, I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR RECOGNIZES
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM ILLINOIS,
MR. JACKSON, FOR
FIVE MINUTES.
MR.
JACKSON: WHO SAYS, MR.
SPEAKER, THE GOVERNMENT
CAN'T
CREATE JOBS?
THE GREATEST
NEED OF THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE
TODAY IS JOBS,
BUT THE QUESTION
BEFORE THEM IS
THIS -- WHO IS
RESPONSIBLE AND
HOW SHOULD JOBS BE
CREATED?
DEMOCRATS, REPUBLICANS,
AND
INDEPENDENTS,
LIBERALS,
MODERATES,
AND CONSERVATIVES ALL
AGREE THAT
THE PRIVATE SECTOR IS
THE PRIMARY SOURCE OF
JOBS.
HOWEVER,
WITH 9% OFFICIAL
UNEMPLOYMENT, THE
REALITY IS
IT'S
MUCH HIGHER, AND 25 MILLION
AMERICANS
EITHER UNEMPLOYED,
UNDEREMPLOYED, IS SELF-EVIDENT
THAT THE PRIVATE SECTOR
HAS NOT
SUPPLIED
ENOUGH JOBS AND EITHER
CANNOT OR
WILL NOT CREATE ENOUGH
FULL-TIME JOBS
TODAY TO EMPLOY
THE
25 MILLION PEOPLE WHO NEED
THEM.
SO WHAT DO WE
DO?
THROW
OUR HANDS UP AND SAY
NOTHING CAN BE
DONE, CONGRESS?
DEMOCRATS
GENERALLY BELIEVE IN
PRIMING THE
PUMP, THROUGH
DEFICIT
SPENDING IF NECESSARY,
TO CREATE JOBS AND
STIMULATE THE
ECONOMY IN ORDER
TO PUT THE
OVERALL ECONOMY
BACK ON TRACK
DURING THESE
TIMES WHEN THE
PRIVATE
SECTOR HAS OBVIOUSLY
FAILED US.
IN THE PAST, MANY
REPUBLICANS
HAVE GENERALLY
AGREED,
BUT THIS
CURRENT TEA PARTY REPUBLICAN
PARTY ALL OF
WHOM HAVE A
GOVERNMENT
JOB AND EMPLOY
GOVERNMENT STAFFS,
DON'T AGREE
AND
GENERALLY ARGUES THE
GOVERNMENT CAN'T CREATE
JOBS.
REALLY?
PRESIDENT FRANKLIN
DELANO
ROOSEVELT, WE ARE REMINDED
IN
THE BOOK
&quot;THE NEW DEAL, A MODERN
HISTORY REVEALS A DIFFERENT
TRUTH&quot; WHICH
IS THE SOURCE OF
THE FOLLOWING
INFORMATION.
F.
DRGE R. WAS SWORN INTO OFFICE
ON MARCH
4, 1933.
HE
CAME UP WITH THE IDEA HIMSELF
OF A
CIVILIAN CONSERVATION CORPS
ON MARCH 13.
THE FIRST JOBS PROGRAM
OF THE
NEW
DEAL.
HE PRESENTED
HIS IDEA TO WHITE
HOUSE AIDE
RAYMOND MOLY ON MARCH
14.
AN IDEA HE HAD
JUST COME UP WITH
THE
NIGHT BEFORE.
IDEA, MR. SPEAKER, WAS TO
PUT PLATOONS
OF YOUNG UNEMPLOYED
MEN
TO WORK IN THE FOREST AND
NATIONAL PARKS.
THAT VERY AFTERNOON A
MEMO AN
SKELTON BILL
WENT OUT TO THE
FOURTH
SECRETARIES THAT WOULD BE
INVOLVED IN IMPLEMENTING
THE
C.C.C.
PLAN, LABOR, AGRICULTURE,
ICKES,
WAR, THE FIRST
INTERDISCIPLINARY AGENCY OF THE
NEW DEAL.
THE
NEXT DAY MARCH
15, THE FOUR
SECRETARIES
RETURNED A JOINT
RESPONSE
PROPOSING A WIDER
RELIEF PROGRAM
ENCOMPASSING NOT
ONLY A
CIVILIAN CONSERVATION
CORPS, BUT A
PUBLIC WORKS
PROGRAM AND GRANT AND
AID TO THE
STATES
AND MUNICIPALITIES FOR
RELIEF.
ON
MARCH 21,
F.D.R. SENT A
MESSAGE
TO CONGRESS INVOLVING,
AMONG OTHER THINGS, HIS IDEA
OF
A
C.C.C.
IN HIS
MESSAGE HE OBSERVED THAT
THE MORE
IMPORTANT, MORE
IMPORTANT
THAN THE MATERIAL
GAINS WILL BE THE MORAL AND
SPIRITUAL VALUE OF
SUCH WORK.
WE CAN
TAKE A VAST ARMY OF THESE
UNEMPLOYED
.
CONGRESS
DEBATED AND PASSED THE
CIVILIAN CONSERVATION
CORPS
PROGRAM IN
EIGHT DAYS ON MARCH
29.
BY
EARLY APRIL, THE
C.C.C. WAS
OPENED FOR
BUSINESS.
THE FIRST
REGISTERED WAS
19-YEAR-OLD
RIZZO OF NEW YORK
WHO ARRIVED ON APRIL
7 AT AN
ARMY
RECRUITING STATION IN A CAB
WITH THREE
OF HIS FRIENDS.
HE BELONGED
TO A FAMILY OF 13
WHOSE FATHER HAD NOT
WORKED IN
THREE
YEARS.
SO HOW
DID THESE GOVERNMENT
CREATED JOBS WORK
OUT?
THE
AVERAGE ENROLLEE SIGNED UP
AT AN AGE
OF 18
1/2.
STAYED FOR
NINE MONTHS.
SIX MONTHS
WITH THE
MINIMUM
TOUR.
TWO YEARS, THE
MAXIMUM.
AND GAINED UP TO
30 POUNDS
DURING
HIS TERM.
THANKS
TO THREE SQUARE MEALS A
DAY
SERVED UP BY
THE ARMY
QUARTER
MASTERS AS FUEL FOR
DAILY LABOR.
THE PROGRAM RAMPED
UP QUICKLY,
BY
JULY THERE WERE 1,300 CAMPS
HOUSING
275,000 ENROLLEES.
ALREADY WORKING
VIGOROUSLY
ON
PROJECTS THAT WOULD
RANK AMONG
THE MOST
NOTABLE LEGACY OF THE
NEW
DEAL, BEFORE THE C.C.C.
ENDING AND
THE WAR MOBILIZATION
IN
1942, THEY BUILT 125,000
MILES
OF ROAD.
46,000
BRIDGES.
MORE THAN
300,000 DAMS TO CHECK
EROSION.
IT
PLANTED MORE
THAN THREE
BILLION
TREES AND STRUNG 89,000
MILES
OF TELEPHONE WIRE.
THE
CAMPS INSTILLED IN MANY OF
THESE YOUNG
MEN THE CONCEPT OF
AN AMERICAN IDENTITY
.
NO DOUBT
THE CAMARADERIE WAS
FOSTERED BY SHARED
RESENTMENT OF
THE
MARSHAL REGIMENT, THE RISING
OF THE
BUGLER'S CALL, THE
MANDATE TO KEEP THEIR
BUNK AND
FOOT LOCKERS
IN ORDER.
THE
HEEDING OF SENIOR OFFICERS
WITHOUT
DISCUSSION.
AND MR. SPEAKER, I
CAN ONLY
IMAGINE THAT
TODAY THESE
ARMY
QUARTER MASTERS WOULD
DEMAND
THAT
OUR YOUNG MEN PULL UP THEIR
PANTS.
THE
ARMY,
TOO, EXPERIENCED
VALUABLE AS THE
WAR SECRETARY
CONFIDED TO PERKINS A YEAR
INTO
THE
PROGRAM, HIS OFFICERS CORPS
HAD
HAD TO LEARN TO GOVERN MEN
BY
LEADERSHIP, EXPLANATION AND
DIPLOMACY RATHER
THAN JUST
DISCIPLINE.
THE KNOWLEDGE, MR. SPEAKER,
IS
PRICELESS.
THE C.C.C. WOULD SERVE AS THE
MODEL FOR NATIONAL SERVICE
PROGRAMS OF A
LATER ERA SUCH AS
THE PEACE
CORPS, AMAR'E CORPS,
AND
VISTA.
--
AMAR'E CORPS, AND VISTA.
THERE
---AMAR'EA CORPS AND
VISTA.
IT WAS SOMETHING YOU COULD TAKE
PRIDE IN.
THERE WASN'T A LOT OF PRIDE
AVAILABLE IN THOSE DAYS.
AMONG THE
NEW DEAL PROGRAMS THE
C.C.C. WOULD INSPIRE
ALMOST
UNIVERSAL
AFFECTION EVEN MORE
SO, MR. SPEAKER, THAN
SOCIAL
SECURITY.
MR. SPEAKER,
THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT CAN CREATE
JOBS.
I YIELD BACK
THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR RECOGNIZES
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM MARYLAND, MR.
BARTLETT, FOR
TWO MINUTES.
MR.
BARTLETT: THANK YOU, MR.
SPEAKER.
ON NOVEMBER
18, RON SMITH, A
RESPECTED AND
BELOVED BALTIMORE
AREA RADIO
TALK SHOW HOST, ON
WBAL,
AS WELL AS A COLUMNIST FOR
THE BALTIMORE
SUNDAY, ANNOUNCED
HIS
RETIREMENT -- &quot;BALTIMORE
SUN,&quot; ANNOUNCED HIS
RETIREMENT
AFTER 26
YEARS BECAUSE OF HIS
DIAGNOSIS OF
INOPERABLE
PANCREATIC
CANCER AND
IMPENDING
DEATH.
I
ASK ALL OF MY COLLEAGUES TO
JOIN ME ALONG
WITH THOUSANDS OF
LOYAL LISTENERS
AND READERS WHO
HAVE
EXPRESSED THEIR DEEP
APPRECIATION AND
ADMIRATION FOR
RON SMITH.
RON
UNFAILINGLY CONTRIBUTED A
VOICE
OF REASON.
WITH UNMATCHED CANDOR
WHILE
PROVIDING A
FORUM FOR CIVIL AND
VIGOROUS DEBATE
ABOUT POLITICS
AND POLICY THAT IS
SORELY NEEDED
EVERYWHERE IN AMERICA.
I FEEL
PRIVILEGED TO HAVE BEEN A
GUEST
A NUMBER OF TIMES ON RON'S
SHOW
ON WBAL.
IT WAS ALWAYS
EQUALLY A
PLEASURE
AND CHALLENGE TO
MEET RON'S HIGH
STANDARDS.
RON
IS A TRUE CONSERVATIVE IN
THE CLASSICAL
AND HISTORICAL
MEANING
OF THE TERM.
WITH EQUAL ENTHUSIASM
AND UTMOST
RESPECT, RON
ASKED TOUGH
QUESTIONS
OF
GUESTS AND CALLERS,
AND DISSECTED
THE ARGUMENTS OF
LIBERAL
ELITES.
DEMOCRATS AND REPUBLICANS AND
OTHERS
WHO CALLED THEMSELVES
CONSERVATIVES.
FROM
A VAST KNOWLEDGE OF BOTH
HISTORY
AND GOVERNMENT, RON
SMITH SHARED
AND WE IN MARYLAND
WERE MOST PRIVILEGED
TO BENEFIT
FROM A
SUCCINCT AND PERSUASIVE
DIALOGUE
AND INTRODUCTION TO
LIBERTY AND
REASON.
THANK
YOU, RON.
GODSPEED.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR RECOGNIZES
THE GENTLEWOMAN
FROM
ILLINOIS, MS. SCHAKOWSKY,
FOR FIVE
MINUTES.
MS. SCHAKOWSKY: WHILE MANY
HOURS
HAVE BEEN SPENT
BY THIS BODY
DEBATING THE WARS IN IRAQ AND
AFGHANISTAN,
FAR TOO LITTLE TIME
HAS BEEN DEVOTED
TO THE UNITED
STATES'
GROWING
DEPENDENCE ON
PRIVATE MILITARY
CONTRACTORS.
THE WEAPON
CARRYING
FOR-PROFIT
SECURITY
COMPANIES, MERCENARIES,
WHO HAVE
BECOME INTEGRAL AND
COUNTERPRODUCTIVE
ACTORS IN THE
WAR
EFFORT.
I BELIEVE
THAT INCREASED
RELIANCE ON HIGHER
GUNS TO
PROVIDE SECURITY
IN CONFLICT
ZONES
UNDERMINES OUR POLICY
OBJECTIVES AND I'M NOT
ALONE.
IN
2007, THEN DEFENSE SECRETARY
ROBERT
GATES STATED THAT THE
MISSION OF
MANY SECURITY
CONTRACTORS
WAS, QUOTE, AT
CROSS-PURPOSES TO
OUR LARGER
MISSION
IN IRAQ, UNQUOTE.
WE SHOULD BE
CONCERNED.
PRIVATE CONTRACTORS DON'T
WEAR
THE
DAMAGE OF THE UNITED STATES.
THEY ANSWER
TO A CORPORATION NOT
A UNIFORM
COMMANDER.
OUR GOVERNMENT
DOESN'T EVEN KNOW
HOW MANY CONTRACT
PERSONNEL WE
HAVE
HIRED BECAUSE LEGAL
JURISDICTION REMAINS MURKY.
WE MAY LACK
THE ABILITY TO PRRKT
CONTRACTORS FOR
ALLEGED --
PROSECUTE
CONTRACTORS FOR
ALLEGED
VIOLATIONS COMMITTED
OVERSEAS.
WE NEED TO END
OUR RELIANCE ON
SECURITY CONTRACTORS
IN CONFLICT
ZONES.
SINCE 2007 I INTRODUCED THE STOP
OUTSOURCING SECURITY ACT
TO
PHASE OUT THE USE
OF
FOR-PROFIT
CONTRACTORS
FROM
MISSION
CRITICAL
TASKS, INCLUDING
SECURITY,
INTELLIGENCE,
AND
INTERROGATION
IN CONFLICT AREAS.
THE
S.O.S. BILL BUILDS ON
LEGISLATION I HAVE
INTRODUCED
SINCE
2001, INCLUDING THE ANDEAN
REGION
CONTRACT OR
ACCOUNTABILITY ACT
TO PROHIBIT
MILITARY
CONTRACTING IN COLUMBIA
AND
NEIGHBORING NATIONS.
WHILE THE PROBLEM APPLIES
TO
OTHER PRIVATE
CONTRACTORS, THERE
IS ONE COMPANY
THAT HAS BECOME
SYNONYMOUS WITH
MISCONDUCT.
BLACKWATER.
OPERATING UNDER A CULTURE
OF
RECKLESSNESS
CREATED BY ITS
FOUNDER, ERIC
PRINCE, BLACKWATER
EMPLOYEES HAVE BEEN
IMPLICATED
IN A WIDE RANGE OF ALLEGED
MISCONDUCT SINCE 2004,
FROM
SHOOTING AND
KILLING CIVILIANS
TO
GUN RUNNING.
FIVE FORMER
BLACKWATER
COMPENGTIFFS,
INCLUDING ITS
FORMER PRESIDENT, WERE
INDICTED
IN
2010 FOR WEAPONS CHARGES.
THE
COMPANY AGREED TO A $42
MILLION ADMINISTRATIVE
SETTLEMENT WITH THE
STATE
DEPARTMENT FOR
288 ALLEGED
VIOLATIONS OF THE
ARMS EXPORT
CONTROL
ACT AND INTERNATIONAL
TRAFFIC AND ARMS
REGULATIONS.
AT
LEAST SEVEN CIVIL SUITS FOR
ALLEGED
ABUSES BY BLACK WATER
PERSONNEL IN IRAQ HAVE BEEN
SETTLED.
AND
LEGAL ACTION IS STILL
PENDING AGAINST
FOUR BLACKWATER
GUARDS ACCUSED
OF MASSACRING 17
CIVILIANS
IN BAGHDAD'S SQUARE IN
2007.
FURTHER
THE IRAQI GOVERNMENT,
OUR ALLY, HAS
REPEATEDLY ASKED
THAT
BLACKWATER BE OUT OFED,
LEAVING THE UNITED STATES STATE
DEPARTMENT TO
REFUSE TO RENEW
THE
COMPANY'S CONTRACT IN 2009.
IN
SHORT, BLACKWATER, NOW
RENAMED Z,
HAS BEEN THE CENTER
OF CONTROVERSY
FOR YEARS, IN
CONGRESSIONAL
COMMITTEES, THE
PRESS, AND AMONG
MEMBERS OF THE
MILITARY.
YET THE COMPANY HAS
RECEIVED
OVER
$1.25 BILLION IN TAXPAYER
MONEY.
RECENTLY MR. PRINCE HAS
LAUNCHED
A
VIDEO GAME, CALLED BLACKWATER,
GLORIFYING
THE DISCREDITED
COMPANY HE
STARTED.
NOW HE'S
ADOPTED ANOTHER
HEAVY-HANDED TACTIC.
ATTEMPTED INTIMIDATION
OF A
MEMBER OF
CONGRESS.
LAST MONTH A LETTER FROM HIS
ATTORNEY WAS HAND
DELIVERED TO
MY
CONGRESSIONAL OFFICE.
I AM
ENTERING THE LETTER IN THE
CONGRESSIONAL RECORD.
IT ACCUSES ME
OF
DEFAMATORY
STATEMENTS,
CHARACTERIZES MY
EFFORTS
TO URGE INVESTIGATIONS
INTO PRINCE AS
A VIOLATION OF
CONGRESSIONAL
POWER, AND
DESCRIBES
POSSIBLE LEGAL ACTION
IF
I PERSIST.
.
I COME TO THE FLOOR
TODAY TO
SPEAK
OUT AGAINST POLICIES AND
ENTITIES
THAT I BELIEVE ARE
DAMAGING TO
OUR NATION.
I WANT
TO MAKE IT CLEAR TO MR.
PRINCE THAT I
WILL NOT STOP
WORKING
TO END OUR RELIANCE ON
PRIVATE SECURITY
CONTRACTORS OR
TO INVESTIGATE
ANY AND ALL
ALLEGATIONS OF
MISCONDUCT.
I WANT
TO MAKE IT CLEAR TO THE
MILITARY MEN AND
WOMEN WHO HAVE
SHARED THEIR CONCERNS
THAT THEY
ARE ENDANGERED
BY THE
BEHAVIOR
OF
HIRED GUNS EMPLOYED BY BLACK
WATER-LIKE
COMPANIES, THAT I
WILL
KEEP SPEAKING OUT TO
PROTECT OUR
MISSION AND OUR
BRAVE TROOPS
FROM RISK.
AND I
WANT TO TELL THE FAMILIES
OF THE MEN AND
WOMEN WHO HAVE
BEEN KILLED IN
INCIDENTS
INVOLVING
BLACKWATER AND OTHER
SUCH
COMPANIES THAT I
WILL
CONTINUE TO
PUSH FOR FULL
INVESTIGATIONS AND
WHENEVER
APPROPRIATE CRIMINAL
CHARGES.
THANK YOU,
MR. SPEAKER.
I
YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
MEMBERS ARE
RECOGNIZED --
REMINDED
TO DIRECT THEIR
REMARKS TO THE
CHAIR.
NOT TO
ANYONE PERSONALLY.
THE CHAIR
RECOGNIZES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM NORTH CAROLINA,
MR. MILLER, FOR FIVE
MINUTES.
MR. MILLER:
THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
AROUND THE WORLD THE
RIGHTS OF
WORKERS TO ORGANIZE
AND BARGAIN
COLLECTIVELY THROUGH A
REPRESENTATIVE OF
THEIR
CHOOSING
WITH THEIR EMPLOYER
OVER
WAGES AND
BENEFITS AND
CONDITIONS OF
EMPLOYMENT IS
RECOGNIZED AS AN
IMPORTANT
HUMAN
RIGHT AND AS A HALLMARK
OF DEMOCRATIC
SOCIETIES.
BUT
IN THE UNITED STATES THOSE
RIGHTS HAVE BEEN UNDER
ASSAULT
BY SOME POLITICIANS
AND BY SOME
EMPLOYERS WHO
WANT TO RETURN
THE CLOCK BACK THREE
QUARTERS
OF A
CENTURY.
WHEN
WORKERS WANT TO JOIN A
UNION
HERE AND BARGAIN
COLLECTIVELY WITH THEIR
EMPLOYER,
TOO MANY EMPLOYERS
INTENTIONALLY
DELAY AND DELAY,
ABUSING THE LEGAL
SYSTEM THAT
DENIES THE EMPLOYEES
THEIR
RIGHTS.
I RISE IN SUPPORT OF THE
PROPOSED NATIONAL
LABOR
RELATIONS BOARD RULE TO
STREAMLINE
AND MODERNIZE UNION
ELECTION
PROCEDURES, AN
IMPORTANT AND
OVERDUE STEP TO
RESTORE
FAIRNESS TO OUR
INEFFICIENT AND
OUTDATED SYSTEM
THAT HAS
ALLOWED TOO MANY
ABUSES.
THE NEW
NLRB RULE WILL GIVE
EMPLOYERS LESS
OPPORTUNITY TO
INTERFERE LEGALLY
WITH
ORGANIZING DRIVES.
THE RULE ALSO ALLOWS
SMALLER
GROUPS OF
WORKERS TO FORM
UNIONS.
UNDER THE CURRENT
SYSTEM,
EMPLOYERS
WILLING TO BREAK THE
LAW HAVE MANY
OPPORTUNITIES TO
DELAY
A UNION
ELECTION,
STRETCHING OUT
THE
TIME PERIOD
WHEN
THEY CAN INTIMIDATE AND
COERCE WORKERS
ALL IN VIOLATION
OF THE
LAW.
THE RULE IS
TO ALLOW THEIR FREE
CHOICE, TO BE
REPRESENTED BY A
UNION.
STREAMLINING
NRLB ELECTIONS IS
A LONG
OVERDUE AND SMALL STEP
TO ASSURE
WORKERS HAVE THE
RIGHT TO SPEAK
THROUGH ONE
VOICE
THROUGH A REPRESENTATIVE
OF THEIR
CHOOSING.
MR. SPEAKER, WE'VE
HEARD THE
ONLY
REPUBLICAN MEMBER OF THE
NLRB BOARD,
NLRB IS THREATENING
TO
RESIGN, SPECIFICALLY DENYING
THE BOARD TO
-- TO DENY THE
BOARD THE
QUORUM TO PERFORM THE
DUTY THE LAWS PLACES UPON
THEM.
REPUBLICANS IN THIS
CONGRESS
HAVE NOW
TRIED TO DEFUND THE
NLRB, TO
TAKE AWAY THE NLRB'S
ABILITY TO PUT
SANCTIONS ON
EMPLOYERS WHO
VIOLATE THE LAW.
AND NOW THEY ARE
TRYING TO SHUT
THE
BOARD DOWN ALTOGETHER BY
ABUSING
THE OTHER BODIES AND
BLOCK
ANY NEW APPOINTMENTS TO
THE BOARD AND BY HAVING
A
REPUBLICAN
MEMBER RESIGN
SPECIFICALLY
TO DENY
THE
NECESSARY QUORUM TO
ACT.
AND
TODAY WE ARE CONSIDERING
THE
SO-CALLED WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND
FAIRNESS ACT, AND
DESPITE THAT
ORWELLIAN NAME,
THE BILL IS
INTENDED
TO DENY
WORKERS
THE RIGHT TO UNIONIZE
WITHOUT
DELAY AND LITIGATION --
TO DENY
THOSE RIGHTS THROUGH
DELAY AND LITIGATION
AND BY
ALLOWING EMPLOYERS
TO
DECIDE
WHICH
EMPLOYEES WHICH WORKERS
TO VOTE ON WHETHER OR NOT THERE
IS A UNION OR NOT,
TO STUFF THE
BALLOT BOX.
UNDER THIS BILL, TO ADD
NEW
WORKERS
TO THE UNION THAT WILL
BE -- THAT
WILL DECIDE WHETHER
TO HAVE A
UNION OR NOT.
UNDER
THE BILL THERE WOULD BE A
WAITING PERIOD IF THERE
IS AN
ELECTION DISPUTE, WHETHER
IT'S
WELL-GROUNDED
OR FRIVOLOUS, A
WAITING
PERIOD FOR PRE-ELECTION
HEARING, A WAITING
PERIOD FOR
THEM
TO RECEIVE THE CONTACT
LIST.
AND THE ONLY GOAL FOR
THAT, FOR
THOSE WAITING PERIODS IS
DELAY.
THE
ARBITRARY WAITING PERIODS
ASSURE THAT ELECTION
WILL BE
DELAYED, AND
NOWHERE IS THERE
ANY
ASSURANCE THAT THE ELECTION
WILL REALLY BE
HELD.
MY REPUBLICAN COLLEAGUES
BLAME
FRIVOLOUS
LAWSUITS FOR MANY OF
THE
ILLS OF OUR
COUNTRY, BUT
THIS BILL
WILL REWARD
FRIVOLOUS
LAWSUITS BY
PROVIDING MORE TIME
FOR
EMPLOYERS TO FIND FAULT,
REAL OR
FABRICATED, BY THE
ELECTION PROCESS AND BY
BLOCKING THE
NLRB'S CURRENT
RULE WHICH
WILL ALLOW ELECTIONS
TO
MOVE AHEAD BEFORE THE
COMPLAINTS ARE
RESOLVED.
THIS BILL
WOULD ALLOW EMPLOYERS
TO
USE LITIGATION, FRIVOLOUS OR
LEGITIMATE,
TO BLOCK ELECTIONS.
FINALLY, THIS
BILL WOULD ALLOW
EMPLOYERS TO STUFF
THE BALLOT
BOX
WITH A RADICAL REWRITE OF
OUR
LABOR LAW SO THAT THE
EMPLOYER
WOULD DECIDE WHICH
EMPLOYEES, WHICH
WORKERS GET
TO
VOTE.
THEY CAN ADD EMPLOYEES WHO
WERE
NEVER ENGAGED
IN THE ORGANIZING
DRIVE AND THEY KEEP --
CAN KEEP
THE
LIST OF VOTERS OF THE
WORKERS ELIGIBLE TO VOTE
FROM
THE -- THOSE
IN SUPPORT OF A
UNION
UNTIL JUST BEFORE THE
ELECTION.
AMERICAN WORKERS DESERVE THE
SAME RIGHTS THAT
WE URGE AROUND
THE WORLD FOR
WORKERS.
THE RIGHT TO FORM
A UNION, THE
RIGHT TO SPEAK
WITH ONE VOICE
AND
BARGAIN WITH THEIR
EMPLOYER.
SO OUR
WORKERS CAN WIN BETTER
WAGES AND
BENEFITS AND REBUILD
THE AMERICAN
MIDDLE CLASS.
I YIELD
BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM VIRGINIA, MR. CONNOLLY,
FOR FIVE MINUTES.
MR. CONNOLLY:
MR. SPEAKER, THE
ECONOMY
RECEIVED AN EARLY
HOLIDAY
GIFT THIS
PAST WEEK
WHEN
BLACK FRIDAY AND
CYBERMONDAY
SHOPPING FIGURES
OUTPERFORMED
EXPECTATIONS.
HOWEVER, WE
STILL FACE
SIGNIFICANT
CHALLENGES.
UNEMPLOYMENT
REMAINS TOO
HIGH
AND GLOBAL MARKETS ARE
SHOWING
SIGNS OF
INSTABILITY.
BOTH OF WHICH
ARE THE
LINGERING
EFFECTS OF THE
GREAT RECESSION.
CASTING
A GRIM SHADOW OVER
ALL
OF
OUR ACTIONS IS THE FACT THAT
SOME
MEMBERS OF THIS BODY STILL
PERSIST IN
IGNORING THE PUBLIC
AND
LETTING IDEOLOGY STANDING
IN THE WAY OF
STRIKING A
REASONABLE
BALANCE TO TAME OUR
NATIONAL DEBT AND GROW THE
ECONOMY.
OF NOTE IS THE RECENT
REPORT
RELEASED BY
THE NONPARTISAN
CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE
SHOWING THAT THE
RECOVERY ACT
WE
PASSED TWO YEARS AGO HAS
BEEN
A SIGNIFICANT SUCCESS IN
AN OTHERWISE
GLOOMY ECONOMIC
PICTURE.
ACCORDING TO THE C.B.O., THE
RECOVERY
ACT INCREASED G.D.P.
GROWTH
BY UP TO 1.9% IN THE
THIRD QUARTER OF
THIS YEAR, A
QUARTER IN WHICH WE HAD
2%
GROWTH.
THAT'S AN EXTRAORDINARY IMPACT.
THANKS TO THAT
RECOVERY ACT,
2.4 MILLION
PEOPLE, ACCORDING
TO
C.B.O., NOW HAVE A JOB, AND
THE OVERALL
UNEMPLOYMENT RATE
WAS 1.3%
LOWER THAN IT
OTHERWISE WOULD
HAVE BEEN IF WE
HAD DONE NOTHING,
AS MY FRIENDS
ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE AISLE,
WANTED US TO
DO.
ACCORDING
TO C.B.O.'S IN DEPTH
ANALYSIS, THE
RECOVERY ACT WILL
CONTINUE TO
HAVE
A SIGNIFICANT
IMPACT ON THE
ECONOMY.
C.B.O.
FOUND IT WILL CONTINUE
TO DRIVE G.D.P.
GROWTH NEXT
YEAR
ADDING 1% TO THE ECONOMY
AND
WILL FURTHER INCREASE
EMPLOYMENT BY
ONE MILLION JOBS.
AFTER
OPPOSING ANY STIMULUS
ACTION IN THE
WORST OF ECONOMIC
CONTRACTION
IN THE LAST 80
YEARS, THE REPUBLICANS
ACTUALLY
CRITICIZE THE
RECOVERY ACT NOW
FOR THE FACT IT
DIDN'T DO
ENOUGH.
THAT SPEAKS LESS TO THE MERITS
OF THE RECOVERY
ACT, I SUGGEST,
THAN IT DOES ABOUT
THE
MAGNITUDE
OF THE GREAT
RECESSION.
AND IT
IS EXTRAORDINARY
CHUTZPAH
FROM THE OTHER SIDE TO
JUST SAY NO
AND NOW CRITICIZE
THE
RECOVERY ACT FROM BEING
INADEQUATE.
THE GREAT RECESSION WAS
IN FACT
THE
NATION'S WORST ECONOMIC
COLLAPSE IN 80
YEARS.
WHAT BEGAN IN THE
SUBPRIME
HOUSING
MARKET QUICKLY SPREAD
THROUGHOUT THE
FINANCIAL
INDUSTRY
THREATENING ECONOMIC
RUIN.
AT ITS HEIGHT, MORE
THAN
700,000
AMERICANS WERE LOSING
THEIR JOBS
EVERY SINGLE MONTH.
MILLIONS MORE
LOST THEIR HOMES
THROUGH
FORECLOSURES.
THE
GREAT RECESSION WAS ALREADY
ONE
OF THE -- AMERICA'S WORST
BEFORE PRESIDENT OBAMA
WAS EVER
SIGNED --
SWORN INTO OFFICE,
AND DURING THAT
ECONOMIC -- WE
HAD
TO PASS THE RECOVERY ACT ON
A PARTY
LINE VOTE, I'M SAD TO
SAY.
MANY
OF MY COLLEAGUES
TALKS
ABOUT THE FAILURE,
RATHER THAN
ACKNOWLEDGING THAT IT'S
ACTUALLY A FUNCTION OF THE
SEVERITY OF THE
RECESSION.
AND FAILING
TO
ACKNOWLEDGE
THEIR OWN
SUPINE DARWINIAN
RESPONSE TO
IT.
THEY
THAME CLAIM THAT AS THE
ECONOMIC TURMOIL, WHICH
BEGAN
IN 2007,
RAGED ALL AROUND US,
AMERICANS WOULD
HAVE BEEN
BETTER SERVED
HAD CONGRESS
SIMPLY DONE NOTHING AND
HOPED
FOR THE
BEST.
AND NOW
AS THE LINGER EFFECTS
OF
THAT RECESSION CONTINUE
TO
HOLD BACK
A ROBUST RECOVERY,
THEY CONTINUE
TO DEFY
REASONABLE BIPARTISAN
ATTEMPTS
TO PUT
PEOPLE BACK TO WORK AND
GET OUR COUNTRY
MOVING AGAIN.
THE
RECOVERY ACT CUT TAXES FOR
95% OF ALL
AMERICANS, BOTH
FAMILIES AND
SMALL BUSINESSES.
IT KEPT
THOUSANDS OF
TEACHERS,
POLICE OFFICERS
AND
FIREFIGHTERS ON THE JOB.
RECOVERY ACT
DOLLARS FUNDED
HIGHWAYS
AND TRANSIT
IMPROVEMENTS IN
EVERY STATE,
PUTTING HUNDREDS OF
THOUSANDS
IN THE
DEPRESSED CONSTRUCTION
INDUSTRY BACK TO WORK.
THERE WAS A
TIME, MR. SPEAKER
WHEN
CUTTING TAXES AND
INVESTING IN
INFRASTRUCTURE WAS
A
BIPARTISAN ENDEAVOR AND HAD
BROAD
BIPARTISAN SUPPORT AS
WELL AS REPUBLICAN SUPPORT.
BUT THERE'S
STILL TIME FOR
REDUMPINGS.
THE PRESIDENT'S AMERICAN JOBS
-- REDEMPTION.
THE PRESIDENT'S AMERICAN
JOBS
ACT
ALLOWS ANOTHER OPPORTUNITY
FOR OUR
REPUBLICAN FRIENDS TO
SUPPORT DEMOCRATS AND
ECONOMIC
RECOVERY.
THE AMERICAN JOBS ACT
PROVIDES
INCENTIVES FOR COMPANIES, LARGE
AND SMALL, TO
HIRE ADDITIONAL
WORKERS.
IT CUTS TAXES ON EVERY
WORKING
AMERICAN IN ORDER TO
SPUR
ECONOMIC DEMAND.
IT PROVIDES
SUPPORT FOR
SOUTHERLY
NEEDED INFRASTRUCTURE
INVESTMENTS
TO REPAIR ROADWAYS
AND
SCHOOLS.
IT
BUILDS ON THE SUCCESS OF THE
RECOVERY ACT WE PASSED TWO
YEARS AGO.
THERE ARE
2.4 MILLION
AMERICANS, MR. SPEAKER, WITH
JOBS TODAY BECAUSE WE
TOOK
ACTION TWO
YEARS AGO.
WITH
14 MILLION MORE WAITING,
WE CAN'T AFFORD
NOW TO DO
NOTHING.
WE MUST ACT, AND I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM TEXAS, MR. POE, FOR FIVE
MINUTES.
MR. POE:
MR. SPEAKER, THIS WEEK
PAKISTANI PRIME
SAID THAT THERE
WILL BE
NO MORE BUSINESS AS
USUAL WITH THE UNITED STATES.
I COULDN'T AGREE MORE.
THE UNITED STATES SHOULDN'T
BE
DOING BUSINESS AS USUAL
WITH
OUR
UNFAITHFUL ALLY, PAKISTAN.
SINCE
2002 WE HAVE GIVEN
PAKISTAN OVER
$14 BILLION IN
SO-CALLED
SECURITY-RELATED AID
AND OVER
$6 BILLION IN
ECONOMIC-RELATED
AID.
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE HAVE NOT
GOTTEN THEIR
MONEY'S WORTH.
PAKISTAN
SEEMS TO BE THE
BENEDICT ARNOLD
NATION IN THE
LIST OF
COUNTRIES WE CALL
ALLIES.
THEY HAVE PROVEN TO BE
DECEPTIVE,
DECEITFUL AND A
DANGER
TO THE UNITED STATES.
HERE'S SOME OF THE
EVIDENCE --
IN MAY OF THIS
YEAR, NAVY
SEALS
DISCOVERED
OSAMA BIN LADEN
LIVING
THE HIGH LIFE IN A
MANSION RIGHT IN THE
BACK YARD
OF THE
PAKISTANI MILITARY
COMMUNITY.
BUT PAKISTAN
CLAIMS THEY HAD NO
WORD OF THE
WORLD'S MOST WANTED
TERRORIST WHO
WAS LIVING RIGHT
UNDER THEIR
NOSES.
THIS IS
QUESTIONABLE AT BEST.
MR. SPEAKER,
THAT DOG JUST
WON'T HUNT.
SINCE THEN, THE MORE WE LEARN
ABOUT PAKISTAN THE
WORSE IT
GETS.
SHORTLY AFTER THAT
RAID,
PAKISTAN ALSO
ARRESTED C.I.A.
INFORMANTS IN PAKISTAN THAT
LED
THE UNITED STATES TO
CAPTURE OR
TAKE OUT
OSAMA BIN LADEN.
PAKISTAN HAS TRIED ALSO TO
CHEAT
THE UNITED STATES IN
FILING
BOGUS
REIMBURSEMENT
CLAIMS FOR ALLEGEDLY
GOING
AFTER
MILITANTS.
40% OF THESE CLAIMS
HAVE BEEN
REJECTED
BY OUR GOVERNMENT.
THERE IS
MORE.
PAKISTAN
TIPPED OFF TERRORISTS
MAKING
I.E.D.'S NOT ONCE BUT
TWICE
IN JUNE OF 2011 AFTER WE
GAVE THEM
INTEL ON THE
BOMB-MAKING
FACTORY AND ASKED
PAKISTAN TO
GO AFTER THEM.
C.I.A.
DIRECTOR LEON PANETTA
ASSERTED THAT
PAKISTAN HAS NOT
DONE ENOUGH TO BRING
OSAMA BIN
LADEN TO
JUSTICE SAYING NOW
THERE IS TOTAL
MISTRUST BETWEEN
THE
UNITED STATES AND PAKISTAN.
MEANWHILE, PAKISTAN IS
CHUMMING
UP TO THE CHINESE.
IT SOUNDS TO ME
LIKE PAKISTAN
IS PLAYING BOTH
SIDES ON THE
WAR ON
TERROR.
THIS SO-CALLED
ALLY TAKES
BILLIONS OF
DOLLARS IN U.S. AID
WHILE AT THE
SAME TIME
SUPPORTING
THE MILITANTS WHO
ATTACK
US.
ACCORDING TO
ADMIRAL MIKE
MULLEN,
THE PAKISTANI
GOVERNMENT SUPPORTED THE
GROUPS
WHO
WERE BEHIND THE SEPTEMBER
TRUCK BOMBING
ATTACK IN
EASTERN AFGHANISTAN THAT
WOUNDED MORE
THAN 70 U.S. AND
NATO
TROOPS.
SO BASED
ON THIS EVIDENCE, I
HAVE
INTRODUCED LEGISLATION TO
FREEZE ALL
U.S. AID
TO PACK
--
PAKISTAN.
BY SENDING AID TO
PAKISTAN, WE
ARE
FUNDING THE ENEMIES AND
UNDERMINING OUR EFFORTS IN THE
WHOLE REGION.
IN THE PAST WEEK,
RELATIONS
BETWEEN
AMERICAN AND PAKISTANI
OFFICIALS HAVE
FURTHER
DETERIORATED.
SATURDAY, NATO AND
AFGHAN
FORCES NEAR
THE BORDER IN
PAKISTAN IN
AFGHANISTAN CAME
UNDER
ATTACK FROM PAKISTANI
FIRE AND RESPONDED IN
SELF-DEFENSE.
24 PAKISTANI
SOLDIERS WERE
KILLED.
BUT PAKISTAN SAYS IT
WAS NATO
WHO
FIRED THE FIRST SHOT.
OF COURSE, WE CANNOT BELIEVE
WHAT PAKISTAN
SAYS.
THEY WILL LIE WHEN
THE TRUTH IS
OBVIOUS.
.
THE FACTS WILL
EVENTUALLY COME
OUT.
BUT HATRED FOR AMERICA IS
STILL
ON AN
ALL-TIME HIGH IN PAKISTAN.
THIS WEEK
ON TV AMERICANS HAVE
SEEN PAKISTANIS
BURNING AMERICAN
FLAGS
AND CURSING OUR NATION.
AND JUST TODAY
IN POLITICO WE
HAVE THIS LOVELY PHOTOGRAPH
OF
PAKISTANI
WOMEN PROCLAIMING DOWN
WITH
THE U.S.A.
PAKISTAN LEADERS ARE
CONTINUING
TO
VILIFY THE UNITED STATES ON
ONE HAND
AND ON THE OTHER HAND
TAKE OUR
MONEY.
MOST
IMPORTANTLY, CRUCIAL NATO
SUPPLY
ROUTES HAVE BEEN CUT OFF
BY PAKISTAN.
STOPPING SUPPLIES
FROM GETTING
TO OUR TROOPS IN AFGHANISTAN.
MONDAY, 300
TRUCKS FULL OF
SUPPLIES WERE
TURNED AWAY AT THE
BORDER.
PAKISTAN HAS CUT OFF
SUPPLIES TO
OUR TROOPS, NOW
IT'S TIME WE CUT
OFF MONEY TO
PAKISTAN.
PAKISTAN HAS
MADE IT PAINFULLY
OBVIOUS THEY WILL
CONTINUE THEIR
POLICY OF
DANGEROUS,
DISHONEST
DECEIT BY PRETENDING
TO BE OUR
ALLY
IN THE WAR ON TERROR WHILE
SIMULTANEOUSLY GIVING
A WINK AND
NOD TO EXTREMISM.
BY
CONTINUING TO PROVIDE AID TO
PAKISTAN, WE ARE FUNDING
THE
ENEMY, ENDANGERING
AMERICANS,
AND
UNDERMINING OUR EFFORTS.
SEVEN IN 10 AMERICANS
BELIEVE WE
NEED TO
STOP OR DECREASE FOREIGN
AID TO PAKISTAN.
AFTER ALL,
IT IS THEIR MONEY.
WE
SHOULD STOP FOREIGN AID TO
PAKISTAN UNTIL
WE KNOW WHOSE
SIDE
THEY ARE ON.
WE
DON'T NEED TO PAY THEM TO
HATE US,
THEY'LL DO IT FOR FREE,
MR. SPEAKER.
MAYBE WE SHOULDN'T PAY THEM AT
ALL.
AND THAT'S JUST THE WAY IT IS.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM
KENTUCKY, MR. CONNOLLY, FOR
FIVE MINUTES.
MR. COURTNEY:
THANK YOU, MR.
SPEAKER.
IT'S BEEN TWO
MONTHS SINCE THE
OCCUPY WALL STREET MOVEMENT HAS
SPREAD ACROSS THIS COUNTRY,
AND
DESPITE ATTEMPTS
TO MARGINALIZE
IT,
PARODY IT, SOMETIMES
SUPPRESS
IT, THE FACT IS
ONE
MESSAGE HAS COME
THROUGH LOUD
AND
CLEAR.
PARTICULARLY
FROM YOUNG
AMERICANS
WHO HAVE PARTICIPATED
IN
THIS GRASSROOTS MOVEMENT
ACROSS THE COUNTRY WHICH
IS THE
SPIRALING COST
OF COLLEGE IS
SMOTHERING OPPORTUNITY
FOR
THOUSANDS AND MILLIONS
OF YOUNG
AMERICANS
ALL ACROSS AMERICA.
YESTERDAY
THE SECRETARY OF
EDUCATION, ARNIE
DUNCAN,
PRESENTED A
-- ARNE DUNCAN,
SPEECH IN NEVADA
WHICH
STARKLY PRESENTED
THE
CHALLENGE WE FACE AS A
NATION.
TAVED THE AVERAGE
STUDENT LOAN
DEBT FOR
GRADUATING STUDENTS IS
$25,000.
THAT'S THE
AVERAGE.
THERE ARE AGAIN MILLIONS
OF
STUDENTS WHO ARE
GRADUATING WITH
SIX-FIGURE DEBT.
IN AN ECONOMY LIKE THE ONE THAT
THEY ARE FACING
TODAY, THIS IS
REALLY AN
OBSTACLE WHICH WILL
PROBABLY
BURDEN THEM FOR THE
REST
OF THEIR LIVES.
AND AS
WE ARE SEEING IN POLLS,
THE COST OF
COLLEGE NOW IS
DISCOURAGING YOUNGER
AMERICANS,
HIGH SCHOOL AGE AMERICANS, FROM
EVEN
CONSIDERING THE POSSIBILITY
OF PURSUING
A HIGHER EDUCATION
DEGREE.
FIRST OF ALL, LET'S
BE VERY
CLEAR HERE,
THE VALUE OF HIGHER
EDUCATION
IS STILL, DESPITE SOME
CRITICS, INDISPUTABLE.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE
UNPLOINT RATE
TODAY,
9% ACROSS THE BOARD IN
TERMS OF OUR
COUNTRY, THE FACT
OF THE
MATTER IS
THOSE WHO HAVE
PURSUED
HIGH SCHOOL AND ABOVE
HAVE MUCH LOWER RATES
OF
UNEMPLOYMENT TODAY
THAN THOSE
WHO HAVE BEEN
UNABLE TO REACH
THOSE
TRAINING LEVELS AND
EDUCATION
LEVELS.
NATIONALLY
TODAY THE GRADUATION
RATE
OF THE U.S. HAS NOW FALLEN
TO
12TH INTERNATIONALLY.
BACK
IN THE 1980'S, THE COLLEGE
BOARD, THE ORGANIZATION
WHICH
TRACKS GRADUATION RATES
ACROSS
THE GLOBE, DETERMINED THAT WE
WERE
NUMBER ONE IN THE WORLD IN
TERMS OF
COLLEGE GRADUATION
RATES.
YET
TODAY IN 2011 WE ARE
12TH.
IF ANYBODY THINKS THAT
THAT
IS A
SITUATION WHICH
BODES WELL FOR
OUR
ABILITY TO COMPETE
INTERNATIONALLY GOING INTO
THE
FUTURE,
THEN FRANKLY THEY ARE
NOT
PAYING ATTENTION IN TERMS
OF
WHERE THE
HIGH VALUE JOBS OF THE
FUTURE
ARE.
THEY ARE,
IN FACT, IN THE HARD
SCIENCES.
THEY ARE IN FACT IN AREAS OF
CRITICAL WORK
FORCE NEEDS WHICH
AS BABY BOOMERS RETIRE IN
GROWING NUMBERS ACROSS THIS
COUNTRY, WE MUST
HAVE IF WE ARE
GOING
TO CONTINUE TO BE A GREAT
NATION.
NOW, LET'S
LOOK AT WHAT'S
HAPPENING
HERE IN WASHINGTON.
I
THINK ONE OF THE REASONS WHY
YOUNG PEOPLE ARE GOING INTO THE
STREETS OF THIS COUNTRY IS
THE
FACT THAT WE HAVE
A CONGRESS
WHICH
IS NOT ONLY OUT OF TOUCH
IN TERMS OF
LISTENING AND
RESPONDING TO THIS.
IN FACT, THEY WANT
TO TAKE US
BACKWARDS.
WHEN I FIRST CAME
TO CONGRESS IN
2007, A NEW
DEMOCRATIC MAJORITY
MOVED
SWIFTLY TO
PASS THE KOHL
LEDGE COST REDUCTION ACT
WHICH
WAS AN EFFORT TO
TRY AND BOOST
THE
PELL GRANT PROGRAM, WHICH IS
THE WORKHORSE
OF HIGHER
EDUCATION AFFORDABILITY,
A
PROGRAM
WHICH BASICALLY HAVE
BEEN
LEVEL FUNDED
FOR SIX PRIOR
YEARS
DESPITE THE FACT THAT
HIGHER
EDUCATION COST HAS
GONE
UP 40%.
WE PASSED THE COLLEGE COST
REDUCTION ACT
WHICH INFUSED NEW
FUNDING
INTO THE PELL
GRANT
PROGRAM.
WE CUT THE INTEREST RATES
FOR
THE STAFFORD
STUDENT LOAN
PROGRAM FROM
6.4% TO
3.2%, AND
WE
PAID FOR EVERY SINGLE PENNY
OF
THOSE EXPENDITURES BY CUTTING
THE BANK
SUBSIDIES WHICH WERE
BASICALLY SUCKING
FEDERAL
DOLLARS AWAY
FROM FAMILIES AND
STUDENTS WHO NEED
THAT CRITICAL
HELP.
LAST YEAR WE
PASSED THE STUDENT
AID
AND FISCAL RESPONSIBILITY
ACT, AGAIN WITH
A DEMOCRATIC
MAJORITY,
WHICH PROVIDES FOR A
CAP IN
TERMS OF LOAN REPAYMENTS,
15%
OF YOUR GROSS --
DISCRETIONARY
INCOME, AND
EXCUSES LOAN
REPAYMENTS AFTER 25
YEARS
UNDER THE STAFFORD STUDENT
LOAN
PROGRAM.
I WAS
PLEASED THAT PRESIDENT
OBAMA, AGAIN JUST
A MONTH OR
SO
AGO, ACTED
TO INCREASE THE
BENEFIT
OF THAT PROGRAM BY
LIMITING THE
DISCRETIONARY
INCOME
PAYMENTS TO 10% OF INCOME
AND
LOWERING THE FORGIVENESS
DATE TO
20 YEARS FROM 25 YEARS.
THIS IS
AN ADMINISTRATION WHICH
GETS IT.
THIS IS
AN ADMINISTRATION WHICH
UNDERSTANDS WHAT MIDDLE CLASS
FAMILIES
WITH CHILDREN WHO WANT
TO IMPROVE THEMSELVES AND
COMPETE IN THEIR
FUTURES NEED
THAT KIND
OF
ASSISTANCE.
WHAT DID THIS
REPUBLICAN
CONGRESS DO?
WE HAD A
RYAN BUDGET LAST APRIL
WHICH
GUTTED, BUTCHERED THE PELL
GRANT PROGRAM AND
WOULD TAKE US
BACK TO 2008
LEVELS.
SO, FOR
EXAMPLE, IN CONNECTICUT
WHERE I COME
FROM, THE YUFF OF
CONNECTICUT WOULD HAVE
SEEN ITS
PELL GRANT
REVENUE FROM 2008,
WHICH WAS ABOUT
$8 BILLION GOING
INTO THE UNIVERSITY OF
CONNECTICUT, WOULD HAVE BEEN CUT
FROM WHERE IT IS TODAY
WHICH IS
$12 BILLION
IN ANNUAL PELL GRANT
REVENUE.
$4 MILLION CUT TO THE UNIVERSITY
OF CONNECTICUT AND
THE GRANT
LEVEL FOR
STUDENTS, THE MAXIMUM
AWARD WOULD
HAVE BEEN CUT FROM
$4,500 A YEAR
TO ROUGHLY $3,000
A YEAR.
THAT IS
CLOSING THE DOORS OF
OPPORTUNITY
TO MILLIONS OF
AMERICANS.
THAT'S WHAT THE
RYAN BUDGET
VALUES AND
THAT'S WHAT ITS SLIGS
WAS AT A
TIME WHEN OUR COUNTRY
WAS
IN CRISIS IN
TERMS OF
NEEDING
SKILLED, QUALIFIED
WORKERS TO DEAL WITH THE
FUTURE
CHALLENGES.
THE CHOICE IS CLEAR
AND FOR
THOSE WHO
CARE ABOUT SPIRALING
EDUCATION
COSTS, THE DEMOCRATIC
AGENDA IS THE
ONE THAT IS ON
YOUR
SIDE.
I
YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM GEORGIA, MR. WOODALL, FOR
FIVE MINUTES.
MR. WOODALL: I
THANK THE SPEAKER
FOR
THE TIME.
I'M
HAPPY TO BE DOWN HERE THIS
MORNING.
I OFF COME DOWN HERE WITH
SOMETHING ON MY MIND,
MR.
SPEAKER, AND INVARIABLY ONE
OF
MY COLLEAGUES SAYS
SOMETHING
THAT INSPIRES
ME EVEN MORE THAN
WHAT I
HAD ON MY MIND WHEN
I
CAME DOWN.
AND THAT'S THE CASE
THIS
MORNING.
MY COLLEAGUE WHO WAS
HERE RIGHT
BEFORE ME SAID
THE VALUE
OF
HIGHER EDUCATION IN
TERMS
OF
FUTURE
EARNINGS IS UNDISPUTABLE.
THE VALUE
OF HIGHER EDUCATION,
MR. SPEAKER, IN TERMS
OF FUTURE
EARNINGS IS
UNDISPUTABLE.
AND
THEN WENT ON TO TALK ABOUT
ALL
THE FEDERAL PROGRAMS THAT
PROVIDE MONEY
SO THAT PEOPLE CAN
SEEK HIGHER EDUCATION.
MY
QUESTION IS, MR. SPEAKER, IF
THE
VALUE IS UNDISPUTABLE, WHY
DO WE HAVE
TO PAY PEOPLE TO
DO
IT?
IF THE VALUE IS
UNDISPUTABLE,
WHY
DO WE HAVE TO PAY PEOPLE TO
DO
IT?
THAT'S WHAT
HAPPENS IN THIS
CHAMBER TOO
OFTEN, MR. SPEAKER.
I
THINK BACK TO 1787, THE
PASSING OF THE
CONSTITUTION.
THE CONSTITUTION
AS CONSERVATIVE
AS IT IS IN TERMS OF PRESERVING
INDIVIDUAL LIBERTIES,
WOULD NOT
HAVE
PASSED, WOULD NOT HAVE BEEN
RATIFIED,
WITHOUT THE ADDITION
OF THE BILL OF RIGHTS.
OUR
FOUNDING FATHERS WERE SO
CONCERNED ABOUT A
FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT TRYING
TO DO TOO MUCH
THAT THE
COLONIES WOULD NOT
RATIFY THE CONSTITUTION
IN THE
ABSENCE OF THE BILL OF
RIGHTS.
THE BILL
OF RIGHTS WHICH SOLE
PURPOSE
IS TO PROTECT INDIVIDUAL
LIBERTIES.
MR. SPEAKER, AS I LOOK
AROUND AT
WHAT
MAKES AMERICA GREAT, IT'S
NEVER
SOMETHING THAT COMES OUT
OF THIS UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
IT'S SOMETHING THAT COMES OUT
OF
A
FAMILY NEXT DOOR BACK HOME.
IT'S SOMETHING THAT COMES OUT
OF
A
COMMUNITY BACK HOME.
IT'S
SOMETHING THAT
COMES OUT OF
INDIVIDUAL
LIBERTY AND FREEDOM
BACK HOME.
AND MY JOB AS A REPRESENTATIVE
OF 900,000
FOLKS IN THE GREAT
STATE
OF
GEORGIA, IS TO PROTECT
THE LIBERTIES
FROM THE NATURAL
INCLINATION THAT EXISTS
IN THIS
BODY TO THINK
THEY HAVE ALL THE
RIGHT
ANSWERS.
WE TALK
ABOUT HIGHER EDUCATION,
MR. SPEAKER, AND THE GREAT STATE
OF GEORGIA WE HAVE WHAT'S CALLED
THE HOPE SCHOLARSHIP
PROGRAM.
IT'S
FUNDED BY LOTTERY MONEY.
I WOULD HAVE
VOTED AGAINST THE
LOTTERY, BUT
THE LOTTERY WON
ANYWAY, AND
NOW IT FUNDS HIGHER
EDUCATION
FOR ALL GEORGIANS, A
HUGE JOB
CREATION TOOL.
FOLKS WANT TO
COME AND RELOCATE
THEIR BUSINESS TO GEORGIA
BECAUSE THEY KNOW KIDS
WITH AN
ACCOMPLISHED
HIGH SCHOOL RECORD
WILL BE ABLE TO GO TO COLLEGE
FOR FREE.
THAT'S A STATE
INITIATIVE, MR.
SPEAKER.
WE ARE NOT GOING TO PASS A
NATIONAL LOTTERY UP
HERE AND TRY
TO PROVIDE FREE COLLEGE
EDUCATION FOR EVERYBODY.
THAT'S NOT THE RIGHT
ANSWER.
THE RIGHT
ANSWER IS TO HAVE
STATES,
TO HAVE THOSE
COMMUNITIES EXERCISE
THOSE
FREEDOMS AND
IMPLEMENT THEIR
IDEAS BACK HOME.
WHEN I WAS GROWING
UP, IT DIDN'T
OCCUR
TO ME AT THE TIME, HOW
MEANINGFUL IT
WOULD BE, BUT
THERE
USED TO BE A CLICHE WHEN
SOMETHING WAS
REALLY HARD YOU
SAY IT
TAKES AN ACT OF CONGRESS
TO SOLVE IT.
HAVE YOU HEARD OF
THAT CLICHE,
MR. SPEAKER?
IT TAKES AN ACT OF CONGRESS TO
SOLVE THAT BECAUSE THE
PROBLEM
IS SO HARD IT'S
HARD TO PASS
SOMETHING IN
CONGRESS.
IT'S HARD
TO GET AN ACT OF
CONGRESS, YET EVERY TIME
WE MAKE
A
MISTAKE, MR. SPEAKER, IN THE
NAME OF
TRYING TO DO GOOD, IN
THE NAME OF TRYING
TO HAVE THE
BEST
IDEA, IN THE NAME OF TRYING
TO TELL EVERYBODY IN
AMERICA IF
ONLY THEY'LL
DO WHAT WE TELL
THEM
TO DO,
THEY WILL BE
HAPPYIER EVERY TIME WE
MAKE A
MISTAKE, IT LITERALLY
TAKES AN
ACT
OF CONGRESS TO FIX IT.
MR. SPEAKER,
WE ARE NOT IN
CHARGE
OF PROVIDING HAPPINESS TO
AMERICA.
WE ARE IN CHARGE
OF PRESERVING
AMERICANS' FREEDOMS
SO THAT THEY
CAN
FIND THEIR OWN HAPPINESS.
MR. SPEAKER, THERE ARE LOTS
OF
COUNTRIES ON
THIS PLANET.
THAT DO
NOT SHARE THE FREEDOMS
THAT WE HAVE.
THERE IS ONLY ONE COUNTRY ON
THIS PLANET
THAT PROTECTS
INDIVIDUAL
LIBERTY AND FREEDOM
AS
WE DO.
WHEN
WE TALK ABOUT THE DIRECTION
OF
AMERICA, MR. SPEAKER, WE HAVE
TO DECIDE
ARE WE GOING TO
PROTECT THOSE THINGS THAT
HAVE
ALWAYS MADE
THIS COUNTRY GREAT,
INDIVIDUAL
LIBERTY AND
FREEDOM, OR ARE WE
GOING TO GO THE WAY
OF THE REST
OF THE WORLD WHICH IS
LOOKING TO
A
CENTRAL GOVERNMENT THAT THINKS
IT HAS ALL THE RIGHT
ANSWERS?
MR. SPEAKER, THEY
HAD IT RIGHT
IN THE SUMMER OF
1787, I HOPE WE
GET IT RIGHT
HERE IN THIS
CONGRESS.
I THANK YOU FOR THE TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR RECOGNIZES
THE GENTLEWOMAN
FROM CALIFORNIA,
MS. WOOLSEY,
FOR FIVE MINUTES.
MS. WOOLSEY: MR. SPEAKER,
OVER
THE
WEEKEND NATO AIR STRIKES
KILLED AT LEAST
24 PAKISTANI
SOLDIERS
IN A TRAGIC FRIENDLY
FIRE I.N.S.
PENT THAT HAS ONCE
AGAIN ELEVATED
TENSIONS BETWEEN
THE -- INCIDENT
THAT HAS ONCE
AGAIN
ELEVATED TENSIONS BETWEEN
THE U.S. AND
PAKISTAN.
REGARDLESS WHO IS AT FAULT
WHETHER OUR SOURCES WERE ACTING
IN SELF-DEFENSE OR
HAD
LEGITIMATE REASON
TO BELIEVE
THEY WERE
FIRING ON INSURGENTS,
THE PAKISTAN
GOVERNMENT IS
FURIOUS
AND THE BILATERAL
RELATIONSHIPPLE IS FACING
A
GRAVE CRISIS.
PAKISTAN SAID THEY ARE
CUTTING
OFF SUPPLY ROUTES INTO
AFGHANISTAN.
THEY HAVE SAID THEY WILL
NO
LONGER
PARTICIPATE IN A
CRITICALLY
IMPORTANT
INTERNATIONAL
CONFERENCE IN
GERMANY
NEXT WEEK.
A CONFERENCE
THAT WILL HELP
CHART
AFGHAN'S FUTURE.
AND
THIS EPISODE IS FANNING
FLAMES
OF ANTI-AMERICAN
SENTIMENT
IN A COUNTRY
WHOSE
PEOPLE ARE ALREADY
HOSTILE.
IN THE
LAST FEW DAYS WE HAVE
SEEN PUBLIC DEMONSTRATIONS
OF
PAKISTANIS BURNING
THE U.S. FLAG
AND
SHOUTING, WHOEVER IS A
FRIEND
OF AMERICA IS A TRAITOR
OF THE LAND.
CLEARLY,
MR. SPEAKER, INSTEAD OF
WINNING THE
HEARTS AND MINDS WE
ARE
GIVING
TERRORISTS A
RECRUITMENT TOOL.
PAKISTAN HAS NOT
ALWAYS BEEN THE
MOST
RELIABLE PARTNER, BUT THEY
ARE
AN ALLY AND LET'S NOT FORGET
A
NUCLEAR POWER.
WITH
WHOM WE SHARE IMPORTANT
MUTUAL
INTERESTS.
WE
NEED THEIR COOPERATION IF
THERE IS
GOING TO BE POLITICAL
RECONCILIATION AND
LONG-TERM
STABILITY
IN NEIGHBORING
AFGHANISTAN.
THIS INCIDENT
LEADS ME TO
BELIEVE
VERY STRONGLY, MORE
STRONGLY THAN EVER
AS A MATTER
OF
FACT, THAT WE MUST REDEPLOY
OUR
TROOPS OUT OF AFGHANISTAN.
WE HAVE VERY
DIFFICULT
DIPLOMATIC
WORK TO DO THERE.
WORK THAT IS
BEING COMPLICATED
AND NOT
FACILITATED BY OUR
MILITARY PRESENCE.
AFTER MORE THAN
10 YEARS OF
FAILED WAR THAT
IS UNDERMINING
OUR SECURITY
INTERESTS, IT'S
TIME TO CHANGE OUR ROLE IN THE
REGION.
FROM ONE
OF MILITARY OCCUPIER TO
ONE
OF CONSTRUCTIVE PARTNER.
PAN STACK AND AFGHANISTAN
ARE
THE
FIRST PLACES WE COULD BE
IMPLEMENTING
THE SMART SECURITY
STRATEGY WE TALKED ABOUT,
SOMETHING -- I
TALKED ABOUT SO
MANY TIMES FROM THIS
VERY SPOT.
WHILE IT'S
TRUE THAT WE SEND
ENORMOUS
AMOUNTS OF FOREIGN AID
TO PAKISTAN,
THE OVERWHELMING
MAJORITY
OF IT
GOES TO THE
MILITARY
WITH VERY LITTLE
TRICKLING DOWN TO THE PEOPLE.
WE
COULD, INSTEAD, SPEND MORE TO
BOOST
PAKISTAN'S LITERACY RATES.
MORE
INVESTMENT AND KEY
INFRASTRUCTURE PROJECTS
ARE THE
GROWTH
OF CIVIL SOCIETY OR LIFE
CHANGING HUMANITARIAN
EFFORTS TO
GIVE ONE
SPECIFIC EXAMPLE,
PAKISTAN IS ONE OF
FOUR
COUNTRIES ON
EARTH, AND
AFGHANISTAN
IS ONE OF THE
OTHERS, THAT
HASN'T COMPLETELY
ERADICATED
POLIO.
FOR
PENNIES ON THE DOLLAR
COMPARED
TO OUR MILITARY
EXPENDITURES
, WE CAN HELP
PROVIDE
THE VACCINATIONS THAT
WOULD
ELIMINATE THIS DIRE PUBLIC
THREAT.
.
PERHAPS
THEN WE CAN CHANGE THAT
11% HAVE A
FAVORABLE VIEW OF
THE UNITED STATES.
PERHAPS
INSTEAD OF
DESTABILIZING
INFLUENCES OF
100,000
TROOPS ON THE GROUND WE
CAN BUILD A
STRONGER
RELATIONSHIP BUILT ON
TRUST,
ONE THAT
EMPOWERS THE PAKISTANI
PEOPLE WITH A
HUMANITARIAN
SURGE
INSTEAD OF A MILITARY
SURGE.
MR. SPEAKER,
IT'S TIME FOR
SMART SECURITY AND IT
STARTS
WITH
BRINGING OUR TROOPS HOME.
I YIELD
BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE GENTLELADY
FROM CALIFORNIA, MS. LEE, FOR
FIVE MINUTES.
MS.
LEE: THANK YOU, MR.
SPEAKER.
AS
A FOUNDING
CO-CHAIR OF BOTH
THE CONGRESSIONAL
OUT-OF-POVERTY CAUCUS
AND
THE
CONGRESSIONAL
HIV-AIDS CAUCUS,
I RISE
TODAY TO DRAW ATTENTION
ONCE
AGAIN TO THE ONGOING
CRISIS OF
POVERTY IN AMERICA.
AND
TODAY I ALSO WANT TO DRAW
PARTICULAR
ATTENTION TO THE
IMPACT OF
POVERTY ON OUR
NATIONAL FIGHT
TO STOP H.I.V.
AND AIDS.
MR. SPEAKER,
DECEMBER 1 IS
WORLD AIDS
DAY, AND THIS YEAR
MARKS 30
YEARS AFTER THE FIRST
DISCOVERY OF AIDS
CASES.
THE UNITED STATES AND
THE
HIV-AIDS
COMMUNITY GLOBALLY
HAVE
MADE TREMENDOUS
PROGRESS
IN OUR
COLLECTIVE RESPONSE TO
THIS
DOMESTIC AND
GLOBAL
CRISIS.
WE HAVE REDUCED THE
STIGMAS
SURROUNDING
THE DISEASE AND
STRENGTHENED EDUCATION
AND
OUTREACH
ACTIVITIES WHICH
CONTINUE TO PREVENT
MILLIONS OF
NEW
CASES OF H.I.V. WORLDWIDE.
THE SCIENTIFIC COMMUNITY HAS
IMPROVED
THE TREATMENT OF
H.I.V.
AND AIDS WITH THERAPIES
AND RECENT
BREAKTHROUGHS HAVE
REVOLUTIONIZED THE
WAY WE THINK
ABOUT
AIDS.
WE HAVE COME A
LONG WAY IN OUR
BATTLE
AGAINST AIDS.
CONTRACTING H.I.V.
NO LONGER
HAS
TO BE A DEATH SENTENCE.
BUT WE HAVE MUCH MORE
WORK TO
DO.
NOT EVERYONE WHO IS H.I.V.
POSITIVE HAS
ACCESS TO THESE
LIFE-SAVING
THERAPIES.
FOR THE ONE IN THREE
AMERICANS
WHO ARE
POOR OR NEAR POOR,
H.I.V.
CAN STILL BE THE SAME
DEATH SENTENCE
THAT IT WAS
DURING
THE REAGAN PRESIDENCY.
TODAY, NEARLY
ONE IN FIVE
AMERICANS WITH H.I.V. DO
NOT
EVEN KNOW THEIR
STATUS AND ONLY
ABOUT HALF OF
AMERICANS WHO DO
KNOW THEIR STATUS ARE
RECEIVING
THE TREATMENT
THAT THEY NEED.
FOR
THE 100 MILLION AMERICANS
EITHER IN POVERTY OR
LIVING ON
THE
EDGE OF POVERTY, MUCH MORE
MUST
BE DONE.
ACCESS TO
DRUG COCKTAILS,
HIGH-QUALITY
HEALTH CARE,
HOUSING AND
HEALTHY FOODS THAT
ARE ALL
CRITICAL FOR PEOPLE
LIVING
WITH H.I.V. ARE OUT OF
THE REACH FOR
FAR TOO MANY.
MR. SPEAKER,
30 YEARS LATER WE
CONTINUE TO
SHORTCHANGE H.I.V.
EFFORTS AND
POVERTY-STRICKEN
COMMUNITIES.
WE
FAIL TO INCLUDE WOMEN,
OUTREACH AND TREATMENT AND WE
LACK THE RESOURCES FOR
COMMUNITIES OF
COLOR.
THIS IS JUST
SIMPLY
UNCONSCIONABLE.
WOMEN OF
COLOR AND YOUNG GAY
AND
BISEXUAL MEN STILL SEVERE
THE MOST
BURDEN OF H.I.V. IN
THE UNITED STATES.
AFRICAN-AMERICANS REPRESENT
APPROXIMATELY
14% OF THE UNITED
STATES POPULATION BUT ACCOUNTED
FOR AN ESTIMATED
44%
OF NEW
INFECTIONS IN
2009.
AND WE
KNOW THE NUMBERS THAT
--
ARE ON THE
RISE IN HISPANIC
COMMUNITIES
AND ASIAN PACIFIC
AS WELL.
THESE
RATES OF INFECTION IS NOT
SOMETHING THAT HAS
HAPPENED IN
ISOLATION.
PEOPLE OF COLOR CONTINUE
TO
FACE HIGHER RATES
OF
UNEMPLOYMENT,
INCARCERATION,
POVERTY AND NEAR
POVERTY THAN
THEIR WHITE
COUNTERPARTS.
WE CAN AND
WE MUST DO
MUCH
BETTER THAN
THIS.
WE
MUST DO MORE FOR THOSE WHO
ARE
DISPROPORTIONATELY IMPACTED
BY
H.I.V. AND AIDS BOTH HERE IN
AMERICA
AND AROUND THE WORLD.
WE MUST
PROVIDE THE
SCIENCE-BASED
COMPREHENSIVE SEX
EDUCATION THAT HELPS
PREVENT
THE SPREAD OF
DISEASES, AND
WE
MUST GROW
PAST OLD FIERCE AND
ENGAGE ALL
COMMUNITIES -- FEARS
AND
ENGAGE ALL
COMMUNITY
STAKEHOLDERS
SURROUNDING THE
TREATMENT OF
THIS DISEASE.
WE
MUST REPEAL LAWS THAT
LEGALIZE AND
PROMOTE
DISCRIMINATION
AND HATE.
WE MUST SUPPORT AND
EXPAND
PROGRAMS
WHICH PROVIDE CRITICAL
SUPPORT FOR
PEOPLE LIVING WITH
H.I.V. AND AIDS
AND
IMMEDIATELY, MIND YOU,
IMMEDIATELY EXTEND TREATMENT
TO
THE HOUSEHOLDS
-- EXCUSE ME --
TO THE THOUSANDS OF
AMERICANS
ON THE WAITING LIST FOR
LIFE-SAVING
DRUGS AND, OF
COURSE, WE MUST
FULLY IMPLEMENT
THE
NATIONAL HIV-AIDS STRATEGY
AND SUPPORT
MEDICAID EXPANSION
UNDER
THE AFFORDABLE CARE ACT.
THESE POLICIES ARE
CRITICAL TO
NEXT
STEPS IN THE FIGHT TO STOP
THIS TERRIBLE DISEASE.
AND WE MUST
PROTECT THE
FRACTION OF
1% OF THE FEDERAL
BUDGET DIRECTED TO
OUR GLOBAL
AIDS
PROGRAM THROUGH PEPFAR AND
THE U.S. GLOBAL
FUND.
FAILING TO SUPPORT THESE
PROGRAMS WOULD
HAVE DRAMATIC
NATIONAL SECURITY
AND
DIPLOMATIC
IMPLICATIONS FOR THE
UNITED STATES.
NOT TO MENTION THE
HUMANITARIAN
DISASTER THAT
WOULD OCCUR.
THAT
IS WHY LAST WEEK I WAS
VERY PROUD TO BE
JOINED BY OVER
MEMBERS OF CONGRESS IN
SEEKING APPROPRIATIONS
OF AT
LEAST
$5.25 BILLION FOR THE
PEPFAR PROGRAM AND
$1.5 BILLION
FOR GLOBAL FUND
TO FIGHT AIDS,
TUBERCULOSIS
AND MALARIA.
MR. SPEAKER, I ASK UNANIMOUS
CONSENT TO ENTER THIS LETTER
INTO THE RECORD.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION.
MS. LEE: FINALLY,
MR. SPEAKER,
THANK YOU.
I
WAS PART OF THE
REMOVAL OF
THE
TRAVEL BAN.
SO LET
ME ENCOURAGE ALL THE
MEMBERS TO
HELP IN THE
WORLDWIDE FIGHT AGAINST
H.I.V.
AND AIDS.
OUR GLOBAL LEADERSHIP WILL
NEVER BE MORE
-- THIS PROMISING
MOMENT WHICH WE COULD MOVE
FORWARD
OR WE COULD GO
BACKWARDS.
SO
I HOPE EVERY MEMBER WILL
JOIN OUR BIPARTISAN
60-PLUS
MEMBERS
OF THE HIV-AIDS
BIPARTISAN CAUCUS.
THANK YOU.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 12-A OF RULE
1, THE CHAIR DECLARES THE HOUSE
IN RECESS
UNTIL THE
HOUR OF
12:00
TODAY.
THE SPEAKER: THE HOUSE WILL BE
IN
ORDER.
THE PRAYER WILL BE
OFFERED BY
OUR GUEST
CHAPLAIN, THE
REVEREND JAY
PHARRELL, CAPE
CORAL UNITED
METHODIST CHURCH,
CAPE CORAL, FLORIDA.
THE
CHAPLAIN: LET US PRAY.
HEAVENLY
FATHER, YOUR WORD SAYS
FROM THOSE TO WHOM
MUCH IS
GIVEN, MUCH WILL BE
DEMANDED.
WE OFFER
OUR GRATITUDE FOR THE
BLESSINGS OF
FREEDOM YOU HAVE
GIVEN
OUR NATION.
YOU HAVE INDEED BLESSED US
WITH
MUCH.
WE
PRAY THAT YOU CONTINUE TO
REMIND US
THAT AMERICA HAS BEEN
BLESSED TO BE A
BLESSING TO
OTHERS.
GRANT THE
MEMBERS OF THIS HOUSE
OF REPRESENTATIVES YOUR WISDOM
AND
GRACE TO
PROVIDE LEADERSHIP
AT
HOME AND AROUND THE WORLD.
HELP
OUR COUNTRY TO CONTINUE TO
BE
A LIGHT TO EVERYONE BY
POINTING
ALL PEOPLE TO THE TRUE
FREEDOM
AND JUSTICE THAT AN
ONLY COME FROM
YOU.
AS WE ENTER
THIS SEASON OF
HOPE,
PLEASE BLESS THIS
CONGRESS AND ALL YOUR
LEADERS
WITH THE
GUIDANCE TO MAKE
DECISIONS
FILLED WITH YOUR
LOVE.
GOD, PLEASE CONTINUE TO
BLESS
AMERICA
AND PLEASE HELP AMERICA
TO
BLESS YOU.
WE ASK
THESE THINGS IN THE NAME
OF YOUR
SON, JESUS CHRIST,
AMEN.
THE SPEAKER: THE CHAIR HAS
EXAMINED THE JOURNAL OF THE
LAST DAY'S
PROCEEDINGS AND
ANNOUNCES TO THE HOUSE
HIS
APPROVAL THEREOF.
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE
1 OF RULE 1,
THE JOURNAL
STANDS APPROVED.
THE PLEDGE OF ALLEGIANCE
WILL
BE LED
BY THE GENTLEMAN FROM
ILLINOIS, MR. HOLTMAN.
MR.
HOLTMAN: PLEASE JOIN ME IN
REAFFIRMING OUR
ALLEGIANCE TO
THIS
GREAT NATION.
I PLEDGE ALLEGIANCE TO THE FLAG
OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
AND TO THE REPUBLIC FOR WHICH
IT STANDS, ONE NATION, UNDER
GOD, INDIVISIBLE, WITH LIBERTY
AND JUSTICE FOR ALL.
THE SPEAKER:
THE CHAIR WILL
ENTERTAIN UP TO 15
REQUESTS FOR
ONE-MINUTE
1350E67S.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE
DOES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
SOUTH CAROLINA
RISE?
&gt;&gt; REQUEST PERMISSION
TO
ADDRESS THE HOUSE
FOR ONE
MINUTE AND
REVISE AND EXTEND MY
REMARKS.
THE SPEAKER:
WITHOUT OBJECTION,
ORDERED.
MR. WILSON: MR. SPEAKER, IN
JUNE,
THE NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS BOARD
PROPOSED A NEW
RULE TO
ACCELERATE THE PROCESS
FOR
UNIONIZATION.
UNION
WORKERS WOULD BE FORCED
INTO MEMBERSHIPS WITHOUT
HAVING
A
REASONABLE TIME FOR MANAGERS
TO
FULLY EXPLAIN THE ADVANTAGES
AND DISADVANTAGES OF
MEMBERSHIP.
THIS AFTERNOON, UNDER
THE
LEADERSHIP
OF EDUCATION AND
WORK FORCE
CHAIRMAN JOHN KLINE,
CONGRESS
WILL VOTE ON THE WORK
FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND FAIRNESS
ACT,
LEGISLATION THAT LIMITS
THE
NLRB'S ABILITY TO DENY
EMPLOYERS AND
WORKERS THE
RIGHTS TO A FREE ELECTION,
A
RIGHT GRANTED TO EVERY
AMERICAN
BY THE LAWS
OF OUR COUNTRY.
IT IS TIME FOR THE
PRESIDENT'S
NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS BOARD
TO STOP
FOCUSING
ON POLICIES
THAT TRAMPLE
OVER THE
RIGHTS OF
AMERICAN WORKERS.
I
ENCOURAGE MY COLLEAGUES TO
VOTE IN FAVOR OF THE BILL
TODAY
AND REAFFIRM
THE PROTECTIONS
WORKERS
AND JOB CREATORS HAVE
RECEIVED FOR
DECADES.
IN
CONCLUSION, GOD BLESS OUR
TROOPS AND WE
WILL NEVER FORGET
SEPTEMBER 11
AND THE GLOBAL WAR
ON TERRORISM.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM NEW YORK RISE?
&gt;&gt; TO ADDRESS
THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
&gt;&gt; MADAM SPEAKER, I RISE IN
OPPOSITION TO LEGISLATION
THAT
WILL HINDER
THE RIGHTS OF
AMERICAN
WORKERS.
THERE ARE SEVERAL
JUNCTURES IN
THE
UNION CERTIFICATION PROCESS
IN WHICH AN
ELECTION CAN BE
DELAYED THROUGH
UNNECESSARY
LITIGATION.
IN JUNE, THE
NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS BOARD
ANNOUNCED
REFORM
S TO
HOLD
ELECTIONS IN A
FAIR
AND TIMELY MANNER THIS
WILL
ADDRESS MORE REFORMS TO
DELAY
ELECTIONS INDEFINITELY.
MR. HIGGINS: I OFTEN CITE THE
HISTORY OF COOPERATIVE
LABOR
RELATIONS AS
ONE OF WESTERN NEW
YORK'S STRENGTH.
BUT THE RECORD
SHOWS SOME WILL
USE
EVERY LOOPHOLE TO PREVENT
WORKERS
VOTING ON WHETHER
TO
BARGAIN
COLLECTIVELY.
THE NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS
BOARD
RULES WILL CLOSE THOSE
LOOPHOLES
AND ALLOW ELECTIONS
TO PROCEED.
WE SHOULD ALLOW
THE REFORMS TO
STAND
AND
INSTEAD FOCUS ON
CREATING JOBS AND
GETTING OUR
ECONOMY
MOVING IN THE RIGHT
DIRECTION.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR
RECOGNIZES THE SPEAKER OF
THE HOUSE
, MR. BOEHNER.
THE SPEAKER:
MADAM SPEAKER, AN
ATTACK
ON ONE WHO
SERVES IS AN
ATTACK
ON ALL WHO SERVE.
I DON'T THINK I
FULLY
UNDERSTOOD THE MEANING
OF THOSE
WORDS
UNTIL LAST JANUARY'S
SENSELESS
ASSAULT ON OUR FELLOW
CITIZENS
AND OUR MOST
FUNDAMENTAL
RESPONSIBILITIES.
THIS HOUSE
RESPONDED IN PRAYER
AND
SOLIDARITY, REMINDING THE
WORLD THAT NO
ACT OF VIOLENCE
COULD
SILENCE THE SACRED
DIALOGUE
OF DEMOCRACY.
IT IS
IN THAT SAME SPIRIT THAT
LATER TODAY WE
WILL GATHER HERE
TO HONOR
GABE ZIMMERMAN, THE
FIRST CONGRESSIONAL
STAFFER TO
GIVE
HIS LIFE IN THE
LINE OF
DUTY.
AND GOD WILLING, THE
LAST.
LIKE EVERY MEMBER OF
THIS BODY,
I
TOOK AN OATH TO UPHOLD AND
DEFEND OUR
CONSTITUTION, AND HE
DI--
AND HE DIED WHILE WELL AND
FAITHLY DISCHARGING HIS
DUTIES.
I THINK
IT IS FITTING AND
APPROPRIATE
TO HONOR GABE
ZIMMERMAN WITH
A PERMANENT
MEMORIAL IN THE UNITED STATES
CAPITOL.
I EXTEND
THE
SYMPATHY
OF THE
WHOLE HOUSE TO HIS FAMILY.
LET
US HONOR GABE'S MEMORY IN
THIS INSTITUTION.
LATER TODAY, I WOULD ASK
THE
HOUSE TO SUPPORT
THE RESOLUTION
AND
WITH THAT, I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLELADY FROM NEW YORK
RISE?
&gt;&gt; TO
ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY IS RECOGNIZED.
&gt;&gt; THANK YOU, MADAM SPEAKER.
LAST WEEK, LIKE
MILLIONS OF
AMERICANS ACROSS THIS COUNTRY,
MY
FAMILY AND I GAVE
THANKS FOR
OUR
BLESSINGS, OUR NATION'S
FREEDOM AND FOR
THE FOOD ON OUR
TABLE PROVIDED BY
THE HARD
WORKING
FARMERS OF OUR COUNTRY
AND
FROM MY DISTRICT.
NOW I
ASK MY COLLEAGUES TO JOIN
ME IN
GIVING THANKS FOR OUR
FARMERS WHO MAKE
THIS GREAT
HARVEST
POSSIBLE.
AMERICA'S FARMS ARE THE BEST
IN
THE WORLD.
OUR FOOD IS
SAFER, HIGHER IN
QUALITY AND
MORE EFFICIENTLY
GROWN THAN ANY
OTHER
COUNTRY.
THE LABOR AND
INNOVATION OF
AMERICA'S FARMERS PUT
FOOD ON
THE
TABLES OF NOT JUST FAMILIES
HERE AT
HOME BUT ACROSS THE
WORLD.
AS OUR
FARMERS BRING THEIR
GOODS
TO MARKET IN THE 21ST
CENTURY
ECONOMY, THEY EXPECT TO
HAVE A 21ST
CENTURY GOVERNMENT
THAT WILL HELP, NOT
HINDER
THEIR
BUSINESS.
MS. HOCHUL:
THAT'S WHEY I
CALLEN
THE SECRETARY OF LABOR
TO SUBMIT
APPLICATIONS FOR
GUEST
WORKERS ONLINE.
NEW YORK
FARMERS ARE
INCREASINGLY
RELYING ON THIS TO
FIND
THE LEGAL HELP THEY NEED.
I WAS SHOCKED TO
LEARN THAT ONE
OF
MY ONION FARMS HAD TO MAIL
ALMOST 20 POUNDS
OF PAPERWORK
TO THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
IN
ORDER TO
PARTICIPATE IN THE
PROGRAM.
THERE MUST BE A BETTER WAY.
AN
ONLINE
APPLICATION PROGRAM
WOULD
SAVE MONEY FOR FARMERS
AND TAXPAYERS AND
I URGE THE
SECRETARY
OF LABOR TO SWIFTLY
IMPLEMENT
THIS PROGRAM.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM ILLINOIS RISE?
&gt;&gt;
REQUEST PERMISSION TO
ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR
ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
&gt;&gt; THANK YOU,
MADAM SPEAKER.
RECENTLY
A CONSTITUENT OF MINE
WROTE TO
ME AND ASKED WHAT IS
GOING ON IN
WASHINGTON?
SHE
SAID HER HUSBAND A SMALL
BUSINESS OWNER, IS
TAXED SO
HARD
THAT MONEY IS TIGHT AND AS
A RESULT THEY CANNOT GROW
THEIR
BUSINESS.
AND SHE SAID IF WE
CANNOT GROW,
WE
CANNOT CREATE NEW JOBS.
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT YOU ARE
DOING FOR JOB
GROWTH.
MR. HULTGREN: AGAIN,
A GOOD
QUESTION.
THE ANSWER IS
SIMPLE.
WE
NEED PRO GROWTH, PRO JOBS
POLICIES.
THE HOUSE HAS PASSED MORE THAN
BILLS THAT DO
JUST THAT
THROUGH LOW
TAXES, REASONABLE
REGULATION, LESS SPENDING
AND
SMALLER,
LESS INTRUSIVE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT.
THESE ARE
COMMON SENSE BILLS,
MOST OF THEM
PASSED WITH
BIPARTISAN SUPPORT.
WHERE ARE
THESE BILLS NOW?
LANGUISHING IN THE
DO-NOTHING
SENATE.
TO MY CONSTITUENT, AND
TO MANY
OTHERS WHO SHARE HER
CONCERN,
MY SIMPLE
RESPONSE IS, WE IN
THE HOUSE
HAVE ACTED, NOW IT'S
TIME
FOR THE SENATE TO DO THE
SAME.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM
CONNECTICUT RISE?
&gt;&gt; TO
ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
&gt;&gt;
MADAM SPEAKER, 25 MILLION
PEOPLE DEAD AROUND
THE WORLD.
MILLION ORPHAN CHILDREN ON
THE CONTINENT OF
AFRICA ALONE.
MADAM SPEAKER, THIS IS
PART OF
THE TOLL
THAT THE HUMAN RACE
HAS BORNE SINCE
THE TERRIBLE
SCOURGE OF
H.I.V. AIDS BEGAN
ITS
WORK A DECADE -- A JEB
RATION
AGO.
MR. HIMES: I
RISE TODAY TO
COMMEMORATE THE
BROTHERS,
SISTERS,
FRIENDS, AND CHILDREN
WE HAVE
LOST TO THIS DISEASE.
I RISE TO
COMMEMORATE THE
STRUGGLE OF THE
33 MILLION
PEOPLE AROUND
THE WORLD WHO ARE
LIVING WITH
THIS TERRIBLE
DISEASE TODAY AND I RISE TO
CELEBRATE THE
NEW AND REAL
POSSIBILITY THAT WE COULD END
AIDS IN THIS GENERATION.
MADAM SPEAKER, THIS GOVERNMENT
FUNDED THE
PEB FAVRE FIGHT THAT
BROUGHT HOPE AND
HEALTH TO
MILLIONS AROUND THE
WORLD AND
FUNNED THE
RESEARCH THAT
ALLOWS
US TO SAY
TODAY THAT WE COULD
END
AIDS.
AS WE DO THE
HARD WORK OF
BALANCING THE
BUDGET, LET'S DO
WHAT WE NEED
TO DO TO END THIS
DISEASE AND MAKE
SURE THAT
FUTURE WORLD
AIDS DAYS ARE ALL
ABOUT
CELEBRATION.
I YIELD
BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM TEXAS
RISE?
MR. POE:
I REQUEST PERMISSION
TO
ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. POE:
MADAM SPEAKER, IN ONE
MONTH, EVERY
HOME IN AMERICA
MUST BE LIT WITH SPECIAL
$3
GOVERNMENT-APPROVED LIGHT
BULB.
THE
75 CENT INCANDESCENT LIGHT
BULB, THOMAS
EDISON'S GREATEST
INVENTION,
WILL BE BANNED BY
THE GOVERNMENT.
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT'S
ANTI-CONSUMER
CHOICE LAW LEAVES
AMERICA'S NO
OTHER OPTION BUT
TO USE A
HARMFUL,
MERCURY-FILLED PRODUCT.
ALSO IT'S A JOB ILL
CANNER.
IT ENDED A
MANUFACTURING
INDUSTRY THAT WENT BACK TO THE
DAYS OF THOMAS
EDISON AND
SHIPPED
MOST OF THOSE JOBS
OVERSEAS.
PRIMARILY TO CHINA.
ISN'T THAT LOVELY.
ALSO
WHERE DOES THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT HAVE THE
CONSTITUTIONAL AUTHORITY TO
FORCE ANYBODY TO
BUY ANYTHING,
FROM HEALTH CARE INSURANCE TO A
BOX OF
DOUGHNUTS OR EVEN A
LIGHT BULB?
IT'S TIME FOR THE
BUREAUCRATS
TO QUIT
FORCIBLY MICROMANAGING
AMERICA, LET
AMERICANS CHOOSE
HOW TO LIGHT
THEIR OWN HOMES.
OTHERWISE, WE WILL HAVE TO
TURN
OUT THE
LIGHTS, THE PARTY IS
OVER, EVEN
FOR THOMAS EDISON'S
LIGHT
BULB.
AND THAT'S
JUST THE WAY IT IS.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM
CALIFORNIA RISE?
&gt;&gt; TO ADDRESS
THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE
AND REVISE AND EXTEND MY
REMARKS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
&gt;&gt; MADAM SPEAKER
WORK
THE
UNEMPLOYMENT
ABOVE 13% AND HOME
FORECLOSURES AT A RECORD
LEVEL,
FAMILIES IN
MY CONGRESSIONAL
DISTRICT ARE
HURTING.
MR. BACA: I STATE, THEY ARE
NOW IF CONGRESS DOES
NOT ACT
SOON, THESE
STRUGGLING FAMILIES
WILL FACE A
$1,000 TAX
INCREASE, A
INCREASE.
AND WHY ARE
FAMILIES FACING
THIS
DEADLINE?
BECAUSE THE
REPUBLICANS REFUSE,
AND I
STATE, THE REPUBLICANS
REFUSE
TO ASK THOSE MAKING MORE
THAN $1 MILLION
A YEAR TO
CONTRIBUTE
THEIR FAIR SHARE.
THE REPUBLICANS
' OBSESSION WITH
EXTENDING THE
BUSH TAX FOR THE
ULTRA RICH
HAS LED TO THE
FAILURES OF THE SUPER
COMMITTEE.
WE ALL KNOW
THE BUSH TAX CUTS
WERE
A HORRIBLE
FAILURE.
THEY
DIDN'T PRODUCE JOBS HERE
IN THE
UNITED STATES, THEY
DIDN'T CREATE ANY NEW
JOBS.
THEY DUG
US INTO A $15 TRILLION
DEBT AND NOW THE
REPUBLICANS
WANT TO
PERMANENTLY EXTEND THIS
MADNESS.
IT
CAN'T JUST BE MY WAY OR THE
HIGHWAY.
LET'S STOP THE
GRIDLOCK.
LET'S PASS
A JOBS BILL.
LET'S WORK TOGETHER ON
A
BALANCED
BUDGET.
I YIELD BACK THE BALANCE
OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM MICHIGAN RISE?
&gt;&gt; I RISE TO
ADDRESS THE HOUSE
FOR
ONE MINUTE AND REVISE AND
EXTEND MY
REMARKS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
&gt;&gt; I RISE TODAY
WITH A TWINGE
OF
SADNESS IN MY HEART AS A PAY
TRIBUTE TO FRED MEIER,
ONE OF
AMERICA'S
MOST ENTREPRENEURIAL
SPIRITS WHO PASSED AWAY
THIS
WEEK JUST SHY OF
HIS 92ND
BIRTHDAY.
HE WAS BORN IN
GREENVILLE,
MICHIGAN IN
1919 AND WAS KNOWN
AS THE FATHER OF THE
SUPERSTORE
HIS
INNOVATION AND
ENTREPRENEURSHIP WILL
LIVE ON
IN
HIS MEIER GROASTRY STORES
WITH OVER
STARS -- STORES
IN FIVE DIFFERENT
STATES.
HE'LL BE
REMEMBERED IN WEST
MICHIGAN FOR
HIS PHILANTHROPY,
FRIENDSHIP AND
CARE OF THE
COMMUNITY
HE LIVED IN.
HE AND
HIS WIFE GAVE BACK AND
INVESTED
MILLIONS IN THEIR
COMMUNITY.
DESPITE
DEPROWING ONE OF THE
MOST
SUCCESSFUL BUSINESSES IN
THE COUNTRY
AND REVOLUTIONIZING
THE
RERE-TAIL MODEL, HE
REMAINED
A TYPICAL WEST
MICHIGAN
DOWN-TO-EARTH PERSON
WHO REMARKED,
MONEY IS ONLY A
TOOL AND MONEY DOESN'T
BUY
HAPPYNESS.
HE KNEW WHAT WAS IMPORTANT AND
KEPT THAT IN THE
FOREFRONT.
FRIENDS,
FAMILY A STRONG
RELATIONSHIP WITH HIS
NEIGHBORS
AND COMMUNITY AND THE THING HE
LOVED TO DO
THE MOST WAS HAND
OUT PURPLE COW
CARDS, FREE ICE
CREAM
CARDS IN -- TO KIDS IN
HIS STORES.
AGAIN, I RISE TO PAY
TRIBUTE TO
HIM, HIS
FAMILY AND THE
INNOVATION AN
ENTREPRENEURIAL
LEGACY
HE LEAVES BEHIND.
MR.
MEIER, YOU WILL BE MISSED
BUT YOU WILL NOT
BE FORGOTTEN.
THANK YOU.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM
RHODE ISLAND RISE?
&gt;&gt; I ASK
UNANIMOUS CONSENT TO
ADDRESS THE
HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
&gt;&gt; AT
A TIME WHEN SO
MANY RHODE
ISLANDERS AND
AMERICANS ARE OUT
OF WORK, WE NEED TO DO
EVERYTHING WE CAN
TO PROVIDE
ASSISTANCE TO
FAMILIES WHILE
INDIVIDUALS CONTINUE TO LOOK
FOR WORK.
THE FEDERAL
EMERGENCY
UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE
IS A
CRITICAL PART
OF
OUR SAFETY NET
THAT SUPPORTS
FAMILIES IN
DIFFICULT
TIMES.
MR. CICILLINE: MR.
CONSTITUENTS
HAVE CONTACTED MY
OFFICE
EXPLAINING THE
IMPACT ON THEIR
FAMILIES OF
NOT EXTENDING
UNEMPLOYMENT
BENEFITS, LIKE
ESTELLA
A SINGLE MOTHER LAID
OFF FROM WORK
WHO NOW RELIES ON
UNEMPLOYMENT
BENEFITS TO
SUPPORT
HERSELF AND HER SON.
SHE'S LOOKING FOR WORK AND IS
CURRENTLY PARTICIPATING IN A
JOB TRAINING PROGRAM
TO IMPROVE
HER
SKILLS AND ENHANCE HER
ABILITY TO FIND A
JOB.
WITHOUT
UNEMPLOYMENT BENEFIT
SHE IS WOULD NOT BE ABLE
TO
SUPPORT HER
HOUSEHOLD AND PAY
HER
BILLS.
IF THE
EMERGENCY FEDERAL
UNEMPLOYMENT
BENEFITS PROGRAM
IS NOT
EXTENDED AT THE END OF
THIS YEAR, IT
WILL BE
DEVASTATING TO
HER AND
THOUSANDS OF
OTHER MESHES.
THESE
AMERICANS WHO WORKED HARD
THROUGHOUT THEIR
LIFES SHOULD
NOT BE
SACRIFICED ON THE ALTAR
OF
PARTISAN POLITICS.
CONGRESS MUST STOP
PLAYING
WASHINGTON-STYLE POLITICAL
GAMES WITH THE FATE OF THESE
FAMILIES AND ACT
NOW TO PROVIDE
SECURITY TO UNEMPLOYED
WORKERS
AND THEIR
FAMILIES WHILE THEY
LOOK FOR
JOBS.
I THANK YOU
AND YIELD BACK THE
BALANCE
OF MY TIME.
.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM YIP IS
RECOGNIZED.
--
INDIANA IS RECOGNIZED.
&gt;&gt; I RISE TODAY TO
EXPRESS MY
EXTREME DISAPPOINT WITH
THE
RECENT
H.H.S. DESESSION TO DENY
INDIANA SENSIBLE WAIVER
REQUEST
THAT LOU OUR
STATES TO EASE INTO
THE
NEW RULE THAT REQUIRES
INSURERS
SELLING POLICIES TO
INDIVIDUALS
TO
DEDICATE 80% TO
MEDICAL
CARE.
THIS DECISION
WAS MADE ON THE
BASIS
THAT INSURERS DOING
BUSINESS IN INDIANA
WERE DEEMED
PROFITABLE
ENOUGH.
C.M.S.
CLAIMED NO PROVIDER WOULD
BE
FORCED TO LEAVE BECAUSE OF
THE
DENIAL OF SUCH A
WAIVER.
IT WAS THE VERY SPECTER
OF
UNSURROUNDING THE PRESIDENT'S
HEALTH CARE LAW THAT
RESULTED IN
THE FIVE PROVIDERS LEAVING
THE
MARKET
THIS SUMMER.
THE
PROVIDERS FROM OUR STATE AND
DENIAL
OF THIS WAIVER WILL LIMIT
COMPETITION AND PUSH
PRICES
HIGHER.
LET THIS SERVE AS A WARNING
TO
OTHER STATES,
CREATIVE AND
CONSUMER-DRIVEN SOLUTIONS TO
MEET OUR
CITIZENS' MEDICAL NEEDS
WILL BE DISPROPORTIONATELY
HARMED UNDER
THE PRESIDENT'S
DENIAL OF THESE WAIVERS.
I
YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLELADY
FROM NEVADA RISE?
MS. BERKLEY: I ASK TO ADDRESS
THE HOUSE FOR ONE MINUTE.
REVISE AND EXTEND.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY IS RECOGNIZED.
MS. BERKLEY: THANK YOU.
MADAM SPEAKER,
NEVADA'S MIDDLE
INCOME FAMILIES HAVE
BORNE THE
BRUNT OF THE
ECONOMIC
CATASTROPHE THAT HAS
DEVASTATED
OUR STATE.
WE NEED TO CREATE
JOBS AND GET
OUR ECONOMY
MOVING AGAIN.
WHAT
WE DON'T NEED IS A MIDDLE
CLASS
TAX HIKE.
BUT THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT SOME
OF
OUR
COLLEAGUES IN THE UNITED
STATES SENATE ARE
PROPOSING AS
THEY CONSIDER WHETHER
TO EXTEND
AND EXPAND THE
PAYROLL TAX CUT
THIS WEEK.
THIS SHOULD BE
A NO-BRAINER.
OPPOSITION TO
THE MIDDLE CLASS
TAX CUT ACT
OF 2011 IS A VOTE TO
RAISE TAXES
ON MIDDLE INCOME
FAMILIES
AND NEVADA AND ACROSS
THE COUNTRY.
THIS WOULD BE
DEVASTATING FOR A
STATE
LIKE NEVADA.
THE
MIDDLE CLASS TAX CUT ACT
WOULD CUT
TAXES FOR 1.2 MILLION
NEVADANS AND 50,000
SMALL
BUSINESSES ACROSS
THE STATE.
WHAT
DOES THAT MEAN?
IT
MEANS THE AVERAGE NEVADAN
KEEPS
$1,600 IN THEIR POCKET.
IT
MEANS
$1,000 TAX HIKE ON
NEVADA
FAMILIES IS PREVENTED.
AND IT MEANS
THAT NEVADA'S SMALL
BUSINESSES HAVE MORE
MONEY TO
CREATE
JOBS.
BUT
INSTEAD OF WHOLESALE SUPPORT
FOR THIS
COMMONSENSE MEASURE, WE
ARE GETTING
EXCUSES AND
ROADBLOCKS.
IT'S TIME FOR
ACTION.
LET'S PASS THIS BILL.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM
NEW JERSEY RISE?
&gt;&gt; TO ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR.
HOLT: AS THE PRESIDENT HAS
DESIGNATED THIS MONTH AS
NATIONAL FAMILY
CAREGIVERS'
MONTH, I RISE TO
GIVE HONOR AND
RECOGNIZE THE TENS OF MILLIONS
OF AMERICANS
AND MILLIONS OF NEW
JERSEYANS WHO PROVIDE
LOVING
CARE FOR
FAMILY MEMBERS AND
FRIENDS LIVING
WITH DISABILITIES
AND
ILLNESSES.
CARE
GIVING IS NOT EASY.
THE
CAREGIVERS THEMSELVES FACE
PHYSICAL
AND MENTAL HEALTH
COMPLICATIONS.
SOME ARE WORKING WITH ALMOST
UNBELIEVABLE ENDURANCE.
SOME OF THESE CAREGIVERS
ARE
PART OF THE
SANDWICH GENERATION.
PROVIDING CARE
FOR THEIR
CHILDREN AS WELL AS THEIR
PARENTS.
THERE ARE ECONOMIC COSTS AS
WELL.
U.S.
EMPLOYERS ESTIMATE THE
COST
TO BE ABOUT
$34 BILLION A YEAR
IN
LOST
PRODUCTIVITY.
I LOOK FORWARD TO
WORKING WITH
MY COLLEAGUES HERE IN CONGRESS
TO
PROVIDE CAREGIVERS WITH THE
HELP THEY NEED
.
RESPITE
CARE, A RE-AUTHORIZED
OLDER
AMERICANS ACT, TAX
CREDITS, JUST BECAUSE THE
CLASS
ACT WILL NOT BE
IMPLEMENTED DOES
NOT MEAN THE NEED
TO PROVIDE
CARE WILL GO
AWAY.
WE HAVE WORK
TO DO.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLELADY
FROM CALIFORNIA RISE?
THE GENTLELADY IS RECOGNIZED.
MRS. CAPPS:
I RISE TO URGE YOU
TO BRING
LEGISLATION TODAY TO
EXTEND
AND EXPAND
THE PAYROLL
TAX CUT.
IF CONGRESS FAILS TO
EXTEND THE
PAYROLL
TAX CUT, THE AVERAGE
AMERICAN
FAMILY WILL PAY
$1,000
MORE IN TAXES
NEXT YEAR.
COUNTLESS FAMILIES IN
MY
DISTRICT ARE STILL
STRUGGLING TO
STAY AFLOAT.
THEY CAN'T AFFORD TO LOSE
$1,000
IN INCOME
NEXT YEAR.
EXTENDING
AND EXPANDING THE
PAYROLL TAX CUT IS
NOT JUST THE
RIGHT THING TO
DO FOR OUR
FAMILIES
ON THE CENTRAL COAST OF
CALIFORNIA, IT'S THE RIGHT
THING
TO DO FOR OUR
ECONOMY.
LEADING
NONPARTISAN ECONOMISTS
ESTIMATE LETTING THE PAYROLL
TAX
EXPIRE
WOULD COST THE ECONOMY,
400,000 JOBS
BY THE END OF NEXT
YEAR.
SUCH TREMENDOUS JOB LOSS WOULD
BE
DEVASTATING TO OUR
STRUGGLING
ECONOMY AND TO
AMERICAN
FAMILIES.
EXTENDING
THE PAYROLL TAX CUTS
SHOULD HAVE
BIPARTISAN SUPPORT
WITH ALL
THE ANTI-TAX
LEGISLATION TAKEN BY OUR
COLLEAGUES ACROSS THE IME YOU
WOULD THINK THIS IS A
NO-BRAINER.
MORE THAN HALF OF THE REPUBLICAN
CONFERENCE VOTED FOR
THE PAYROLL
TAX
LAST DECEMBER.
MADAM SPEAKER, LET'S
EXTEND THE
PAYROLL
TAX CUT NOW.
IT'S A WIN
FOR THE MIDDLE.
IT'S A WIN FOR SMALL
BUSINESSES.
AND
IT'S A WIN FOR OUR ECONOMY.
I
YIELD.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM MISSOURI RISE?
THE GENTLEMAN
IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. CLAY: THANK YOU,
MADAM
SPEAKER OF THE THE
ATTEMPT
TO
INCRIMINATE, DISCOURAGE,
OR
PREVENT CERTAIN PEOPLE
FROM
VOTING HAS
A LONG AND NOTORIOUS
HISTORY.
UNFORTUNATELY
VOTER SUPPRESSION
ISN'T
JUST A PART OF
OUR PAST.
IT'S A
CURRENT EVENT.
SOUTHERN STATES
USE TACTICS SUCH
AS
LITERACY TESTS AND POLL TAXES
TO DENY
AFRICAN-AMERICANS,
NATIVE AMERICANS, AND POOR
IMMIGRANTS THEIR RIGHT TO VOTE.
WHILE CIVIL
RIGHTS ACHIEVEMENTS
IN THE 1960'S
DID AWAY WITH
THESE
TACTICS, THE STRATEGY
CONTINUES.
THE OLD
WAYS HAVE BEEN REPLACED
WITH
VOTER I.D. LAWS, OUTRAGEOUS
REGISTRATION REQUIREMENTS,
DISHONEST INACTIVE
VOTER LISTS,
UNFAIR
PURGING EVER VOTER ROLLS.
DISINFORMATION
CAMPAIGNS, AND
UNLAWFUL DIS
ENFRANCHISEMENT.
WITH ANYONE'S RIGHT
TO VOTERS
THREATENED, WE ARE ALL
THREATENED.
WE NEED TO STOP THESE
BLATANT
ATTEMPTS
TO DENY AMERICAN
CITIZENS THE RIGHT TO
VOTE.
I
YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLELADY
FROM
TEXAS RISE?
THE GENTLELADY IS RECOGNIZED.
MS. JACKSON LEE:
MADAM SPEAKER,
I'M DELIGHTED
TO JOIN MY
COLLEAGUE, CONGRESSMAN
CLAY,
BEFORE I DO
THAT LET ME RISE AS
WELL TO EXPRESS MY
SUPPORT FOR
THE
GABE ZIMMERMAN LEGISLATION
WE WILL
ADDRESS TODAY AND
PAY
TRIBUTE TO HIS
BRAVERY AND LOSS.
WE COME
TO THE FLOOR TODAY AS
PARTNERS
WITH MANY IN THIS
CONGRESS AGAINST
VOTER
INTIMIDATION
AND TO SPEAK ON
BEHALF OF THE
CONGRESSIONAL
BLACK CAUCUS
TO COLLABORATE WITH
MANY
FRIENDS ACROSS THE CAUCUSES
AND
ACROSS THE INTEREST OF THE
DEMOCRATIC CAUCUS AND
CERTAINLY
WE HOPE TO INCLUDE
OUR FRIENDS
ON
THE OTHER SIDE OF THE AISLE.
SINCE THE
ELECTION, OVER 40
STATES HAVE
IMPLEMENTED VOTER
I.D., VOTER
SUPPRESSION LAWS.
MADAM SPEAKER, WE ARE NOT
AGAINST KNOWING WHO IS
VOTING.
BUT WE ARE AGAINST THE
TURNING
BACK THE BLOCK OF
WHAT THE
VOTING
RIGHTS ACT ATTEMPTED TO
DO SOME
40-PLUS YEARS AGO.
WHEN BEFORE THAT TIME
POLL TAX
WAS
UTILIZED OR ASKING THOSE
FROM THE
AFRICAN-AMERICAN
COMMUNITY
HOW MANY JELLY BEANS
WERE IN A
JAR.
JUST
RECENTLY I SENT A LETTER TO
THE U.S.
ATTORNEYS OFFICE
REGARDING
VOTER INTIMIDATION AND
VOTER OPPRESSION.
WE RISE TODAY TO
SAY THAT WE
WILL STAND AGAINST
SUCH
OPPRESSION AND
ASK THE JUSTICE
DEPARTMENT
TO NOT CLEAR VOTER
I.D. LAWS.
WITH THAT I YIELD BACK
MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM NEW YORK
RISE?
&gt;&gt; I
WOULD LIKE TO ADDRESS THE
HOUSE FOR ONE MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR.
RANGEL: AT A TIME THAT
GOVERNMENT IS
HELD IN SUCH LOW
ESTEEM, IT'S
TIME THAT WE ALL
REALLY
SAY TO EACH OTHER THAT WE
ALL
LOVE AMERICA AND WE RESPECT
AMERICA, AND
ALL OVER THE WORLD
PEOPLE
ARE JUST TRYING TO GET
HERE.
RECENTLY WE TALKED ABOUT IN
GOD
WE TRUST.
AND THE
QUESTION IS WHETHER
GOD'S
GOING TO CONTINUE TO
TRUST
US BECAUSE THE
FACT IS THAT ONE
OF THE THINGS THAT
MAKES OUR
COUNTRY DIFFERENT
IS THAT PEOPLE
DON'T COME HERE TO
BECOME RICH.
THEY COME HERE
TO BE RESPECTED.
AND THAT
IS WHAT WE HAVE LEARNED
NO MATTER WHETHER
IT'S JEW OR
GENTILE OR
MORMAN, EVERY
RELIGION EMPHASIZES THE
FACT
THAT WE HAVE
A MORAL OBLIGATION
TO
TAKE CARE OF THOSE PEOPLE
THAT
ARE VULNERABLE.
WHETHER IT'S OUR KIDS, OLD
FOLKS, AND SICK
PEOPLE.
WE DON'T TALK THAT WAY
IN THE
HOUSE.
WE TALK ABOUT
MEDICARE,
EDUCATION,
MEDICARE, SWST, BUT
ALL OF
THOSE THINGS INCLUDING
THE
OPPORTUNITY TO HAVE A JOB
MAKES AMERICA WHAT
IT'S SUPPOSED
TO BE.
IT'S
THE HOPE FOR THE FUTURE
THAT OUR KIDS WILL HAVE
A BETTER
OPPORTUNITY
THAN WE
DID.
LET'S SAY
GOD BLESS AMERICA.
LET'S WORK AND MAKE
CERTAIN WE
DO ALL THAT WE
CAN DO.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLELADY
FROM HAWAII RISE?
&gt;&gt; I
REQUEST UNANIMOUS CONSENT
TO ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY IS RECOGNIZED.
MS. HANABUSA: MADAM SPEAKER,
LET'S NOT
FORGET.
WE
TALK ABOUT THE GREAT
DEPRESSION AND HOW CLOSE WE HAVE
COME TO
IT.
AND
LET'S RECOGNIZE AND REALIZE
WHAT WE AS
A COUNTRY DID THEN.
WE PASSED THE SOCIAL SECURITY
ACT OF
1935.
LET'S ALSO
NOT FORGET THAT PART
OF
THAT IS THE PROTECTION
OF NOT
ONLY
OUR SENIORS BUT ALSO OF
THOSE WHO ARE
UNEMPLOYED THROUGH
NO FAULT OF
THEIR OWN.
THAT IS WHAT WE ARE LOOKING
AT.
MADAM SPEAKER,
WE MUST RECOGNIZE
THAT
IT IS TIME TO EXTEND THAT
UNEMPLOYMENT OR IT IS
GOING TO
COST OUR ECONOMY
$30 BILLION AND
WE ARE
GOING
TO ALSO AEFFECT A
MILLION PEOPLE.
MADAM SPEAKER, LET'S
ALSO
RECOGNIZE WHAT
MAKES US A GREAT
COUNTRY.
IT IS NOT
OUR MILITARY MIGHT.
WHAT MAKES US A
GREAT COUNTRY IS
COMPASSION.
IT IS THE FACT
THAT WE HAVE
DEFINED OURSELVES BY
HOW WE
TREAT
OUR PEOPLE.
LET'S
NEVER FORGET THAT.
IT IS
TIME TO BE COMPASSIONATE,
MADAM SPEAKER.
IT IS TIME FOR US TO
EXTEND THE
UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE.
THANK YOU,
MADAM SPEAKER.
I
YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLEMAN
FROM
KENTUCKY RISE?
MR. YARMUTH:
REQUEST PERMISSION
TO
ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. YARMUTH: ABOUT ONE YEAR AGO
REPUBLICANS WERE INSISTING THAT
BEFORE WE DO ANYTHING TO HELP
UNEMPLOYED AMERICANS WE
HAD TO
GUARANTEE TAX RATES FOR THE
RICHEST OF THE RICH
WE MADE AT
THE
LOWIERS LEVEL IN 50 YEARS.
BEFORE
DOING ANYTHING TO HELP
THOSE WHO WERE
STRUGGLING, THEY
DEMANDED WE GIVE MORE TO
THOSE
WHO WERE
HURTING THE LEAST.
BUT THAT WAS JUST
THE BEGINNING.
NOW
THEY ARE RESISTING A TAX CUT
THAT WOULD GIVE AMERICAN
FAMILIES AN AVERAGE OF
$1,000
PER
YEAR.
THESE ARE
THE SAME FAMILIES
WHICH
HAVE SEEN THEIR
INCOMES
DROP BY
$6,000 IN JUST THE LAST
TWO YEARS.
REPUBLICANS ARE
PUTTING MORE AND
MORE MONEY INTO THE
POCKETS OF
MILLIONAIRES AND TAKING
IT OUT
OF THE
POCKETS OF AMERICAN
FAMILIES.
THEY HAVE GONE
FROM SIMPLY NOT
HELPING WORKING
AMERICANS TO
ACTIVELY
MAKING IT HARDER FOR
THEM TO GET BY.
THESE ARE NOT THE
PRIORITIES OF
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
I
URGE MY COLLEAGUES TO SUPPORT
THE EXTENSION
OF THE PAYROLL TAX
CUT AND
STAND UP FOR THIS
COMMONSENSE
POLICY THAT WILL
HELP MILLIONS
OF AMERICAN
FAMILIES.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM NEW JERSEY RISE?
MR.
PAYNE: TO ADDRESS THE HOUSE
FOR ONE MINUTE.
REVISE AND EXTEND MY
REMARKS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. PAYNE: MADAM SPEAKER,
I RISE
TODAY
TO URGE MY REPUBLICAN
COLLEAGUES
TO MOVE FAST AND JOIN
FORCES
TO EXTEND THE
UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE
AND
PAYROLL
TAX CUTS.
NOW MORE
THAN EVER MOST
REPUBLICANS
ARE CONTENT WITH
CUTTING OFF THE
UNEMPLOYMENT
INSURANCE AND RAISING
TAXES ON
MILLIONS
OF MIDDLE CLASS
AMERICANS
WHILE
REFUSING TO
RAISE TAXES
ON THE
RICHEST 1%.
THE
UNEMPLOYMENT RATE FOR THE
MONTH OF OCTOBER
IN MY
CONGRESSIONAL DISTRICT
IN NEW
JERSEY
ARE BETWEEN 9% AND 10%
WHICH
IS ABOVE THE NATIONAL
AVERAGE.
IF CONGRESS
DOES NOT ACT BY THE
END
OF
THIS YEAR, 2.2 MILLION
UNEMPLOYED WORKERS,
INCLUDING MY
CONSTITUENTS, WILL LOSE THEIR
UNEMPLOYMENT
INSURANCE BENEFITS
BY FEBRUARY,
2012.
WHILE
TIMES COULD NOT BE ANY
TOUGHER, REPUBLICANS
ALSO REFUSE
TO EXTEND
THE PAYROLL TAX
HOLIDAY CUT
ENACTED EARLIER THIS
YEAR THAT
GAVE VIRTUALLY ALL
WORKING AMERICANS A
MUCH NEEDED
TAX CUT.
FAILING TO EXTEND
THE PAYROLL
TAX CUT
WILL STRIP OVER $120
BILLION
FROM THE POCKETS OF
CONSUMERS.
WE MUST ACT NOW
AND EXTEND THE
UNEMPLOYMENT
INSURANCE AND
PAYROLL
TAX CUTS.
YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLELADY
FROM CALIFORNIA RISE?
THE
GENTLELADY IS RECOGNIZED.
MS. CHU: DAWN, A
SINGLE MOTHER
OF
TWO SPENDS EVERY DAY BEING
LOOKING FOR A
JOB.
AFTER 20
YEARS WORKING SHE WAS
LAID OFF IN JULY AND
NOW THE
ONLY THING PAYING
HER HEAT
AND
ELECTRICITY BILLS,
THE ONLY
THING PUTTING FOOD
ON THE TABLE,
IS
HER HODDEST UNEMPLOYMENT
BENEFIT.
IN JUST
35 DAYS AND
COUNTING,
HER SAFETY NET WILL BE PULLED
AWAY IF CONGRESS FAILS
TO
ACT.
IF WE
DON'T EXTEND EMERGENCY
UNEMPLOYMENT BENEFITS WHEN
THEY
EXPIRE, BY
MID FEBRUARY, 2.1
MILLION AMERICANS WILL
HAVE
THEIR BENEFITS
CUT OFF.
AND
BY THE END OF THE YEAR, SIX
MILLION WILL BE
WITHOUT THIS
CRITICAL
LIFELINE.
TODAY ONE OUT
OF EVERY 11
AMERICANS IS OUT
OF WORK.
CONGRESS HAS
NEVER ALLOWED
UNEMPLOYMENT BENEFITS
TO EXPIRE
WHEN
UNEMPLOYMENT WAS THIS HIGH
FOR THIS LONG.
WE SHOULD NOT
START NOW.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 8 OF RULE
20,
THE CHAIR WILL POSTPONE FURTHER
PROCEEDINGS
TODAY ON MOTION TO
SUSPEND THE RULES ON WHICH A
RECORDED VOTE OR THE YEAS AND
NAYS ARE
ORDERED, OR ON WHICH
THE
VOTE OCCURS -- INCURS
OBJECTION
UNDER CLAUSE 6 OF
RULE
20.
ANY
RECORD THE VOTE ON
THE
POSTPONED QUESTION
WILL BE TAKEN
LATER.
.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM TENNESSEE
SEEK
RECOGNITION?
&gt;&gt; I MOVE TO
SUSPEND THE RULES
AND
PASS HOUSE RESOLUTION 364.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CLERK WILL REPORT THE TITLE.
THE CLERK:
HOUSE RESOLUTION
364, DESIGNATING
ROOM
H.V.C.
215 OF THE
CAPITOL VISITOR
CENTER
AS THE GABRIEL ZIMMERMAN
MEETING ROOM.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN
WILL HAVE 0
MINUTES.
MR.
FLEISCHMANN: I ASK THAT ALL
MEMBERS HAVE FIVE LEGISLATIVE
DAYS TO REVISE AND EXTEND THEIR
REMARKS ON THE LEGISLATION.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION.
MR.
FLEISCHMANN:
HOUSE
RESOLUTION
364 WOULD DESIGNATE
ROOM
H.V.C. 215 OF THE CAPITOL
VISITOR
CENTER AS THE GABRIELLE
ZIMMERMAN
MEETING ROOM THIS
RESOLUTION HAS BROAD
BIPARTISAN
SUPPORT
WITH 367 CO-SPONSORS.
ON
JANUARY 8, 2011, THIS
COUNTRY AND THIS
BDY SUFFERED A
HORRENDOUS TRAGEDY.
ON
THAT DAY, CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS
WAS HOSTING A CONGRESS
ON THE
CORNER
GATHERING AT A
LOCAL SUPERMARKET
WHERE SHE MET
AND
CONVERSED DIRECTLY WITH
CONSTITUENTS.
DURING THAT EVENT, A
GUNMAN
SHOT AND
KILLED SIX PEOPLE
WHILE CRITICALLY
WOUND 13G
OTHERS,
INCLUDING CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS.
I AM HEARTENED TO
HEAR OF THE
AMAZING PROGRESS THE
CONGRESSWOMAN IS MAKING IN
HER
RECOVERY AND
OUR PRAYERS GO OUT
TO HER AND HER FAMILY.
SADLY, ON
THAT DAY, SIX PEOPLE
LOST
THEIR LIVES.
AMONG THE DEAD
WERE A
6-YEAR-OLD
GIRL, CHIEF JUDGE
JOHN ROWE
OF THE UNITED STATES
DISTRICT COURT OF
ARIZONA, AND
CONGRESSMAN
-- CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS' DIRECTOR OF
COMMUNITY
OUTREACH GABRIEL
ZIMMERMAN.
EARLIER THIS
YEARING, WE
HONORED CHIEF
JUDGE ROWE IN
NAMING A
COURTHOUSE AFTER HIM.
TODAY,
WE HONOR CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS' STAFFER
GABRIEL
ZIMMERMAN.
GABE
ZIMMERMAN WAS ONLY 30
YEARS OLD AND
ENGAGED TO BE
MARRIED WHEN HE WAS KILLED.
HE
GRADUATED FROM THE
UNIVERSITY
OF CALIFORNIA AT
SANTA
CRUZ IN 2002.
IN
2006, RECEIVED A MASTER'S
DEGREE IN SOCIAL
WORK FROM
ARIZONA
STATE UNIVERSITY.
PRIOR TO
JOINING CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS' STAFF,
HE WORKED AS A
SOCIAL
WORKERS ASSISTING
TROUBLED YOUTH.
GABE
ZIMMERMAN BEGAN HIS
CONGRESSIONAL CAREER IN
2007 AS
A
CONSTITUENT SERVICE
SUPERVISOR
FOR THEN
NEWLY-ELECTED CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS.
IN
THAT ROLE, HE
SUPERVISED HER
CONSTITUENT
SERVICES, OPERATION
--
AND WORKED DIRECTLY WITH THE
PEOPLE OF ARIZONA'S
EIGHTH
CONGRESSIONAL
DISTRICT.
HE WAS
LATER PROMOTED TO
DIRECTOR OF
COMMUNITY OUTREACH
WHERE HE
ORGANIZED HUNDREDS OF
EVENTS TO COORDINATE JUT REACH
TO CONSTITUENTS.
AS
THE
FIRST CONGRESSIONAL
STAFFER TO BE
MURDERED IN THE
PERFORMANCE OF HIS
OFFICIAL
DUTIES, THIS
RESOLUTION SEEKS
TO HONOR GABE
ZIMMERMAN'S
ULTIMATE
SACRIFICE TO THE
CITIZENS OF
OUR -- OF ARIZONA.
THIS IS ALSO A
GESTURE OF
SINCEREST
GRATITUDE FROM THE
MEMBERS OF THE
CHAMBER WHO RELY
ON
THEIR DEDICATED STAFF TO
HELP
THEM SERVE THE CITIZENS OF
THIS NATION.
I SUPPORT
THE PASSAGE OF THIS
RESOLUTION
AND URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO DO THE SAME.
I
RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLELADY FROM THE
DISTRICT OF
COLUMBIA.
MS. NORTON:
MADAM SPEAKER, I
YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME AS
I MAY
CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLELADY IS
RECOGNIZED.
MS. NORTON:
I WANT TO COMMEND
REPRESENTATIVE
WASSERMAN
SCHULTZ AND THE
BIPARTISAN
CO-SPONSORS
OF
HOUSE RESOLUTION
364.
I RECOGNIZE, MADAM SPEAKER
THAT
THIS IS
AN UNPRECEDENTED BILL,
BUT THE
BILL COMMEMORATES AN
UNPRECEDENTED
ACT.
THE SACK
-- SACRIFICE OF LIFE
OF THE
STAFFER OF ONE OF OUR
MEMBERS
, REPRESENTATIVE -- ONE
OF
OUR MEMBERS WHO HERSELF IS
STILL
RECOVERING FROM THAT
TRAGEDY, REPRESENTATIVE
GABE
RELL GIFFORDS.
-- GABRIELLE
GIFFORDS.
WE DO NOT
OFTEN HAVE
OPPORTUNITY TO SPEAK
ON THE
FLOOR OF
THE HOUSE OF OUR
STAFF, WHOSE
DUTIES ARE
PERFORMED ALMOST
ENTIRELY
BEHIND THE SCENES.
THE
TRAGEDY IN ARIZONA DOES
REMIND
US THAT STAFFERS ARE
OFTEN
EXPOSED AS MUCH AS
MEMBERS.
-- AS
MEMBERS TO HARM AND ARE
IN
HARM'S WAY.
THEREFORE, I THINK
IT ENTIRELY
APPROPRIATE
THAT WE COMMEMORATE
THIS LOSS
OF LIFE FIRST IN THE
-- THIS LOSS OF
LIFE, THE FIRST
IN THE HISTORY OF
CONGRESS, MY
BYNAMING A ROOM AFTER
GABRIEL
ZIMMERMAN
IN OUR VISITOR'S
CENTER AND
I ASK THAT MY
REMARKS BE PUT IN THE
RECORD
AND THAT
THERE BE UNANIMOUS
CONSENT
THAT THE BILL BE
MANAGED BY
ITS SPONSOR,
REPRESENTATIVE
GABBIE GIFFORDS.
I'M
SORRY.
REPRESENTATIVE WASSERMAN
SCHULTZ.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLELADY FROM FLORIDA WILL
CONTROL THE TIME.
MS. WASSERMAN SCHULTZ:
THANK
YOU.
MADAM SPEAKER, I YIELD SUCH
TIME AS
I MAY CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLELADY IS
RECOGNIZED.
MS. WASSERMAN SCHULTZ: I RISE
TODAY TO OFFER HOUSE
RESOLUTION
364, DESIGNATING
H.V.C. 215 OF
THE CAPITOL VISITORS
CENTER AS
THE
GABRIEL ZIMMERMAN MEETING
ROOM.
ON JANUARY 8, IN
TUCSON,
ARIZONA, TRAGEDY STRUCK THIS
COUNTRY IN A
SHOOTING THAT
SHOCKED OUR
NATION ANDER TO
THROUGH THE FABRIC
OF THE
CONGRESSIONAL
COMMUNITY.
SIX
PEOPLE DIED THAT HORRIFIC
DAY,
INCLUDING GABRIEL
ZIMMERMAN A CONGRESSIONAL
STAFFER FOR OUR
FRIEND AND
COLLEAGUE REPRESENTATIVE
GABRIELLE
GIFFORDS OF ARIZONA'S
EIGHTH CONGRESSIONAL
DISTRICT.
NOW LESS
THAN A YEAR AFTER THIS
HORRIBLE DAY,
IT IS FITTING
THAT THE UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES, THROUGH
PASSAGE OF THIS
RESOLUTION,
PROPERLY HONOR THE
SACRIFICE
AND SERVICE
OF
ONE OF OUR OWN.
GABE ZIMMERMAN
SERVED AS
COMMUNITY OUTREACH
DIRECTOR FOR
CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS.
HE WAS PERFECTLY SUITED FOR
THIS POSITION,
AS ANYONE WHO
KNEW
HIM WOULD TELL YOU.
THAT'S BECAUSE
WORKING AS
COMMUNITY OUTREACH
DIRECTOR
MARRIED TWO GREAT
PASSIONS IN
HIS LIFE,
HIS
DRIVE TO HELP
INDIVIDUALS
AND A FIRM
CONVICTION
THAT AMERICA'S
GOVERNMENT
NEEDED TO BE
OPEN,
ACCESSIBLE,
AND RESPONSIVE TO
EVERY AMERICAN.
ASK ANY MEMBER OF
CONGRESS HERE
WHAT IS ONE
OF THE
MOST
VALUABLE POSITIONS IN
THEIR
OFFICE, AND
THEY'LL TELL YOU IT
IS
OUR CONSTITUENT OUTREACH
DIRECTOR.
THEY LISTEN EACH AND EVERY DAY
TO THE
CONCERNS OF OUR
CONSTITUENTS,
THEIR PROBLEMS,
THEIR
SUGGESTIONS, THEIR
COMPLAINTS AND THEN THEY
WORK
TO HELP
THEM.
THE HOURS ARE
LONG.
NIGHTS AND WEEKENDS AT HOME
WITH FAMILY OR OUT
WITH FRIENDS
ARE OFTEN
SACRIFICED TO ATTEND
COMMUNITY MEETINGS.
EACH AND EVERY ONE OF US
HAVE
STAFF
MEMBERS WORKING FOR US
WHO SHOW SUCH
DEDICATION AND
THE
HALLWAYS OF THE CAPITOL
HAVE
ECHOED FOR TWO CENTURIES
WITH THE
HURRIED FOOTSTEPS OF
CONGRESSIONAL
STAFFERS
SERVING
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE THIS
RESOLUTION DESIGNATING THE
GABRIEL ZIMMERMAN
MEETING ROOM
IS NOT PUT
FORWARD TO MARK
GABE'S
DEATH BUT RATHER TO
RECOGNIZE
HIS COMMITMENT IN
LIFE TO
MAKING OTHER'S LIVES
BETTER.
ASK
THOSE WHO
KNEW HIM AND THEY
WILL
TELL YOU GABE HAD
A WAY
ABOUT HIM
THAT INVITED
CONVERSATION.
HE
COULD WALK INTO ANY ROOM AND
FIND A
WAY TO CONNECT TO
PEOPLE.
HE OFTEN PUT IN EXTRA
HOURS AND
WAS
OFTEN KNOWN TO PAY OUT OF
HIS OWN POCKET FOR
POOR
CONSTITUENT'S BUS
FARE.
GABE'S DEDICATION
AN
CHEERFULNESS HAD A
PROFOUND
EFFECT
ON THOSE WITH WHOM HE
CAME IN CONTACT.
DAYS AFTER THE
SHOOTING, WELL
AFTER
DARK, A GENTLEMAN CAME TO
REPRESENTATIVE
GIFFORDS' TUCSON
OFFICE, TEARS IN
HIS
EYES,
VISIBLY SHAKING
HE
EXPLAINED
THAT DAYS BEFORE, GABE HAD
TAKEN THE TIME SIT DOWN
WITH
HIM
AN EVEN THOUGH HE CAME IN
LATE IN THE DAY, HE
LISTENED TO
HIM,
TREATED HIM LIKE HUMAN
BEING AND
MADE IT CLEAR HE WAS
GOING
TO HELP HIM.
THE
GENTLEMAN COULDN'T BELIEVE
THAT SUCH A GOOD PERSON HAD
BEEN TAKEN SO YOUNG.
AMONG
HIS COLLEAGUES IN TUCSON,
GABE WAS
PROFOUNDLY WELL LIKE.
THEY
TOLD ME WHEN I
VISITTED
AFTER THE
SHOOTING THAT GABE
WAS
ALWAYS EXCITED TO
COME INTO
WORK
AND THAT HE CHERISHED THE
ABILITY TO WORK
FOR A MEMBER OF
CONGRESS
AND FOR
ONE HE SO
ADMIRED.
HIS
CO-WORKERS KIDINGLY CALLED
HIM PRINCE CHARMING BECAUSE HE
WAS ALWAYS THERE FOR
THEM,
ALWAYS READY
TO COME TO THEIR
RESCUE.
IN REPRESENTATIVE GIFFORDS,
GABE FOUND SOMEONE
FOR WHOM HE
CARED
DEEPLY AS A MENTOR, AS
HIS
BOSS, AS A FRIEND AND AS A
MEMBER OF CONGRESS
WHO SHARED
HIS PASSION
FOR SELFLESSLY
HELPING
OTHERS.
WHILE REPRESENTATIVE
GIFFORDS
COUNTED
ON HIM TO BE HER EYES
AN EARS
IN THE DISTRICT, HER
HUSBAND MARK SAYS
SHE LOOKED AT
HIM AS
A YOUNGER BROTHER.
TRAGICALLY,
THIS LOYAL,
DETERMINED, TALENTED PUBLIC
SERVANT, SOMEONE
WHO WAS A TRUE
APOSTLE OF
OUR REPRESENTATIVE
DEMOCRACY, UNKNOWINGLY ALSO
MADE THE
ULTIMATE SACRIFICE FOR
HIS
COUNTRY.
GABE ZIMMERMAN
IS THE
FIRST
CONGRESSIONAL STAFFER IN THE
HISTORY OF
THIS INSTITUTION TO
BE KILLED WHILE CARRYING OUT
HIS OFFICIAL DUTIES.
IT IS
IN THIS HISTORICAL AND
HALLOWED
MOMENT THAT WE VOTE ON
THIS
RESOLUTION TO NAME THE
CONGRESSIONAL MEETING ROOM
CURRENTLY KNOWN
AS H.V.C. 215
THE
GABRIEL ZIMMERMAN ROOM.
AS THOSE OF US
WHO WORK ON THE
HILL KNOW
WELL, H.V.C. 215 IS
FREQUENTLY
USED FOR STAFF
MEETINGS
OF EVERY VARIETY.
I CAN THINK
OF NO MET BETTER
WAY TO
MEMORIALIZE DWABE'S
SACRIFICE THAN TO HAVE THIS
MEETING
PLACE CARRY HIS NAME.
OVER THE
PAST FOUR MONTHS, A
BIPARTISAN GROUP OF
400 OF OUR
COLLEAGUES,
402 TO BE EXACT,
HAVE
SIGNED ON TO THIS
RESOLUTION IN
SOLIDARITY AS
CO-SPONSORS OF THE
RESOLUTION
HONORING
GABE'S SACRIFICE.
THIS MAKES THIS
RESOLUTION
AMONG JUST A SELECT
FEW PIECES
OF LEGISLATION
IN
HISTORY TO
HAVE GARNERED
SUCH
BROAD
SUPPORT IN THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
WITH THIS VOTE, WE HONOR THE
LIFE OF GABE
ZIMMERMAN AND ALSO
RECOGNIZE ALL CONGRESSIONAL
STAFFS WORKING IN
EVERY CORNER
OF OUR
GREAT NATION FOR THEIR
DEDICATION TO
CONGRESS AND THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE.
FROM
NOW ON, EACH TIME WE ENTER
THE
GABRIEL ZIMMERMAN MEETING
ROOM, LET US BE
REMINED OF GABE
AND
THE SERVICE AND SACRIFICE
OF
EVERY CONGRESSIONAL STAFFER.
I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO JOIN ME
IN
SUPPORT OF HOUSE RESOLUTION
364 AND
I RESERVE THE BALANCE
OF
MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLELADY
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM TENNESSEE.
MR.
FLEISCHMANN: MADAM SPEAKER,
I WISH TO YIELD
THREE MINUTES
TO THE
GENTLEMAN
FROM ARIZONA,
MR. IS
WEEK ERT WHO CO-AUTHORED
THIS IMPORTANT RESOLUTION.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR
THREE
MINUTES.
MR. IS
WEEK ERT: THANK YOU --
MR. IS WEEK
ERT: THANK YOU --
MR.
SCHWEIKE TRMBINGS: THANK
YOU.
I RISE IN SUPPORT OF THIS
RESOLUTION.
AS A MEMBER OF CONGRESS, EACH
OF US
CONSIDER YOU ARE OUR
STAFF
MORE THAN EMPLOYEES.
WE WORK WITH THEM.
THEY REPRESENT
OUR DISTRICTS.
BUT THEY ARE PART OF
OUR TEAM.
THEY ARE PART OF OUR
FAMILY.
AND THEY'RE ALSO
THE VOICE, THE
EYES
AND EARS IN OUR
COMMUNITIES.
THEY SOLVE
PROBLEMS AND THEY
WORK VERY LONG HOURS.
OFTEN
, AND I PARTICULARLY FEEL
BAD ABOUT
THIS, WE OFTEN FORGET
TO
SAY THANK YOU TO THOSE
SAFFERS -- STAFFERS.
TODAY WE SAY
THUNGE GABRIEL
ZIMMERMAN
WHO IS TRULY ONE OF
THESE
DEDICATED STAFFERS.
HE
HAD A GREAT REPUTATION OF
BEING ONE
OF THE MOST CARING
INDIVIDUALS
YOU COULD POSSIBLY
EVER MEET.
AND AFTER RECEIVING
HIS
MASTER'S DEGREE AT
ARIZONA
STATE
UNIVERSITY, A FINE
INSTITUTION,
HE CHOSE TO GIVE
BACK
TO ARIZONA AND GIVE BACK
TO THE COMMUNITY
IN SOUTHERN
ARIZONA.
MAKING OUR
STATE A BETTER
PLACE.
BUT
ON THE MORNING OF JANUARY 8
, HE
HAD ORGANIZED A
CONGRESSWOMAN
ON
THE CORNER
MEETING OUTSIDE
TUCSON.
SO CONSTITUENTS
COULD TALK AND
MEET WITH
CONGRESSWOMAN
GABRIELLE GIFFORDS.
REPRESENTING THAT
SATURDAY
MORNING IN SOUTHERN ARIZONA WAS
WHAT
DEMOCRACY IS ALL ABOUT.
IT IS
DEMOCRACY AT ITS FINEST.
THEN THE
UNIMAGINABLE HAPPENED.
GABE ZIMMERMAN IS
THE FIRST
CONGRESSIONAL
STAFFER TO LOSE
HIS LIFE
IN THE SERVICE OF THIS
HOUSE.
TODAY,
WE HONOR GABRIEL'S
TALENTS,
THE COMPASSION, AND
THE WONDERFUL
THINGS HE DID FOR
ARIZONA
, FOR SOUTHERN ARIZONA,
FOR THE
COMMUNITY, AND NAMING
SOMETHING AS SIMPLE
AS A ROOM
WILL NEVER
BE ENOUGH FOR HIS
SACRIFICE, BUT IT IS THE RIGHT
THING TO
DO, FOR GABE, FOR THE
THING
HE IS DID FOR ARIZONA,
THE
THING HE IS DID FOR
TUCSON,
AND ALSO
FOR THIS CONGRESSIONAL
FAMILY.
AND THINK
ABOUT THIS.
YEARS FROM NOW, THERE'LL BE
A YOUNG
STAFFER GETTING THEIR
FIRST
TOUR OF THIS BODY,
BUILDING, AND THEY'RE
GOING TO,
IN
THAT TOUR, COME ACROSS THE
GABRIEL
ZIMMERMAN ROOM AND WHEN
THEY READ ABOUT
IT, THEY'RE
GOING TO UNDERSTAND THE
SACRIFICE
THAT HE GAVE JUST
LIKE SO
MANY MEMBERS HERE GIVE,
BUT GABRIEL GAVE
THE ULTIMATE
SACRIFICE, HIS
LOVE AND HIS
TALENT
FOR THIS BODY AND FOR
THIS FAMILY.
MADAM SPEAKER, I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN
FROM ARIZONA YIELDS
BACK.
THE GENTLELADY FROM FLORIDA.
.
MS. WASSERMAN SCHULTZ: THANK
YOU.
IT'S NOW MY
PRIVILEGE TO YIELD
TWO
MINUTES TO A GOOD FRIEND OF
CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS AND A
WONDERFUL
REPRESENTATIVE OF THE
GREAT STATE OF
ARIZONA, MR.
GRIJALVA.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM ARIZONA IS
RECOGNIZED FOR TWO MINUTES.
MR.
GRIJALVA: THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
I RISE IN
SUPPORT
OF HOUSE
RESOLUTION
364 WHICH ENSHRINES
THE MEETING
ROOM IN THE VISITORS
CENTER IN
THE NAME OF GABE
ZIMMERMAN.
MY
COLLEAGUES HAVE RETOLD
THE
TRAGEDY THAT HAPPENED
IN
TUCSON
JANUARY.
THE DEATH,
THE INJURIES, AND AS
WE RECOVER
FROM THAT TRAUMA, LED
BY THE
COURAGE AND STRENGTH OF
CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS, THIS
MOMENT IS
AN IMPORTANT MOMENT AS
WE COMMEMORATE SACRIFICE
AND
HONOR
THE SERVICE OF GABE
ZIMMERMAN.
I WANT TO QUOTE
FROM WHAT -- A
STATEMENT THAT
HIS MOM MADE,
EMILY, AT
A PRESS CONFERENCE ON
JULY 20.
IT IS RIGHT
TO HONOR GABE HERE
AT THE
CAPITOL WHERE CONGRESS IS
CHARGED WITH
RESPONDING TO THE
NEEDS
OF THOSE PEOPLE WHO STOOD
IN THAT
LINE AT THAT GROCERY
STORE,
TO ALL AMERICANS BY
GRAFTING OUR NATION'S LAWS.
WHILE HE
WAS THE FIRST
CONGRESSIONAL STAFF PERSON IN
THE UNITED STATES
HISTORY TO BE
KILLED IN THE LINE OF DUTY,
IT'S
NOT HIS DEATH BUT
HIS WORK AND
HIS
IDEALS THAT SHOULD BE
RECOGNIZED HERE.
IDEALS SHARED BY THOUSANDS
OF
CONGRESSIONAL STAFF PEOPLE OVER
HUNDREDS OF YEARS
OF THIS
NATION'S HISTORY.
GABE
THOUGHT A LOT ABOUT AND
GUARD A LOT ABOUT THE
IMPORTANCE
OF CIVIC
ENGAGEMENT IN AN OPEN
AND CIVIL SOCIETY.
THAT
CONCEPT, THAT GOAL, WHICH
IS A
CORNERSTONE OF OUR
DEMOCRACY, CAN BE
REMEMBERED IN
THIS ROOM ALONG
WITH THE
IDEALISTIC YOUNG
MAN WHO DIED.
I THINK HIS
MOM SAID IT BEST.
SO AS
WE HONOR GABE, WE HONOR
THOSE STAFF
PEOPLE THAT WORK FOR
US,
THAT WILL MAKE -- SOMETIMES
MAKE US LOOK
BETTER THAN WE ARE.
TO
THOSE STAFF PEOPLE THAT WORK
FOR US
THAT SOMETIMES HAVE TO
DEAL
WITH THE
CONTROVERSIES THAT
WE CREATE.
AND
DOING -- IN DOING SO THEY
EXTEND
SERVICE AND SUPPORT TO
THE
PEOPLE THAT WE REPRESENT.
NO
FINER EXAMPLE THAN GABE
ZIMMERMAN AND
I'M HONORED TO
SUPPORT THIS
RESOLUTION AND
HONORED TO BE
FROM A COMMUNITY
THAT CAN
-- THAT GABE WAS FROM.
THANK YOU
SO MUCH.
I YIELD
BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN YIELDS BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM TENNESSEE.
&gt;&gt; I WISH TO
YIELD ONE MINUTE TO
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
ARIZONA, MR.
GOSAR.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM ARIZONA IS
RECOGNIZED FOR ONE MINUTE.
MR.
GOSAR: I STAND HERE TODAY
WITH MY COLLEAGUES TO
SUPPORT
THE DEDICATION OF A
MEETING ROOM
IN THE
CAPITOL VISITOR CENTER TO
GABE
ZIMMERMAN, A MAN KNOWN FOR
SPEAKING TO
BRING HEALTHY
POLITICAL
DISCOURSE THROUGH
CIVIL
SERVICE.
I WOULD FIRST
LIKE TO REAFFIRM
MY CONDOLENCES TO
GABE'S FAMILY
AND
LOVED ONES FOR THEIR LOSS.
HE WILL BE
MISSED.
BOTH
A DEVOTED CONGRESSIONAL
AIDE AND
COMMUNITY LEADER, GABE
SERVED
CONGRESSWOMAN GABBY
GIFFORDS'
DISTRICT WITH A SMILE
AND WILLINGNESS TO
GO ABOVE AND
BEYOND
IN ASSISTING BOTH HIS
OFFICE AND HIS FELLOW
CITIZENS.
WITH
AN EXTROVERTED PERSONALITY
AND DEEP
CONCERN FOR OTHERS'
WELL-BEING,
CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS HAS
NOTED THAT
ZIMMERMAN BECAME
THE GO-TO
PERSON
FOR CONSTITUENTS IN THE
DISTRICT.
HE WAS WHAT YOU CALL BACK
HOME,
GOOD PEOPLE.
WE CAN
ALL APPRECIATE AND LEARN
FROM GABE THAT REPRESENTING
OUR
CITIZENS MEANS
GOING BEYOND WHAT
IS ASKED
OF US TO
ASSIST THEM.
GABE
ZIMMERMAN LIVED THIS MANTRA
DAY BY
DAY.
IT IS WITH
GREAT RESPECT THAT I
SUPPORT
THIS BILL TO DEDICATE
THIS
PLACE OF MEETING TO HONOR A
MAN WHO LOST
HIS LIFE THROUGH A
SENSELESS ACT OF
VIOLENCE.
I JOIN THE
ARIZONA DELEGATION IN
HOPING HIS
SACRIFICE AND THE
PRINCIPLES
OF HIS PUBLIC SERVICE
ARE REMEMBERED AND
HONORED BY
ALL THOSE
THAT SEEK
TO MAKE OUR
NATION A BETTER
PLACE.
I YIELD BACK MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN YIELDS BACK OF THE THE
GENTLELADY FROM FLORIDA.
MS. WASSERMAN SCHULTZ: IT'S MY
PRIVILEGE TO
YIELD THREE
MINUTES
TO THE
DISTINGUISHED GENTLEMAN
FROM MARYLAND,
MR. HOYER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MARYLAND IS
RECOGNIZED FOR THREE MINUTES.
MR. HOYER: I THANK MY
FRIEND,
DEBBIE WASSERMAN SCHULTZ, ONE
OF
GABBY
GIFFORDS' CLOSEST FRIENDS.
ACKNOWLEDGE THE PRESENCE
OF HER
EXTRAORDINARY
STAFFER, GABBY
GIFFORDS'
LEADER ON HER STAFF.
WHO
HERSELF LOST A VALUED MEMBER
OF
HER STAFF AND GABBY'S STAFF.
MADAM SPEAKER,
ALL
OF US WHO
SERVE
IN THIS HOUSE KNOW THAT WE
COULD
NOT DO THE WORK WE DO
WITHOUT THE HELP
OF OUR
EXTRAORDINARILY ABLE
AND HIGHLY
MOTIVATED STAFF.
THEY
WORK LONG HOURS.
WITH PAY
BELOW THEIR
COUNTERPARTS IN THE
EXECUTIVE
BRANCH AND
THE PRIVATE SECTOR.
MANY
ARE YOUNG.
IN THEIR 20'S AND
30'S.
WITH AN ENERGY AND
PASSION FOR
PUBLIC SERVICE
THAT GIVE US ALL
GREAT HOPE FOR
THE FUTURE.
GABE
ZIMMERMAN WAS ONE OF THOSE
PASSIONATE AND
DEDICATED
STAFFERS.
WHO
LOVED HIS JOB, WHO LOVED HIS
FELLOW
STAFFERS, AND WHO LOVED
HIS CONGRESSWOMAN.
HE WAS WORKING
FOR A BELOVED
FRIEND AND COLLEAGUE
OF ALL OF
OURS,
CONGRESSWOMAN GABBY
GIFFORDS.
GABE
ZIMMERMAN WAS A BRIDGE
BETWEEN THE
CONGRESSWOMAN AND
INDIVIDUALS AND CONSTITUENT
GROUPS IN HER
DISTRICT.
FOSTERING AND
EXPANDING EACH DAY
THE
MOST IMPORTANT RELATIONSHIPS
A MEMBER OF CONGRESS MAINTAINS.
WITH
THEIR CONSTITUENTS.
WITH THE
PEOPLE WHO HAVE
ENTRUSTED THEM
WITH THE
RESPONSIBILITY OF
REPRESENTING
THEM
IN THIS GREAT BODY.
GABE ZIMMERMAN
WAS THE FIRST
CONGRESSIONAL STAFFER AS HAS
BEEN SAID A NUMBER
OF TIMES IN
HISTORY
TO LOSE HIS LIFE IN THE
LINE
OF DUTY.
IN
222 YEARS OF HISTORY OF THIS
BODY.
HE
LOST HIS LIFE
PROTECTING
,
PROMOTING
, AND DEFENDING
DEMOCRATCY.
GABE
ZIMMERMAN WAS NOT THE
OBJECT OF
ATTACK BUT A VICTIM.
ALONG WITH SIX OTHERS
OF A
ZPHESSIC TERRORIST
INTENT ON
ASSASSINATING
CONGRESSWOMAN --
DOMESTIC
TERRORIST INTENT ON
ASSASSINATING CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS AND
RANDOMLY KILLING
PEOPLE PARTICIPATING
IN ONE OF
DEMOCRACY'S MOST BASIC
ACTIVITIES, THE
DISCUSSION
BETWEEN
CONSTITUENTS AND THEIR
REPRESENTATIVE.
MEMBERS
OF MY OWN STAFF, AND I'M
SURE
THE MEMBERS OF THE STAFFS
OF EVERY
MEMBER HERE, WERE
PROFOUNDLY SHAKEN
BY THIS EVENT.
REALIZING
THAT IT COULD HAVE
BEEN THEM
OR INDEED ANY STAFFER
PARTICIPATING
WITH THEIR MEMBER
IN ANY
PUBLIC OR EVEN PRIVATE
EVENT.
IT IS
ENTIRELY FITTING,
THEREFORE,
THAT WE RENAME IN HIS
MEMORY
A ROOM WHERE EVERY DAY
MEMBERS
AND OUR STAFFS COME
TOGETHER TO FURTHER
THE
REPRESENTATION
OF THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
EVERY DAY
WHEN WE ENTER THAT
ROOM
WE WILL REMEMBER GABE
ZIMMERMAN.
GABE
ZIMMERMAN DIED
WHILE
SERVING HIS COUNTRY.
AND
WE HONOR HIM FOR THAT
SERVICE.
BUT LET ME
SAY TO EVERY STAFFER
WHO
SERVES WITH US.
BY DOING SO
WE HONOR YOU AS
WELL.
YOUR CONTRIBUTIONS
AND THE
CONTRIBUTIONS
OF ALL STAFF
WHO
LIKE GABE STRIVE TO MAKE
THIS
COUNTRY A
BETTER ONE FOR ALL
AMERICANS.
WE SEND
TO GABE'S PARENTS OUR
DEEPEST SYMPATHY
FOR A LOSS THAT
CANNOT
BE COMPENSATED, BUT TELL
THEM
THAT WE SHARE THEIR
EXTRAORDINARY PRIDE
IN THIS
AMERICAN HERO.
AND I YIELD BACK THE BALANCE
OF
MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM TENNESSEE.
MR.
FLEISCHMANN: MADAM SPEAKER,
I
WISH TO YIELD TWO MINUTES
TO
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
ARIZONA, MR.
QUAIL
-- QUAYLE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM ARIZONA IS
RECOGNIZED FOR TWO MINUTES.
MR. QUAYLE: I THANK THE
GENTLEMAN FOR YIELDING.
MADAM SPEAKER, I RISE TODAY IN
SUPPORT OF HOUSE RESOLUTION
364,
WHICH
WILL NAME HVC-215 AFTER
GABE
ZIMMERMAN.
JANUARY
8, 2011, WAS A DARK DAY
IN OUR
COUNTRY HISTORY.
SIX
OF OUR CITIZENS LOST THEIR
LIVES
AND CONGRESSWOMAN GIFFORDS
WERE SEVERELY
INJURED DURING A
SENSELESS ACT OF
VIOLENCE.
THERE IS NOTHING THIS
HOUSE CAN
DO TO EASE THE
PAIN OF THE
FAMILIES
AND FRIENDS WHO LOST
LOVED ONES THAT
DAY.
FOR THEM
TUCSON'S PAINFUL
MEMORIES
MAY NOT BE FULLY
RECEIVED.
BUT WHAT WE CAN DO IS CONTINUE
TO HONOR THOSE WE
LOST.
GABE
ZIMMERMAN, CHRISTINA TAYLOR
GREEN,
JOHN ROLL, DOROTHY
MORRIS,
PHYLLIS SCHNECK, AND
DOUGH LAN
STOODARD AND MAKE SURE
THEY ARE NEVER
FORGOTTEN.
THE LOSS
OF GABE ZIMMERMAN
AFFECTED
THIS BODY DEEPLY.
WE ALL KNOW STAFFERS
LIKE GABE,
TIRELESS
PUBLIC SERVANTS WHO
WORK LONG HOURS
AND WEEKENDS FOR
MODEST PAY.
CONGRESSIONAL OFFICE WOULDN'T
BE
ABLE TO FUNCTION
WITHOUT PEOPLE
LIKE GABE.
AND YET THEY RARELY
RECEIVE THE
CREDIT
THEY DESERVE.
SHORTLY
AFTER THE SHOOTING,
GABE'S FRIENDS
C.J. TOLD THE
&quot;LOS ANGELES TIMES&quot; ABOUT A
VISIT HE
AND GABE MADE TO THE
LINCOLN MEMORIAL.
HE SAID,
QUOTE, WHEN WE WENT TO
THE
LINCOLN MEMORIAL ON A COLD,
DAMP
JANUARY MORNING THE WIND
WHIPPED THROUGH THE
PLACE AND IT
WAS FREEZING
COLD, BUT GABE HAD
TO READ EVERY SINGLE
WORD OF THE
GETTYSBURG
ADDRESS, HE PUT HIS
ALL
INTO HIS WORK.
HE
PUT HIS ALL INTO HIS LIFE,
END
QUOTE.
MADAM SPEAKER,
GABE'S LIFE WAS
CUT TOO
SHORT, BUT HIS LIFE WILL
BE FOREVER
HONORED.
AND YEARS FROM
NOW WHEN YOUNG
INTERNS AND
STAFFERS
VISIT
HVC-215,
THEY WILL BE REMINDED
BY GABE
ZIMMERMAN'S STORY OF HIS
FASHION, HIS SERVICE TO
HIS
STATE,
AND COUNTRY, AND THE
EXAMPLE THAT HE SET.
I YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY FROM FLORIDA.
MS. WASSERMAN SCHULTZ: THANK
YOU, MADAM SPEAKER.
IT'S NOW MY
PRIVILEGE TO YIELD
TWO
MINUTES TO A
CLOSE FRIEND OF
CONGRESSWOMAN GIFFORDS AND
SOMEONE WHO
HE HAS STOOD BY, THE
GENTLEMAN FROM WASHINGTON, MR.
SMITH.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM WASHINGTON IS
RECOGNIZED FOR TWO MINUTES.
MR. SMITH: THANK
YOU, MADAM
SPEAKER.
I THANK THE LEADERSHIP OF THIS
HOUSE, BOTH DEMOCRAT AND
REPUBLICAN, AND ALL THE
CO-SPONSORS FOR
BRINGING THIS
RESOLUTION
BEFORE US AND
HONORING GABE
ZIMMERMAN BY
NAMING A ROOM IN THE
CAPITOL
VISITORS CENTER AFTER
HIM.
I CAN THINK
OF NOBODY WHO BETTER
PERSONIFIED THE IDEA
OF PUBLIC
SERVICE
THAN GABE ZIMMERMAN.
A LOT OF PEOPLE GET
INVOLVED IN
POLITICS FOR A LOT
OF DIFFERENT
REASONS, BUT I THINK THE
BASE
REASON THAT WE
ALL SHOULD WANT
TO BE
INVOLVED IN IT IS TO
REPRESENT PEOPLE.
AND WHEN YOU READ THE STORIES
ABOUT
GABE AND THE SERVICE
THAT
HE DID, EVEN
BEFORE HE WORKED
FOR
CONGRESSWOMAN GIFFORDS, YOU
CAN SEE SOMEONE
WHO TRULY
UNDERSTOOD WHAT IT MEANT
TO BE A
REPRESENTATIVE.
GABE MADE SO MUCH OF
HIS LIFE
ABOUT
CARING FOR OTHER PEOPLE.
AND THERE
CAN BE NO HIGHER
CALLING.
IN NAMING THIS ROOM AFTER HIM,
WE HAVE A PERMANENT
REMINDER TO
EVERYBODY WHO
COMES THROUGH THIS
CAPITOL ABOUT WHAT THIS
PLACE IS
ALL ABOUT.
IT'S ABOUT SERVING OUR PEOPLE.
IT'S ABOUT
PUBLIC SERVICE.
AND ON
THE BASE FUNDAMENTAL
LEVEL, GABE
UNDERSTOOD THAT TO
DO HIS
JOB RIGHT,
TO REPRESENT
HIS
DISTRICT, TO REPRESENT THIS
COUNTRY, HE
NEEDED TO MAKE SURE
THAT
EVERYBODY IN HIS DISTRICT
BELIEVED THAT THEY HAD
A VOICE
IN
CONGRESS.
AND THAT'S NOT
AN EASY THING TO
DO.
WE
REPRESENT, GOSH,
7PED
HUNDRED,000 PEOPLE.
BUT THERE --
700,000 PEOPLE, BUT
THERE
WAS NOBODY WHO GABE
WOULDN'T REACH OUT TO
AND LISTEN
TO.
I HAVE NO DOUBT THERE ARE
THOUSANDS IF NOT TENS OF
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE WHO HAVE
A
BETTER
APPRECIATION, WHO BELIEVE
MORE IN THEIR GOVERNMENT,
BECAUSE OF THE WORK THAT GABE
ZIMMERMAN
DID.
THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT WE NEED TO
BE
PERMANENTLY REMINDED OF.
BY NAMING
THIS ROOM AFTER HIM WE
WILL OFFER THAT OPPORTUNITY TO
EVERYBODY WHO COMES
TO THIS
CAPITOL.
I ALSO THINK IT IS
REFLECTIVE ON
CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS AS WELL.
GABE WORKED
FOR GABBY BECAUSE HE
BELIEVED IN HER AND
BELIEVED IN
WHAT
SHE WAS DOING.
AND
SHE, TOO, PERSONIFIES THAT
NOTION THAT
WE ARE HERE
TO
REPRESENT PEOPLE.
ALL OF THEM.
WHETHER
WE AGREE WITH THEM OR
NOT.
IT'S NOT JUST A MATTER OF
TAKING
THE
ONCE WE AGREE WITH.
YOU HAVE TO FIGHT
ALMOST EXTRA
HARD
FOR THE ONES YOU DON'T
AGREE WITH BECAUSE
THAT'S WHAT
MAKES REPRESENTATIVE DEMOCRACY
WORK.
BELIEVING IN THIS COUNTRY.
CONGRESSWOMAN GIFFORDS
AND HER
STAFF DO THAT AS WELL AS ANY
GROUP OF PEOPLE THAT
I HAVE EVER
ENCOUNTERED.
AND IT'S FITTING THAT
WE HONOR
GABE.
WE OFFER OUR
CONDOLENCES TO HIS
PARENTS.
THE ENCOURAGEMENT THAT HE
HAS
PERSONIFIED
THAT THIS
INSTITUTION IS ALL ABOUT.
WE WILL NEVER FORGET THAT.
THANK YOU.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM TENNESSEE.
MR. FLEISCHMANN:
MADAM SPEAKER,
MAY I
INQUIRE AS TO HOW MUCH
TIME I HAVE
REMAINING?
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM TENNESSEE HAS 10
1/2 MINUTES REMAINING.
THE GENTLELADY
FROM FLORIDA HAS
6 1/2
MINUTES
REMAINING.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
TENNESSEE.
MR. FLEISCHMANN:
THANK YOU,
MADAM SPEAKER.
MADAM SPEAKER, I WISH TO
YIELD
ONE MINUTE TO
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
ARIZONA, MR. FRANKS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM ARIZONA IS
RECOGNIZED FOR ONE MINUTE
.
MR.
FRANKS: MADAM SPEAKER, IT'S
HARD TO ADD
TO ALL OF THE THINGS
THAT
HAVE BEEN SAID
TODAY ABOUT
GABE
ZIMMERMAN, BUT I IDENTIFY
WITH EACH ONE OF
THEM.
I
WOULD SIMPLY SAY TO YOU,
THOUGH, I
NEVER MET GABE.
I DID HAVE
THE PRIVILEGE TO MEET
HIS LOVELY,
PRECIOUS FAMILY.
AND IT WAS
CLEAR TO ME THAT
EVERYONE WHO
KNEW GABE LOVED
HIM.
IF THEY KNEW HIM WELL, THEY
LOVED HIM
MORE.
HIS
SELFLESS SPIRIT OF SERVICE
IS
AN INSPIRATION TO ALL OF US
AND ALSO A REMINDER
OF HOW SHORT
OUR TIME HERE MAY
BE.
SO, MADAM CHAIRMAN,
I WANT TO
SUGGEST TO YOU THAT EVERYONE
IN
THIS PLACE SHOULD
EMBRACE THIS
BILL BECAUSE IT IS
A TESTAMENT
TO THE
NOBLE DEDICATION OF A
YOUNG
CONGRESSIONAL STAFFER WHO
LOST HIS LIFE IN THE
SERVICE OF
HIS COUNTRY.
AND I HAD
THE PRIVILEGE OF BEING
IN THE
ROOM WHEN THIS ROOM WAS
DEDICATED TO HIM AND
I HOPE THAT
ALL OF US
CAN EMBRACE THIS.
I URGE MY COLLEAGUES
TO VOTE YES
AND
HONOR GABE ZIMMERMAN AND THE
LEGACY OF SERVICE
THAT HE LEFT
BEHIND.
THANK YOU, MADAM SPEAKER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY FROM FLORIDA.
.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLELADY
FROM FLORIDA MS.
WASSERMAN SCHULTZ: I
YIELD ONE
MINUTE TO MR. PASTOR.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. PASTOR:
I RISE IN SUPPORT
OF THIS LEGISLATION
AND I TOO
WANT TO
THANK BOTH THE SPONSORS
OF THE
RESOLUTION, THE CO-SPON
ORS --
CO-SPONSORS AND THE
LEADERSHIP
ON THE REPUBLICAN
AND DEMOCRATIC
SIDE FOR
BRINGING THIS
RESOLUTION
BEFORE
US AND
HAVING IT TODAY.
I URGE
ALL MY COLLEAGUES TO
VOTE AYE.
IT'S A
TRIBUTE TO GABE
ZIMMERMAN WHO GAVE
HIS LIFE IN
TUCSON.
ALSO IT'S A TRIBUTE TO HIS
FAMILY.
HIS MOTHER
WAS A PUBLIC SERVANT
IN TUCSON, SHE
WORKED FOR MANY
YEARS IN THAT
COMMUNITY, SO HE
KNEW
WHAT PUBLIC SERVICE WAS
THROUGH HIS
FAMILY.
IT'S ALSO
A TRIBUTE AND A
RECOGNITION OF
THE SERVICE THAT
ALL PUBLIC
EMPLOYEES GIVE TO
OUR
COUNTRY AND MAKE -- IN
MAKING OUR LIFE
EVERY DAY A
LITTLE
BETTER.
SO MAY GABE REST
IN PEACE AND
MAY
WE CONTINUE TO GIVE THANKS
AND GRATITUDE
TO THE PUBLIC
SERVANTS WHO GIVE
QUALITY TO
OUR LIFE.
I YIELD BACK MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN YIELDS BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
TENNESSEE.
MR.
FLEISCHMANN: I WISH TO
YIELD TWO
MINUTES TO THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
TEXAS, MR.
OLSON.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR
TWO
MINUTES.
MR. OLSON:
MADAM SPEAKER,
THIS
IS
A SOMBER OCCASION.
BUT
I WANTED TO SPEAK IN
SUPPORT OF
CONGRESSIONAL ACTION
DEDICATING THE
ROOM IN THE
CAPITOL
VISITORS CENTER AS THE
GABRIEL
ZIMMERMAN MEETING ROOM.
GABE AND FIVE
OTHERS LOST THEIR
LIVES ON JANUARY
8 OF THIS YEAR
IN
A PARKING LOT IN TUCSON,
ARIZONA,
WHEN A DERANGED MAN
OPENED FIRE ON
INNOCENT PEOPLE.
GABE
WAS JUST DOING HIS JOB.
WHILE
I'VE NEVER HAD THE
PLEASURE TO MEET GABE,
I FEEL
LIKE I
KNOW A LOT ABOUT GABE.
HE
WORKED FOR GABBIE GIFFORDS,
A -- FOR
GABBIE GIFFORDS, WHO
HAS
BECOME A GOOD FRIENDS
THROUGH OUR WORK
ON THE SCIENCE
AND TECHNOLOGY
COMMITTEE IN THE
LAST
CONGRESS.
SHE
SHOWED ME SOMETHING RARE IN
WASHINGTON, TRUE
BIPARTISANSHIP.
IT
SAYS A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT
ABOUT
GABE THAT HE HAD HER
TRUST AND CONFIDENCE.
I ALSO
FEEL I KNOW GABE BECAUSE
LIKE
HIM, I WAS A CONGRESSIONAL
STAFFER.
I SERVED
IN THE OFFICES OF TWO
TEXAS
SENATORS, SENATOR PHIL
GRAMM AND
SENATOR JOHN CORNYN,
FOR NEARLY NINE YEARS.
THERE IS
NOTHING I WOULDN'T DO
TO
PROTECT MY BOSSES.
GABE
WAS PUT IN A POSITION THAT
NO CONGRESSIONAL
STAFFER IN
AMERICAN
HISTORY HAS FACED.
ASKED TO SACRIFICE
HIS LIFE FOR
HIS
BOSS AND INNOCENT PEOPLE.
WHEN SHOTS
RANG OUT, HE WAS IN
THE LINE
OF FIRE.
HE
DIDN'T RUN.
HE MADE
THE ULTIMATE SACRIFICE
AND
BECAME THE FIRST
CONGRESSIONAL
STAFFER TO GIVE
HIS LIFE IN
THE LINE OF DUTY.
ONE
FINAL COMMENT ABOUT GABE'S
COURAGE.
PRIOR TO MY
TIME AS A SENATE
STAFFER,
I SERVED FOR NEARLY 10
YEARS AS A
PILOT IN THE UNITED
STATES NAVY
.
OUR
MILITARY HEROES WHO LAY
DOWN
THEIR LIVES FOR THEIR
COMRADES ARE
CELEBRATED AND
REMEMBERED AN FITCH OUR
NATION'S
HIGHEST MILITARY
HONORS AND
ARE MEMORIALIZED IN
HISTORY.
WHILE
GABE ZIMMERMAN WAS NOT
WEARING A
UNIFORM WHEN HE DIED,
HE
DESERVES TO BE MEMORIALIZED
TODAY.
WE
DO SO TODAY
BY PERMANENTLY
AFFIXING HIS NAME ON
A PLAQUE
IN THE
CAPITOL VISITORS CENTER.
WE CAN
NEVER, EVER FORGET
GABE'S SACRIFICE
FOR THE UNITED
STATES OF
AMERICA AND BY
PASSING H.RES.
364, WE ENSURE
THAT GABE'S
SHORT LIFE IS
FOREVER
REMEMBERED, REVERED AND
IMMORTALIZED.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY FROM FLORIDA.
MS. WASSERMAN SCHULTZ:
THANK
YOU, MADAM SPEAKER.
IT'S MY PLEASURE TO YIELD
ONE
MINUTE TO THE
GENTLELADY FROM
CALIFORNIA, MS. SPEIER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLELADY IS
RECOGNIZED FOR
ONE
MINUTE.
MS. SPEIER:
THANK YOU, MADAM
SPEAKER.
I THANK THE AUTHOR OF
THIS
RESOLUTION FOR
GIVING US ALL
THE OPPORTUNITY
TO RECOGNIZE
GABE ZIMMERMAN
AND TO HONOR HIS
MEMORY
AND TO EXTEND TO HIS
FAMILY,
ROSS ZIMMERMAN, EMILY
NOTTINGHAM,
AND BEN ZIMMERMAN,
OUR GRATITUDE
FOR GIVING THEIR
SON
AND BROTHER IN SERVICE TO
THIS
COUNTRY.
WE'VE SAID IT
ALREADY,
GABE
ZIMMERMAN,
A YOUNG MAN A
PASSIONATE,
IDEALIZIST,
30-YEAR-OLD MAN,
ENGAGED TO BE
MARRIED TO
HIS BELOVED KELLY,
LOST HIS
LIFE IN A GUNFIRE
WHILE -- IN GUNFIRE
WHILE
ASSISTING HIS
CONGRESSWOMAN,
GABBIE GIFFORDS.
IN THE
ROUTINE COURSE OF
AFFAIRS IN THIS
HOUSE, OUR
STAFF MEMBERS OFTEN
SACRIFICE
THEIR PEACE
OF MIND IN SERVICE
TO THE
NEEDS OF OUR
CONSTITUENTS.
IN
MANY OF OUR HECTIC MOMENT
THEY SACRIFICE
THEIR FAMILY
TIME AND THE EVENTS
WITH
CHILDREN
THAT CREATE A LIFETIME
OF
MEMORIES.
GABE SEMI-ERMAN
LOVED HIS
MUSTN'T AND
HIS NATION
THAT HE
SERVED
-- ZIMMERMAN LOVED HIS
COMMUNITY AND HIS
NATION THAT
HE
SERVED AND IT IS APPROPRIATE
THAT
WE RECOGNIZE HIM AND
AFLICKS --
AFFIX A PLAQUE IN
HIS HONOR.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM TENNESSEE.
MR. FLEISCHMANN: I
YIELD TWO
MINUTES TO THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
TEXAS, MR. POE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR TWO
MINUTES.
MR. POE: I THANK THE GENTLEMAN
FOR
YIELDING.
GABE
ZIMMERMAN, I DIDN'T KNOW
HIM, BUT
I KNOW MANY PEOPLE
JUST LIKE HIM.
THEY ARE
CALLED THE
CONGRESSIONAL
STAFFERS.
GABE ZIMMERMAN
DEDICATED HIS
LIFE
TO PUBLIC SERVICE AND DIED
DEDICATING HIS LIFE
TO PUBLIC
SERVICE.
HE DIED FROM
AN ASSASSIN'S
BULLET IN
JANUARY OF THIS YEAR
HOSTING A CONGRESS
ON YOUR
CORNER
EVENT FOR GABBIE
GIFFORDS
WHICH HE ORGANIZED.
THERE ARE
MANY MEN AND WOMEN
JUST LIKE
GABE ZIMMERMAN WHO
COME
TO WORK EVERY
DAY AND WORK
IN
CONGRESS.
THESE
STAFFERS WORK VERY LONG
HOURS, SOMETIMES LATE
INTO THE
NIGHT, THEY WORK
WEEKENDS, THEY
DEAL
WITH PEOPLE FROM OUR
DISTRICTS, AND
SOMETIMES THEY
GET
LITTLE OR NO APPRECIATION
FOR THEIR
HARD WORK.
CONGRESSMAN
GIFFORDS IS BLESSED
TO HAVE
A WONDERFUL STAFF.
I HAD THE
PLEASURE TO BE WITH
HER LEGISLATIVE
DIRECTOR PETER
AMBLER AND
HER DIRECTOR OF
OPERATIONS
JENNIFER COX WHEN
THEY HOSTED ME AT THE
ARIZONA
BORDER SO
I COULD TALK TO
RANCHERS IN
ARIZONA.
THIS
OCCURRED AFTER GABBIE WAS
SHOT AND
WOUNDED.
I WAS
IMPRESSED WITH THESE
STAFFERS AND
THEIR WORK IN
KEEPING UP THE MISSION
OF OUR
FELLOW MEMBER OF
CONGRESS,
GABBIE GIFFORDS.
AS
SHE WAS RECOVERING FROM HER
WOUNDS.
THE ENERGY AND
DRIVE OF THESE
BRIGHT
AMERICANS REPRESENTS
REALLY ALL
THAT IS GOOD ABOUT
OUR COUNTRY.
SO ON
THIS DAY, IT IS GOOD THAT
MEMBERS OF
CONGRESS REMEMBER
AND
GIVE THANKS FOR
GABE
ZIMMERMAN, HIS
COLLEAGUES, AND
REPRESENT -- HIS
COLLEAGUES IN
REPRESENTATIVE GIFFORDS'
OFFICE, FOR
REPRESENTATIVE
GABBIE
GIFFORDS, AND ALL THE
MEN AND WOMEN
WHO ALLOW THIS
GREAT
BODY TO CONTINUE TO BE
THE PEOPLE'S HOUSE.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY FROM FLORIDA.
MS. WASSERMAN SCHULTZ: THANK
YOU, MADAM SPEAKER.
IT'S
MY PLEASURE TO YIELD ONE
MINUTE TO
A WOMAN WHO I
EXPERIENCED
AMONG THE MOST
EMOTIONAL
EXPERIENCES IN MY
LIFE, ALONG WITH
OUR COLLEAGUE
FROM
NEW YORK, REPRESENTATIVE
GILLIBRAND,
WHEN
WE WATCHED
REPRESENTATIVE GIFFORDS
OPEN
HER EYES
AFTER HER INJURY, THE
GENTLELADY FROM
CALIFORNIA, OUR
LEADER, NANCY
PELOSI.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLELADY IS
RECOGNIZED FOR
ONE
MINUTE.
MS. PELOSI:
THANK YOU, MADAM
SPEAKER.
I THANK
CONGRESSWOMAN WASSERMAN
SCHULTZ FOR TAKING THE
TIME
TODAY TO BRING THIS IMPORTANT
LEGISLATION TO THE FLOOR.
YES, WE
DID INDEED EXPERIENCE
AN
EMOTIONAL MOMENT TO SEE
GABBIE OPEN HER
EYES, BUT WE
ALL
EXPERIENCE AN EMOTIONAL
MOMENT HERE
ON AUGUST 1, WHEN
CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS CAME
BACK
TO THE FLOOR OF CONGRESS
TO CAST
A VOTE.
WITH
ALL THE SMILES THAT WE HAD
THAT DAY
, AND THE
HISTORY, WE
HAD
WITHIN US THE SORROW FOR
THOSE WHO LOST
THEIR LIVES
LAST
JANUARY.
UP WITH OF THOSE WAS GABE
ZIMMERMAN.
I'M
PLEASED AND SADDENED TO
COME TO THE FLOOR
TODAY TO JOIN
MY
COLLEAGUES, THANK YOU,
CONGRESSMAN
FLEISCHMANN,
CONGRESSWOMAN
WASSERMAN SCHULTZ
AND THE CONGRESSWOMAN FROM THE
DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA FOR THEIR
LEADERSHIP
HERE AND JOIN IN A
BIPARTISAN WAY, ESPECIALLY
WITH
THE
LEADERSHIP OF CONGRESSWOMAN
WASSERMAN SCHULTZ
AND THE
ARIZONA
DELEGATION IN A
BIPARTISAN
FASHION SPEAKING ON
BEHALF OF THIS
RESOLUTION.
AS HAS BEEN
MENTIONED, GABE
ZIMMERMAN AND
FIVE OTHERS WERE
TRAGICALLY TAKEN
FROM US ON
JANUARY
8 OF THIS YEAR IN THE
ATTACK
ON CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS.
ALL THE NATION WATCHED
AND
PRAYED
.
TODAY IN
PERMANENTLY NAMING A
ROOM
IN THE CAPITAL COMPLEX
AFTER GABE, WE HONOR
HIS LIFE.
AS
GABE'S MOTHER, EMILY NOTTING
MA'AM, SAID, IT'S NOT
GABE'S
DEATH BUT
HIS WORK AND HIS
IDEALS THAT
SHOULD BE
RECOGNIZED HERE.
GABE'S
IDEALS WERE ROOTED IN
SERVICE, HE HAD
WORKED AS HAS
BEEN
MENTIONED, AS A SOCIAL
WORKER,
ASSISTING TROUBLED
YOUTH,
SERVED ON THE BOARDS OF
SEVERAL COMMUNITY
ORGANIZATIONS
IN
DUESON AND ASSISTED THE
CONSTITUENTS
OF CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS.
THE WORK HE DID MADE
A
DIFFERENCE
TO VETERANS SEEKING
BENEFITS THEY WERE
OWED, TO
SENIORS WHO
HAD LOST THEIR
SOCIAL SECURITY CHECKS.
AS THIS RESOLUTION
NOTES, MORE
THAN
15,000 INDIVIDUALS SERVING
AS CONGRESSIONAL
STAFF AND
HONORING GABRIEL
ZIMMERMAN
TODAY.
WE RECOGNIZE ALL OF
THEM FOR
THEIR SERVICE.
I WANT TO
PARTICULARLY
ACKNOWLEDGE
PIA
CORAZON, THE
CHIEF OF
STAFF FOR
CONGRESSWOMAN
FWIFFEREDS FOR
HER
LEADERSHIP IN GUIDING
THE
STAFF THROUGH THIS
TRAGIC TIME
BUT NOT FOR ONE
MINUTE
DIMINISHING THE
CONCERN AND
SERVICE TO THE
PEOPLE OF THE
DISTRICT
THAT GABBIE GIFFORDS
REPRESENTS IN
TUCSON.
TODAY WE
PRAY FOR GABE'S
FAMILY, HIS
MOTHER EMILY, HIS
FATHER ROSS,
HIS STEPMOTHER
PAMELA,
HIS BROTHER DAN, HIS
FIANCEE
-- FIANCEE KELLY, AND I
HOPE
IT IS A COMFORT TO THEM TO
KNOW
THAT GABE WILL BE FOREVER
REMEMBERED HERE IN THE
CAPITOL
COMPLEX.
WHEN PEOPLE SEE THAT NAME, THAT
SIGNAGE, WHETHER
IT'S ABOVE THE
DOOR OR
DIRECTIONS TO IT, SOME
MAY ASK
THE QUESTION, WHO IS
GABE
ZIMMERMAN?
THEY
MAY NOT KNOW HIM BY NAME,
BUT
THEY KNOW HIM BY HIS
SACRIFICE.
AND
WE ALL HONOR THAT HERE
TODAY.
MAY
HE REST IN PEACE, MAY HIS
MEMORY
ALWAYS BE A BLESSING TO
US.
WE KNOW THAT IT IS,
BUT WE WANT
EVERYONE
ELSE TO KNOW IT AS
WELL.
WITH THAT, AGAIN, I
THANK
CONGRESSMAN
WASSERMAN SCHULTZ
FOR HER
LEADERSHIP,
PERSISTENCE,
DETERMINATION,
RELENTLESSNESS IN MAKING THIS
POSSIBLE IN HONORING
GABE.
WE
HONOR THE WORK OF ALL OF OUR
STAFF, PAST,
PRESENT, AND
FUTURE.
WITH THAT, MADAM SPEAKER,
I
YIELD BACK THE BALANCE
OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM TENNESSEE.
MR.
FLEISCHMANN: MAY I INQUIRE
HOW MUCH TIME
I HAVE LEFT?
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
TENNESSEE HAS
FIVE
AND A HALF MINUTES LEFT
THIS GENTLELADY
FROM FLORIDA
HAS 3
1/2 MINUTES LEFT.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
TENNESSEE.
MR.
FLEISCHMANN: I YIELD THREE
MINUTES TO THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
ARIZONA, MR. FLAKE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR
THREE MINUTES.
MR. FLAKE:
I THANK THE
GENTLEMAN FOR
YIELDING AND
THANK THOSE WHO BROUGHT
THIS
RESOLUTION TO THE
FLOOR,
PARTICULARLY
THE GENTLEWOMAN
FROM
FLORIDA AND THE HARD WORK
SHE PUT INTO
IT AND THE STAFF
OF GABBIE GIFFORDS
WORKING HARD
TO GET
THIS DONE AND FOR THE
FAMILY
OF GABE ZIMMERMAN TO
MAKE
SURE THIS CAME TO THE
FLOOR
TODAY.
I WAS FORTUNATE
ENOUGH TO BE IN
TUCSON A FEW
HOURS AFTER THE
SHOOTING AND WAS
WITH THOSE
ASSEMBLED
AT THE HOSPITAL, WITH
FRIENDS AND COMMUNITY
ACTIVISTS
AND
OTHERS WHEN IT WAS
CONFIRMED THAT
GABE ZIMMERMAN
HAD LOST
HIS LIFE.
I
WISH THAT ALL WITHIN THE
SOUND
OF MY VOICE TODAY COULD
FEEL
IN THAT ROOM AND THAT DAY
AND THE
DAYS THAT FOLLOWED THE
LOVE THAT
WAS FELT FOR THIS
GOOD
MAN, FOR THE WORK HE DID
FOR OUR
COLLEAGUE, FOR HOW MUCH
HE IS
LOVED THROUGHOUT THE
STATE OF
ARIZONA.
THE STATE
OF ARIZONA WILL NOT
FORGET
WHAT HE HAS DONE AND
WITH
THIS RESOLUTION TODAY,
WITH THIS
NAMING, WE ENSURE
THAT
THIS INSTITUTION DOES NOT
FORGET GABE AS WELL.
ALL
OF US AS MEMBERS OF
CONGRESS
HERE, TO HAVE A FLAK
OUTSIDE OF OUR OFFICE
THAT
DENOTES THAT WE
ARE SERVING THE
PEOPLE OF OUR
REPRESENTATIVE
STATES.
WHEN WE RETIRE
OR WHEN WE LEAVE
AFTER SERVING
HERE, WE WILL
TAKE THOSE PLAQUES
WITH
US.
MAYBE THEY'LL DECORATE
OUR
OFFICE AT HOME
OR OUR ROOM AT
HOME.
I THINK
IT IS
FITTING THAT THIS
FLAK WILL
REMAIN HERE FOREVER.
AND
WILL HONOR THE SERVICE OF
GABE
ZIMMERMAN AND ALSO THE
SERVICE OF MANY
STAFF WHO WORK
SO HARD,
THAT ARE OFTEN
FORGOTTEN AND NOT
APPRECIATED
FOR THE WORK THEY DO.
IT'S
AN HONOR TO BE HERE.
I
APPRECIATE AGAIN THOSE WHO
HAVE HELPED BRING
THIS
RESOLUTION TO THE
FLOOR,
PARTICULARLY
THE FAMILY OF GABE
ZIMMERMAN.
I HOPE THEY KNOW
HOW MUCH WE
APPRECIATE
THEIR
SACRIFICE, AND
GABE'S
SACRIFICE.
I YIELD
BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY FROM FLORIDA.
MS. WASSERMAN SCHULTZ: THANK
YOU, MADAM SPEAKER.
BEFORE I YIELD BACK,
I WANT TO
SHARE ONE
MORE STORY TO REALLY
DEMONSTRATE TO THE
ENTIRE
COUNTRY
THE HEART OF THE YOUNG
MAN
THAT WE'RE HONORING HERE
TODAY, BECAUSE EVEN THOSE WHO
ONLY
OCCASIONALLY CAME INTO
CONTACT
WITH GABE ZIMMERMAN
WERE
TOUCHED BY HIS PASSING
BECAUSE OF THE WAY
HE TREATED
THEM
IN LIFE THE WEEKS
FOLLOWING
GABE'S DEATH, THE
NIGHT SECURITY GUARD
CAME AND
KNOCKED ON THE
DOOR OF
CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS'
TUCSON
OFFICE.
HE WAS WORKING LATE
AND HER
STAFF
OPENED THE DOOR.
THE GUARD
CAME HOPE THAT THE
PERSON THAT
HE SO OFTEN TALKED
TO AT NIGHT
HADN'T REALLY BEEN
KILLED.
TEARING UP HE SAID HE
HADN'T
KNOWN GABE'S
NAME BUT SAID THAT
HE
OFTEN FOUND GABE WORKING
LATE AND THAT GABE
WOULD ASK
HIM ABOUT HIS
FAMILY OR HIS
WEEK OR JUST TALK
ABOUT SPORTS,
GABE ALWAYS
TREATED HIM WITH
DIGNITY, WHICH MEANT
SO MUCH TO
HIM, AND
THAT'S THE IMPORTANCE
OF THE LEGISLATION WE HAVE
IN
FRONT OF US
TODAY IS THAT
KNOWING THAT WE ARE
GOING TO
FOREVER DESIGNATE
H.V.C. 215 AS
THE
GABRIEL ZIMMERMAN MEETING
ROOM
SENDS A MESSAGE TO ALL OUR
STAFF AND
THE HEARTS OF ALL WHO
SERVE THAT WE
WILL HONOR THEIR
SERVICE, HONOR THEIR
COMMITMENT, HONOR
THEIR
WILLINGNESS TO
MAKE A PERSONAL
SACRIFICE, TO DEVOTE
THEIR
LIVES TO HELPING
OTHERS, THAT
WAS
THE EPITOME OF GABE ZIMMER
MAP, AND
I WANT TO CLOSE --
ZIMMERMAN, AND
I WANT TO CLOSE
BY
THANKING THE ENTIRE ARIZONA
DELEGATION,
PARTICULARLY MR.
FRANKS
AND MR. FLAKE AND MOST
ESPECIALLY
DAVE SCHWEIKERT WHO
HAD
SUCH COURAGE IN SPONSORING
THIS LEGISLATION
WITH ME,
WAS
PASSIONATELY
COMMITTED TO
GARNERING CO-SPONSORS FOR
IT
AND REALLY
WORKED INCREDIBLY
HARD TO
BRING IT
TO THE FLOOR
AND I WANT TO THANK THE
LEADERSHIP OF BOTH THE
DEMOCRATS
AND REPUBLICAN
MEMBERS
, THIS IS A VERY
CHALLENGING AND DIFFICULT TIME
FOR OUR
NATION, MADAM SPEAKER,
YOU
KNOW, IT'S MY HOPE THAT AS
HARD AS
IT IS AND AS HARD IT
HAS
BECOME FOR US TO ENGAGE IN
CIVIL DISCOURSE,
THAT WE REALLY
ALL REDOUBLE OUR
EFFORTS AS WE
HAVE
ALL PUBLICLY STATED THAT
WE'RE
WILLING AND INTERESTED IN
DOING, MYSELF
INCLUDED, TO MAKE
SURE THAT
WE CAN EARN THE
RESPECT
AND EARN EVERY DAY THE
PRIVILEGE THAT OUR
CONSTITUENTS
HAVE GIVEN
US TO REPRESENT THEM
HERE IN OUR
NATION'S CAPITOL
AND IN DOING SO
WE WILL HONOR
GABE'S
MEMORY, HONOR THE
SERVICE
OF OUR
COLLEAGUE AND
FRIEND GABRIELLE GIFFORDS
AND
KNOW THAT
GABRIEL ZIMMERMAN DID
NOT DIE IN
VAIN.
THANK YOU I YIELD
BACK THE
BALANCE OF OUR TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM FLORIDA YIELDS
BACK THE BALANCE OF
HER
TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM TENNESSEE.
MR.
FLEISCHMANN: I YIELD TWO
MINUTES
TO THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA, MR. PAULSEN.
MR.
PAULSEN: THANK YOU, MADAM
SPEAKER.
I WANT
TO THANK THOSE THAT PUT
THIS
RESOLUTION TOGETHER WHICH
IS SO
IMPORTANT.
I HAVE HAD
AN HONOR TO KNOW
GABBY
GIFFORDS SINCE 2005
BEFORE WE
EITHER WERE ELECTED.
I KNOW SHE WOULD WANT
TO BE ON
THE HOUSE
FLOOR TO HONOR THE
LIFE OF GABE ZIMMERMAN.
HER DIRECTOR OF
COMMUNITY
OUTREACH WHO
LOST HIS LIFE IN
THAT SENSELESS
ATTACK ON
JANUARY
8.
AS A
FORMER STAFFER, MYSELF, I
KNOW
FIRSTHAND THAT WORKING FOR
A MEMBER OF CONGRESS
ISN'T LIKE
MOST
JOBS.
YOU RARELY
GO HOME AT 5:00 OR
6:00.
YOU WORK LONG HOURS.
I
TYPICALLY DO NOT HAVE
WEEKENDS
OFF.
BUT TO THOSE
STAFF WHO WORK FOR
ALL OF US,
EVERY ONE OF THE
HOUSE
MEMBERS, REWARD -- THE
REWARD COMES FROM
WORKING FOR
CONSTITUENTS
ON BEHALF
OF OUR
DISTRICTS,
OUR STATES AND OUR
GREAT COUNTRY.
AND ALL
OF OUR STAFF ARE
EXTENSIONS OF THE MEMBERS
THAT
THEY WORK
FOR.
GABBY'S STAFF
IS CERTAINLY
REFLECTION OF WHO SHE IS, A
LOYAL,
DEDICATED PUBLIC
SERVANT.
AND
GABE ZIMMERMAN IS NO
DIFFERENT.
I DIDN'T KNOW HIM, BUT I
DO
KNOW THAT HE
CARED FOR HIS
COMMUNITY, HE CARED
FOR HIS
COUNTRY, GABE WAS A
PASSIONATE
ADVOCATE FOR
CHILDREN, FOR
SOCIAL
JUSTICE, FOR
ANTI-RACISM.
AND GABE
DIDN'T WEAR THE
UNIFORM OF
A SOLDIER OR POLICE
OFFICER
BUT HE DID GIVE
HIS
LIFE WHILE SERVING
HIS COUNTRY.
SO IT IS ABSOLUTELY
FITTING
THAT INSIDE THE CONGRESSIONAL
VISITOR CENTER
WHERE THOUSANDS
OF
PEOPLE VISIT EVERY YEAR, A
ROOM WILL
BEAR GABE ZIMMERMAN'S
NAME
IN HIS HONOR.
I HOPE
THAT THIS DEDICATION
WILL
ALSO SERVE AS A
REMINDER
TO ALL OF
US OF THE PASSION AND
THE LOYALTY AND
THAT DEAD CAGE
THAT GABE
SHOWED EVERY DAY AS A
CONGRESSIONAL
STAFFER.
SO MY THOUGHTS CONTINUE
TO BE
WITH
GABE'S FAMILY, WITH GABBY
AND HER
HUSBAND, MARK, AND WITH
ALL OF
GABBY'S STAFF WHO HAVE A
CONSTANT REMINDER OF
HOW
VALUABLE
LIFE REALLY IS.
I
YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN YIELDS BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM TENNESSEE.
MR. FLEISCHMANN:
MADAM SPEAKER,
IN
CLOSING I WISH TO THANK
CONGRESSMAN
SCHWEIKERT,
CONGRESSWOMAN
WASSERMAN SCHULTZ
FOR
THEIR CO-AUTHORSHIP OF THIS
VERY, VERY IMPORTANT
LEGISLATION, HONORING
GABE
ZIMMERMAN.
I WANT TO THANK
THE ENTIRE
ARIZONA DELEGATION FOR
ALL
THEIR TIRELESS
EFFORTS IN THIS
REGARD
.
AND I
ALSO WISH TO URGE ALL OF
MY
COLLEAGUES IN THIS GREAT
HOUSE,
THE PEOPLE'S HOUSE, TO
SUPPORT THIS BILL LATER
TODAY.
WITH
THAT I YIELD BACK.
THANK YOU.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN YIELDS BACK THE
BALANCE OF HIS TIME.
AND THE QUESTION IS WILL THE
HOUSE
SUSPEND THE RULES AND
AGREE TO HOUSE
RESOLUTION
364.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED WILL
SAY NO.
IN THE OPINION OF THE CHAIR,
2/3 HAVING RESPONDED IN THE
AFFIRMATIVE, THE RULES ARE
SUSPENDED, THE
RESOLUTION --
MS. WASSERMAN SCHULTZ: MADAM
SPEAKER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY FROM FLORIDA.
MS. WASSERMAN SCHULTZ: WITH
THAT I REQUEST THE YEAS AND
NAYS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
YEAS AND NAYS ARE
REQUESTED,
AND ALL THOSE IN FAVOR OF
TAKING THIS VOTE BY THE
YEAS
AND NAYS
WILL RISE AND REMAIN
STANDING UNTIL COUNTED.
A SUFFICIENT NUMBER HAVING
ARISEN, THE YEAS AND NAYS ARE
ORDERED.
AND
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 8 OF
RULE 20, FURTHER PROCEEDINGS ON
THIS QUESTION
WILL BE
POSTPONED.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM GEORGIA SEEK RECOGNITION?
MR. WOODALL:
MADAM SPEAKER, BY
THE DIRECTION OF THE COMMITTEE
ON RULES, I CALL UP HOUSE
RESOLUTION
477 AND ASK
FOR ITS
IMMEDIATE CONSIDERATION.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: AND
THE CLERK WILL REPORT THE
RESOLUTION.
THE CLERK: HOUSE
CALENDAR
NUMBER
94, HOUSE RESOLUTION
477.
RESOLVED, THAT UPON THE
ADOPTION OF THIS RESOLUTION IT
SHALL BE IN ORDER TO CONSIDER
IN THE HOUSE THE BILL H.R.
3463, TO REDUCE FEDERAL
SPENDING AND THE DEFICIT BY
TERMINATING TAXPAYER FINANCING
OF PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION
CAMPAIGNS AND PARTY CONVENTIONS
AND BY TERMINATING THE ELECTION
ASSISTANCE COMMISSION.
ALL POINTS OF ORDER AGAINST.
-- AGAINST
CONSIDERATION OF THE
BILL ARE
WAIVED.
THE BILL SHALL BE CONSIDERED AS
READ.
ALL POINTS OF ORDER AGAINST
PROVISIONS IN THE BILL ARE
WAIVED.
THE PREVIOUS QUESTION SHALL BE
CONSIDERED AS ORDERED ON THE
BILL AND ANY AMENDMENT THERETO
TO FINAL PASSAGE WITHOUT
INTERVENING MOTION EXCEPT, ONE,
ONE HOUR OF DEBATE EQUALLY
DIVIDED AND CONTROLLED BY THE
CHAIR AND RANKING MINORITY
MEMBER OF THE COMMITTEE ON
HOUSE ADMINISTRATION, AND TWO,
ONE MOTION TO RECOMMIT.
SECTION 2, AT ANY TIME AFTER
THE ADOPTION OF THIS RESOLUTION
THE SPEAKER MAY, PURSUANT TO
CLAUSE 2-B OF RULE 18, DECLARE
THE HOUSE RESOLVED INTO THE
COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE HOUSE ON
THE STATE OF THE UNION FOR
CONSIDERATION OF THE BILL H.R.
527. TO AMEND CHAPTER 6 OF
TITLE 5, UNITED STATES CODE,
COMMONLY KNOWN AS THE
REGULATORY FLEXIBILITY ACT, TO
ENSURE COMPLETE ANALYSIS OF
POTENTIAL IMPACTS ON SMALL
ENTITIES OF RULES, AND FOR
OTHER
PURPOSES.
THE FIRST
READING OF THE BILL
SHALL BE
DISPENSED WITH.
ALL POINTS OF ORDER AGAINST
CONSIDERATION OF THE BILL ARE
WAIVED.
GENERAL DEBATE SHALL BE
CONFINED TO THE BILL AND SHALL
NOT EXCEED ONE HOUR, WITH 40
MINUTES EQUALLY DIVIDED AND
CONTROLLED BY THE CHAIR AND
RANKING MINORITY MEMBER OF THE
COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY AND
20 MINUTES EQUALLY DIVIDED AND
CONTROLLED BY THE CHAIR AND
RANKING MINORITY MEMBER OF THE
COMMITTEE ON SMALL BUSINESS.
AFTER GENERAL DEBATE THE BILL
SHALL BE CONSIDERED FOR
AMENDMENT UNDER THE FIVE MINUTE
RULE.
IN LIEU OF THE AMENDMENTS IN
THE NATURE OF A SUBSTITUTE
RECOMMENDED BY THE COMMITTEES
ON THE JUDICIARY AND SMALL
BUSINESS NOW PRINTED IN THE
BILL, IT SHALL BE IN ORDER TO
CONSIDER AS AN ORIGINAL BILL
FOR THE PURPOSE OF AMENDMENT
UNDER
THE FIVE-MINUTE RULE AN
AMENDMENT IN THE NATURE OF A
SUBSTITUTE CONSISTING OF THE
TEXT OF THE RULES COMMITTEE
PRINT DATED NOVEMBER 18, 2011.
THAT AMENDMENT IN THE NATURE OF
A SUBSTITUTE SHALL BE
CONSIDERED AS READ.
ALL POINTS OF ORDER AGAINST
THAT AMENDMENT IN THE NATURE OF
A SUBSTITUTE ARE WAIVED.
NO AMENDMENT TO THAT AMENDMENT
IN THE NATURE OF A SUBSTITUTE
SHALL BE IN ORDER EXCEPT THOSE
PRINTED IN PART A OF THE REPORT
OF THE COMMITTEE ON RULES
ACCOMPANYING THIS RESOLUTION.
EACH SUCH AMENDMENT MAY BE
OFFERED ONLY IN THE ORDER
PRINTED IN THE REPORT, MAY BE
OFFERED ONLY BY A MEMBER
DESIGNATED IN THE REPORT, SHALL
BE CONSIDERED AS READ, SHALL BE
DEBATABLE FOR THE TIME
SPECIFIED IN THE REPORT EQUALLY
DIVIDED AND CONTROLLED BY THE
PROPONENT AND AN OPPONENT,
SHALL NOT BE SUBJECT TO
AMENDMENT, AND SHALL NOT BE
SUBJECT TO A DEMAND FOR
DIVISION OF THE QUESTION IN THE
HOUSE OR IN THE COMMITTEE OF
THE WHOLE.
ALL POINTS OF ORDER AGAINST
SUCH AMENDMENTS ARE WAIVED.
AT THE CONCLUSION OF
CONSIDERATION OF THE BILL FOR
AMENDMENT THE COMMITTEE SHALL
RISE AND REPORT THE BILL TO THE
HOUSE WITH SUCH AMENDMENTS AS
MAY HAVE BEEN ADOPTED.
ANY MEMBER MAY DEMAND A
SEPARATE VOTE IN THE HOUSE ON
ANY AMENDMENT ADOPTED IN THE
COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE TO THE
BILL OR TO THE AMENDMENT IN THE
NATURE OF A SUBSTITUTE MADE IN
ORDER AS ORIGINAL TEXT.
THE PREVIOUS QUESTION SHALL BE
CONSIDERED AS ORDERED ON THE
BILL AND AMENDMENTS THERETO TO
FINAL PASSAGE WITHOUT
INTERVENING MOTION EXCEPT ONE
MOTION TO RECOMMIT WITH OR
WITHOUT INSTRUCTIONS.
SECTION 3, AT ANY TIME AFTER
THE ADOPTION OF THIS RESOLUTION
THE SPEAKER MAY, PURSUANT TO
CLAUSE 2-B OF RULE 18, DECLARE
THE HOUSE RESOLVED INTO THE
COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE HOUSE ON
THE STATE OF THE UNION FOR
CONSIDERATION OF THE BILL H.R.
3010, TO REFORM THE PROCESS BY
WHICH FEDERAL AGENCIES ANALYZE
AND FORMULATE NEW REGULATIONS
AND GUIDANCE
DOCUMENTS.
THE
FIRST READING OF THE BILL
SHALL
BE DISPENSED WITH.
ALL POINTS OF ORDER AGAINST
CONSIDERATION OF THE BILL ARE
WAIVED.
GENERAL DEBATE SHALL BE
CONFINED TO THE BILL AND SHALL
NOT EXCEED ONE HOUR EQUALLY
DIVIDED AND CONTROLLED BY THE
CHAIR AND RANKING MINORITY
MEMBER OF THE COMMITTEE ON THE
JUDICIARY.
AFTER GENERAL DEBATE THE BILL
SHALL BE CONSIDERED FOR
AMENDMENT UNDER THE FIVE-MINUTE
RULE.
IT SHALL BE IN ORDER TO
CONSIDER AS AN ORIGINAL BILL
FOR THE PURPOSE OF AMENDMENT
UNDER THE FIVE-MINUTE RULE THE
AMENDMENT IN THE NATURE OF A
SUBSTITUTE RECOMMENDED BY THE
COMMITTEE ON THE JUDICIARY NOW
PRINTED IN THE BILL.
THE COMMITTEE AMENDMENT IN THE
NATURE OF A SUBSTITUTE SHALL BE
CONSIDERED AS READ.
ALL POINTS OF ORDER AGAINST THE
COMMITTEE AMENDMENT IN THE
NATURE OF A SUBSTITUTE ARE
WAIVED.
NO AMENDMENT TO THE COMMITTEE
AMENDMENT IN THE NATURE OF A
SUBSTITUTE SHALL BE IN ORDER
EXCEPT THOSE PRINTED IN PART B
OF THE REPORT OF THE COMMITTEE
ON RULES ACCOMPANYING THIS
RESOLUTION.
EACH SUCH AMENDMENT MAY BE
OFFERED ONLY IN THE ORDER
PRINTED IN THE REPORT, MAY BE
OFFERED ONLY BY A MEMBER
DESIGNATED IN THE REPORT, SHALL
BE CONSIDERED AS READ, SHALL BE
DEBATABLE FOR THE TIME
SPECIFIED IN THE REPORT EQUALLY
DIVIDED AND CONTROLLED BY THE
PROPONENT AND AN OPPONENT,
SHALL NOT BE SUBJECT TO
AMENDMENT, AND SHALL NOT BE
SUBJECT TO A DEMAND FOR
DIVISION OF THE QUESTION IN THE
HOUSE OR IN THE COMMITTEE OF
THE WHOLE.
ALL POINTS OF ORDER AGAINST
SUCH AMENDMENTS ARE WAIVED.
AT THE CONCLUSION OF
CONSIDERATION OF THE BILL FOR
AMENDMENT THE COMMITTEE SHALL
RISE AND REPORT THE BILL TO THE
HOUSE WITH SUCH AMENDMENTS AS
MAY HAVE BEEN ADOPTED.
ANY MEMBER MAY DEMAND A
SEPARATE VOTE IN THE HOUSE ON
ANY AMENDMENT ADOPTED IN THE
COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE TO THE
BILL OR TO THE COMMITTEE
AMENDMENT IN THE NATURE OF A
SUBSTITUTE.
THE PREVIOUS QUESTION SHALL BE
CONSIDERED AS ORDERED ON THE
BILL AND AMENDMENTS THERETO TO
FINAL PASSAGE WITHOUT
INTERVENING MOTION EXCEPT ONE
MOTION TO RECOMMIT WITH OR
WITHOUT INSTRUCTIONS.
SECTION 4, IT SHALL BE IN ORDER
AT ANY TIME THROUGH THE
LEGISLATIVE DAY OF DECEMBER 2,
2011, FOR THE SPEAKER TO
ENTERTAIN MOTIONS THAT THE
HOUSE SUSPEND THE RULES, AS
THOUGH UNDER CLAUSE 1-C OF RULE
15, RELATING TO A MEASURE
ADDRESSING RAILWAY LABOR.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM GEORGIA IS
RECOGNIZED FOR ONE HOUR.
MR. WOODALL:
THANK YOU, MADAM
SPEAKER.
FOR THE PURPOSE OF DEBATE
ONLY,
I'D LIKE TO
YIELD THE CUSTOMARY
30 MINUTES TO
MY FRIEND FROM
MASSACHUSETTS, MR.
MCGOVERN,
PENDING WHICH
I YIELD MYSELF
SUCH TIME AS I MAY CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. WOODALL: DURING
CONSIDERATION OF THIS
RESOLUTION, MADAM SPEAKER, ALL
TIME IS YIELDED FOR THE PURPOSE
OF DEBATE ONLY,
AND I ASK
UNANIMOUS CONSENT THAT ALL
MEMBERS MAY HAVE FIVE
LEGISLATIVE DAYS TO REVISE AND
EXTEND THEIR REMARKS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION.
MR. WOODALL:
MADAM SPEAKER,
HOUSE RESOLUTION 477 IS A
STRUCTURED RULE FOR THE
CONSIDERATION
OF THREE BILLS.
H.R.
527, THE REGULATORY
FLEXIBILITY
ACT, H.R. 3010, THE
REGULATORY ACCOUNTABILITY
ACT
AND H.R.
3463,
A MEASURE TO
REDUCE FEDERAL SPENDING AND THE
DEFICIT BY
TERMINATING TAXPAYER
FINANCING
OF PRESIDENTIAL
ELECTION
CAMPAIGNS.
IT
DEMANDS THAT AGENCY
RULEMAKING BE
HELD ACCOUNTABLE.
RECLAIMING
THAT AUTHORITY THAT
IS
VESTED HERE IN THIS HOUSE.
H.R.
527, THE REGULATORY
FLEXIBILITY ACT,
REQUIRES
AGENCIES TO
ANALYZE THE IMPACT
THAT A
NEW REGULATION WOULD
HAVE ON
SMALL BUSINESSES BEFORE
THE REGULATION IS
ADOPTED BY
REQUIRING ALL FEDERAL
AGENCIES
TO
OBTAIN INPUT AND DEVELOP AND
CONDUCT REGULAR
REGULATORY
REVIEWS
OF EXISTING
REGULATIONS, THIS
BILL, I
BELIEVE, COMPLEMENTS AND
CODIFIES PRESIDENT
BARACK
OBAMA'S
COMMITMENT IN EXECUTIVE
ORDER
15563 WHICH SOLICITS
PUBLIC
INPUT.
H.R.
3010, THE REGULATORY
ACCOUNTABILITY
ACT, MAKES
FURTHER POSITIVE
CHANGES.
IT
REFORMS AND MODERNIZES THE
PROCEDURES ACT.
IT MAKES AGENCIES
MORE
ACCOUNTABLE AND
REGULATIONS
MORE COST-EFFECTIVE,
AND A
RECENT
STUDY, MADAM SPEAKER,
THAT THE
SMALL BUSINESS
ADMINISTRATION
COMMISSIONED,
THEY
ESTIMATED HAT COST
OF THE
U.S.
FEDERAL REGULATORY BURDEN
HIT
$1.75 TRILLION.
THAT'S NOT TO
SAY THERE AREN'T
BENEFITS THAT OUTWEIGH
THAT
BURDEN.
BUT
WHEN THE BURDEN IS THAT
SUBSTANTIAL,
WE HAVE TO HAVE A
PROCESS IN PLACE THAT
BALANCES
THOSE
BENEFITS AND BURDENS.
THAT'S
ALL H.R. 3010 ASKS TO
DO.
TIME AND TIME
AGAIN, THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE HAVE DEMANDED
MORE ACCOUNTABLE FROM
THEIR
CONGRESS.
MORE
ACCOUNTABILITY FROM THEIR
GOVERNMENT.
THIS COLLECTION OF BILLS TODAY
NOT ONLY
PROVIDES THAT
ACCOUNTABILITY TO
CONGRESS BUT
REQUIRES THAT
ACCOUNTABILITY OF
OUR EXECUTIVE
BRANCH AGENCIES.
AS
WE TALK ABOUT
ACCOUNTABILITY, MADAM SPEAKER,
IT IS IMPORTANT TO
NOTE THAT
THESE BILLS ARE
PAID FOR BY
TERMINATING THE
ELECTION
ASSISTANCE COMMISSION.
YOU'LL
REMEMBER, MADAM SPEAKER,
THAT WAS A
COMMISSION CREATED
IN 2002
THAT WAS
SUPPOSED TO
SUNSET BY 2005.
AND
YET HAS CONTINUED EVEN
UNTIL TODAY.
THAT COMMISSION WAS
SET UP IN
THE
AFTERMATH OF THE HANGING
CHADS OF
OF THE 2000
PRESIDENTIAL
ELECTION TO HELP
STATES IMPLEMENT ELECTION
REFORMS, TO HELP
STATES MAKE
SURE THE INTEGRITY OF
THEIR
ELECTORAL PROCESS
WAS
PRESERVED.
AND YET TODAY,
SIX YEARS AFTER
THE EXPECTED
SUNSET OF THAT
COMMISSION, WE
HEAR FROM OUR
STATE
SECRETARIES OF STATE THAT
THEY NO
LONGER NEED THAT
COMMISSION.
THAT THAT COMMISSION IS NOT
PROVIDING
USEFUL BENEFITS TO
THEM.
BY TERMINATING
THAT, WE'LL SAVE
THE AMERICAN
TAXPAYER MORE THAN
$600 MILLION
OVER THE NEXT
DECADE.
MADAM SPEAKER, TAKEN TOGETHER,
THESE THREE
MEASURES,
H.R. 527,
H.R.
3010, AND H.R. 3463 HELP
SMALL
BUSINESSES INCREASE AGENT
--
HELP SMALL BUSINESSES,
INCREASE
AGENCY TRANSPARENCY,
AND
INCREASE PUBLIC
PARTICIPATION IN THE
ENTIRE
REGULATORY
PROCESS.
THEY SAVE MONEY
FOR HARDWORKING
AMERICAN TAXPAYERS
AND ARE
POSITIVE
REFORMS THAT THIS
CONGRESS
CAN PASS IN A
BIPARTISAN WAY.
I
HOPE THAT MY COLLEAGUES ON
BOTH SIDES OF
THE AISLE WILL
SUPPORT THESE
UNDERLYING
MEASURES AND
I HOPE THEY'LL
SUPPORT THIS RULE SO
WE MAY
CONSIDER THEM TODAY.
WITH THAT, I
RESERVE THE
BALANCE OF
MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MASSACHUSETTS.
MR. MCGOVERN: THANK YOU, MADAM
SPEAKER.
I THANK MY FRIEND FROM FWEA FOR
YIELDING
ME THE CUSTOMARY 30
MINUTES.
I YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME AS
I
MAY CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION E, THE
GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. MCGOVERN: I
RISE IN STRONG
OPPOSITION TO THIS
RESTRICTIVE
RULE AND
-- NOT ONLY
RESTRICTIVE, BUT
VERY
CONVOLUTED RULE.
AND I RISE IN OPPOSITION TO THE
THREE BILLS THAT WOULD BE
MADE
IN ORDER
BY THIS RULE.
REGULATORY
UNCERTAINTY IS
SOMETHING INVENTED BY
REPUBLICANS THAT
ALLOWS THEM TO
USE
CURRENT ECONOMIC PROBLEMS
TO PURSUE
AN AGENDA SUPPORTED
BY
THE BIG BUSINESS COMMUNITY
YEAR
IN AND YEAR OUT.
IN OTHER WORDS,
IT'S A SIMPLE
CASE OF
POLITICAL OPPORTUNISM,
NOT A SERIOUS EFFORT
TO DEAL
WITH HIGH
UNEMPLOYMENT.
THOSE AREN'T MY
WORDS, THOSE
ARE THE
WORDS OF
BRUCE BARTLETT
A REPUBLICAN
WHO WORKED
FOR
RONALD
REAGAN, GEORGE H.W.
BUSH,
JACK KEMP AND RON PAUL.
THINK ABOUT
WHAT MR. BARTLETT
IS
SAYING IN HIS LAST SENTENCE.
REPUBLICAN WOULD RATHER
PLAY
POLITICAL GAMES RATHER THAN
PUTTING PEOPLE BACK TO
WORK.
THEY WOULD
RATHER FIDDLE WHILE
ROME BURNS
INSTEAD OF PUTTING
OUT
THE FIRE.
LOOK
AT THE REPUBLICAN TRACK
RECORD SINCE THE START
OF THE
112TH CONGRESS.
NO JOBS BILLS.
NOT ONE.
BUT
WE FOUND TIME TO DEBATE
BILLS
DEFUNDING PLANNED
PARENTHOOD AND
NATIONAL PUBLIC
RADIO.
THERE'S
NO EXTENSION OF THE
PAYROLL TAX CUT
OR UNEMPLOYMENT
INSURANCE.
BUT WE CAN SPEND
HOURS DEBATING
THE NEED TO
ALLOW UNSAFE PEOPLE
THE RIGHT TO
CARRY CONCEALED
WEAPONS FROM STATE TO STATE.
NO EFFORT TO TAKE
AWAY TAX
BREAKS
FOR OIL COMPANIES WHO
CONTINUE TO MAKE
BILLIONS OF
DOLLARS IN
PROFITS
EACH MONTH.
BUT WE CAN
FIND TIME TO MAKE
OUR AIR DIRTIER
AND OUR
BOUGHTER
LESS SAFE BY
DISMANTTHELLING CLEAN AIR
ACT
AND CLEAN WATER
ACT.
SERIOUSLY,
MADAM SPEAKER, THE
AGENDA OF THE FAR
RIGHT
CONTINUES TO DOMINATE THIS
HOUSE LEADERSHIP.
THAT AGENDA IS
OUT OF TOUCH
WITH THE NEEDS
OF THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
WE HAVE A
JOBS CRISIS IN THIS
COUNTRY.
THE RICH ARE GETTING
RICHER AND
EVERYONE ELSE IS
STRUGGLING.
YET THE
REPUBLICANS CONTINUE TO
SIDE WITH
THE PEOPLE WHO DON'T
NEED ANY HELP.
THEY
KILLED THE SUPER COMMITTEE
BECAUSE
THEY WOULD RATHER
PROTEBLINGT TAX
CUTS FOR
MILLIONAIRES THAN DEAL
WITH THE
DEFICIT.
THEY ARE
REFUSING TO TAKE UP
THE EXTENSION
OF THE PAYROLL
TAX CUT
THAT EXPIRES AT THE END
OF THE YEAR BECAUSE THEY DON'T
WANT THEIR
MILLIONAIRE FRIENDS
TO PAY
A LITTLE BIT
MORE.
SO
THIS WEEK, WE CONSIDER
ANTI-REGULATORY BILLS THAT
MAKE
OUR
COUNTRY LESS SAFE AND OUR
CITIZENS LESS
HEALTHY.
WE'LL
CONSIDER A BILL THAT PUTS
MORE CORPORATE MONEY
INTO THE
POLITICAL
SYSTEM.
AND WE'LL
DEBATE A BILL THAT
MAKES IT HARDER
FOR WORKERS TO
ORGANIZE.
NOT ONE OF THESE
BILLS WILL PUT
PEOPLE BACK
TO WORK.
NOT ONE WILL
HELP STRUGGLING
FAMILIES KEEP THEIR HEAT ON
DURING THE WINNER.
NOT ONE WILL
HELP REPAIR OUR
AGING
INFRASTRUCTURE.
TO QUOTE MR.
BARTLETT AGAIN,
PEOPLE
ARE INCREASINGLY
CONCERNED
ABOUT UNEMPLOYMENT,
BUT
REPUBLICANS HAVE NOTHING TO
OFFER THEM, END QUOTE.
AND THAT'S THE
TRUTH, MADAM
SPEAKER.
REPUBLICANS HAVE ABSOLUTELY
NOTHING TO OFFER.
THE
PRESIDENT PROPOSED AND I
HAVE
CO-SPONSORED THE AMERICAN
JOBS BILL.
IT'S A PROPOSAL
THAT WOULD HELP
PUT
AMERICANS BACK TO WORK.
IT WOULD
EXTEND THE PAYROLL TAX
CUT
AND UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE.
WOULD HELP REPAIR
OUR
AGING
INFRASTRUCTURE AND
WOULD
PROVIDE AID TO CITIES AND
STATES SO THEY DON'T HAVE
TO
LAY OFF MORE
TEACHERS AND
POLICE OFFICERS AND
MORE
FIREFIGHTERS.
IT'S A BILL
THAT IS PAID FOR.
IT DOESN'T ADD
ONE CENT TO THE
DEFICIT.
AND IT'S
MADE UP OF MEASURES
THAT
REPUBLICANS AND DEMOCRATS
HAVE SUPPORTED IN THE
PAST.
LET ME REPEAT THAT.
WHAT THE PRESIDENT
HAS PROPOSED
ARE
A SERIES OF MEASURES THAT
REPUBLICANS AN DEMOCRATS HAVE
SUPPORTED IN THE PAST.
THE
IDEA THAT A PROGRAM WAS
GOOD
UNDER PRESIDENT BUSH BUT
NOT UNDER
PRESIDENT OBAMA
DOESN'T MAKE MUCH
SENSE TO ME
BUT THAT SEEMS
TO BE THE
THOUGHT
PROCESS THAT PASSES FOR
GOVERNING UNDER THIS
REPUBLICAN
LEADERSHIP SYSTEM OF
WHERE IS
THE
REPUBLICAN PLAN?
THEY DON'T HAVE ONE.
IT'S NOT
ENOUGH TO CROSS OUR
FINGERS
AND HOPE OUR ECONOMY
IMPROVES.
IT'S IN THE ENOUGH
TO CLOSE OUR
EYES
AND WISH MORE PEOPLE WOULD
FIND
A JOB.
ACTIONS SPEAK LOUDER THAN
WORDS
AN IT IS CLEAR
BY THE
REPUBLICAN
LEADERSHIP'S ACTIONS
THAT THEY DON'T CARE
ABOUT THE
ECONOMY.
EITHER
THAT, OR THEY ARE MAKING
A CONSCIOUS
DECISION NOT TO ACT
SIMPLY FOR POLITICAL GAIN.
EITHER
WAY, AMERICANS ARE
HURTING BECAUSE OF THEIR
INACTION.
MADAM SPEAKER, OUR ECONOMY IS
NOT WHERE IT NEEDS TO BE.
THERE ARE STILL TOO MANY
UNEMPLOYED PEOPLE IN THIS
COUNTRY.
THERE ARE
STILL TOO MANY PEOPLE
STRUGGLING TO MAKE ENDS
MEET,
STRUGGLING TO PAY
THEIR BILLS
AND
PUT FOOD ON THE TABLE.
BUT THIS NOTION
THAT RED TAPE
IS
WHAT'S KEEPING OUR ECONOMY
FROM GETTING OFF
THE GROUND AND
THAT THOUGHTFUL
REGULATIONS ARE
PREVENTING PEOPLE FROM
GETTING
JOBS IS JUST UNTRUE.
WE
DON'T NEED TO WASTE TIME
DEBATING BILLS THAT
MAKE OUR
AIR AND
WATER DIRTIER AND LESS
SAFE.
WE DON'T NEED
TO WASTE TIME
WITH
BILL DECEMBER
FUNDING NPR
AND
PLANNED PARENTHOOD.
WE
DON'T NEED TO PAES TIME
DEBATING
BILLS TO REAFFIRM OUR
NATIONAL MOT FAUX
TOE.
WHAT WE NEED TO
DO IS GET OUR
ECONOMY MOVING
AND CREATE JOBS.
REPUBLICANS HAVE BEEN IN
CHARGE
FOR 330
DAYS.
THAT'S
330 DAYS WITHOUT A JOBS
BILL.
IT'S NOT ENOUGH TO CALL
SOMETHING A JOBS
BILL IF IT
DOESN'T PUT SOMEONE BACK
TO
WORK.
NO,
MADAM SPEAKER, WE NEED A
REAL JOBS BILL.
WE NEED
DEFINITIVE ACTION THAT
SHOWS
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE THAT
WE CARE ABOUT
THEIR WELL BEING.
THAT
WE UNDERSTAND WHAT THEY'RE
GOING THROUGH.
AND THAT
WE ARE HERE TO HELP.
IN
SHORT, THAT WE ARE ON THEIR
SIDE.
THE
BILLS WE
WILL BE
CONSIDERING THIS WEEK JUST
DON'T GET THE
JOB DONE.
IT'S
BEEN 330 DAYS AND
REPUBLICANS STILL
DON'T GET IT.
I CAN'T SAY THAT
I'M SURPRISED.
DISAPPOINTED, BUT NOT
SURPRISED.
I RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MASSACHUSETTS
RESERVES HIS TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM GEORGIA.
MR. WOODALL: I
YIELD MYSELF
SUCH TIME AS
I MAY CONSUME.
I
LOOK AT THE CLOCK ABOVE YOUR
HEAD, I THINK IT'S
BEEN ABOUT
11 MINUTES
SINCE MY COLLEAGUE
DEBBIE
WASSERMAN SCHULTZ CALLED
FOR A
TONING DOWN OF THE
RHETORIC AND FOCUSING MORE
ON
POLICY.
I DON'T THINK WE WERE ABLE TO
MAKE IT
TO MINUTE
15.
I'LL QUOTE MY FRIEND
AS HE
REFERRED TO REPUBLICANS.
EITHER THEY DON'T CARE
ABOUT
THE ECONOMY,
OR THEY ARE JUST
ACTING FOR
POLITICAL GAIN.
IS THAT ALL
THERE IS?
EITHER
FOLKS DON'T CARE, OR
THEY'RE JUST
ACTING FOR GAIN.
IT
COULD BE THAT THEIR
PRINCIPLES ARE
DIFFERENT.
IT
COULD BE THAT THEIR
PRINCIPLES ARE DIFFERENT.
BUT
I DON'T BELIEVE THAT.
I BELIEVE OUR PRINCIPLES
ARE
THE SAME
BECAUSE WHAT THESE
BILLS DO IS ONE THING
AND ONE
THING ONLY.
LET'S
BALANCE THE REGULATORY
BURDEN WITH THE
BENEFITS THAT
IT
PROVIDES.
MADAM SPEAKER,
WHO IS IT IN
AMERICA
THAT DOES NOT BELIEVE
THAT
BALANCE IS IMPORTANT IN
WHAT WE DO
HERE IN CONGRESS?
I
HEAR IT BACK HOME ALL THE
TIME.
ROB, BALANCE.
I WANT YOU TO GET
THINGS DONE,
BUT
I DON'T WANT YOU TO GET
THINGS DONE
THAT ARE THE WRONG
THING
FOR THE WRONG REASON.
I WANT YOU TO
COMING TO AND
WORK ON
THESE ISSUES WHO SIT,
MADAM SPEAKER THAT DOES
NOT
BELIEVE THAT
REGULATION TO
PROTECT HEALTH AND
SAFETY IS
IMPORTANT.
I DO.
I COME FROM ONE
OF THE FARTHEST
RIGHT DISTRICTS IN THE
COUNTRY.
I BELIEVE HEALTH
AND SAFETY ARE
IMPORTANT
THINGS TO REGULATE.
BUT
I BELIEVE WE SHOULD BALANCE
THOSE REGULATIONS.
YOU
KNOW, WHEN WE DOUBLED THE
BUDGET OF THE
ENVIRONMENTAL
PROTECTION
AGENCY BETWEEN
AND
2009, WHERE DO YOU THINK
THAT MONEY WENT, MADAM SPEAKER.
THE
ENVIRONMENT THAT I LIVE IN
IN GEORGIA
WAS CLEAN AND
THRIVING IN
2008.
BUT WHEN YOU
DOUBLE THE AMOUNT
OF MONEY THAT YOU
GIVE TO
REGULATORS, THEY HAVE ONLY ONE
THING THEY CAN DO WITH
IT, AN
THAT'S REGULATE MORE.
REGULATE MORE.
WE
NEED BALANCE.
AND THAT'S ALL THESE
BILLS ARE
ASKING FOR.
THERE'S NOT A
-- I HAVE ALL THE
COMMITTEE
REPORTS IF ANY OF MY
COLLEAGUES WOULD
LIKE TO LOOK
AT THEM,
THERE'S
NOT A LINE IN
ANY OF THESE
PAILINGS THAT SAY
THOU
SHALL NOT REGULATE.
WHAT
IT SAYS IS, THOU SHALL
REGULATE
WITH BALANCE.
A FRIEND OF MINE
WAS WALKING
THROUGH
THE OCCUPY ATLANTA
PROTEST THE
OTHER DAY A
FELLOW
CAME UP AND
SHOOK HIS FIST AT
HIM, ONE OF
THE PROTESTERS
SHOOK
HIS FIST AT MY FRIEND AND
SAY,
IT'S ALL ABOUT JOBS.
MY FRIEND LOOKED
HIM IN THE CRY
AND
SAID, THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU SHOULD GO OUT AND HIRE
SOMEBODY.
THE GUY
SAID, I'M NOT TALKING
ABOUT PROVIDING
JOBS, I WANT A
JOB MYSELF.
THAT'S RIGHT.
EVERY
SINGLE BILL THIS
CONGRESS
CONSIDERS THAT HELPS JOB
CREATORS HELPS
JOBS.
WE'VE GOT
TO END THE RHETORIC
OF LOVING
JOBS AND HATING JOB
CREATORS, MADAM SPEAKER.
THERE'S
ONLY ONE OPPORTUNITY
THAT WE
AS AMERICANS HAVE FOR
EMPLOYMENT AND
THAT IS FINDING
AN EMPLOYER
.
AND
LINE AFTER LINE AFTER LINE
OF THESE BILLS
SAY, BEFORE YOU
FUNNISH
-- PUNISH AMERICAN
INDUSTRY, MAKE SURE THE BALANCE
IS THERE.
LET'S BE CLEAR, MADAM SPEAKER.
IT'S NOT THAT
THESE JOBS DON'T
HAVE TO BE PERFORMED.
TIME
AND TIME AGAIN I HEAR MY
COLLEAGUES BEMOANING
THE FACT
THAT WE'RE
NOT CREATING JOBS
AND I TOO
BEMOAN THE FACT THIS
THIS ADMINISTRATION HAS NOT
CREATED
JOBS BUT THAT'S NOT OUR
ONLY PROBLEM.
OUR PROBLEM IS JOBS THAT ARE
LEAVING THIS COUNTRY,
MA'AM.
OUR PROBLEM
IS DESTROYING EVEN
MORE
JOBS.
TRI-IS
GOING TO CONTINUE TO
OPERATE
AROUND -- INDUSTRY IS
GOING TO CONTINUE
TO OPERATE
AROUND
THIS PLANET.
WE CAN
EITHER EMBRACE IT HERE
IN
THIS
COUNTRY IN A BALANCED
WAY OR WE CAN
RUN THEM ALL
EVERSEAS.
THERE'S SOMETHING I BELIEVE WE
SOMETIMES DO
DISAGREE ABOUT IN
THIS CONGRESS AND
THAT IS THAT
GOVERNMENT
CANNOT CREATE
JOBS.
GOVERNMENT
CAN CREATE AN
ENVIRONMENT IN WHICH
JOB
CREATORS CAN CREATE
JOBS.
I CANNOT
PASS A BILL IN THIS
CONGRESS, NO MATTER
HOW HARD I
TRY,
MADAM SPEAKER, NO MATTER
HOW
HARD I WORK, THAT
WILL MAKE
EVERYBODY IN
THIS COUNTRY
RICHISM CANNOT DO IT
BUT THIS
CONGRESS HAS
SUCCEEDED ALL TOO
OFTEN AT PASSING
BILLS THAT CAN
MAKE EVERYBODY POOR.
PLANS, MADAM SPEAKER,
IS WHAT
THESE BILLS CONTAIN.
WHAT THIS
RULE DOES, AND IT'S
IMPORTANT, BECAUSE IT'S
A NEW
OPERATION WE'RE
DOING HERE IN
THIS
HOUSE, I'M VERY PROUD OF
IT, I
HOPE MY FRIENDS ON THE
OTHER SIDE ARE
PROUD.
THIS IS
NOT AN OPEN RULE TODAY.
I DON'T WANT TO CLAIM
IT IS.
WHAT WE
DID AT THE RULE
COMMITTEES, WE ASKED OUR
COLLEAGUES, ANYONE WHO HAS
A
PROPOSAL
THAT THEY BELIEVE WILL
MAKE THESE
BILLS BETTER, SEND
THOSE
AMENDMENTS TO THE RULES
COMMITTEE FOR CONSIDERATION.
ANYBODY.
DEMOCRAT,
REPUBLICAN, SEND
THOSE
AMENDMENTS TO THE RULES
COMMITTEE FOR CONSIDERATION.
THIS IS WHAT WE DID IN THE
RULES COMMITTEE.
WE
RECEIVED SIX DEMOCRATIC
AMENDMENTS FOR
H.R. 5
7.
SIX
IDEAS -- 527.
IDEAS FROM MEMBERS OF THE
HOUSE, THEY ALL
CAME FROM THE
DEMOCRATIC SIDE OF THE AISLE.
AND WE MADE EVERY
SINGLE ONE OF
THOSE IDEAS
AVAILABLE FOR
DEBATE HERE
ON THE HOUSE FLOOR
TODAY.
YOU DIDN'T
USED TO SEE THAT,
UNDER REPUBLICAN
ADMINISTRATIONS OR DEMOCRATIC
ADMINISTRATIONS, THAT'S
WHAT
WE'RE DOING HERE IN A
BIPARTISAN WAY.
H R.
3010, SENT OUT A NOTICE TO
THE
ENTIRE CONGRESS, SEND YOUR
IDEAS FOR
MAKING H R. 3010
BETTER, SEND
THEM TO THE RULES
COMMITTEE
SO WE CAN CONSIDER
THEM FOR CONSIDERATION
ON THE
HOUSE
FLOOR.
THERE WERE
12 IDEAS THAT WERE
SUBMITTED,
MADAM SPEAKER, ONE
REPUBLICAN IDEA,
11 DEMOCRAT
IDEAS.
THREE OF THOSE DEMOCRATIC
IDEAS
WERE
WITHDRAWN.
THAT LEAVES
US WITH EIGHT, AND
WE BROUGHT
ALL BUT ONE.
MY COLLEAGUE FROM
GEORGIA, MR.
JOHNSON, HIS
AMENDMENT WAS NOT
MADE IN ORDER BECAUSE
MY
COLLEAGUE, MR.
OLSON, HAD AN
AMENDMENT
THAT WAS
SUBSTANTIALLY SIMILAR.
KNOWING THAT TIME IS
VALUABLE
ON THE
HOUSE FLOOR WE WANT TO
CONSIDER
IDEAS ONLY ONCE.
SEVEN
DEMOCRATS, ONE REPUBLICAN
AMENDMENT
MADE IN ORDER.
I AM NOT HERE
TO DEBATE THE
UNDERLYING
PROVISIONS.
WE PROVIDED
TIME TO DO THAT.
BUT I WANT
TO DEFEND THIS RULE
AS AN EXAMPLE OF WHAT
WE OUGHT
TO
DO.
IT'S
IS IT A LITTLE MORE CONVOW
--
IS IT A LITTLE MORE
CONVOLUTED
THAN I WISH IT WAS?
YES,
IT IS.
IT
PROVIDES FOR TIME FOR DEBATE
ON
EVERY SINGLE IDEA SUBMITTED.
THAT'S AN
IMPORTANT CHANGE IN
THIS
HOUSE, MADAM SPEAKER.
I AM GRATEFUL THAT WE HAVE
BEEN
ABLE TO DO
IT.
I RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN RESERVES THE BALANCE
OF HIS TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MASSACHUSETTS.
MR. MCGOVERN: MADAM SPEAKER, I
YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME AS I MAY
CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. MCGOVERN: I WANT MY
COLLEAGUES TO UNDERSTAND THAT
ONE OF THE AMENDMENTS THEY
DIDN'T MAKE IN ORDER WAS THE
AMENDMENT OFFERED BY OUR
COLLEAGUE, CONGRESSMAN JOHNSON,
WAS BASICALLY STATE
ING THAT
IF
THE
EXPERTS CONCLUDE THAT IF IT
HAD A NET JOB
CREATION, IT
SHOULDN'T BE
BLOCKED BY ALL THE
STUFF
IN THIS
BILL BECAUSE WE
HAVE JOBS RIGHT NOW.
IT'S
INTERESTING THAT'S THE ONE
THAT
MY REPUBLICAN FRIENDS
CHOSE TO BLOCK BECAUSE IT HAS
TO DEAL WITH JOBS.
ANOTHER AMENDMENT THAT THEY
BLOCKED WAS
ONE I OFFERED.
I
OFFERED IT MANY, MANY TIMES
IN THE RULES COMMITTEE
AND THAT
IS TO
BASICALLY BRING TO THE
FLOOR AN
AMENDMENT THAT WOULD
ALLOW US
TO VOTE TO STRIP BIG
OIL
COMPANIES OF TAXPAYER, YOU
KNOW,
FUNDED GIVEAWAYS,
SUBSIDIES IS
WHAT I CALL THEM.
AND I
TRIED TO BRING IT UP ON
THE FLOOR A
GAZILLON DIFFERENT
WAYS.
I TOLD THERE
IS GERMANENESS
ISSUE.
OFTENTIMES THE RULES COMMITTEE
WAIVES ALL THE
RULES SO THAT
SOMETIMES
NONGERMANE AMENDMENTS
CAN COME TO THE
FLOOR.
I MEAN, WHEN
YOU TALK ABOUT
BALANCE,
THE FACT THAT
TAXPAYERS
ARE SUBSIDIZING
BIG
OIL COMPANIES THAT
MADE OVER
$100
BILLION IN PROFIT, YOU
KNOW, LAST YEAR
, CONTINUING
TAXPAYER SUBSIDIES
TO THESE BIG
OIL
COMPANIES, YET,
WHEN YOU
LOOK AT THE REPUBLICAN BUDGET
THAT THEY
PASSED THEY FIND WAYS
TO BALANCE THE
BUDGET ON EVERY
SINGLE PROGRAM
THAT IMPACT
MIDDLE INCOME AND
LOW-INCOME
PEOPLE IN
THIS COUNTRY.
WHAT
THEY DO IS CHOOSE TO
BALANCE THE
BUDGET BY LOWERING
THE
QUALITY OF LIFE
AND
STANDARD
OF LIVING FOR EVERYDAY
PEOPLE.
AND THOSE STRUGGLING TO GET IN
THE
MIDDLE.
THERE'S NO BALANCE
HERE.
IN TERMS OF
BIPARTISANSHIP,
THE
PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES
CAME TO
THIS CHAMBER AND HE
GAVE A SPEECH IN
WHICH HE
OUTLINED HIS JOBS
BILL WHICH
INCLUDED A
NUMBER OF
INITIATIVES
ALL WHICH HAD IN
THE
PAST ENJOYED
BIPARTISAN
SUPPORT.
BUT I
GUESS BECAUSE
HE'S
PRESIDENT,
HE'S DEMOCRAT,
REPUBLICAN LEADERSHIP
DOESN'T
WANT TO HAVE
THOSE DEBATES
HERE
ON THE FLOOR
, GIVE HIM MANY
VICTORIES
BECAUSE THAT MIGHT
NOT
BE POLITICALLY
ADVANTAGEOUSOUS TO
THEM.
LET'S BE FRANK ABOUT WHAT'S
GOING ON
HERE.
THIS IS
ABOUT IN MY OPINION
ABOUT POLITICAL
OPPORTUNISM.
THIS IS ABOUT
LEADERSHIP OF
THIS
HOUSE BLOCKING IMPORTANT
LEGISLATION TO PUT PEOPLE
BACK
TO WORK.
JUST BECAUSE THEY CAN.
JUST BECAUSE IT'S
BEEN PROPOSED
BY
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES.
WE NEED
TO FOCUS ON JOBS IN
THIS
CONGRESS.
WE NEED
TO BE FOCUSED ON
HELPING PEOPLE GET BACK
TO
WORK.
I DON'T CARE
WHAT PART OF THE
COUNTRY YOU'RE FROM, PEOPLE
ARE
HURTING, PEOPLE
ARE STRUGGLING.
AND THEY ARE
LOOKING FOR US TO
DO
SOMETHING, SOMETHING
MEANINGFUL.
NOT TO BRING BILLS TO THE
FLOOR
LIKE THIS IN THE
SCHEME OF
THINGS MEAN NOTHING OR
TO HAVE
THESE
GREAT DEBATES OVER
REAFFIRMING OUR NATIONAL
MOTTO
OR ON
BILLS THAT MAKE IT EASIER
FOR UNSAFE PEOPLE
TO CARRY
CONCEALED
WEAPONS FROM STATE TO
STATE.
I
MEAN,
WE'RE DEBATING THOSE
THINGS
WHEN THERE ARE MILLIONS
OF
PEOPLE THAT ARE
OUT OF WORK
I
THINK IS OUTRAGEOUS.
AND MADAM SPEAKER,
AT THIS TIME
I AM PROUD TO YIELD
THREE
MINUTES TO THE GENTLEMAN FROM
NEW JERSEY, MR.
ANDREWS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM NEW JERSEY IS
RECOGNIZED FOR THREE MINUTES.
MR. ANDREWS: I
ASK UNANIMOUS
CONSENT TO
REVISE AND EXTEND.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. ANDREWS:
THANK YOU, MADAM
SPEAKER.
MADAM SPEAKER
, AS WE STAND HERE
TODAY
I'D LIKE US TO PAUSE FOR
A MOMENT AND THINK
ABOUT AN
AMERICAN FAMILY
THAT IS NOT
HERE, THE HUSBAND
WORKS IN A
HOME DEPOT, THE
WIFE WORKS AS
AN ADMINISTRATIVE
ASSISTANT IN
THE HOSPITAL AND
THEY MAKE
TOGETHER ABOUT
$50,000 A YEAR.
AND
THEY'RE AMONG THE FORTUNATE
AMERICANS WHO HAVE JOBS BUT
THEY'RE FRANKLY
VERY WORRIED
BECAUSE IT
SEEMS LIKE THE
HARDER THEY WORK
THE LESS
GROUND THEY
GAIN.
THEY'RE
GOING BACKWARDS THE
HARDER
THEY WORK.
THE HOUSE
NEEDS TO UNDERSTAND
THAT
A MONTH FROM TOMORROW,
UNLESS
THIS HOUSE ACTS, THAT
FAMILY'S TAXES
WILL RISE BY
$1,000
.
A MONTH
FROM TOMORROW UNLESS
THE HOUSE
AND THE OTHER BODY
AND THE PRESIDENT
ACT, THAT
FAMILY'S
TAXES WILL GO UP BY
$1,000 A YEAR.
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS SAID HE
WILL SIGN LEGISLATION
THAT
PREVENTS
THAT TAX INCREASE FROM
HAPPENING
.
THE DEMOCRATIC
LEADER OF THE
OTHER
BODY, SENATOR REID, HAS
SAID HE
WILL MOVE AND SUPPORT
LEGISLATION THAT
PREVENTS THAT
FROM HAPPENING.
LAST NIGHT
THE MINORITY LEADER,
THE REPUBLICAN LEADER
OF THE
OTHER BODY
INDICATED THAT HE
WAS NOW
MOVING
TO A POSITION IN
FAVOR OF LEGISLATION
PREVENTING
THAT FROM HAPPENING.
HOUSE
DEMOCRATS ARE PREPARED AT
THIS
MOMENT ON THIS BILL, ON
THIS DAY TO SUPPORT
LEGISLATION
THAT
WILL POSTPONE THAT TAX
INCREASE
ON MIDDLE-CLASS
FAMILIES.
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE WANT
US
TO
WORK
TOGETHER, AND I WOULD
TRUST THAT THE
VAST MAJORITY OF
THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE WOULD SAY
THAT
IN THESE ECONOMIC TIMES
WORKING
TOGETHER TO SUSPEND
$1,000
TAX INCREASE ON A
$50,000 A
YEAR FAMILY IS
SOMETHING WE OUGHT
TO WORK
TOGETHER
ON.
PRESIDENT OBAMA AGREES.
SENATOR REID
AGREES.
IT LOOKS LIKE
SENATOR MCCONNELL
AGREES.
LEADER PELOSI AND THE HOUSE
DEMOCRATS AGREE.
BUT WE DON'T
HAVE THAT BILL ON
THE FLOOR THIS
AFTERNOON.
THIS
IS OUR OPPORTUNITY,
COLLEAGUES, TO
MOVE AWAY FROM
THE DAILY BACK
AND FORTH OF
REPUBLICAN
VERSUS DEMOCRAT
POLITICS AND DO
SOMETHING FOR
WHICH
THERE IS BROAD AGREEMENT
AND I
THINK URGENT NEED.
NOW, WE HAVE 30
DAYS TO GET
THIS DONE,
AND OUR TRACK RECORD
IS NOT VERY
PROMISING ON
MEETING DEADLINES
AROUND HERE.
MY
SUGGESTION IS LET'S MOVE
THIS
AGENDA ON THIS DAY AT THIS
TIME
AND PUT BEFORE THE HOUSE A
BILL
THAT WOULD SUSPEND THIS
$1,000
TAX INCREASE ON
MIDDLE-CLASS
FAMILIES, ALL WAGE
EARNERS ACROSS
THIS COUNTRY.
CERTAINLY THIS IS
SOMETHING WE
SHOULD
AGREE.
CERTAINLY THIS
IS THE HOUSE
SHOULD
DEVOTE ITS TIME FOR AND
THAT'S
SOMETHING WE SHOULD ACT
ON IT
TODAY.
I
YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN YIELDS BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM GEORGIA.
MR. WOODALL:
MADAM SPEAKER,
I
YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME AS I MAY
CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. WOODALL: EVEN THOUGH I AM A
FRESHMAN IN THIS BODY I AM
TRYING TO
FIND
METRICS TO FIND
OUT
WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE.
THE
METRIC I FOUND WHEN
DEBATING
A RULE, THE LESS THEY
TALK
ABOUT THE RULE THE BETTER
JOB WE DID CRAFTING
IT.
WE SPEND OUR TIME
TALKING ABOUT
OTHER
ISSUES ON THE FLOOR -- I
HAPPEN TO
AGREE WITH MY FRIEND
FROM
NEW JERSEY.
$1,000
FOR A FAMILY EARNING
$50,000 A
YEAR, THAT'S REAL
MONEY.
NOW, I WOULD
SAY TO MY FRIEND
FROM
MASSACHUSETTS, IF YOU TAKE
THAT
$1.75 TRILLION BURDEN THAT
THE
SMALL BUSINESS
ADMINISTRATION TELLS US IS UPON
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
BECAUSE OF
REGULATIONS,
THAT'S ACTUALLY
$5,000 PER
PERSON, PER PERSON.
THAT'S
$15,000 PER THREE-MEMBER
FAMILY.
AND SO, YES, I
AGREE WITH MY
FRIEND FROM
NEW JERSEY THAT
WE
SHOULD
COOPERATE ON FOCUSING ON
THOSE
BURDENS.
THE
BURDEN WE ARE FOCUSING ON
TODAY EVEN LARGER
THAN WHAT WE
ARE DEBATING TODAY.
I'D
BE HAPPY TO YIELD TO MY
FRIEND.
MR. ANDREWS: WILL THE MAJORITY
PUT ON THIS
FLOOR BEFORE THE
31ST
OF DECEMBER A BILL THAT
SUSPENDS THIS TAX INCREASE
ON
MIDDLE-CLASS
AMERICANS?
MR. WOODALL: MY FRIEND
FLATTERS
ME BY
THINKING I HAVE THE
INFORMATION AS A YOUNG
FRESHMAN
ON THE HOUSE
FLOOR.
BUT I
WILL TELL YOU THIS, I
TELL YOU TWO THINGS
ARE TRUE.
IT'S
A PUZZLER FOR ME ON THE
PAYROLL TAX HOLIDAY THAT'S
GONE
ON THIS
YEAR.
ON THE ONE
HAND I WILL TELL YOU
THAT
REPUBLICANS ARE PART OF
LOWER TAXES, NOT
HIGHER TAXES.
THAT SPEAKS TO
THIS ISSUE.
WE'RE
ALSO THE PARTY OF MAKING
SURE THAT
WE'RE PAYING FOR
THOSE
COMMITMENTS THAT WE'RE
MAKING.
SOCIAL SECURITY IS DIFFERENT
FROM ANY
OTHER TAX IN THAT
WHEN
I GO AND TALK
TO MY GRANDFATHER
HE SAYS, ROB, I
WANT THAT
SOCIAL SECURITY.
I PAID INTO IT ALL
MY LIFE.
WELL, WE ARE NOT PAYING
INTO IT
RIGHT
NOW.
THE PROPOSAL IS NOT
TO PAY INTO
IT NEXT
YEAR.
THE PROPOSAL
WAS NOT TO PAY
INTO
IT LAST YEAR.
I'D BE INTERESTED TO
ASK MY
FRIEND IF
HE'S PREPARED TO
SUPPORT LOWERING
THOSE
SOCIAL
SECURITY BENEFITS BECAUSE,
AGAIN, THIS
IS --
MR.
ANDREWS: WILL THE GENTLEMAN
YIELD?
MR. WOODALL: I
WILL YIELD.
MR.
ANDREWS: I WILL NOT SUPPORT
THAT.
I WANT A
SURTAX ON PEOPLE
MAKING MORE THAN
$1 MILLION A
COVER
IT.
LET ME
ASK THE GENTLEMAN
ANOTHER
QUESTION.
I UNDERSTAND
THERE ARE
DIFFERING VIEWS
IN HIS PARTY
AND
FRANKLY OURS AS TO WHETHER
AN
EXTENSION OF THE TAX CUT FOR
MIDDLE-CLASS
FAMILIES SHOULD
CONTINUE.
AND I'M NOT
ASKING HIM TO SAY
IT
WOULD PASS.
THAT'S BEYOND THE
REACH OF ANY
MEMBER.
EVEN THE
SPEAKER.
BUT IS
THE MAJORITY PREPARED TO
MAKE A COMMITMENT TO THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE,
AT LEAST GET
TO VOTE
ON IT, THAT WOULD LET
THE MAJORITY WORK ITS
WILL AND
VOTE YES
OR NO ON AVOIDING THIS
TAX INCREASE
ON MIDDLE-CLASS
AMERICANS?
MR. WOODALL: WELL, I WOULD SAY
TO
MY FRIEND THAT THE MAJORITY,
AGAIN,
SPEAKING OUT AS A YOUNG
FRESHMAN
BUT I KNOW ENOUGH
ABOUT THE
LEADERSHIP THAT THE
MAJORITY IS PROTECTING
SOCIAL
SECURITY, NOT JUST FOR
THIS
GENERATION BUT THE
NEXT
GENERATION
AND BEYOND.
AND THE QUESTION IS
GOING TO
BE,
CAN WE FIND A PROPOSAL --
BECAUSE THE ONE THAT WAS
PASSED
LAST YEAR WAS
NOT A PROPOSAL
THAT
BOTH
LOWERED TAX BURDENS
AND
PROTECTED THE
SOLVENCY OF
MEDICARE AND
SOCIAL SECURITY.
WE MUST BE
SURE NOT
TO FURTHER
BANKRUPT A
PROGRAM THAT WE ALL
AGREE IS ALREADY GOING
BANKRUPT.
I LOOK FORWARD TO THAT
DEBATE,
MADAM SPEAKER,
BETWEEN NOW AND
THE END OF THE YEAR, AND
IT'S
NOT JUST THAT
TAX THAT'S
EXPIRING.
I KNOW MY
FRIEND IS ALSO
CONCERNED
ABOUT THE
BUSH-OBAMA
TAX CUTS THAT
WERE EXTENDED
IN
DECEMBER OF
2010 AND WANTS TO
BE SURE THAT THOSE
WILL BE
EXTENDED IN
2011.
AND INTO
2013.
MR. ANDREWS:
THOSE INCOME TAX
REDUCTIONS WERE
EXTENDED
THROUGH DECEMBER
31 OF 2012.
SO THERE'S
NOT AN URGENT
IMMINENT TO ADDRESSING
THAT
ISSUE AS THERE
IS TO THIS.
I
PUT THE QUESTION THIS WAY.
FULLY UNDERSTAND THERE ARE
DIFFERENT VIEWS AS TO
WHETHER
OR NOT WE SHOULD
AVOID THIS
MIDDLE-CLASS TAX I
CREASE.
I'M
SIMPLY ASKING WHETHER --
TAX
INCREASE.
I'M SIMPLY ASKING
WHETHER THE
GENTLEMAN SUPPORTS GIVING US
A
CLEAR
UP-DOWN VOTE ON ALLOWING
THAT TO HAPPEN?
MR. WOODALL:
I HAPPEN TO
SUPPORT
UP-DOWN VOTES ON ALL
SORTS OF
THINGS.
I
BELIEVE THE HOUSE WORKS BEST
WHEN
THEY WORK ITS WILL.
THAT'S THE CHANGES
WE HAVE SEEN
THIS YEAR WE HAVE NOT SEEN IN
YEARS' PAST.
I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT,
MADAM
SPEAKER, FOR
US TO BRING THOSE
VOTES TO THE
FLOOR.
BUT IT'S ALSO
IMPORTANT TO MAKE
SURE THAT
FOLKS HAVE ALL THE
INFORMATION IN THE
SAME WAY
FOLKS MIGHT BE TEMPTED
TO
MISCHARACTERIZE THESE BALANCING
PROVISIONS THAT WE'RE
BRINGING
FORTH TODAY AS SOME
SORT OF
REPUBLICAN
CHICANNORY.
AND
HASTEN THE BANKRUPTCY OF
SOCIAL SECURITY AS
BEING
SOMETHING AS
NO CONSEQUENCE AT
ALL.
THERE ARE
CONSEQUENCES TO THIS
DECISION.
I SAY TO MY
FRIEND, I LOOK TO A
ROBUST DEBATE ON THAT BECAUSE
IT'S
IMPORTANT TO AMERICAN
FAMILIES.
WITH THAT, MADAM SPEAKER,
I'D
LIKE
TO REITERATE H.R. 527, SIX
DEMOCRATIC
AMENDMENTS OFFERED,
SIX DEMOCRATIC
AMENDMENTS MADE
IN ORDER.
THE HOUSE WORKS BEST
WHEN THE
HOUSE WORKS ITS
WILL.
THIS RULE TODAY
IS PROVIDING
THAT OPPORTUNITY.
I RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN RESERVES HIS TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MASSACHUSETTS.
MR. MCGOVERN: I YIELD 30
SECONDS TO THE GENTLEMAN FROM
NEW JERSEY.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM NEW JERSEY IS
RECOGNIZED FOR 30 SECONDS.
MR. ANDREWS: MADAM SPEAKER,
THANK YOU.
I THANK MY FRIEND
FROM GEORGIA
FOR
ENGAGING IN GOOD
SPIRIT IN
THIS
DIALOGUE.
I WANT TO MAKE IT
CLEAR, I
THINK IT'S THE
POSITION OF OUR
PARTY VERY
CLEARLY, THE
HOUSE
SHOULD VOTE ON
WHETHER
TO AVOID
THIS
$1,000 TAX INCREASE ON THE
MIDDLE CLASS.
THAT'S OUR POSITION.
I THINK YOU CAN HEAR
THAT THE
MINORITY
POSITION -- THE
MAJORITY POSITION IS
A LITTLE
MORE NUANCE
THAN THAT.
IT'S
A YES OR NO QUESTION.
WE
THINK THERE OUGHT TO BE A
VOTE ON
INCREASING THE TAX ON
THE
MIDDLE CLASS.
WE'RE READY TO PUT OUR
CARDS IN
THE MACHINE AND
DO THAT.
I YIELD
BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN'S TIME HAS EXPIRED.
MR. MCGOVERN:
MADAM SPEAKER,
I
YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME AS I MAY
CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. MCGOVERN: MY FRIEND ON THE
OTHER SIDE SAYS HIS PARTY LIKES
TO
PAY FOR
THINGS.
THAT STATEMENT
STARTLED ME A
LITTLE BIT BECAUSE THEY DIDN'T
THINK IT WAS IMPORTANT TO PAY
FOR THE BUSH TAX
CUTS.
MOSTLY FOR
THE RICH WHICH HAVE
NOW BANKRUPTED
US.
THEY DIDN'T THINK IT WAS
IMPORTANT TO PAY FOR
THE
MEDICARE PRESCRIPTION
DRUG BILL
THAT WAS
A LOT MORE EXPENSIVE
THAN THEY
PROMISED.
NOT PAID
FOR.
THEY DON'T THINK
ABOUT PAYING
FOR
THE TWO WARS THAT WE'RE
FIGHTING IN
AFGHANISTAN AND
IRAQ.
I MEAN, YOU
KNOW, WE HAD
BALANCED
BUDGETS
WHEN BILL
CLINTON LEFT OFFICE.
IT WAS AFTER
THAT THAT
EVERYTHING
GOT OUT OF WHACK,
AND IT WAS BECAUSE
OF THESE TAX
CUTS
MOSTLY FOR THE WEALTHY, A
PRESCRIPTION DRUG
BILL AND TWO
WARS ALL OF
WHICH WERE NOT PAID
FOR.
.
I
HOPE MY FREPPEDS ON THE OTHER
SIDE HAVE TIMELY
GOT RELIGION ON
THIS ISSUE THAT
IT IS IMPORTANT
TO TRY TO
PAY FOR THINGS AS YOU
GO
ALONG.
TO
EMBRACE PAY-GO AS DEMOCRATS
HAVE
DONE.
AND
WITH THAT, MADAM SPEAKER, I
WOULD LIKE TO
YIELD TWO MINUTES
TO THE
THE GENTLEWOMAN FROM
CALIFORNIA, MS. HAHN
.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
IS
RECOGNIZED FOR TWO MINUTES.
MS. HAHN: THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
I'D LIKE TO
THANK THE GENTLEMAN
FROM
MASSACHUSETTS, MR.
MCGOVERN, FOR YIELDING ME THIS
TIME.
MR. SPEAKER,
I JUST DON'T THINK
AMERICANS
CAN WAIT.
AND
HERE WE ARE TODAY AGAIN
DEBATING LEGISLATION
THAT WILL
DO
NOTHING TO CREATE JOBS OR
HELP FAMILIES
DURING THESE TOUGH
ECONOMIC
TIMES.
AND I AGREE
WITH MY COLLEAGUE
FROM
NEW JERSEY, WE JUST THINK
THAT THERE
NEEDS TO BE A VOTE ON
THE HOUSE FLOOR
ON THIS PAYROLL
TAX CUT WHICH
SO FAR MY FRIENDS
ON
THE OTHER SIDE ARE NOT
AGREEING TO.
YOU KNOW,
120 MILLION AMERICAN
FAMILIES HAD
$1,000 MORE IN
THEIR
POCKETS THIS PAST YEAR
BECAUSE
OF THE PAYROLL TAX
HOLIDAY THAT WE
PASSED.
AND
I BELIEVE WE NEED TO PASS A
NEW MIDDLE TAX CUT
, ONE THAT
WILL SAVE
THE TYPICAL FAMILY
$1,500.
NOW,
I AGREE
WITH MY FRIEND FROM
GEORGIA ABOUT JOB
CREATORS.
I LOVE
JOB CREATORS.
BUT I
THINK I HAVE A DIFFERENT
POINT
OF VIEW ON WHAT HELPS OUR
JOB
CREATORS.
AND WHAT
HELPS OUR SMALL
BUSINESSES.
I
SPENT SATURDAY, NOVEMBER 26,
SMALL BUSINESS SATURDAY,
SHOPPING
IN SMALL BUSINESSES.
AND I WALKED
INTO EVERY ONE OF
THEM
AND I TALKED TO THEM ABOUT
WHAT
WOULD HELP THEM.
CAN WE DO IN CONGRESS TO
HELP YOU AS
A SMALL BUSINESS?
AND ALMOST
EVERY SINGLE ONE OF
THEM
SAID, YOU KNOW WHAT
WE
NEED?
NEED CUSTOMERS.
WE NEED
AMERICANS TO HAVE JOBS
AND WE NEED THEM
TO HAVE MONEY
IN THEIR POCKETS
THAT THEY WILL
SPEND
IN OUR SMALL BUSINESSES.
THAT WILL HELP US AND
I
GUARANTEE IF WE
GOT MORE
CUSTOMERS, WE
WOULD EXPAND AND
WE
WOULD HIRE MORE PEOPLE.
AND
YOU KNOW THAT IT'S OUR SMALL
BUSINESS
THAT IS HAVE HIRED
ALMOST
60% OF THE NEW JOBS THAT
WE HAD IN
THIS COUNTRY.
SO
$1,500 THAT WILL GO BACK INTO
THE
ECONOMY.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY IS RECOGNIZED FOR AN
ADDITIONAL ONE MINUTE.
MS. HAHN: WE KNOW
THAT THAT
$1,500 THROUGH
THIS MIDDLE CLASS
TAX CUT
WOULD HELP BUSINESSES IN
THIS COUNTRY.
AND
I KNOW WE HAVE BEEN CALLED
THE
DO-NOTHING CONGRESS, BUT IN
THIS
INSTANCE IF WE DO NOTHING,
AMERICANS WHO CAN
LEAST AFFORD
IT
WILL SEE A
TAX INCREASE COME
RIGHT AFTER
THE
HOLIDAYS.
AND
I DARE SAY AMERICANS WHO
WILL SEE
THAT KIND OF A TAX
INCREASE IN
JANUARY MIGHT WORRY
ABOUT HOW
THEY ARE SPENDING
THEIR MONEY THIS DECEMBER.
AND IT MAY JUST
AFFECT THEIR
GENEROSITY
NOT ONLY TO THEIR OWN
FAMILIES BUT TO THOSE
WHO ARE IN
NEED IN
THIS COUNTRY.
THANK YOU.
I YIELD BACK MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEWOMAN YIELDS BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MASSACHUSETTS
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM GEORGIA
IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR.
WOODALL: I YIELD MYSELF SUCH
TIME AS I MAY CONSUME
TO SAY I'M
ALWAYS HAPPY
TO FIND THINGS I
AGREE
ON ACROSS THE AISLE.
I SAY TO MY FRIEND
FROM
CALIFORNIA WE ARE
BOTH NEW IN
THIS
HOUSE.
I
SPENT MY SATURDAY DOING THOSE
VERY SAME THINGS AND
MY SMALL
BUSINESS
OWNERS TOLD ME THAT
VERY SAME THING.
THEY TOLD ME ONE MORE
THING,
THEY SAID DO
GET THE FOOT OF
GOVERNMENT
OFF THE THROAT OF MY
SMALL BUSINESS.
THEY DID SAY, ROB,
YOU CANNOT
HELP
ME BY COG MORE BUT YOU CAN
-- BY DOING MORE BUT YOU
CAN HELP ME BY
DOING LESS.
YOU
CAN HELP ME BY GETTING OUT
OF THE WAY AND
LETTING ME DO
WHAT I
DO.
THE QUESTION THEN
BECOMES HOW DO
WE GET
THOSE CUSTOMERS IN THAT
STORE?
THERE ARE TWO VISIONS FOR
MAKING
THAT
HAPPEN.
WE CAN EITHER
TRY TO DISPENSE
MORE FAVORS
FROM WASHINGTON,
D.C.,
MR. SPEAKER.
WE CAN TRY
TO PUMP MORE MONEY
THAT WE DON'T
HAVE THAT WE ARE
BORROWING FROM OUR CHILDREN AND
GRANDCHILDREN OUT
OF WASHINGTON,
D.C.
OR
WE CAN
TRY TO GET FOLKS
HIGHER
AND BETTER PAYING JOBS.
MORE
JOBS.
AND
THAT'S WHAT THIS RULE'S
ABOUT
TODAY, MR. SPEAKER.
WE ARE RUNNING JOBS
OUT OF THIS
COUNTRY.
WE ARE FORCING JOBS OUT
OF THIS
COUNTRY.
THE NEW REPORT CAME OUT OF OVER
150 NATIONS,
MR. SPEAKER, WE ARE
NUMBER 69
IN HOW EASY IT IS FOR
BUSINESSES TO COMPLY WITH THE
TAX BURDEN, FOR
EXAMPLE.
NUMBER
69.
WE SHOULD
BE THE BEST PLACE ON
EARTH TO DO
BUSINESS.
WHAT IS IT
THAT RAISES SALARIES?
SOMETIMES MY FRIEND ON
THE LEFT
SUGGESTS THAT
WE COULD JUST
RAISE THE
MINIMUM WAGE AND JUST
GUARANTEE EVERYBODY
MONEY, BUT I
DON'T BELIEVE WE CAN.
WHAT WE CAN DO
IS GIVE FOLKS AN
OPPORTUNITY TO INCREASE
THEIR
PRODUCTIVITY.
MR. SPEAKER, NO WORKER ON
THE
PLANET
WORKS HARDER THAN THE
AMERICAN
WORKER.
NO WORKER
ON THE PLANET HAS MORE
PRODUCTIVITY
THAN THE AMERICAN
WORKER.
AND REGULATION
AFTER REGULATION
AFTER
REGULATION SLOWS THE
AMERICAN WORKER DOWN.
YOU
WANT TO PUT MORE MONEY IN
THE
AMERICAN WORKER'S POCKET?
YOU
LET THE AMERICAN WORKER BE
MORE PRODUCTIVE
BY PROVIDING
SOME BALANCE
.
AGAIN,
NOTHING WE ARE TALKING
ABOUT TODAY,
MR. SPEAKER, SAYS
THOUSAND
-- THOU SHASHT NOT
REGULATE.
WE
KNOW WE ARE GOING TO
REGULATE.
WHAT WE ARE SAYING IS
LET'S
REGULATE WITH
BALANCE.
THEN MY FRIENDS'
SMALL
BUSINESSES AND
MY SMALL BUSINESS
ALSO HAVE
THOSE CUSTOMERS
THAT
THEY NEED TO GET
THIS ECONOMY
MOVING AGAIN.
I RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM GEORGIA RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MASSACHUSETTS
IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. MCGOVERN:
MR. SPEAKER, I
YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME AS I MAY
CONSUME.
I
JUST WANT
TO -- MY COLLEAGUES
TO UNDERSTAND THAT
IF WE WERE TO
EXTEND THE
PAYROLL TAX,
ACCORDING TO
MARK ZANDI, A
REPUBLICAN ECONOMIST,
ADVISED
JOHN MCCAIN
IN HIS PRESIDENTIAL
CAMPAIGN, THAT WOULD
CREATE
750,000 JOBS.
AND HE
ALSO SAYS THAT WE ARE
LIKELY TO GO INTO
RECESSION IF A
PAYROLL TAX
EXPIRES, IF MY
REPUBLICAN
FRIENDS DON'T ALLOW
US TO
HAVE A VOTE UP OR DOWN
ON
IT, I'M
GOING TO ASK PEOPLE TO
VOTE NO ON A
PREVIOUS QUESTION
SO WE
CAN HAVE AN UP
OR DOWN
VOTE AND PEOPLE
HAVE AN
OPPORTUNITY TO MAKE THEIR VIEWS
KNOWN.
THE OTHER THING IS WE
HEARD THIS
TALK ABOUT THE COST OF
REGULATION.
AGAIN SOME OF THE NUMBERS
THAT
HAVE BEEN
TOUTED HERE I
QUESTION.
VERY
SERIOUSLY.
O.M.B.'S
CALCULATIONS
DEMONSTRATE
THAT REGULATION HAS
A POSITIVE NET
EFFECT ON THE
ECONOMY
AND NOT BY A LITTLE.
IN 2008
THE BUSH
ADMINISTRATION'S
O.M.B.
ESTIMATED THAT
REGULATORY COSTS
FOR MAJOR RULES
WERE BETWEEN $46
BILLION AND
$54 BILLION.
AND THE
BENEFITS OF THOSE
REGULATIONS WAS BETWEEN
$122
BILLION AND
$656 BILLION.
SO IT GOES BACK
TO THE POINT I
WAS MAKING
EARLIER AND THAT IS,
WHAT WE SHOULD BE
DOING ON THIS
FLOOR TODAY
IS DEBATING A BILL
TO PUT PEOPLE BACK
TO WORK.
WE SHOULD
BE EXTENDING THE
PAYROLL TAX CUT.
WE
SHOULD ALSO BE
TALKING ABOUT
AN
ISSUE THAT THE PRESIDENT PUT
FORWARD, THESE
BIPARTISAN
INITIATIVES.
WE SHOULD BE DOING
THINGS THAT
WILL MAKE A REAL
DIFFERENCE IN
PEOPLE'S
LIVES.
MY FRIEND TALKS ABOUT THE
AMERICAN WORKER.
THERE IS
NO CONGRESS, NO
REPUBLICAN LEADERSHIP IN MY
LIFETIME THAT HAS
BEEN MORE
HOSTILE
TO THE AMERICAN WORKER
THAN THE
LEADERSHIP THAT RUNS
THIS HOUSE RIGHT NOW.
BRINGING BILL AFTER
BILL AFTER
BILL TO
THIS FLOOR TO TAKE AWAY
THE RIGHTS OF
WORKERS AT EVERY
SINGLE
LEVEL.
YOU
WANT TO KNOW ONE OF THE
PROBLEMS
WITH JOBS MOVING
OVERSEAS?
IS
THAT
SOME OF THE INCENTIVES
IN
OUR TAX LAWS
HAVE MADE IT
EASIER AND
EVEN ATTRACTIVE FOR
COMPANIES TO PACK UP
AND GO
OVERSEAS.
AND HIRE
CHEAPER LABOR.
ONE OF THE
PROBLEMS WITH THESE
SERIES OF BILLS WE ARE DEALING
WITH HERE TODAY IS
THAT IT WILL
RESULT
IN A RUSH TO THE BOTTOM.
IN
TERMS OF REGULATION.
THE
LOWEST COMMON DENOMINATOR IN
TERMS OF
CLEAN WATER AND AIR
STANDARDS.
AMONG OTHER THINGS THIS
LEGISLATION SAYS THAT WE
SHOULD
TAKE INTO
CONSIDERATION THE
STANDARDS IN OTHER
COUNTRIES.
SO CHINA'S
GOING TO NOW SET OUR
CLEAN
WATER AND OUR CLEAN AIR
STANDARDS?
GIVE ME
A BREAK.
LET'S GET
REAL.
LET'S BRING
SOMETHING TO THE
FLOOR THAT
WILL MAKE A
DIFFERENCE IN THE LIVES OF
THE
AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
ESPECIALLY
THOSE WHO AREN'T
EMPLOYED.
LET'S BRING A REAL JOBS BILL TO
THE
FLOOR.
LET'S DO
SOMETHING MEANINGFUL.
I
RESERVE MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MASSACHUSETTS
RESERVES HIS TIME OF THE THE
GENTLEMAN FROM GEORGIA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. WOODALL: I THANK
YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
WE COULD LIKELY GO BACK
AND
FORTH
ALL DAY LONG WITH MY
FRIEND FROM
MASSACHUSETTS
BELIEVING
THAT HE
LOVES WORKERS
MORE,
WITH ME BELIEVING ME I
LOVE WORKERS MORE.
WITH THEM
BELIEVING TO DEFINE
LOVING
OF WORKERS
MEANS WE HAVE
TO REGULATE
THEM DIFFERENTLY
FROM WASHINGTON,
D.C.
FOR ME LOVING WORKERS
MEANS WE
ARE GOING TO FREE THEM TO DO
THOSE
THINGS THEY DO BEST WHICH
IS
PRODUCE.
BUT I HAVE
NO FURTHER SPEAKERS
REMAINING AND I WOULD ASK
MY
FRIEND IF HE HAS
FURTHER
SPEAKERS.
MR. MCGOVERN:
WE DO.
MR. WOODALL:
I RESERVE THE
BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM GEORGIA RESERVES.
MR. MCGOVERN: I YIELD TWO
MINUTES TO
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
GEORGIA, A MEMBER OF THE
JUDICIARY COMMITTEE, MR.
JOHNSON.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM GEORGIA, MR.
JOHNSON,
IS RECOGNIZED.
MR.
MCGOVERN: WHOSE AMENDMENT
WAS NOT
MADE IN ORDER BY THE
RULES
COMMITTEE.
MR. JOHNSON:
THANK
YOU, MR.
SPEAKER.
I RISE IN OPPOSITION
TO THIS
RULE
AND THE UNDERLYING BILLS.
INSTEAD
OF CREATING JOBS, THE
GROVER
NORQUIST TEA PARTY
REPUBLICANS ARE
ASSAULTING THE
VERY
REGULATIONS THAT ENSURE WE
HAVE CLEAN AIR,
SAFE
WATER, AND
FOOD
ALONG WITH SAFE
PRESCRIPTION DRUGS AND OTHER
PRODUCTS THAT
AMERICANS
CONSUMER.
THEY WANT
US TO CREATE SO MANY
BARRIERS AND OBSTACLES
THAT IT
WOULD
ESSENTIALLY MAKE IT
IMPOSSIBLE FOR FEDERAL
AGENCIES
TO DO THEIR JOBS.
ALL
IN THE NAME OF SIMPLY
INCREASING THE
PROFITS OF BIG
BUSINESS.
THE REGULATORY
ACCOUNTABILITY
ACT
WOULD REQUIRE AGENCIES TO
PERFORM 60
ADDITIONAL ANALYSES,
AND OTHER PROCEDURAL
ACTIONS
WITHIN THE RULE
MAKING PROCESS
FURTHER
SLOWING DOWN AN
ALREADY
BURDENSOME
PROCESS.
TALKING ABOUT
BUREAUCRATIC RED
TAPE, THEY
WANT TO TAKE IT
TO
THE NEXT LEVEL.
THEY
WANT TO DUCT TAPE AND
BLINDFOLD AND
PUT A STRAITJACKET
ON FEDERAL
AGENCIES ISSUING
REGULATIONS THAT HELP
AMERICANS.
THIS WOULD
ALSO MAKE IT MUCH
EASIER FOR LARGE
CORPORATIONS TO
EVADE THEIR
OBLIGATIONS TO
PROTECT THE
PUBLIC BY GIVING
SPECIAL INTERESTS MULTIPLE
POINTS IN THE
PROCESS, TO TIE UP
THE
PROCESS IN KNOTS.
THE REGULATORY
FLEXIBILITY
IMPROVEMENT
ACT IS NO
BETTER.
IT'S
A WOLF IN SHEEP'S CLOTHING.
DON'T
BE FOOLED.
THIS IS NOT ABOUT
HELPING SMALL
BUSINESSES,
IT'S ABOUT HALTING
REGULATIONS.
AND
INCREASING THE PROFITS
OF
BIG BUSINESS.
UNDER THE GUISE OF
SMALL
BUSINESS
PROTECTION, IT WOULD
SUBJECT ANY
REGULATION THAT
COULD
CONCEIVABLY HAVE ANY
DIRECT IMPACT ON
SMALL
BUSINESSES
TO A MORE LENGTHY
PROCESS THEREBY DELAYING
THE
IMPLEMENTATION
OF VIRTUALLY ANY
ACTION
, ANY AGENCY PROPOSES AND
WASTING ENERGY
-- WASTING AGENCY
TIME
WHILE DOING SO.
I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO OPPOSE
THIS RULE
AND THE UNDERLYING
BILLS.
I YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM GEORGIA YIELDS
BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MASSACHUSETTS
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM GEORGIA, MR.
WOODALL, IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. WOODALL: I RESERVE MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MASSACHUSETTS.
MR. MCGOVERN: I'M THE
LAST
SPEAKER ON
OUR SIDE.
MR. SPEAKER, I ASK
UNANIMOUS
CONSENT TO INSERT IN THE RECORD
THE STATEMENT OF
ADMINISTRATION
POLICY WHICH IS OPPOSED
TO THIS
LEGISLATION.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: WITHOUT
OBJECTION.
MR. MCGOVERN:
MR. SPEAKER,
JOBS,
JOBS, JOBS.
THAT'S WHAT WE SHOULD
BE
FOCUSING ON TODAY.
NOT GUNS, NOT
ABORTION, NOT
REAFFIRMING OUR NATIONAL MOTTO,
JOBS.
WE NEED
TO PUT PEOPLE BACK TO
WORK, BUT THAT DOESN'T
SEEM TO
BE PART OF THE
REPUBLICAN
AGENDA.
AND IT'S
HURTING OUR COUNTRY.
AT THE END
OF THIS YEAR AS YOU
HAVE
ALREADY HEARD DURING THIS
DEBATE
THE PAYROLL TAX CUTS
SIGNED
INTO LAW BY PRESIDENT
OBAMA WILL EXPIRE.
WITHOUT
ACTION, MIDDLE CLASS
AMERICANS WILL SEE THEIR
TAXES
GO UP BY
$1,000 NEXT YEAR.
WITHOUT
ACTION, G.D.P. GROWTH
WILL FALL
BY HALF A PERCENT.
AND WILL
COST THE ECONOMY
400,000 JOBS
ACCORDING TO THE
ECONOMIC
FORECASTING GROUP
MACROECONOMIC
ADVISORS.
EXTENDING THIS
TAX CUT IS
NOT
JUST GOOD FOR
AMERICAN FAMILIES,
IT'S GOOD FOR THE
AMERICAN
ECONOMY.
ACCORDING
TO AMAR'E PRIZE
FINANCIAL,
EXTENDING THE PAYROLL
TAX CUT COULD
ADD MORE THAN ONE
MILLION
JOBS TO THE ECONOMY.
MR. SPEAKER,
THIS IS THE KIND OF
LEGISLATION THAT WE
NEED TO BE
DEBATING.
NOT RIGHT RING
HOT BUTTON SOCIAL
ISSUES OR BILLS WHEN
YOU ADD IT
UP DON'T MEAN ANYTHING TO
ANYBODY IN THIS COUNTRY.
WHERE IS
THIS EXTENSION OF THE
PAYROLL TAX?
IT'S NOT IN THIS
RULE, IT'S NOT
IN THE
MAJORITY LEADER'S
SCHEDULE.
IN FACT THE REPUBLICANS SEEM TO
BE IGNORING
THIS ISSUE.
IT'S
SAD.
IT'S SAD THAT THE
REPUBLICAN
LEADERSHIP WOULD
RATHER RAISE
TAXES
ON
MIDDLE CLASS AMERICANS
SIMPLY --
BASICALLY TO PROTECT
TAX BREAKS
FOR MILL YARS --
MILLIONAIRES.
IF THERE WAS A VOTE RIGHT
NOW ON
A BILL THAT WAS
GOING TO
CUT ONE
PENNY
OUT -- IT WAS GOING TO
CAUSE
DONALD TRUMP ONE PENNY
MORE IN
TAXES, THE OTHER SIDE
WOULD BE -- WOULD
OVERFILL WITH
SPEAKERS.
BUT WE ARE
TALKING ABOUT MIDDLE
INCOME AMERICANS.
STRUGGLING AMERICANS.
THAT IF WE
DON'T ACT BY THE END
OF
THIS YEAR THEY WILL SEE A
$1,000 INCREASE
IN THEIR TAXES.
NOW,
WE COULD CHANGE ALL THAT
HERE
TODAY.
WE COULD CHANGE
THAT HERE TODAY
AND
ACTUALLY BRING TO THE FLOOR
SOMETHING THAT IS
MEANINGFUL.
IF WE
DEFEAT THE PREVIOUS
QUESTION, I WILL
OFFER AN
AMENDMENT TO
THE RULE TO REQUIRE
THAT WE VOTE ON
A PAYROLL TAX
HOLIDAY EXTENSION
FOR NEXT YEAR.
.
IF WE DON'T PASS
AN EXTENSION A
LITTLE LESS
WILL BE IN THE
PAYCHECKS.
I
ASK UNANIMOUS CONSENT TO PUT
THE
TEXT OF THE AMENDMENT
PRIOR
TO THE VOTE ON THE
PREVIOUS
QUESTION.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION.
MR. MCGOVERN: I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO VOTE NO AND
DEFEAT THE PREVIOUS QUESTION SO
WE CAN MAKE SURE THAT
WORKING
FAMILIES
DO NOT
SEE THEIR
PAYROLL TAXES
GO UP WHILE WE'RE
STILL STRUGGLING
TO RECOVER
FROM A
RECESSION.
THIS IS
EXACTLY THE TYPE OF
ACTION THAT PEOPLE ALL
OVER THE
COUNTRY
ARE HOPING THIS
CONGRESS
WILL MOVE ON.
I URGE A NO
VOTE ON THE RULE
AND I
YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF
MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MASSACHUSETTS,
MR. MCGOVERN, HAS YIELDED BACK
HIS
TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
GEORGIA.
MR. WOODALL: THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
I YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME AS I
MAY CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. WOODALL: I'M PROUD
TO BE
HERE WITH YOU
TODAY.
WHEN WE TALK ABOUT
JOBS, JOBS,
JOBS, THAT'S WHY I CAME
TO
CONGRESS AND THAT
IS
EXACTLY
WHAT WE ARE TALKING ABOUT IN
THIS RULE TODAY,
AND I HOPE,
MR. SPEAKER, YOU
HAD SEEN WITH
GREAT CONCERN WHAT
I HAVE SEEN
HERE
TODAY.
AND THAT
IS A COMPLETE
DISCONNECT
, IT APPEARS, WITH MY
COLLEAGUES ON
THE OTHER SIDE
WITH THE
UNDERSTANDING THAT
INCREASING REGULATION,
NEEDLESSLY
INCREASING
REGULATION
BURDENS THE AMERICAN
WORKER,
UNDERMINES THE AMERICAN
ECONOMY,
THWARTS JOBS.
AND I SAY,
MR. SPEAKER, THAT
THIS IS ONE OF THOSE
THINGS
ON
WHICH IF WE
DISAGREE WE'RE JUST
GOING
TO HAVE TO
AGREE TO
DISAGREE BECAUSE IF IS
AS CLEAR
TO ME
THAT THE SKY IS BLUE THAT
WHEN
YOU INCREASE THE
REGULATORY BURDEN YOU
MAKE THE
AMERICAN FAMILY
POORER FOR IT.
NOW, I'LL --
I KNOW I CAN'T ASK
FOR A SHOW OF
HANDS, MR.
SPEAKER,
AND I SAY, WHO WANTS
DIRTIER
DRINKING WATER IN THEIR
DISTRICT, WHO IS IT THAT
DOESN'T DRINK
FROM THE SAME
SPIGOT AS
THE REST OF US, WHO
IS IT THAT DOESN'T
SHOP AT THE
SAME GROCERY
STORES AS
THE REST
OF
US, WHO IS IT THAT DOESN'T
DRIVE ON THE
SAME ROADS AS THE
REST OF
US?
WE ARE ALL IN THIS
BOAT
TOGETHER.
WE ARE
ALL IN THIS BOAT
TOGETHER, MR. SPEAKER.
I COME FROM THE DEEP
SOUTH.
AND WHEN
WE TALK ABOUT
ENVIRONMENTAL ISSUES,
IT ALWAYS
GETS ME SO
PUMPED UP BECAUSE
NOBODY
SPENDS MORE TIME OUTSIDE
THAN I DO.
NOBODY
CARES MORE ABOUT THE
ENVIRONMENT THAN I DO.
AND
YET TIME AND
TIME AGAIN YOU
HEAR
THAT CHARACTERIZATION THAT
SOMEHOW ASKING
FOR A BALANCED
REGULATORY
ENVIRONMENT, A
BALANCED
REGULATORY ENVIRONMENT
IS
SOMEHOW ANTI-ENVIRONMENT OR
ANTI-AMERICAN.
I MUST TELL YOU,
MR. SPEAKER,
THESE BILLS BEFORE US
TODAY,
THE
REGULATORY FLEXIBILITY
IMPROVEMENT
ACT, THE REGULATORY
ACCOUNTABILITY
ACT, THAT'S WHY
I
CAME TO CONGRESS.
THAT
IS WHY I CAME TO CONGRESS.
WE
CANNOT MAKE EVERYBODY RICH,
BUT
WE CAN MAKE EVERYBODY
POORER, AND
WHEN WE REGULATE
WITHOUT REGARD TO THE BENEFITS
OF THAT
REGULATION, WITHOUT
REGARD TO THE
BURDENS OF THAT
REGULATION, THAT'S WHAT
WE DO.
MY
FRIEND QUOTED ABOUT THE
O.M.B., TALKING ABOUT THE VALUE
OF REGULATION.
I DON'T DISPUTE THAT AT
ALL.
I AM ABSOLUTELY
CERTAIN THAT
THERE ARE SOME
REGULATORY
INITIATIVES THAT
DO IN FACT
PRODUCE A BENEFIT.
ALL I'M ASKING FOR
IS WE
BALANCE
THAT BENEFIT BY
WHATEVER BURDEN IT CAUSES.
IT'S A RHETORICAL
QUESTION, MR.
SPEAKER, BUT DO
FOLKS HONESTLY
BELIEVE
THAT THE REGULATORY
BURDEN
SHOULD EXIST
IRRESPECTIVE
OF THE BENEFITS
THAT IT
PROVIDES?
THAT'S WHAT
WE DO IN THESE TWO
PIECES OF
LEGISLATION, MR.
SPEAKER, WE ASK
REGULATORY
AGENCIES
TO EXAMINE THOSE
BENEFITS AND BURDEN.
NOW, I COME
FROM A DISTRICT, AS
MY FRIEND FROM MASSACHUSETTS
TALKS
ABOUT, PARTISAN POLITICS,
I COME FROM A DISTRICT
THAT WAS
A PROUD
NO VOTE ON BOTH THE
RIDICULOUS STIMULUS BILLS
FROM
THE BUSH ADMINISTRATION
AND THE
RIDICULOUS STIMULUS BILLS
FROM
THE OBAMA ADMINISTRATION
.
WE ARE
EQUAL OPPORTUNITY NO
VOTES ON
RIDICULOUSNESS.
AND THAT IS
WHAT WE HAVE HERE
AS WE TRY TO
RECLAIM SOME
REGULATORY AUTHORITY
FROM THE
EXECUTIVE BRANCH
AGENCIES.
I'LL BE THE
FIRST TO SAY, MR.
SPEAKER,
I
THINK THE CONGRESS
WENT A LITTLE
LIGHT ON
PRESIDENT BUSH.
I THINK THE LAST TWO
YEARS THE
DEMOCRATIC
CONGRESS WENT A
LITTLE
LIGHT ON PRESIDENT
OBAMA.
I THINK WE HAD A
CONSTITUTIONAL
DUTY
TO DEFEND OUR LEGISLATIVE
PREROGATIVE TO MAKE THE
RULES
THAT THIS NATION
ABIDES BY.
NOT AN
UNELECTED BUREAUCRAT
DOWNTOWN BUT
ELECTED OFFICIALS
RIGHT HERE IN
WASHINGTON, D.C.
WE ARE HERE
IN THE PEOPLE'S
HOUSE.
THOSE THAT HAVE TO GO HOPE
AND
SUBJECT
OURSELVES TO VOTERS
EVERY TWO YEARS, THIS IS
WHERE
THAT AUTHORITY
BELONGS AND WE
SHOULD HAVE THOSE
VOTES, YES
AND NO,
WE SHOULD HAVE THOSE
VOTES ON WHETHER OR NOT
THAT'S
OUR SHARED VISION OF
AMERICA.
I AM GOING TO GET
A LITTLE
OFFTOPIC,
MR. SPEAKER.
IT'S CLEAR TO
ME WE ARE GOING
TO BE
TALKING ABOUT THE PAYROLL
TAX OVER THE
NEXT WEEK OR 10
DAYS.
I WANT TO ENCOURAGE ALL
OF MY
COLLEAGUES TO UNDERSTAND
THAT'S
NOT
A FREE DISCUSSION.
EVERY PENNY
THAW CHOOSE NOT TO
DEPOSIT IN THE SOCIAL SECURITY
-- THAT YOU CHOOSE NOT TO
DEPOSIT IN THE
SOCIAL SECURITY
FRUND IS
THE CLOSER TO
BANKRUPTCY THE
SOCIAL SECURITY
TRUST FUND COMES.
IT IS EASY,
IT IS EASY TO SAY
YOU ARE GOING TO GET
SOMETHING
FOR NOTHING BUT
WE'RE
NOT.
$15
TRILLION IN DEBT, MR.
SPEAKER.
$15
TRILLION.
WE'VE ALREADY BEEN
GIVEN AWAY
SOMETHING FOR NOTHING FOR
FAR
TOO
LONG.
THE QUESTION IS
, HOW CAN WE
BOTH HELP
THE MIDDLE-CLASS
TAXPAYER WITH
THEIR TAX BURDEN
AND PRESERVE SOCIAL SECURITY
FOR GENERATIONS TO COME?
IT'S NOT
A FREEBY, MR. SPEAKER.
-- FREEBIE,
MR. SPEAKER.
THESE ARE
TOUGH
QUESTIONS THAT
ASK SERIOUS QUESTIONS.
NOT ON A
MOTION TO RECOMMIT.
MOTION TO
INSTRUCT,
BUT
IN THOUGHTFUL CONSIDERATION
FROM THE COMMITTEE.
BOTH THE UNDERLYING
PROVISION
AND THE RULE
ITSELF HAS GONE
THROUGH REGULAR ORDER.
MR. SPEAKER,
THERE'S NO NEED TO
RUSH THESE BILLS TO THE
FLOOR.
WE CAN TAKE THEM
THROUGH THE
PROCESS TO MAKE
SURE THAT THEY
ARE
THOUGHTFULLY EXAMINED LINE
BY LINE
BY LINE, AND THESE
BILLS
HAVE BEEN.
INTERESTINGLY
ENOUGH, MR.
SPEAKER,
THAT'S ALL THESE BILLS
ARE ASKING
OF OUR
ADMINISTRATIVE BRANCH
AGENCIES,
THAT THE
REGULATIONS THAT THEY
ARE
PROMULGATING BE EXAMINED
LINE BY
LINE BY LINE TO MAKE
CERTAIN
THAT THE BENEFITS
OUTWEIGH THE BURDENS.
IT'S A SURPRISE TO ME,
MR.
SPEAKER,
THIS IS SOMETHING WE
ARE EVEN ARGUING
ABOUT
TODAY.
I THINK IT'S
COMMON SENSE.
CERTAINLY IN MY
DISTRICT IT'S
COMMON
SENSE.
PERHAPS OTHER
CONSTITUENCIES
FEEL DIFFERENT.
BALANCING THE
BENEFITS WITH THE
BURDENS.
DON'T LET FOLKS TELL YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER,
THAT REGULATIONS COME
WITHOUT A
BURDEN.
I'LL TELL YOU A GOOD
EXAMPLE.
I
GOT A CARDBOARD BOX
MANUFACTURER IN MY
DISTRICT.
MAY NOT
BE GLAMOROUS WORK BUT
IT'S IMPORTANT
WORK.
I WAS VISITING
THE PLANT THE
OTHER
DAY.
THEY SAID,
ROBB, WHEN THEY WERE
-- ROB,
WHEN THEY WERE TALKING
ABOUT THE ETHANOL
REGULATIONS,
DID THEY TALK ABOUT THE
IMPACT
THE ETHANOL
REGULATIONS WOULD
HAVE ON
CARDBOARD BOXES?
I SAID, NO.
WHEN
YOU INSERT ETHANOL IN A
GALLON OF
GASOLINE, YOU DECIDED
YOU WERE GOING TO
RAISE THE
PRICE OF
CORN AND WE USE
CORNSTARCH IN THE GLUE THAT
HOLDS OUR
BOXES TOGETHER.
AND WE
USE CORNSTARCH WITH OUR
FIBER TO MAKE
OUR BOXES
STRONGER.
AND EVERY TIME YOU PASS A
REGULATION THAT
INCREASES THE
USE OF ETHANOL
AND DECREASES
THE
AVAILABILITY OF CORN TO
OTHER SOURCES, YOU
RAISE THE
PRICE OF OUR
BOXES.
YOU
PRODUCE BOXES ANYWHERE IN
THE WORLD
AND IF WE
CAN'T STAY
COMPETITIVE WE ARE
GOING TO
LOSE THIS BUSINESS
OVERSEAS.
MR. SPEAKER,
THERE ARE
UNINTENDED CONSEQUENCES
TO THE
WORK OF
THIS BODY EVERY SINGLE
DAY, AND
THE ARROGANCE TO
BELIEVE WE
CAN FORESEE THEM ALL
ASTONISHES
ME.
WE
MUST UNDERSTAND OUR
FALLABLITY.
WE MUST UNDERSTAND THAT WE
CANNOT FORESEE ALL
THOSE
CONSEQUENCES
AND SO EVERY TIME
WE HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY TO
MEASURE,
MR. SPEAKER, EVERY
OPPORTUNITY TO LOOK AT THE PROS
AND THE CONS TO
ENSURE WE ARE
GETTING
IT RIGHT,
MR. SPEAKER,
EVERY TIME
WE PASS A
REGULATION
WE STEAL
FREEDOM FROM SOMEONE
SOMEWHERE.
UNDERSTAND THAT.
EVERY TIME WE
PASS A REGULATION
WE STEAL
FREEDOM FROM SOMEBODY
SOMEWHERE.
OUR
GOVERNMENT IS A
SOCIAL
CONTRACT WHERE WE
AGREE
TO GIVE
UP
INDIVIDUAL LIBERTY SO WE CAN
EXIST
COLLECTIVELY.
WE HAVE PUBLIC
SERVICES FORE
SAFETY, FOR
FIRE, ON AND ON --
FOR
SAFETY, FOR FIRE, ON AND ON
AND ON
BUT IT COMES AT THE
EXPENSE
OF PERSONAL LIBERTY BUT
WE DECIDE THAT THE
EXPENSE IS
WORTH IT.
MR. SPEAKER, THESE
BILLS DO
THAT
TODAY.
BALANCE
BENEFITS AND BURDENS,
PROVIDE THAT INFORMATION
TO THE
AMERICAN
VOTER AND LET'S MAKE
SURE THAT
WHAT WE'RE DOING IS
WORTH IT.
MR. SPEAKER, THIS IS AN
EXAMPLE
OF HOW ONE
OUGHT TO DO A RULE,
HOW ONE
OUGHT TO OPEN UP THE
PROCESS,
HOW ONE OUGHT TO
ENCOURAGE DEBATE
ON ALL OF THE
IDEAS THAT
ARE BROUGHT TO
THIS
HOUSE FLOOR.
I ENCOURAGE STRONG
SUPPORT FOR
THIS RULE.
I
ENCOURAGE STRONG SUPPORT FOR
THE
UNDERLYING LEGISLATION.
AND WITH THAT I
YIELD BACK THE
BALANCE OF MY TIME AND I MOVE
THE PREVIOUS
QUESTION.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
QUESTION IS ON ORDERING
THE
PREVIOUS
QUESTION ON THE
RESOLUTION.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
THE NOES HAVE IT.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM GEORGIA,
MR.
WOODALL.
MR. WOODALL: I ASK
FOR THE YEAS
AND NAYS, PLEASE,
MR. SPEAKER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
YEAS AND NAYS ARE
REQUESTED.
THOSE FAVORING
A VOTE BY THE
YEAS AND NAYS WILL
RISE.
A SUFFICIENT NUMBER HAVING
ARISEN, THE YEAS AND NAYS ARE
ORDERED.
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 8 OF RULE
20, FURTHER PROCEEDINGS ON THIS
QUESTION WILL BE POSTPONED.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM MINNESOTA RISE?
&gt;&gt;
MADAM SPEAKER, I ASK
UNANIMOUS CONSENT THAT ALL
MEMBERS MAY HAVE FIVE
LEGISLATIVE DAYS TO REVISE AND
EXTEND THEIR REMARKS AND
INCLUDE
EXTRANEOUS MATERIAL ON
H.R.
3094.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION.
PURSUANT
TO HOUSE RESOLUTION
AND RULE 18, THE CHAIR
DECLARES THE HOUSE
IN THE
COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE HOUSE ON
THE STATE OF THE UNION
FOR
CONSIDERATION
-- FOR THE
CONSIDERATION OF
H.R. 3094.
THE CHAIR APPOINTS
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM TEXAS, MR. POE,
TO PRESIDE
OVER THE COMMITTEE
OF THE WHOLE.
THE CHAIR: THE HOUSE IS
IN THE
COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE HOUSE ON
THE STATE OF THE UNION FOR
CONSIDERATION OF H.R.
3094.
THE CLERK WILL REPORT BY
TITLE.
THE CLERK: A
BILL TO AMEND THE
NATIONAL
LABOR RELATIONS ACT
WITH RESPECT TO REPRESENTATION
HEARINGS AND THE TIMING OF
ELECTIONS OF
LABOR
ORGANIZATIONS
UNDER THAT ACT.
THE CHAIR:
PURSUANT TO THE
RULE,
THE BILL IS CONSIDERED AS
READ FOR THE
FIRST
TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA,
MR. KLINE, AND THE GENTLEMAN
FROM CALIFORNIA, MR. GEORGE
MILLER, EACH WILL CONTROL 30
MINUTES.
THE CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA, MR.
KLINE.
MR. KLINE:
THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
MR. CHAIRMAN, I
RISE IN SUPPORT
OF
H.R. 3094, THE WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND
FAIRNESS ACT
AND
YIELD MYSELF SUCH TIME AS I MAY
CONSUME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. CLINES: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
THE --
MR.
KLINE: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE ARE ASKING,
HOW
CAN WE
GET THIS ECONOMY MOVING
AGAIN, WHAT WILL
IT TAKE TO
FINALLY
PUT PEOPLE BACK TO
WORK?
AND WASHINGTON IS RESPONDING
WITH
A NUMBER OF
ANSWERS.
SOME THINK
WE SHOULD SUPPORT
MORE SPENDING,
MORE TAXES AND
MORE
REGULATIONS.
IN ESSENCE
THEY'RE ASKING THE
COUNTRY
TO DOUBLE
DOWN ON THE
SAME
FAILED POLICIES OF THE
PAST.
MY REPUBLICAN COLLEAGUES AND I
BELIEVE WE SHOULD
CHART A
DIFFERENT COURSE, ONE
THAT
INCLUDES
REMOVING REGULATORY
ROADBLOCKS TO JOB
CREATION.
THE WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND
FAIRNESS ACT
IS
PART OF THAT
EFFORT.
THE LEGISLATION SAYS WE
SHOULDN'T
ALLOW UNELECTED
BUREAUCRATS TO DICTATE
POLICIES
THAT MAKE OUR
WORKPLACES LESS
COMPETITIVE.
IN JUNE, THE NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS
BOARD PROPOSED
SWEEPING
CHANGES TO THE RULES
GOVERNING UNION
ELECTIONS.
UNDER
THE BOARD'S RADICAL
SCHEME, EMPLOYERS
WOULD HAVE
JUST
SEVEN DAYS TO FIND AN
ATTORNEY AND NAVIGATE
A HOST OF
COMPLICATED
LEGAL ISSUES BEFORE
CONFRONTING AN
NLRB ELECTION
OFFICIAL.
EMPLOYEES WILL
HAVE AS LITTLE
AS 10
DAYS.
10 DAYS, MR.
CHAIRMAN, TO
DECIDE
WHETHER THEY WANT TO
JOIN
A UNION, DENYING THEM AN
OPPORTUNITY TO
GAIN VALUABLE
INFORMATION
AND MAKE AN
INFORMED
DECISION.
THE
NLRB IS ALREADY TELLING
EMPLOYERS LIKE BOEING WHERE
THEY CAN AND CANNOT
CREATE
JOBS.
NOW, THE BOARD
WANTS TO TAKE
AWAY
A WORKER'S RIGHT TO MAKE A
FULLY INFORMED
DECISION IN THE
UNION
ELECTION.
THIS PROPOSAL
LARGELY PROHIBITS
EMPLOYERS FROM
RAISING
ADDITIONAL LEGAL
CONCERNS,
DENIES
ANSWERS TO QUESTIONS
THAT CAN
INFLUENCE THE VOTE AND
TURNS OVER
TO UNION LEADERS
EVEN
MORE PERSONAL EMPLOYEE
INFORMATION.
.
LET'S GET SOMETHING
STRAIGHT.
THE BOARD
SCHEME ISN'T ABOUT
MODERNIZING
THE ELECTION
PROCESS.
THIS IS A DRACONIAN
EFFORT TO
STIFLE
EMPLOYERS' SPEECH AND
AMBUSH WORKERS WITH
A UNION
ELECTION.
LESS
DEBATE, LESS INFORMATION,
AND
LESS OPPOSITION.
THAT'S BIG LABOR'S
APPROACH TO
WORKERS' FREE
CHOICE AND IT'S
BEING
RAPIDLY IMPLEMENTED BY THE
ACTIVISTS
NLRB.
MR. SPEAKER,
FOR FOUR YEARS
DEMOCRATS CONTROLLED THIS
CONGRESS.
TO MY
KNOWLEDGE NOT ONCE DID
THEY TRY TO STREAMLINE
THE UNION
ELECTION
PROCESS, NOT ONCE.
THEY DID CHAMPION A
FAILED
EFFORT TO STRIP WORKERS
OF THEIR
RIGHT
TO A SECRET
BALLOT, BUT
THEY DIDN'T
BOTHER TO
OFFER ANY
SOLUTIONS TO THE
ALLEGED
PROBLEMS
THEY NOW SAY PLAGUE THE
ELECTION PROCESS.
TODAY
UNION ELECTIONS TAKE PLACE
ON AN AVERAGE OF
31 DAYS, GIVING
WORKERS A MONTH TO
CONSIDER THE
MONUMENTAL QUESTION OF WHETHER
OR NOT TO JOIN A
UNION.
ONE MONTH.
CASES WHERE
DELAYS HAVE
OCCURRED?
YES.
WITHOUT A DOUBT THESE ARE
THE
EXCEPTIONS TO THE
RULE, AND
FORMER AND CURRENT MEMBERS OF
THE
NLRB HAVE CITED PARTISAN
SHIFTS ON THE BOARD
AS THE
LEADING CAUSE
OF SUCH DELAY.
A BROKEN BOARD
IS NO EXCUSE FOR
TRAMPLING
ON THE RIGHTS OF
AMERICAN WORKERS.
I'M
AWARE THE BOARD RECENTLY
REVISED, MEANING
YESTERDAY, ITS
EARLIER
PROPOSAL AND
SETASIDE
SOME OF THE
MORE EGREGIOUS
PROVISIONS, HOWEVER
THE LATEST
ITERATIONS STILL
DENIES
EMPLOYERS ACCESS
TO A FAIR
ELECTION PROCESS, STILL
DRIVES
WORKERS OF THE OPPORTUNITY
TO
MAKE A FULLY
INFORMED DECISION,
AND STILL
PERPETUATES THE THREAT
OF MORE
PUNITIVE MEASURES IN THE
FUTURE.
THE BOARD
TEAMS UTTERLY
DETERMINED TO
FINALIZE A FLAWED
PROPOSAL
REGARDLESS OF THE
DAMAGE TO THE
INTEGRITY OF THE
BOARD AND OUR WORKPLACES.
WE MUST ACT
NOW.
THE WORK
FORCE DEMOCRACY AND
FAIRNESS ACT
REAFFIRMS WORK
FORCE
PROTECTIONS OUR NATION HAS
ENJOYED FOR
DECADES.
EMPLOYERS CURRENTLY HAVE A FAIR
OPPORTUNITY TO PREPARE
FOR A
PRE-ELECTION HEARING.
THE BILL
ENSURES EMPLOYERS HAVE
AT
LEAST 14
DAYS, TWO WEEKS, A
FAIR
OPPORTUNITY TO PREPARE FOR
THE
HEARING.
EMPLOYERS AND
UNIONS CAN
CURRENTLY SEEK BOARD REVIEW
OF
ISSUES
RAISED BEFORE THE
ELECTION OF THE THE BILL
PRESERVES THEIR
RIGHT TO SEEK
BOARD
REVIEW BEFORE THE
ELECTION.
WORKERS CURRENTLY
HAVE AN
AVERAGE OF
31 DAYS TO
DECIDE
THEIR VOTE.
THE BILL
GUARANTEES WORKERS AT
LEAST 35 DAYS.
BEFORE
THE BOARD'S RECKLESS
SPECIALTY
HEALTH CARE DECISION,
A
COMMONSENSE STANDARD
DETERMINED WHICH EMPLOYEES
WOULD
PARTICIPATE
IN THE ELECTION.
ONCE AGAIN,
H.R. 3094 TAKES
STEPS
TO RESTORE TRADITIONAL
STANDARD,
ENSURING EMPLOYEES
CONTINUE TO HAVE FREEDOM AND
OPPORTUNITIES IN THE
WORKPLACE
AND
EMPLOYERS CAN EFFECTIVELY
MANAGE THEIR LABOR
COSTS.
DESPITE
THE HEATED RHETORIC WE
WILL HEAR FROM OPPONENTS
TODAY,
THE BILL
IS A RESPONSIBLE EFFORT
TO
SET IN LAW, SET IN LAW, MR.
CHAIRMAN,
PROTECTIONS WORKERS
AND EMPLOYERS HAVE LONG ENJOYED.
I URGE MY COLLEAGUES TO
SUPPORT
THE BILL
AND I RESERVE THE
BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA,
MR. MILLER, IS RECOGNIZED.
MR.
MILLER: I YIELD TWO
MINUTES
TO
THE GENTLEWOMAN FROM NEW
YORK,
MS. SLAUGHTER A. MEMBER OF
THE RULES COMMITTEE.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEWOMAN FROM
NEW YORK IS RECOGNIZED FOR TWO
MINUTES.
MS. SLAUGHTER: THANK YOU, SIR.
I
APPRECIATE THE GENTLEMAN
YIELDING.
MR. SPEAKER, WITH MILLIONS OF
AMERICANS OUT
OF WORK, JOB
CREATION CERTAINLY SHOULD BE
THE
NUMBER ONE PRIORITY OF
THIS
CONGRESS.
AND YET WHERE
ARE WE TODAY?
NOT CREATING ANY
JOBS HERE.
BUT
WHEN USING THE PRECIOUS
FLOOR TIME
CONSIDERING
THE BILL
THAT
ATTACKS THE RIGHTS OF ALL
AMERICAN WORKERS AND
HAS NO
CHANCE OF
BECOMING LAW.
THAT
UNFORTUNATELY IS SOMETHING
WE DO WEEK
AFTER WEEK HERE.
AS MY COLLEAGUES
HAVE POINTED
OUT, RATHER
THAN
MINIMIZING
DELAY IN
UNION VOTING PROCEDURE,
TODAY'S
BILL MANDATES DELAY.
THE BILL
EMPOWERS EMPLOYERS TO
INTERFERE IN UNION
ELECTIONS BY
ADDING ANTI-UNION
EMPLOYEES TO
VOTING
BLOCKS, GERRYMANDERING
THE
ELECTIONS.
THAT
BY ITSELF SHOULD BE ENOUGH
TO VOTE AGAINST
THIS BILL.
LETTING EMPLOYER
DELAY AND
MANIPULATE
UNION ELECTIONS IS AN
ATTEMPT
TO PUT THE FOX IN CHARGE
OF THE HEN
HOUSE.
IT IS
A DIRECT ATTACK ON THE
ABILITY OF WORKERS
TO BARGAIN
COLLECTIVELY TO PROTECT THEIR
RIGHTS AND WE HAVE
SEEN IN
AMERICA
WITH LOTS OF PROTESTS
AND
UPRISINGS THAT AMERICAN
CITIZENS DON'T LIKE THAT
SO
MUCH.
NOW, WHEREVER YOU
WORK, WHETHER
IT'S
UNION OR NOT, IF YOU
APPRECIATE A
40-HOUR WORKWEEK,
FOR SICK LEAVE AND
VACATION
DAYS, FOR
SAFER WORKING
CONDITIONS, DON'T BLAME
THE MEN
AND WOMEN
FOR THE UNEMPLOYMENT
CRISIS, BUT
THANK THEM FOR
BRINGING THOSE THINGS TO YOU.
IT WAS
NOT A BEN NEVILLENT
EMPLOYER THAT GAVE YOU
THOSE.
IT WAS THE UNION MOVEMENT.
RATHER THAN CONSIDERING
A BILL
TO ATTACK THE
AMERICAN WORKER,
WE SHOULD
BE WORKING
TOGETHER AS
WE
PLEA ON THE FLOOR DAY AFTER
DAY
TO CREATE JOBS SO THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE'S
SITUATION
GROSS MORE DIRE
EVERY DAY.
SO I
URGE MY COLLEAGUES TO
OPPOSE
THIS BILL AND SEE IF WE
CAN
GET TO WORK TO CREATE JOBS.
I YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEWOMAN
YIELDS
BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
THE GENTLELADY JUST SAID WE
SHOULD
BE ADDRESSING
LEGISLATION
TO CREATE
JOBS.
THAT'S
EXACTLY WHAT WE ARE DOING
TODAY.
AT THIS TIME
I'M VERY PLEASED TO
YIELD THREE
MINUTES TO THE
CHAIRMAN OF THE
SUBCOMMITTEE ON
HEALTH
EMPLOYMENT AND LABOR
PENSIONS, THE GENTLEMAN FROM
TENNESSEE, MR.
ROE.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
TENNESSEE IS RECOGNIZED FOR
THREE MINUTES.
MR. ROE: THANK
YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
I RISE TODAY TO URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO
SUPPORT THE WORK
FORCE DEMOCRACY AND PROTECTION
ACT.
OUR COUNTRY IS IN THE MIDDLE
OF
A JOBS
CRISIS.
THE
NATIONAL UNEMPLOYMENT RATE
IS HOVERING
AT 9%, IN TENNESSEE
WHERE
I LIVE IT'S HIGHER.
MILLIONS OF AMERICAN
FAMILIES
ARE
STRUGGLING TO MAKE ENDS
MEET.
AMIDST THIS ECONOMIC
UNCERTAINTY, THE HOUSE HAS
PASSED
OVER 20 BILLS, JOBS
BILLS, THAT
WOULD HELP SECURE
OUR ECONOMY
THAT'S SITTING ON
THE SENATE SIDE
RIGHT DOWN THE
HALLWAY HERE
UNVOTED ON.
SADLY THE SENATE
ISN'T
THE ONLY
ROAD
BLOCK TO ECONOMIC RECOVERY,
THAT'S WHY
WE ARE HERE TODAY.
TO REIN IN
A NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS BOARD THAT'S RUN
AMUCK.
I GREW UP IN A UNION
HOUSEHOLD.
MY FATHER WAS A
MEMBER
OF THE
UNITED RUBBER WORKERS
UNION AND
I KNOW ABOUT THIS.
LIVED WITH IT.
GREW UP WITH
IT.
IN
JUNE WHAT PROBLEM ARE WE
TRYING TO FIX?
CURRENTLY ELECTIONS ARE
HELD AS
THE CHAIRMAN SAID WITHIN
31 DAYS
AND
UNIONS WIN ALMOST 70% OF THE
ELECTIONS HELD.
LET'S SAY THE FIRST OF OCTOBER
OF THIS YEAR YOU
WANTED TO HAVE
AN
ELECTION, BY THE END OF THAT
MONTH YOU COULD VOTE ON
WHETHER
A
WORKER WANTED TO BE IN THE
UNION OR
NOT.
A VERY
FAIR PROCESS.
IF THIS RULE GOES
INTO EFFECT AS
HE SAID, SEVEN DAYS FOR
AN
EMPLOYER
TO FIND REPRESENTATION
TO
GO THROUGH OVER 400 PAGES OF
RULES, ON THIS VERY
COMPLICATED
SUBJECT,
IT
GETS WORSE.
RELY ONLY 10
DAYS, AS LITTLE AS
DAYS, TO VOTE.
SO A WORKER WOULD HAVE
TO MAKE
THEIR MIND UP
IN SOME CASES, IT
COULD BE AS QUICK
AS 10 DAYS.
IMAGINE VOTING ON
THE PRESIDENCY
OF THE UBS IN
-- UNITED STATES
IN
10 DAYS.
IT GETS
WORSE.
WORKERS WOULD THEN
BE REQUIRED
BY LAW
TO HAND OVER PERSONAL
INFORMATION.
WHAT WE WANT TO DO
IS ALLOW THE
EMPLOYEE TO DECIDE WHAT
INFORMATION IS GIVEN TO THE
UNION ABOUT HOW THEY
WANT TO GET
CONTACTED.
MR. SPEAKER -- MR. CHAIRMAN, I
SHOULD
SAY, THIS JUST
ISN'T
RIGHT.
NOR IS THE
NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS
DECISION
TO REDEFINE
HOW
A BARGAINING UNIT IS
DETERMINED
RIGHT.
INSTEAD OF
CREATING JOBS,
EMPLOYERS WILL BE
FORCED TO
NEGOTIATE WITH
A MULTITUDE OF
SMALL BARGAINING
UNITS WHICH
WILL RAISE
LABOR
COSTS AND
DESTROY POSSIBILITY
OF
ADVANCEMENT OPPORTUNITIES.
SOMETHING MUST BE DONE
TO
RESTORE THE FAIRNESS
TO THE
UNION ELECTION
PROCESS.
THAT'S
WHY I'M A PROUD
CO-SPONSOR OF THIS LEGISLATION.
THE
BILL SIMPLY DOES THIS.
GIVES 14
DAYS TO PASS BEFORE A
PRE-ELECTION HEARING IS
HELD.
THIS HEARING
WILL ALLOW BOTH
SIDES TO RAISE ANY
RELEVANT OR
MATERIAL ISSUES
IN A
NONADVERSARIAL
ENVIRONMENT.
IT WOULD PROTECT
THE WORKERS'
RIGHT TO
MAKE AN INFORMED CHOICE
BY
REQUIRING AN
ELECTION TAKE
PLACE IN NOT LESS THAN
35 DAYS.
WE
OWE IT TO OUR CONSTITUENTS,
LET THEM HEAR BOTH SIDES
OF THE
STORY, AND MAKE
UP THEIR OWN
MINDS.
WORKERS' PRIVACY
SHOULD ALSO BE
PROTECTED.
ALLOWING THE EMPLOYERS OF A
UNION'S ACCESS TO WHAT
THE
EMPLOYEE
DECIDES THEY WANT TO BE
CONTACTED.
THIS BILL
ALSO RESTORES
LONG-STANDING RULES
FOR DEFINING
WHAT
A BARGAINING UNIT IS.
IT'S OVER THREE
DECADES OF
RULES.
MR. CHAIRMAN,
THERE'S ONLY ONE
WAY I CAN
DESCRIBE THIS BILL AS
COMMON SENSE.
I RESPECT THE RIGHT
OF THE
WORKERS TO FORM
UNIONS.
THAT'S THEIR RIGHT
UNDER THE
LAW.
BUT I BELIEVE THAT
THE UNION
ELECTION SHOULD FOLLOW A
PROSES
IS THAT IS
BALANCED AND PROTECTS
THE RIGHTS
OF EMPLOYEES AND
EMPLOYERS.
NOT JUST THE
UNIONS.
I URGE SUPPORT OF THIS
BILL AND
I YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN YIELDS
BACK HIS TIME
OF THE THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. MILLER: I YIELD MYSELF FOUR
MINUTES.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR FOUR
MINUTES.
MR. MILLER:
MR. SPEAKER, MEMBERS
OF THE HOUSE.
DURING THE
DEPTH OF THE GREAT
DEPRESSION CONGRESS GAVE THE
AMERICAN WORKER THE RIGHT
TO
BAND TOGETHER WITH
CO-WORKERS
AND BARGAIN FOR A
BETTER LIFE.
FOR MORE
THAN 75 YEARS THE
NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS ACTED
TO
VEST THE ULTIMATE DECISION TO
FORM OR
BELONG TO A UNION
WITH
THE WORKERS
THEMSELVES.
THE PRINCIPLE UNDERLYING
THIS
LAW WHEN WORKERS
DECIDE THEY
WANT A
UNION, THEY SHOULD GET A
UNION.
THESE
RIGHTS AND THIS LAW HAVE
SERVED THIS
COUNTRY WELL.
IT'S
BUILT THE MIDDLE CLASS.
BROUGHT US THE
40-HOUR WORKWEEK,
SAFE
WORKPLACES.
THESE RIGHTS
ENSURE THAT
ECONOMICALLY SECURE FAMILIES
THE
PROSPECT THAT OUR
CHILDREN COULD
BUILD EVEN
A BETTER LIFE.
THESE RIGHTS HAVE BEEN AN
UNQUALIFIED
SUCCESS.
THEY HELP TO
CREATE AN ECONOMIC
ENGINE UNPARALLELED
IN THE
HISTORY OF THE
WORLD.
BUT
ESPECIALLY THIS YEAR FORCES
HAVE GATHERED THAT
WOULD DO
ANYTHING TO TAKE
AWAY THOSE
RIGHTS FROM
AMERICAN WORKERS,
FROM AMERICAN
FAMILIES.
THESE
FORCES SUBSCRIBE TO THE
PERVIS IDEOLOGY THAT
SAYS
WORKERS SHOULD
JUST ACCEPT
WHATEVER
THE POWERFUL DECIDE
THAT'S GOOD ENOUGH
FOR THEM AND
THAT'S THE
END OF THE
DISCUSSION.
THEY
USE REAL CRISES AS AN
EXCUSE
TO GAIN MORE POWER.
WE HAVE
SEEN IT IN WISCONSIN AND
OHIO ACROSS THE
COUNTRY WHERE
THE
REAL GOAL WAS TO TAKEWAY THE
RIGHTS OF WORKERS
NOT TO SOLVE
THE ECONOMIC PROBLEMS OF THOSE
STATES.
WHERE THE REAL GOAL
WAS TO
CONSTRAIN WORKERS
FROM
COLLECTIVE BARGAINING
PROCESS
NOT TO DEAL
WITH THE ECONOMIC
PROBLEMS OF
THOSE STATES.
WHERE
THEY DON'T CONTROL THE
STATE HOUSES
AND STATE
LEGISLATURES, THEY HAVE COME TO
THE CONGRESS OF THE
UNITED
STATES.
THIS BILL TODAY IS PART OF THAT
SCHEME.
THIS BILL IS PART OF A
NATIONAL
EFFORT BY THE
REPUBLICAN PARTY,
BY
THE CHAMBER OF COMMERCE, AND
THE
BUSINESS -- MUCH OF THE
BUSINESS
COMMUNITY IN THIS
COUNTRY
TO STRIP WORKERS
OF
THEIR RIGHTS
AT WORK.
TO TAKE
ORDINARY WORKING MEN AND
WOMEN AND THEY WILL
THEM THEY
WILL HAVE NO
RIGHT TO JOIN A
UNION.
THEY WILL NOT BE ABLE TO
GATHER
FOR
AN ELECTION BECAUSE THIS
LEGISLATION PREVENTS THAT
ELECTION FROM HAPPENING.
HOW DOES
IT DO THAT?
IT DOES
THAT, ONE, BY HAVING THE
EMPLOYER
BE IN THE BARGAINING
UNIT.
NOT THE EMPLOYEE AS IS DICTATED
UNDER
THE LAW AND AS AFFIRMED BY
THIS
CONGRESS OVER AND OVER
AGAIN.
THAT DECISION BELONGS TO
THEM.
HOW DOES
IT DO THAT?
IT
STUFFS THE BALLOT BOX AT THE
OUTSET
AND THE EMPLOYER MAKING
UP THE
BARGAINING UNIT AS
OPPOSED
TO THE EMPLOYEE.
THEN THEY
THROW IN THE ABILITY
TO HAVE
WHATEVER FRIVOLOUS
APPEALS,
ISSUES YOU WANT TO
RAISE, NO
MATTER HOW FRIVOLOUS,
THEY MUST
BE RAISED BEFORE THIS
TIME,
BEFORE THE ELECTION, AND
ALL OF THE
APPEALS MUST BE
DECIDED.
SO WHILE
THEY TALK ABOUT HOW
THIS
GIVES US
A TIGHT TIME
FRAME, WHAT WE
SEE IS ENDLESS
DELAYS,
ENDLESS RUNNING UP OF
LEGAL COSTS, OF
ATTORNEYS ON
BOTH SIDES, ALL
IN THE IDEA OF
BUYING
TIME FOR THE EMPLOYER TO
INTIMIDATE
THE EMPLOYEES FROM
JOINING THE
UNION, TO CONSTANTLY
HOLD
BUSINESSES IN THE
WORKPLACE,
FACE TO FACE
BUSINESSES,
TO ADVOCATE AGAINST
THE
UNION SO THEY
CAN TURN
AROUND
THE DECISION THAT THE
EMPLOYEES ESSENTIALLY
HAVE MADE
WHEN THEY SAY
WE WANT TO GO TO
AN ELECTION, WE WANT
TO HAVE A
UNION.
THIS IS OUR
BARGAINING UNIT.
AND
THAT'S THE GOAL HERE IS TO
DESTROY
THE ABILITY OF THIS LAW
TO
FUNCTION.
AND YOU
CANNOT HAVE THE
SITUATION WHERE THAT
EXISTS IN
THIS COUNTRY BECAUSE THIS
LAW IS
NOT ONLY
IMPORTANT TO EMPLOYEES
IN THE WORKPLACE,
IT'S
IMPORTANT
TO
MILLIONS, MILLIONS OF
AMERICANS WHO ARE
IN THE MIDDLE
CLASS
IN THIS ECONOMY TODAY.
THESE ARE
PEOPLE WHO ARE THERE
BECAUSE
OF THE COLLECTIVE
BARGAINING RIGHTS OF PEOPLE OVER
THE
LAST 75 YEARS IN
THIS
COUNTRY TO BRING
THE BENEFITS,
TO BRING THE
WAGES, TO
BRING THE
JOB
SECURITY, TO BRING THE
HEALTH CARE BENEFITS, TO
BRING
THE PENSION
BENEFITS, AND
PROTECTIONS TO MIDDLE CLASS
FAMILIES.
WE HAVE SEEN AS THE
UNIONS HAVE
DECLINED,
SO HAVE THE WAGES, SO
HAVE THE BENEFITS
OF WORKERS TO
THEIR OWN
PRODUCTIVITY.
THE AMERICAN WORKER CONTINUES TO
INCREASE THEIR
PRODUCTIVITY.
THEY ARE THE MOST
PRODUCTIVE
WORKERS IN ALMOST EVERY SECTOR
OF OUR ECONOMY
IN THE WORLD.
AND
YET MORE MORE OF THEIR
PRODUCTIVITY IS
BEING SIPHONED
OFF
BY THE 1% IF YOU WILL.
BY THE EMPLOYERS
WHO DECIDE THEY
NEED MORE
BONUS, BY THE
EMPLOYERS WHO DECIDE
THEY NEED
BIGGER
PAYCHECKS, BY THE
EMPLOYERS WHO
DECIDE THEY NEED
MORE SHAREHOLDER
DIVIDEND.
EMPLOYERS
WHO DECIDE THEY NEED
MORE GOLDEN
PARACHUTES.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN'S TIME
HAS EXPIRED.
MR. MILLER: THAT'S WHAT THIS IS
ABOUT.
IT'S ABOUT STEALING FROM THE
AMERICAN WORKERS AND NOT
GIVING
THEM A
RIGHT TO CONTINUE TO
BARGAIN FOR THE BENEFIT
OF THEIR
FAMILIES
AND THEIR COMMUNITY.
WE OUGHT
TO REJECT THIS BILL
TODAY.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN'S TIME
HAS EXPIRED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: THANK
YOU.
MR. CHAIRMAN,
I'D LIKE TO YIELD
TWO
MINUTES TO
THE CHAIRMAN OF
THE
SUBCOMMITTEE ON WORK FORCE
PROTECTIONS,
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MICHIGAN, MR. WALBERG.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MICHIGAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR TWO
MINUTES.
MR. WALBERG: THANK
YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
MR. SPEAKER, AS I A
FORMER
UNITED STEEL
WORKERS UNION
MEMBER STAND HERE
TODAY, THE
UNEMPLOYMENT RATE
IN MICHIGAN
STANDS
AT 10.6% AND IN AREAS OF
MY
DISTRICT IT IS AS HIGH AS
14%.
OUR PRIMARY
FOCUS IN CONGRESS AS
PASSED IN THE
REPUBLICAN JOBS
PLAN AND
SEATED IN THE
SENATE
RIGHT NOW, OUR
PRIMARY FOCUS IS
TO GET
BURDENSOME GOVERNMENTS
REGULATIONS OUT
OF OUR WAY AND
OUT OF THE
WAY OF THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE AND LET THEM GET BACK
TO
WORK.
THE
NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS
BOARD HAS TAKEN ACTIONS
THAT
DIRECTLY
OPPOSE AMERICAN JOB
PROVIDERS AND
JOB CREATORS.
HOW CAN
ANY MICHIGANIAN
OPERATING A
BUSINESS EXPECT TO
COMPETE
ON A
LEVEL PLAYING FIELD
WITH
NLRB MEMBERSHIP LIKE CRAIG
BECKER WHO ONCE
WROTE, AND I
QUOTE, EMPLOYERS SHOULD BE
STRIPPED OF
ANY LEGALLY INTEREST
IN THEIR
EMPLOYEES' ELECTION OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
AND ALSO
THAT, AND I QUOTE,
EMPLOYERS HAVE
NO STANDING TO
INSERT --
TO ASSERT THEIR
EMPLOYEES' RIGHT TO FAIR
REPRESENTATION.
.
IN THEIR
RECENT ACTION TO
CREATE AN
AMBUSH-STYLE ELECTION
PROCESS, THE NLRB
TOOK A
SPECIAL INTEREST
ATTORNEY OVER
THE WILL
OF THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
THE ROGUE MAJORITY
OF THE NLRB
WANTS TO SET
CONDITIONS THAT
STIFLE JOB CREATION
AND
EXPANSION.
JOB CREATORS ARE
TERROR FIND OF
THE
NLRB'S ACTIONS TO CREATE AN
AMBUSH-STYLE
ELECTION PROCESS
THAT
WILL PREVENT EMPLOYEES
FROM MAKING
AN INFORMED
DECISION.
AND MORE
STUNNINGLY, THEY
REVERSED 30
YEARS OF PRECEDENT
THROUGH THEIR
SPECIALLY HEALTH
CARE
DECISION WHICH WOULD ALLOW
UNIONS
TO CARVE UP A WORK SITE
HOWEVER THEY CHOOSE.
AMERICA'S JOB CREATORS
AND WORK
FORCE DESERVE
FAIRNESS TO
ENSURE
THAT UNION
REPRESENTATIONS LIKE
ELECTIONS
FOR OUR
POLITICAL LEADERSHIP
ARE
DONE IN A
JUST MANNER THAT
ALLOW ALL
PARTICIPANTS TO MAKE
AN
INFORMED
DECISION ON THEIR
REPRESENTATION STATUS.
THE WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND
FAIRNESS ACT
WILL ENSURE THAT
EMPLOYEES AND EMPLOYERS WILL
HAVE A LEVEL
PLAYING FIELD THAT
THE NLRB
AND ITS SPECIAL
INTEREST
ALLIES ARE DETERMINED
TO TILT.
AND I YIELD BACK.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN'S TIME
HAS EXPIRED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. MILLER: I
RECOGNIZE THE
GENTLEMAN FROM NEW JERSEY, MR.
ANDREWS,
THE RANKING
MEMBER OF
THE
COMMITTEE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR HOW
MANY
MINUTES?
--
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR HOW MANY
MINUTES?
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
HAS YIELDED TIME TO
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM NEW JERSEY BUT
FOR HOW MANY MINUTES?
MR. MILLER:
THREE.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR THREE
MINUTES.
MR.
ANDREWS: MR. CHAIRMAN, THE
AMERICAN DREAMS
HAVE BEEN BASED
ON A
BASIC DEAL -- IF YOU GO TO
WORK EVERY DAY AND
WORK AS HARD
AS YOU CAN,
YOU'LL MAKE A
DECENT
WAGE.
IF YOU GET SICK AND
HAVE TO GO
TO THE
HOSPITAL, YOU'LL HAVE
HEALTH
BENEFITS THAT MEANS YOU
WON'T LOSE EVERYTHING YOU
HAVE
BECAUSE YOU GOT
SICK.
AT THE END
OF THE 40TH HOUR OF
THE WEEK YOUR
TIME BELONGS TO
YOU AND
YOUR
FAMILY, NOT TO
BOSS, UNLESS YOUR BOSS IS
WILLING
TO PAY YOU TIME AND A
HALF.
AND YOU DON'T HAVE TO WORK
UNTIL THE
DAY YOU DIE BECAUSE
YOU CAN
EARN A DECENT PENSION
AND SPEND THE
GOLDEN MOMENTS
AND
DAYS OF YOUR LIFE
TAKING
CARE OF YOUR
GRANDCHILDREN AND
FAMILY.
THAT'S THE DEAL.
NONE OF
THAT EXISTED FOR MOST
AMERICANS
BEFORE COLLECTIVE
BARGAINING
EXISTED.
AMERICA
HAS A MIDDLE CLASS
BECAUSE AMERICA
HAS COLLECTIVE
BARGAINING.
THIS BILL IS NOT ABOUT THE
NUMBER OF DAYS
BEFORE AN
ELECTION OR THE
SIZE OF A
BARGAINING
UNIT.
THIS BILL
RAISES THE ISSUE OF
WHETHER YOU
TRULY BELIEVE IN
COLLECTIVE
BARGAINING.
AND WHAT
THIS BILL DOES IS SAY
TO THE MINORITY OF EMPLOYERS
IN
AMERICA, AND I THINK
THEY ARE
THE MINORITY BY
FAR, WHO
WOULD
CHOOSE TO
SUBVERT AN ELECTION
PROCESS
, WHO WOULD CHOOSE TO
INTIMIDATE AND COERCE
THEIR
WORKERS INTO
VOTING AGAINST A
UNION, THIS BILL
GIVES THEM THE
ROAD MAP OF
EXACTLY HOW TO DO
THAT.
IT IS A
SUBVERSION OF THE
AMERICAN MIDDLE CLASS BECAUSE
IT'S
A
SUBVERSION OF COLLECTIVE
BARGAINING.
OUR GRAND FATHERS
AND GRAND
MOTHERS
STOOD ON PICKET LINES
TO
FIGHT FOR COLLECTIVE
BARGAINING.
THE
PEOPLE OF OHIO STOOD ON
ELECTION DAY
TO FIGHT FOR
COLLECTIVE
BARGAINING.
COLLEAGUES, LET
US TOGETHER
STAND
TODAY AGAINST THIS
LEGISLATION AND FOR
COLLECTIVE
BARGAINING
AND THE AMERICAN
MIDDLE
CLASS.
I
YIELD BACK.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN YIELDS
BACK THE BALANCE OF HIS TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA,
MR. KLINE, IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: MR. CHAIRMAN, AT
THIS TIME I'M
PLEASED TO YIELD
TWO MINUTES
TO THE GENTLELADY
FROM
ALABAMA, MRS. ROBY.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
ALABAMA IS RECOGNIZED FOR
TWO
MINUTES.
MRS. ROBY:
THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
MR.
CHAIRMAN, I RISE
TODAY IN
SUPPORT OF
H.R. 3094, THE WORK
FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND FAIRNESS
ACT, A BILL
I PROUDLY SPONSOR.
AS A REPRESENTATIVE
FROM
ALABAMA, A RIGHT TO
WORK STATE,
THE CONTINUED
ACTIVIST AGENDA
OF THE NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS
BOARD IS
ALARMING.
ITS PROPOSED RULES
ARE A CLEAR
EXAMPLE
THAT THE WHITE HOUSE
AND
THE NLRB ARE
COMMITTED TO A
CULTURE
OF UNION FAVORITISM.
THE
NLRB'S PROPOSALS UNDERMINE
THE RIGHTS OF
EMPLOYERS AND
EMPLOYEES BY EMPOWERING
UNIONS
TO
MANIPULATE THE WORK FORCE
FOR
THEIR OWN GAIN.
THE
WORK FORCE DEMOCRACY AND
FAIRNESS ACT IS
ONE OF MANY
BILLS PUT FORWARD
BY MY
REPUBLICAN COLLEAGUES THAT
WILL
PREVENT THE NLRB
FROM IMPOSING
SWEEPING CHANGES
TO OUR
NATION'S
WORKPLACES.
ADDITIONALLY AND MOST
IMPORTANTLY, THIS BILL
RESTORES
KEY
LABOR PROTECTIONS THAT BOTH
WORKERS AND
EMPLOYERS HAVE
ENJOYED FOR
DECADES.
I WANT TO
SAY THAT AGAIN.
THIS BILL
RESTORES KEY LABOR
PROTECTIONS THAT BOTH
WORKERS
AND
EMPLOYERS HAVE ALREADY
ENJOYED FOR
DECADES.
CONGRESS HAS THE
RESPONSIBILITY
TO
ENSURE THAT THE NLRB'S LABOR
INTERESTS ARE
NOT UNDERMINING
AN EMPLOYER'S
EFFORTS TO CREATE
JOBS
AND GROW THEIR
BUSINESSES.
AT
A TIME WHEN APPROXIMATELY 14
MILLION AMERICANS
ARE
UNEMPLOYED AND
SEARCHING FOR
WORK, NOT TO MENTION THE
MILLIONS THAT HAVE
GIVEN UP,
CONGRESS MUST IMPLEMENT
POLICIES THAT
ENCOURAGE NEW
JOBS,
NOT HINDER THEM.
THIS
LEGISLATION WILL REIN IN
THE ACTIVIST
NLRB AND WE AFFIRM
PROTECTIONS
WORKERS AND JOB
CREATORS HAVE
RECEIVED FOR
DECADES.
THANK YOU, MR. CHAIRMAN,
AND I
YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLELADY FROM
ALABAMA YIELDS BACK HER
TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. MILLER: I YIELD TWO MINUTES
TO THE GENTLEWOMAN FROM
CALIFORNIA, MS. WOOLSEY,
THE
RANKING SUBCOMMITTEE MEMBER
OF THE
COMMITTEE.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLELADY IS
RECOGNIZED FOR TWO
MINUTES.
MS. WOOLSEY: H.R.
3094, THE
SO-CALLED WORK
FORCE DEMOCRACY
AND FAIRNESS
ACT, WHAT A GREAT
TITLE FOR
LEGISLATION THAT
ASSAULTS THE
MAJORITY'S
YEAR-LONG WAR AGAINST
UNIONS,
AGAINST
WORKERS AND THE
NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS BOARD.
THIS IS JUST THE
LATEST OF
THAT, AND
THEY GAVE IT THIS
WONDERFUL
TITLE.
SINCE THEY TOOK
CONTROL OF THIS
BODY
IN JANUARY, MY COLLEAGUES
ON THE OTHER
SIDE OF THE AISLE
HAVE BEEN DOING EVERYTHING IN
THEIR POWER TO
STACK THE DECK
BEGINS LABOR
UNIONS AND THOSE
WHO ASPIRE TO
JOIN THEM.
SEEMINGLY, THE
BILLS THEY BRING
TO THE FLOOR
ARE DESIGNED
TO
MAKE LIFE
EASIER FOR THE
CORPORATE SPECIAL
INTERESTS
AND, AS
USUAL, HARD-EARNED
WORKERS WHO JUST
WANT A FAIR
SHAKE.
CURIOUS, SINCE
THE LABOR
MOVEMENT
IS THE MOST POWERFUL
FORCE
FOR ECONOMIC SECURITY AND
UPPER
MOBILITY THAT WE HAVE IN
THIS COUNTRY AND
UNIONS ARE THE
REASON THERE IS A
STRONG MIDDLE
CLASS
IN THE UNITED STATES OF
AMERICA THAT
THEY WOULD WANT TO
ATTACK IT.
WE NEED TO
REMOVE OBSTACLES TO
UNION
ELECTIONS AND WE NEED TO
CREATE
WAYS FOR MEMBERS TO JOIN
UNIONS, NOT
PREVENT THEM FROM
BEING UNION
MEMBERS.
IT'S BAFFLING
TO ME THAT
MY
REPUBLICAN FRIENDS
FROM
ABSOLUTELY NO
PLANS TO CREATE
ANY KIND OF
JOB, BUT A
CAREFULLY
ORCHESTRATED PLAN TO
UNDERMINE THE
RIGHTS AND
PROTECTIONS OF
WORKING PEOPLE.
INSTEAD OF
HELPING PEOPLE WHO
ARE REELING
FROM THIS SLUGGISH
ECONOMY, THEY
WORK TO CREATE
DISTRACTIONS
AND TO CREATE
SCAPEGOATS.
MR. SPEAKER,
WORKERS DESERVE
BETTER
THAN A GOVERNMENT OF, BY
AND
THE WEALTHIEST 1%.
VOTE NO ON
H.R. 3094.
MR.
CHAIRMAN, I'D LIKE TO ASK
UNANIMOUS CONSENT
TO ENTER
A
LETTER FROM THE
A.F.L. THAT
EXPRESSES THEIR
VIEWS AGAINST
THIS
LEGISLATION.
I'D LIKE TO
ENTER THEIR WORDS
INTO
THE
RECORD.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLELADY'S
REQUEST
WILL BE COVERED
BY
GENERAL
LEAVE AND THE TIME HAS
EXPIRED BY
THE GENTLELADY FROM
CALIFORNIA.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: MR. CHAIRMAN,
I'M
VERY PLEASED
TO YIELD TO
ANOTHER
MEMBER OF THE COMMITTEE
ONE
MINUTE, THE GENTLEMAN FROM
NEVADA, DR.
HECK.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
NEVADA IS RECOGNIZED FOR ONE
MINUTE.
MR. HECK: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
MR. CHAIRMAN, I RISE TODAY TO
POSE AN IMPORTANT QUESTION TO
NEVADANS
-- HOW WOULD YOU FEEL
ABOUT
HAVING ONLY
10 DAYS'
NOTICE THAT AN ELECTION
WOULD
BE
HELD?
THAT WOULD GIVE YOU
ONLY 10
DAYS TO
RESEARCH THE CANDIDATES
AND FIND OUT WHERE THEY
STAND
ON THE
ISSUES.
10 DAYS
TO DECIDE WHO BEST
REPRESENTS
YOU, YOUR VOICE,
YOUR
VALUES.
AND
TO MY DISTINGUISHED
COLLEAGUES IN THIS BODY,
HOW DO
YOU THINK
YOUR CONSTITUENTS
WOULD REACT
IF WE CHANGED THE
LAW SO
THAT THEY HAD ONLY 10
DAYS' NOTICE THAT
AN ELECTION
WOULD BE
HELD?
IT
WOULD BE UNCONSCIONABLE FOR
CONGRESS TO ADVOCATE ITS
RESPONSIBILITY
AND ALLOW A
BOARD
OF UNELECTED BUREAUCRATS
TO DO
SOMETHING THAT THIS BODY
WOULD NEVER DO
ITSELF.
THAT'S
THE DEBATE TODAY,
WHETHER OR NOT
CONGRESS ALLOWS
THE
NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS
BOARD TO RADCALLY CHANGE THE
WAY UNION
-- RADICALLY CHANGE
THE
WAY UNION ELECTIONS ARE
GOVERNED WITH LITTLE OR
NO
INPUT FROM
THOSE MOST AFFECTED
BY BY
THIS DECISION.
I ASK MY
COLLEAGUES TO VOTE YES
FOR
THE WORK FORCE DEMOCRACY
AND
FAIRNESS
ACT.
I
YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
NEVADA YIELDS BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. MILLER: TWO
MINUTES TO THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
NEW JERSEY, MR.
PAYNE,
A MEMBER OF THE
COMMITTEE.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
NEW JERSEY IS RECOGNIZED FOR
TWO
MINUTES.
MR. PAYNE:
THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
THE
H.R. 3094, THE WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND
FAIRNESS ACT,
REALLY
AS YOU KNOW SHOULD BE
CALLED THE
ELECTION PREVENTION
ACT.
I'M GRATEFUL CONCERNED
ABOUT
TODAY'S --
I'M GRAVELY
CONCERNED ABOUT TODAY'S
LEGISLATIVE
PROPOSAL.
CURRENT LAW SAYS THAT
WORKERS
SHOULD
BE ABLE TO ASSOCIATE
WITH
OTHER UNITS, ENTER ANY
APPROPRIATE
BARGAINING UNIT.
THIS BILL SAYS
THAT EVERY
WORKER
SHOULD BE IN A
BARGAINING UNIT
UNLESS PROVEN
OTHERWISE.
THAT'S JUST THE
REVERSE OF THE
WAY
LAW SHOULD BE.
IT ALLOWS
EMPLOYERS TO STUFF
THE
BALLOT BOXES WITH
WORKERS
WHO
ARE NOT ENGAGED IN THE
ORGANIZING
DRIVE IN THE FIRST
PLACE,
THEREFORE, LIKELY TO
VOTE NO.
IT INCREASES THE
CHANCES THAT
WORKERS
PETITION FOR AN
ELECTION
WILL BE
REJECTED WHICH
THE
NLRB HAS PROPOSED RULE
WHICH IS
WOULD ELIMINATE
LOOPHOLES IN CURRENT
LAW THAT
ALLOWS UNSCRUPULOUS
EMPLOYERS
TO DELAY ELECTIONS, FRUSTRATING
WORKERS'
EFFORTS TO ORGANIZE
THIS
WOULD IMPOSE ARBITRARY
DELAYS
AND BLOCK THOSE PENDING
NLRB
RULES TO ELIMINATE
AVOIDABLE
DELAYS.
THE FACT OF
THE MATTER IS THIS
BILL
ENCOURAGES FRIVOLOUS
LITIGATION.
THE ORIGINAL BILL PROVIDES
EMPLOYERS WITH AN
UNQUALITIED
RIGHT
TO RAISE A NEW ISSUE AT
ANY POINT
IN THE PRE-ELECTION
HEARING IN ORDER TO DRAG
OUT
THE HEARING.
THIS WOULD INCLUDE
ANY ISSUE
THAT MAY
REASONABLY BE EXPECTED
TO IMPACT THE
ELECTION'S
OUTCOME THIS BILL DOES
NOT
LIMIT THESE PROBLEMS
BUT STATES
THAT
THESE ISSUES, EVEN WHEN
IMMATERIAL TO AN ELECTION
ARE
CONSIDERED
RELEVANT.
BASED
ON THIS FACT, A HEARING
COULD GO
ON INDEFINITELY.
THAT'S WHAT THE PURPOSE
OF THIS
IS
FURTHERMORE, PARTIES COULD
BRING
UP ISSUES SUCH AS
ECONOMIC
CONDITIONS, UNFAIR
LABOR
PRACTICES OR OTHER ITEMS
NOT NORMALLY
CONSIDERED IN
HEARINGS.
THIS SEEMS TO REQUIRE
THAT THE
BOARD MUST FINISH
A REQUEST FOR
REVIEW
BEFORE ANY ELECTION CAN
BE
DIRECTED.
THIS
WILL ENCOURAGE EMPLOYEES
TO FILE
REQUESTS,
MR. CHAIRMAN,
I ASK
UNANIMOUS CONSENT TO ADD
THREE
LETTERS INTO THE RECORD.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN'S --
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN'S
REQUEST IS COVERED
UNDER
GENERAL LEAVE.
THE GENTLEMAN'S TIME HAS
EXPIRED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
RESERVES, THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA.
MR. PAYNE: MAY I HAVE 15
SECONDS, MR. CHAIRMAN.
&gt;&gt; I YIELD THE GENTLEMAN
SECONDS.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR
15 SECONDS.
MR. PAYNE: I'D LIKE TO
INCLUDE
IN THE RECORD A
LETTER FROM THE
NATIONAL
OTHER
SPACE WORKERS A
LETTER FROM A
BUILDING AND
CONSTRUCTION
TRADE, PRESIDENT
MARK
AYERS, AN AN -- A LETTER
FROM THE
SCIU'S INTERNATIONAL
PRESIDENT.
YIELD
BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN
CONTINUES TO
RESERVE.
THE GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
&gt;&gt;
MR. CHAIRMAN, I'D LIKE TO
YIELD TWO MINUTES TO
ANOTHER
DISTINGUISHED MEMBER
OF THE
COMMITTEE, THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
FLORIDA, MR. ROSS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN VECK --
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN VECK
NICED FOR TWO MINUTES.
MR. ROSS: THANK YOU MR.
CHAIRMAN AN THANK YOU FOR
BRINGING FORTH
THIS MOST
NECESSARY LEGISLATION.
I RISE IN SUPPORT
OF HOUSE
RESOLUTION
3094.
SIMPLY PUT THE
NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS BOARD HAS LOST ALL
CREDIBILITY.
FROM ITS ANTI-AMERICAN ATTACK
ON
BOEING TO ITS
INABILITY TO
ALLOW DELTA
EMPLOYEES TO CHOOSE
THEIR
OWN LABOR
FUTURE, THE
NLRB HAS BECOME
NOTHING MORE
THAN
A TAXPAYER FUNDED BIG
PAYER
ADVOCATE.
THIS ACT
IS JUST WHAT IT SAYS
IT IS,
LEGISLATION THAT IF
PASSED WILL
ENSHRINE THE RIGHTS
OF
WORKERS TO
BOTH INFORMATION
AND
CHOICE, TWO THINGS MY
FRIENDS ON
THE OTHER SIDE OF
THE AISLE BELIEVE IN AS
WELL.
WHAT'S
TRULY SAD IS THAT
TAXPAYERS
ALREADY LIVING UNDER
THE EXPLODING
DEBT ARE PAYING
THE
SALARIES OF NLRB ATTORNEYS
AND
ADMINISTRATORS TO SHIP JOBS
OVERSEAS.
THE
PROPOSED RULE
REQUIRING
LECH BE
HELD IN AS LITTLE AS 10
DAYS
GIVES WORKERS VIRTUALLY NO
OPPORTUNITY TO INFORM
THEMSELVES ABOUT THEIR
RIGHT,
SHOW HOW
RADICAL THIS NLRB HAS
BECOME, WE
MUST ASK OURSELVES
WHEN, IN THE HISTORY
OF THIS
GREAT REPUBLIC,
HAS SHORTENING
THE
TIME FOR AN ELECTION BEEN
CONSIDERED
MORE FAIR?
WE HEAR
MEMBERS FROM THE OTHER
SIDE OF THE AISLE SAYING EVEN
REQUIRING
SOME TO SHOW
IDENTIFICATION TO
VOTE IS
UNFAIR
AND RESTRICTIVE BUT
DRASTICALLY
CUTTING SHORT THE
TIME FOR AN ELECTION IS
MORE
FAIR?
AS IF THAT WAS NOT RADICAL
ENOUGH, THE DECISION
ON
MICROUNIONS OVERTURNS
30 YEARS
OF SUCCESSFUL
PRECEDENT.
FOR EXAMPLE, AT RETAIL
STORES,
MULTIPLE LABOR
UNIONS COULD
TARGET
AND ORGANIZE DIFFERENT
GROUPS
OF WORKERS.
DEPARTMENT
MANAGERS, STOCK
CLERKS AND SECURITY
GUARDS
COULD
FORM SEPARATE UNIONS THIS
WILL PIT
WORKER AGAINST WORKER
AND THEY'LL SPEN
MORE TIME
WORKING WITH UNIONS
THAN
FOCUSING ON
THEIR JOBS AN
BUSINESS.
THE QUESTION WE MUST ASK
IS
WHAT ARE THEY SO
AFRAID OF?
THE ANSWER
IS, THEY ARE AFRAID
OF AN AMERICAN
WORKER FREE TO
WORK HARD
AND EARN THE FRUITS
OF
THAT LABOR.
THEY'RE AFRAID OF THE
AMERICAN
WORKER GIVEN
THE RIGHT TO
CHOOSE
THEIR OWN FUTURE.
I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT ANYONE ELSE,
BUT
I TRUST THE AMERICAN WORKER
TO MAKE THE
RIGHT DECISION.
I DON'T
TRUST THE GOVERNMENT.
I
YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
RESERVES.
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. MILLER
: I YIELD TWO MINUTES
TO THE
GENTLEMAN, MR. KUCINICH.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
--
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KUCINICH: THE
RIGHT TO
ORGANIZE IS
A FUNDAMENTAL RIGHT
OF
SOCIETY.
WORKERS'
RIGHTS ARE HUMAN
RIGHTS.
THIS BILL
SEEKS TO FRUSTRATE
WORKERS RIGHTS TO
AN LECH
THROUGH
ATTACKING THE NATIONAL
LABOR RELATIONS BOARD.
TODAY,
WORKERS HAVE TO WAIT AN
AVERAGE OF
121 DAYS TO CAST A
BAT LOT IN AN
ELECTION.
DAYS TO WAIT FOR UNION
REPRESENTATION.
HOW LONG SHOULD WORK
VERSE TO
WAIT TO BE ABLE
TO ASSERT
THEIR
FUNDAMENTAL RIGHTS IN
A
DEMOCRATIC SOCIETY, IF
WE
REALLY
BELIEVE IN DEMOCRACY?
SOME OF US BELIEVE
THAT WHEN A
MAJORITY
OF WORKERS WANT TO BE
ABLE
TO HAVE A UNION, THEY
SHOULD
BE ABLE
TO DO SO
FORTHWITH.
WE
BELIEVE IN GOVERNMENT OF THE
PEOPLE.
WHY, THEN,
WOULD CORPORATIONS
WANT TO BLOCK
OR FRUSTRATE THE
RIGHT
OF WORKERS TO ORGANIZE?
I THINK
IT'S OBVIOUS.
WHEN WORKERS ARE
ORGANIZED THEY
HAVE THE ABILITY TO BE
ABLE TO
PARTICIPATE IN
BEING ABLE TO
SAY WHAT THEIR
WAGES ARE WORTH.
THIS IS ABOUT
WAGES, IT'S ABOUT
BENEFITS, IT'S ABOUT
WORKPLACE
SAFETY,
ABOUT WORKING
CONDITIONS.
WORKERS' RIGHTS ARE HUMAN
RIGHTS.
THIS
ASSAULT ON THE NLRB IS
TRANSLATED INTO
A FUNDAMENTAL
ASSAULT ON
OUR DEMOCRACY.
IF
WE BELIEVE IN DEMOCRACY, WE
BELIEVE
IN A RIGHT
TO ORGANIZE
A RIGHT
TO COLLECTIVE BAR
GEANING, A RIGHT
TO DECENT
WAGES
AN BENEFIT A RIGHT TO A
SECURE ENVIRONMENT A RIGHT
TO
WORKERS TO
PARTICIPATE IN A
SECURE ENVIRONMENT.
THIS IS AMERICA, LET'S LIFT
UP
THE STANDARD OF
WORKERS, NOT
ATTACK IT BY
MAKING THE DAY OF
THEIR ELECTION AND CLAIMING A
UNION FARTHER AND FARTHER
AWAY,
ALMOST TO THE POINT
OF
NULLIFICATION.
STAND UP FOR
HE AMERICAN
WORKERS, DEFEAT THIS BILL.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
OHIO YIELDS BACK.
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
RESEVENS.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: I YIELD
TWO MINUTES
TO THE DISTINGUISHED GENTLEMAN
FROM
VIRGINIA, MR. HURT.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR TWO
MINUTES.
MR. HURT: I RISE IN
SUPPORT OF
THE
BILL OFFERED BY CHAIRMAN
KLINE AND THANK HIM FOR
HIS
LEADERSHIP ON THIS ISSUE.
WE HAVE SEEN A
VAST EXPANSION
IN THE
SIZE AND SCOPE OF THE
FOVET WHICH HAS RESULTED IN
A
SUFFERING ECONOMY
AND JOB
MARKET
AND UNFRIENDLY BUSINESS
ENVIRONMENT FOR JOB CREATION
AND INVESTMENT.
A
RECENT TROUBLING EXAMPLE OF
THE OVERREACH IS
THE NATIONAL
LABOR RELATION BOARD'S RULE
MAKING WHICH
WOULD ALTER THE
PROCEDURES THAT GOVERN UNION
ELECTIONS.
THIS WOULD DO LITTLE MORE
THAN
EMPOWER BIG LABOR
BOSSES BY
RESTRICTING
EMPLOYERS FROM
TALKING TO EMPLOYEES IN THE
PROCESS,
PREVENTING THEM
GAINING ACCESS
TO CRITICAL
INFORMATION
NECESSARY FOR THEIR
VOTES AND
DIMINISHING THE
FUNDAMENTAL
RIGHTS OF EMPLOYEES
AND EMPLOYERS
AROUND THE
COUNTRY
THIS GOVERNMENT
INTERVENTION IN THE WORKPLACE
IS AN
ATTACK ON OUR ECONOMIC
FREEDOM AND WILL
ONLY PROVIDE
MORE
UNCERTAINTY IN OUR ECONOMY
AT
A TIME WHEN WE ARE
STRUGGLING TO RECOVER.
WITH
FAR TOO MANY FIFTY
DISTRICT
VIRGINIANS AND
AMERICANS OUT
OF WORK WE
MUST
PUT AN END
TO ARBITRARY RULE
MAKING THAT COMPRISE
THE
NLRB.
WE MUST PROVIDE
OUR JOB
CREATORS THE OPPORTUNITY
TO
HIRE AND
GROW OUT THE
UNCERTAINTY CAUSED
BY
UNNECESSARY AN BURDEN SOMEBODY
GOVERNMENT REGULATIONS.
WE MUST PRESERVE THE
PROTECTIONS AND
FREEDOMS THAT
AMERICAN
WORKERS DESERVE,
ALLOWING THEM TO
PARTICIPATE IN
A
FULL AN FAIR ELECTION
PROCESS.
I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO SUPPORT
THIS
IMPORTANT LEGISLATION AND
I
YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM VIRGINIA
YIELDS
BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA --
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
VIRGINIA
YIELDS BACK HIS TIME
THEY FEEL
GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA
RESERVES.
MR. MILLER: I YIELD ONE MINUTE
TO MS. PELOSI.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLELADY IS
RECOGNIZED.
MS. PELOSI: I THANK
THE
GENTLEMAN FOR
YIELDING AND FOR
HIS LEADERSHIP
ON BEHALF OF
WORKING
FAMILIES AND FOR
BRINGING THE OPPOSITION
TO THIS
LEGISLATION
TO THE FLOOR TODAY.
MR. SPEAKER,
AND MY COLLEAGUES,
MORE THAN
75 YEARS AGO,
PRESIDENT
FRANKLIN ROOS VELL
SIGNED A BILL
WHICH CREATED THE
NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS
BOARD
AND SAID HE
DID SO TO GIVE
EVERY
WORKER THE FREEDOM OF
CHOICE AND
ACTION WHICH IS
JUSTLY
HIS.
TODAY WE SAY
WHICH IS JUSTLY
HIS
OR HERS.
THAT WAS
A VERY IMPORTANT
MOMENT FOR
WORKERS BECAUSE IT
SAID
THAT THEY COULD NEGOTIATE,
THEY COULD
BARGAIN
COLLECTIVELY.
GIVING GREAT LEVERAGE
TO
WORKERS IN
OUR COUNTRY.
AN IT WAS NECESSARY.
THE
FREEDOM OF CHOICE IN ACTION
HAS RESTED AT THE
CORE OF A
GROWING,
THRIVING AMERICAN WORK
FORCE.
IT HAS CREATED
THE AMERICAN
MIDDLE
CLASS THAT HAS MADE OUR
COUNTRY
GREAT AND IS THE BACK
BONE OF
OUR DEMOCRACY.
THIS LEGISLATION ON
THE FLOOR
TODAY
UNDERMINES FREEDOM OF
CHOICE IN
ACTION.
IT
WILL WEAKEN OUR MIDDLE CLASS
AND AGAIN
WEAKEN OUR DEMOCRACY.
FOR MONTHS
IN WISCONSIN, OHIO
AND OTHER
STATES NATIONWIDE,
AMERICANS HAVE SEEN REPUBLICAN
GOVERNORS
AND LEGISLATURES
ATTACK
TEACHERS, FIREFIGHTERS,
AND POLICE OFFICERS
AND OTHER
PUBLICER IS
VABTS.
AND WE'VE --
SERVANTS AND WE'VE
SEEN AMERICAN
WORKERS, UNION
AND
NONUNION ALIKE, FIGHT BACK,
INSPIRING THE NATION.
MY COLLEAGUES ON THE OTHER
SIDE
OF THE AISLE
HAVE PROMOTED MANY
MYTHS ABOUT
WHAT THEIR
MISGUIDED
LEGISLATION THAT
THEY'RE
BRINGING FORWARD
TODAY
AND HOW IT
WILL IMPACT THE
NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS
BOARD.
SO I'D
LIKE TO CLARIFY A FEW
FACTS.
FIRST, THE BILL
-- THIS BILL
MANDATES DELAY.
RATHER THAN MINIMIZES
IT.
IT
ENCOURAGES FRIVOLOUS
LITIGATION
RATHER THAN
DISCOURAGES
IT.
IT
CONVOLUTES AND DISTORT
ELECTIONS RATHER
THAN
SIMPLIFYING THEM.
SIMPLY PUT, THIS
LEGISLATION
WOULD
DENY WORKERS THEIR RIGHT
TO A
FREE AND FAIR ELECTION TO
FORM A UNION.
IT
ADDS EXTENSIVE DELAY TO THE
PROCESS AS
WORKERS ORGANIZE
WITH THE
CLEAR INTENTION OF, IF
MY COLLEAGUE,
CONGRESSMAN
GEORGE
MILLER, THE RANKING
MEMBER
OF THE LABOR --
EDUCATION
AND LABOR COMMITTEE
HAS SAID,
WEARING DOWN WORKERS
SO THEY GIVE UP
FIGHTING FOR A
BETTER DEAL.
IT'S AN
AGE-OLD TACTIC.
IT
MUST BE REJECTED.
AT
A TIME WHEN AMERICANS ARE
DEMANDING JOBS AND JOB
GROWTH,
ECONOMIC
GROWTH FOR OUR
COUNTRY,
TODAY'S LEGISLATION IS
THE
LONG -- WRONG PRIORITY.
WE NEED TO BE
SOLVING THE
PROBLEM AN CHALLENGE
OF
CREATING
JOBS AND NOT ADDING TO
THE
PROBLEMS AS THIS BILL WOULD
DO.
THERE'S A
GREAT DEAL OF WORK TO
BE
DONE, REIGNITING THE
AMERICAN DREAM.
IGNITING THE AMERICAN DREAM
IS
WHAT
FRANKLIN ROOSEVELT DID
WHEN HE SIPED THIS
BILL AND
MANY OTHER
INITIATIVES OF THAT
ERA.
AND THEY
CORRECTED MANY ILLS IN
OUR ECONOMY
AND OUR SOCIETY AND
COMMUNITIES
ACROSS THE
COUNTRY
IN
TERMS OF FAIRNESS.
FAIRNESS
, AN AMERICAN VALUE.
SO WE
WANT TO REIGNITE THE
AMERICAN
DREAM TO BUILD LADDERS
OF
SUCCESS FOR
ALL WHO WANT TO
WORK
HARD, PLAY BY THE RULES,
REMOVE
OBSTACLES TO FULLER
PARTICIPATION IN OUR
ECONOMY SO
THAT MANY
MORE
WORKERS CAN
PARTICIPATE IN
AMERICA'S
PROSPERITY.
THIS IS
ABOUT, AGAIN,
STRENGTHENING THE
MIDDLE CLASS,
THE BACK
BONE OF
OUR DEMOCRACY,
INSTEAD THIS LEGISLATION
WILL
HAVE
THE OPPOSITE EFFECT OF
ERODING
RIGHTS AND OPPORTUNITY.
I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO VOTE
NO.
I YIELD
BACK THE MANS OF MY
TIME.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLELADY FROM
CALIFORNIA
YIELDS BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM CALIFORNIA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: CAN I INQUIRE AS TO
THE
TIME REMAINING ON
EACH
SIDE.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN
FROM
MINNESOTA HAS 13
1/2 MINUTES.
AND
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
CALIFORNIA HAS
14 3/4 MINUTES
LEFT.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA.
MR. KLINE: I'LL
BE SUBMITTING
TO THE RECORD THIS
LETTER FROM
THE POLISH
DEMOCRATIC WORK
FORCE
WITH 243 ASSOCIATIONS IN
SUPPORT OF THIS
LEGISLATION.
NOW
I'M PLEASED TO YIELD TWO
MINUTES TO
ANOTHER MEMBER OF
THE
COMMITTEE,
DISTINGUISHED GENTLEMAN
FROM
INDIANA, DR.
BROW SHON.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN'S
REQUEST IS
COVERED UNDER
GENERAL LEAVE.
THE GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED.
MR.
BREW SHON: THE NATIONAL --
&gt;&gt;
THE NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS
BOARD
HAS HAD A BIAS IN
DECISION
MAKING.
THOUGH THIS
ADDRESSES SEVERAL
ONEROUS
RULES I WANT TO FOCUS
ON
ONE IN PARTICULAR.
AUGUST 1 OF THIS YEAR, THE
BRD
OVERTURNED DECADES OF
PRECEDENT
WITH ITS DECISION IN
THE
HEALTH CARE CASE AND BY
STANDING UP TO THIS WE
CAN STOP
AN OUT
OF CONTROL AGENCY FROM
CAUSING
IRREPARABLE HARM TO
WORKERS ACROSS THE NATION.
MR. BUCSHON: THEY WILL
NO
LONGER -- THIS
WILL ENCOURAGE
UNIONS TO CREATE THE
SMALLEST
SO-CALLED MICROUNIONS
POSSIBLE
AND COULD RESULT IN EMPLOYERS
HAVING TO NEGOTIATE
WITH
MULTIPLE UNITS
WITHIN THEIR OWN
BUSINESS,
AND THIS UNDERMINES
THE
WORKERS' ABILITY TO THINK
ABOUT
WHETHER TO JOIN A UNION
AND
MAY POTENTIALLY FRACTURE
THE
WORK FORCE.
H
R. 3094 REINSTATES, I SHOULD
SAY
AGAIN,
REINSTATES THE
DECISIONAL STANDARD FOR
DERCHG
EMPLOYEES
MAKE UP AN
APPROPRIATE BARGAINING
UNIT.
THIS BILL IS
ABOUT FAIRNESS FOR
WORKERS AND
EMPLOYERS.
IT
RETURNS THE BOARD TO THE
PRECEDENT
THAT IT HAS OPERATED
ON FOR THE
LAST 20 TO 30 YEARS
URN BOTH REPUBLICAN AND
DEMOCRATIC
ADMINISTRATIONS.
RETURNING TO THIS PRECEDENT
WILL PROVIDE
CERTAINTY AND
CLARITY
TO WORKERS AND
EMPLOYERS AND
IT WILL UNDUE --
DUN DO THE
BIASED BEHAVIOR OF
THE
CURRENT BOARD.
I SUPPORT
THIS BILL
AND URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO
DO THE SAME.
I YIELD
BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN YIELDS
BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
RESEVENS.
THE JELL FROM CALIFORNIA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. MILLER: I YIELD TWO
MINUTES
TO MR. HOLT.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR TWO
MINUTES.
MR. HOLT:
I THANK THE
GENTLEMAN.
TODAY THE MAJORITY
IS SHOWING
THE
AMERICAN PUBLIC AGAIN THAT
THE MAJORITY DOESN'T THINK WE
HAVE A
JOBS CRISIS
IN AMERICA.
GETTING AMERICANS PACK TO
WORK
IS NOT
THEIR TOP PRIORITY.
GETTING THE AMERICAN ECONOMY
BACK ON TRACK AND
CREATING JOBS
IS MY
FIRST, SECOND, AND THIRD
PRIORITY.
AND
UNTIL THE MAJORITY GETS TO
WORK, WE'RE NOT
GOING TO MOVE
THIS
COUNTRY FORWARD.
DEMOCRATS REMAIN
COMMITTED TO
CREATING
JOBS IMMEDIATELY AND
EXPANDING
EDUCATIONAL
OPPORTUNITY FOR ALL AMERICANS.
AND
RATHER THAN BRINGING TO THE
FLOOR
LEGISLATION TO HELP
CREATE
JOBS,
WE'RE WASTING TIME
WITH THIS ATTEMPT
TO UNDERMINE
WORKEST' RIGHT
THE RIGHT TO
ORGANIZE, TO HAVE SAFE
WORKING
CONDITIONS,
FAIR
WAGES, YOU
KNOW,
ON MONDAY NIGHT, I HAD A
TOWN HALL
AND NOT ONE PERSON,
NOT
ONE, WANTED TO TALK
WITH ME
ABOUT THE
NLRB OR ITS RULE
MAKING.
MANY WANTED TO TALK ABOUT JOB
CREATION.
WANTED TO MAKE SURE
WE WERE
INVESTING
IN OUR CHILDREN'S
EDUCATION.
I
OFFERED AN AMENDMENT TO THIS
BILL TO
HELP KEEP TEACHERS IN
THE
CHILDREN'S
CLASSROOMS.
I
OFFERED A REAL SOLUTION TO A
REAL PROBLEM.
NOT A SPECIAL INTEREST
GIVEAWAY
TO
BIG BUSINESS.
UNFORTUNATELY, THE MAJORITY
BLOCKED MY
AMENDMENT ON
PROCEDURAL
GROUNDS.
NOW ACROSS THE
COUNTRY,
BUDGET
CUTS AND
TEACHER LAYOFFS FORCED
SCHOOLS TO
REDUCE DAYS OF THE
SCHOOL
YEAR OR CUT
CLASSES IN
LITERACY OR
ARTS OR MUSIC OR
PHYSICAL EDUCATION
OR INCREASE
CLASS
SIZES OR REDUCE LIBRARY
HOURS.
MY AMENDMENT WOULD HAVE
INVESTED IN
A WORK FORCE --
IN
OUR WORK FORCE
, MY AMENDMENT
WOULD HAVE
SUPPORTED NEARLY
400,000 EDUCATION JOBS.
ENOUGH FOR
STATES TO AVOID
HARMFUL LAYOFFS
AND REHIRE TENS
OF THOUSANDS OF TEACHERS
WHO
LOST THEIR JOBS
OVER RECREN
YEARS.
I
HEARD FROM A STUDENT WHO
SAID,
TEACHER LAYOFFS IS A BAD
THING, HE SAID.
I HAD MANY
OVERSIZED CLASSES
THIS YEAR.
OUR
STUDENTS DON'T GET A SECOND
CHANCE TO
ACHIEVE IN SCHOOL.
OUR FUTURE DEPENDS
ON A
WELL-EDUCATED WORK FORCE.
THAT'S WHAT WE
SHOULD BE DOING
-- DEALING
WITH TODAY.
MY
AMENDMENT WOULD HAVE
SUPPORTED OUR CHILDREN,
THIS
BILL
IGNORES THOSE PLEAS FOR
HELP.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR.
KLINE: THANK YOU,
CHAIRMAN.
I AM PLEASED TO YIELD TO
ANOTHER DISTINGUISHED MEMBER
OF
THE COMMITTEE,
FOUR MINUTES,
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
SOUTH
CAROLINA, MR. GOWDY.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECK THESED FOR FOUR MINUTES.
MR. GOWDY:
THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
I WANT TO THANK CHAIRMAN KLINE
FOR HIS LEADERSHIP ON THIS AND
SO
MANY
ISSUES, OTHER ISSUES ON
THE
EDUCATION WORK FORCE
COMMITTEE.
MR. CHAIRMAN, WHEN SO MANY OF
OUR FELLOW CITIZENS ARE
LOOKING
FOR WORK, WHEN SO MANY
OF OUR
FELLOW CITIZENS
WANT NOTHING
MORE THAN
TO BE ABLE
TO MEET
THEIR
FAMILIARAL OBLIGATIONS AND
OBLIGATIONS TO THE --
FAMILYAL
OBLIGATIONS AND THEIR
OBLIGATIONS TO THE
DEMUENT, --
COMMUNITY, WHEN SO MANY
AMERICANS WANT NOTHING MORE
THAN
THE
MOST FUNDAMENTAL OF ALL
FAMILY
VALUES
WHICH A JOB AND
THEY LOOK AND THEY
SEE THAT
AMERICA IS
INCREASINGLY
COMPETING WITH
OTHER COUNTRIES
FOR WORK,
IT IS NO
LONGER JUST
COMPETITION AMONG
THE STATES.
WE'RE
COMPETING WITH OTHER
COUNTRIES
FOR WORK.
AND THE
NLRB CONTINUES TO PURSUE
AN
ACTIVIST, POLITICALLY
MOTIVATED AGENDA
, THWARTING
ECONOMIC RECOVERY
AND CONTINUING
TO PLACE OUR
COMPANIES AT A
COMPETITIVE DISADVANTAGE
WORLDWIDE AND,
MR. CHAIRMAN,
VIRTUALLY
EVERYONE IS FAMILY
WITH THE MOST
GLARING
EXAMPLE OF
NLRB OVERREACH
AND UNION
PANDERING
WHICH IS THE COMPLAINT
AGAINST BOEING,
DESPITE NOT A
SINGLE
EXAMPLE OF A JOB BEING
LOST
IN WASHINGTON STATE,
DESPITE NOT
A SINGLE EXAMPLE OF
A WORKER
LOSING A SINGLE BENEFIT
OR RIGHT
IN WASHINGTON STATE,
THE
NLRB SUED BOEING SEEKING TO
HAVE
BOEING CLOSE ITS SOUTH
CAROLINA
FACILITY, MOTHBALLING A
$1
BILLION FACILITY, DISPLACING
1,000 WORKERS AND
RETURN THE
WORK TO
WASHINGTON STATE.
AND THEN,
MR. CHAIRMAN, THEY HAD
THE
UNMITIGATED TEMERITY, AS WE
RECENTLY
LEARNED, TO JOKE ABOUT
IT
IN EMAILS.
TO JOKE
ABOUT A COMPETITOR
CALLED AIRBUS WHICH
IS BOEING'S
NUMBER
ONE COMPETITOR.
WANTING WORK
AND NOT GETTING IT
IS NOT
A LAUGHING MATTER.
BOEING IS
EXHIBIT A.
AMONG THE
EVIDENTRY REASONS THAT
THE
NLRB HAS OVERREACHED ITS
STATUTORY
MISSION, BUT IT IS NOT
THE ONLY
PIECE OF EVIDENCE, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
CURRENTLY UNION ELECTIONS TAKE
PLACE ON AVERAGE
WITHIN 31 DAYS
OF THE
FILING OF AN ELECTION
PETITION.
ADDITIONALLY UNIONS ARE
VICTORIOUS MORE
OFTEN THAN NOT
WHEN
THERE IS AN ELECTION, BUT,
MR. CHAIRMAN, THAT'S NOT GOOD
ENOUGH.
THE NLRB
WANTS MORE.
SO THEY PROPOSED
SWEEPING
CHANGES TO
THE ELECTION PROCESS,
SHIFTING THE
BALANCE OF POWER
EVEN FURTHER
TOWARDS UNION
SEEKING
EMPLOYEES BY PROMOTING
RUSH ELECTIONS AND RULING THAT
ELECTIONS CAN
TAKE PLACE IN AS
LITTLE AS SEVEN TO
10 DAYS, THE
BOARD SEVERELY LIMITS
THE
OPPORTUNITY FOR WORKERS
TO HEAR
ALL SIDES
OF AN
ISSUE AND THEY
CAN INFORM --
AND MAKE AN
INFORMED
DECISION.
ADDITIONALLY EMPLOYERS WOULD
ONLY HAVE SEVEN DAYS
TO RETAIN
LEGAL COUNCIL AND
DECIPHER THE
COMPLEX
LABYRINTH OF FEDERAL
LABOR LAW BEFORE PRESENTING
THEIR CASE BEFORE AN
NLRB
HEARING
OFFICER.
SO
EDUCATION WORK FORCE CHAIRMAN
JOHN KLINE SMARTLY
INTRODUCED
H.R. 3094,
THE WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY
AND FAIRNESS
ACT, TO
SIMPLY,
MR. CHAIRMAN, LEVEL THE
PLAYING FIELD.
THIS LEGISLATION
REQUIRES NO
UNION ELECTION
OCCUR LESS THAN
35 DAYS, THUS GRANTING
ALL
PARTIES THE ABILITY
TO PRESENT
THEIR ARGUMENTS AND
ENSURING
WORKERS HAVE THE
ABILITY TO
REACH AN
INFORMED DECISION.
H.R.
3094 ACKNOWLEDGING THAT
FULL
AND COMPLETE --
ACKNOWLEDGES
THAT FULL AND
COMPLETE INFORMATION IS
TREASURED WHEN EMPLOYEES
ARE
CONTEMPLATING HOW THEY
WILL
VOTE.
SOME UNIONS HAVE
ALREADY
ENDORSED
PRESIDENT OBAMA IN AN
ELECTION
THAT IS WELL NIHG A
YEAR OFFER
OFF BUT -- NIGH A
YEAR OFF BUT SOMEHOW 31 DAYS IS
TOO LONG FOR EMPLOYERS IN AN
ELECTION THAT'S EVER BIT AS
IMPORTANT TO THEM.
THE HYPOCRISY AND BLIND ADVOCACY
HAS TO STOP,
MR. CHAIRMAN.
THE
PURPOSE OF THE NLRA IS TO
BALANCE
THE RIGHTS OF EMPLOYERS,
EMPLOYEES
AND THE GENERAL
PUBLIC.
THE
NLRA IS NOT
CALCULATED TO
DRIVE UP
UNION MEMBERSHIP
BECAUSE
THEY'RE A LOYAL
CONSTITUENCY FOR THE
DEMOCRAT
PARTY.
BECAUSE THE
NLRB, THROUGH ITS
FILINGS
AND PROPOSED RULES
AND
REGULATIONS,
HAS LOST ALL
PRETEBS
OF -- PRETENS OF
OBJECTIVITY
AND LABOR ISSUES,
PIECES
OF LEGISLATION LIKE THIS
ONE ARE NECESSARY.
I YIELD BACK.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN YIELDS
BACK THE BALANCE OF HIS TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA IS
RECOGNIZED.
&gt;&gt; I YIELD TWO MINUTES
TO THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM
CONNECTICUT,
MS. DELAURO.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEWOMAN FROM
CONNECTICUT IS RECOGNIZED FOR
TWO MINUTES.
MS. DELAURO:
MR. SPEAKER, THIS
LEGISLATION WILL
DELAY WORKERS'
ATTEMPTS TO UNIIZE AND
WILL DENY
--
UNIONIZE AND DENY AMERICANS
THEIR
RIGHTS TO BARGAIN
COLLECTIVELY.
IN THE NEXT THREE WEEKS WE HAVE
JOBS LEGISLATION TO CONSIDER,
MIDDLE CLASS TAX CUTS AND
UNEMPLOYMENT BENEFITS TO EXTEND.
A 2012 BUDGET TO PASS.
THE LABOR EDUCATION, HEALTH AND
HUMAN SERVICES APPROPRIATIONS
SUBCOMMITTEE HAS NOT EVEN SEEN A
BILL YET.
AND YET
JUST AS THEY HAVE
ALL
YEAR
LONG, THE
MAJORITY HAS
CHOSEN TO WASTE
PRECIOUS TIME,
TIME THAT WE SHOULD BE
SPENDING
ON THE
PEOPLE'S BUSINESS, TO
CONTINUE THEIR
MISGUIDED WAR
AGAINST
WORKERS' RIGHTS.
ONCE
AGAIN THE MAJORITY'S PUT
FORWARD A BILL THAT
HAS NO OTHER
PURPOSE THAN
TO ROLL BACK
HARD-WON GAINS
BY AMERICAN
WORKERS AND
ERODE THE RIGHT OF
COLLECTIVE BARGAINING IN
THIS
COUNTRY.
THE LEGISLATION BEFORE US
ATTEMPTS TO
DENY THE RIGHT TO
FORM A CRUNE BY
IMPOSING
EXCESSIVE
DELAYS ON THE PROCESS,
STIFLING THE FLOW
OF INFORMATION
TO
WORKERS AND LOOKING THE OTHER
WAY WHILE
WORKERS' RIGHTS ARE
BEING
VIOLATED.
HOW LONG IS THIS
MAJORITY GOING
TO PERSIST
IN THIS WRONG-HEADED
CRUSADE AGAINST
HARDWORKING
AMERICAN MEN
AND
WOMEN?
THE SAME
HARDWORKING MEN AND
WOMEN WHO
BUILT THE MIDDLE CLASS
OF
THIS NATION.
MR. SPEAKER,
LAST MONTH THE
C.B.O. FOUND THAT WAGES
HAVE
STAGNATED
IN THIS COUNTRY AND
MEDIUM
INCOME HAS FALLEN IN
RECENT
TEAM, EVEN AS THE INCOME
OF THE TOP 1%
HAS TRIPLED.
IT IS NO
COINCIDENCE THAT THIS
HAS HAPPENED.
WHILE UNION MEMBERSHIP HAS
DECREASED.
BUT THE MAJORITY PERSISTS IN
TRYING TO
SQUEEZE MIDDLE CLASS
WORKERS
AND ACCELERATE THIS RACE
TO THE BOTTOM.
THIS IS NOT
THE AMERICAN WAY AND
IT IS
NOT WHAT THE
AMERICAN
PEOPLE
WANT.
IN OHIO LAST MONTH
THEY REJECTED
YET ANOTHER
REPUBLICAN ATTEMPT
TO EVISCERATE
THE RIGHT TO
COLLECTIVE
BARGAINING.
IT IS TIME TO STOP THESE
ATTACKS
ON BASIC
AMERICAN RIGHTS, IT'S
TIME TO ROLL UP OUR
SLEEVES AND
GET
TO WORK ON CREATING JOBS,
REDUCING THE
DEFICIT AND
RESTORING ECONOMIC
GROWTH TO
THIS NATION.
SAY NO TO THIS
LEGISLATION.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEWOMAN'S
TIME HAS EXPIRED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
I YIELD TO
ANOTHER
MEMBER OF THE
COMMITTEE, TWO MINUTES,
THE
DISTINGUISHED
GENTLEMAN FROM
PENNSYLVANIA, MR. PLATTS.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
PENNSYLVANIA IS RECOGNIZED FOR
TWO MINUTES.
MR. PLATTS: THANK YOU,
MR.
CHAIRMAN.
I APPRECIATE THE GENTLEMAN
YIELDING.
I CO-SPONSORED AND
RISE TODAY IN
SUPPORT
OF HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES BILL
BECAUSE IT
AIMS TO RESTORE KEY
PROTECTIONS TO THE
AMERICAN
WORKPLACE.
PROTECTIONS FOR BOTH
WORKERS AND
THEIR
EMPLOYERS FROM OVERREACH
BY THE
NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS
BOARD.
THIS LEGISLATION INTENDS TO
PROTECT JOB
GROWTH BY
DETERRING
HARMFUL
NLRB REGULATIONS.
THE
NLRB'S RECENT NOTICE OF
PROPOSED
RULE MAKING WOULD
SIGNIFICANTLY ALTER UNION
PROCEDURES, THUS
UNDERMINING THE
RIGHTS OF
EMPLOYERS AND
EMPLOYEES
ALIKE.
THE PROPOSED
RULES WILL UNABLY
SHORTEN THE TIME BETWEEN THE
FILING OF A PETITION
AND THE
ELECTION
DATE WHICH WILL LIMIT
THE OPPORTUNITY FOR A FULL
HEARING OF
CONTESTED ISSUES,
INCLUDING THE APPROPRIATE
BARGAINING
UNIT, VOTER
ELTJIBBLET
AND ELECTION
MISCONDUCT.
I SHARE THE CONCERNS OF
MY
CONSTITUENTS
REGARDING THE SHORT
AND --
SHOOTEREN --
SHORTENED
TIME FRAME FOR
ELECTIONS AND THE
POTENTIAL
IT MAY HAVE ON AN
EMPLOYERS' ABILITY
TO
COMMUNICATE
WITH HIS OR
HER OWN
EMPLOYEES REGARDING
UNIONIZATION.
H.R. 3094 AIMS TO ENSURE THAT
EMPLOYERS AND EMPLOYEES ARE ABLE
TO PARTICIPATE IN A FAIR UNION
ELECTION PROCESS.
BY PROVIDING 14 DAYS FOR
EMPLOYERS TO PREPARE
THEIR CASE
TO
PRESENT BEFORE THE
NLRB,
PROVIDING EMPLOYEES
WITH AT
LEAST
35 DAYS TO DELIBERATE OVER
THE
PROS AND CONS OF UNIONIZING
PRIOR
TO VOTING ON THIS ISSUE.
DISCOURAGING THE PRACTICE
OF
AMBUSH ELECTIONS AND
GUARANTEEING THE RIGHT OF
EMPLOYERS TO DISCUSS THE
PROS
AND CONS.
THIS LEGISLATION IS
NOT ABOUT
WHETHER EMPLOYEES
SHOULD HAVE
THE RIGHT
TO UNIONIZE
.
AS A
FORMER TEAMSTER MEMBER, I
CERTAINLY STRONGLY
SUPPORT THAT
RIGHT.
THIS
LEGISLATION
IS ABOUTING
EMPLOYEES
A FAIR AND DELIBERATE
OPPORTUNITY TO
MAKE THAT
DECISION
, ONE OF THE MOST
IMPORTANT DECISIONS
THEY'LL MAKE
IN THEIR LIFE
BECAUSE IT DEALS
WITH
THEIR
LIVELIHOOD.
OUTSIDE OF
FAMILY MATTERS AND
HEALTH
CONCERNS, DECIDING
WHERE
YOU WORK
AND IN WHAT TYPE OF
ENVIRONMENT IN WHICH
YOU WORK IS
GOING TO BE PROBABLY MORE
IMPORTANT THAN ANYTHING ELSE
YOU
DO RELATED TO
YOUR CAREER.
WHAT
THIS LEGISLATION SAYS IS,
WE THINK EMPLOYEES SHOULD
HAVE A
FAIR
OPPORTUNITY TO MAKE THAT
DECISION.
I SUPPORT THIS LEGISLATION AND
URGE A
YES VOTE.
I
YIELD BACK.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN YIELDS
BACK THE BALANCE OF HIS TIME.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. MILLER:
I YIELD TO THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM CALIFORNIA,
MS.
WATERS.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEWOMAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
MS. WATERS: I RISE IN STRONG
OPPOSITION TO
THE WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND FAIRNESS
ACT.
THIS BILL WOULD SEVERELY
UNDERMINE WORKERS'
RIGHTS TO
ORGANIZE
AND IF IMPLEMENTED WILL
EVENTUALLY SILENCE AND END
UNIONS AS WE KNOW
THEM.
CONGRESSMAN
GEORGE MILLER WAS
CREATE IN -- CORRECT IN
REFERRING TO THIS
BILL AS THE
ELECTION
PREVENTION ACT.
H.R.
3094 WOULD REQUIRE THE
NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS BOARD
TO HEAR
TRIVIAL APPEALS FROM
COMPANIES
IN ORDER TO STOP
ELECTIONS.
THIS IS AN
OUTRIGHT ASSAULT ON
MIDDLE CLASS
WORKERS AND THE
FAMILIES THEY
SUPPORT.
THE MIDDLE CLASS
IS IN DECLINE.
A
C.B.O. REPORT FOUND THAT
BETWEEN
1979 AND 2007 THE TOP 1%
OF EARNERS
EXPERIENCED INCOME
GROWTH OF
275%, THAT'S THE TOP
1%.
WHILE
THE MIDDLE INCOME
EARNERS
ONLY SAW
40% IN GROWTH OVER THE
SAME PERIOD.
STATISTICS LIKE THESE ARE
STARTLING AND
PAY A DIS-- PAINT
A DISTINCT PICTURE
OF THIS
COUNTRY AS ONE
THAT IS QUICKLY
EVOLVING INTO A
TWO-TEARED
SOCIETY
WITH NO ROOM AT THE TOP
AT
ALL FOR THE MIDDLE CLASS.
THE WORK FORCE DEMOCRACY
AND
FAIRNESS ACT IS
NOTHING MORE
THAN
AN OUTRIGHT ASSAULT ON THE
MIDDLE CLASS.
IF THIS MISGUIDED AND
DANGEROUS
LEGISLATION IS
PASSED, YOU WILL
SEE
AN EVEN MORE RAPID DECLINE
OF THE MIDDLE CLASS IN OUR
COUNTRY.
I URGE ALL MEMBERS OF THE HOUSE
TO REBUKE THIS
MISGUIDED
LEGISLATION AND
INSTEAD FOCUS ON
POLICIES THAT
FACILITATE JOB
GROWTH.
I
YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEWOMAN'S
TIME HAS EXPIRED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: MR. CHAIRMAN, AGAIN,
MAY I ASK
HOW MUCH TIME IS
REMAINING?
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA HAS SIX MINUTES
REMAINING.
AND
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
CALIFORNIA HAS
9 3/4 MINUTES
REMAINING.
MR. KLINE: I
HAVE TWO SPEAKERS
WHICH MAY OR MAY
NOT ARRIVE SO I
WILL BE
PREPARED TO CLOSE AND
I'LL RESERVE
.
MR. MILLER:
I'LL YIELD TO THE
MINORITY WHIP
TWO MINUTES.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MARYLAND IS RECOGNIZED FOR TWO
MINUTES.
MR. HOYER: I THANK THE GENTLEMAN
FOR
YIELDING.
MR. SPEAKER, I
RISE IN STRONG
OPPOSITION
TO THIS MISNAMED BILL
WHICH WOULD PROMOTE
NEITHER
DEMOCRACY
NOR FAIRNESS IN THE
WORKPLACE.
NOW, I HAVE JUST
BEEN ON THIS
FLOOR
A FEW MINUTES BUT IT'S
IRONIC THAT I'VE
HEARD SPEAKER
AFTER SPEAKER
IN FAVOR OF THIS
BILL
BUT WHO VOTE CONSISTENTLY
AGAINST WORKING
MEN AND
WOMEN'S
RIGHT TO ORGANIZE AND BARGAIN
COLLECTIVELY.
IRONIC PERHAPS
.
THE RIGHT OF WORKERS
TO ORGANIZE
AND BARGAIN
COLLECTIVELY FOR
BETTER AND FAIRER
CONDITIONS HAS
BEEN PROTECTED
BY OUR LAWS SINCE
THE
ERA OF THE NEW DEAL.
WHICH
WAS OPPOSED BY SO MANY.
THIS
LEGISLATION IS PART OF AN
AGENDA FRANKLY THAT THE
REPUBLICAN PARTY
CONTINUES TO
PURSUE
WHICH NO ECONOMIST
BELIEVES
CREATES JOBS IN THE
COMING YEAR.
THIS BILL
BEFORE US WON'T DO
ANYTHING TO
HELP THE ECONOMY OR
CREATE JOBS
, PERIOD.
AND
IT PLACES OBSTACLES IN FRONT
OF WORKERS
SEEKING TO EXERCISE
THEIR RIGHT
TO ORGANIZE.
NOW I WANT TO
POINT OUT TO MY
FRIENDS THAT
INTERESTINGLY
ENOUGH IN
TERMS OF TRYING TO
PROTECT
ELECTIONS, THERE'S ALL
ABOUT -- YOU CAN'T
HAVE AN
ELECTION BEFORE BUT THERE'S
NOTHING IN THIS
LEGISLATION YOU
HAVE
TO HAVE AN ELECTION BY.
THAT
WOULD PERHAPS BE MORE
CRITICAL.
IF SAID NOT SOONER
THAN THIS,
BUT
NOT LATER THAN THIS.
THAT WOULD SHOW
THAT YOU REALLY
WANTED
TO PURSUE ELECTIONS FOR
WORKING
MEN AND WOMEN SO THEY
COULD ORGANIZE AND
BARGAIN
COLLECTIVELY FOR PAY AND
BENEFITS AND
WORKING CONDITIONS.
BUT IT
DOESN'T SAY THAT.
IT SAYS, YOU
SIMPLY CAN'T HAVE
IT BEFORE.
IT NEVER SAYS
YOU HAVE TO HAVE
IT.
IT NEVER SAYS YOU
CAN'T DELAY IT
BY SUIT AFTER
SUIT AFTER SUIT.
IT NEVER SAYS
YOU'VE GOT TO GET
THE
ISSUE, IT NEVER SAYS YOU'VE
GOT TO GET
THE EMPLOYEES THE
RIGHT
BY A
CERTAIN DATE.
I ASK FOR
AN ADDITIONAL MINUTE.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MARYLAND IS RECOGNIZED FOR AN
ADDITIONAL MINUTE.
MR. HOYER: THIS BILL BEFORE US
WON'T DO ANYTHING TO
HELP THE
CAN ECONOMY OR CREATE JOBS, AS
I
SAID.
CONTINUE TO HAVE THE STRONGEST
FAITH IN THE AMERICAN
WORKER,
THAT THEY ARE THE
MOST TALENTED
AND
MOST PRODUCTIVE IN THE
WORLD.
WE
SHOULD NOT BE ROLLING BACK
THEIR
PROTECTIONS.
INSTEAD WE SHOULD
FOCUS ON
HELPING
TO GET MORE AMERICANS
BACK TO WORK
AND AS FOR THE NLRB
, THE
REAL TRAUMA IS IT IS NOW A
PRO-WORKER AND
EMPLOYER NLRB AS
OPPOSED TO
SIMPLY A PRO-EMPLOYER
NLRB.
THAT'S THE PROBLEM
YOU HAVE.
THE COURTS
SOUGHT TO ENSURE
EQUAL
TREATMENT.
THE
NLRB OUGHT TO ENSURE EQUAL
TREATMENT.
IT HAS NOT BEEN DOING
THAT FOR
SOME PERIOD OF
TIME.
AND NOW,
IN MY VIEW, IT IS.
GOD BLESS THEM.
THAT'S WHAT
THEY SHOULD DO.
EMPLOYERS
AND EMPLOYEES UGGET
TO
GET A FAIR SHAKE AND A FAIR
ELECTION.
AND I AGREE
WITH THAT PREMISE.
TIMING
IS OBVIOUSLY OF CONCERN
TO BOTH
PARTIES.
I WOULD HOPE THAT
WE WOULD
DEFEAT THIS
BILL AND THEN IF WE
WANT TO TALK
ABOUT ASSURING
ELECTIONS
, WE PROTECT DEMOCRACY
AND PROTECT
WORKERS.
I THANK
THE GENTLEMAN FOR
YIELDING HIS TIME.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN'S TIME
HAS EXPIRED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA.
MR. KLINE:
I RESERVE.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
CALIFORNIA.
MR. MILLER: I YIELD ONE MINUTE
TO THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
MASSACHUSETTS, MR. LYNCH.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN VECK NICED.
MR. LYNCH: THANK YOU.
I THANK
THE GENTLEMAN FOR
YIELDING.
I COME
BEFORE YOU AS AN IRON
WORKER FOR 18 YEARS
BEFORE
COMING TO
CONGRESS.
I
PRACK
DISEASE AN ATTORNEY
FOR
18 YEARS BEFORE
COMING TO
CONGRESS.
I PRACTICED
IN FRONT OF THE
NATIONAL
LABOR RELATIONS BOARD.
I HAVE
HEARD TIME AND TIME
AGAIN BY MY COLLEAGUES
THAT THE
NLRB,
NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS
BOARD IS AN
ADVOCATE FOR
UNIONISM,
AN ADVOCATE FOR BIG
LABOR,
IT'S NOTHING MORE THAN
OVERREACHING AND
TRYING TO
CREATE
UNIONS.
FOR
THOSE WHO LEE THAT I ASK
YOU TO LOOK AT
THE AMERICAN
WORK FORCE.
WHAT PERCENTAGE,
SINCE THE NLRB
IS
CREATING THESE UNIONS AND IS
OVERREACHING, WHAT
PERCENT
AMMING
OF THE AMERICAN WORK
FORCE IS
WORKING UNDER A
UNION
AGREEMENT RIGHT NOW?
THE ANSWER IS
11%.
SO
IF THOSE GUYS ARE IN THE
TANK, THE
NLRB IS IN THE TANK
FOR CREATING
UNIONS, THEY'RE
BATTING ABOUT
.110.
THEY'RE DOING
A LOUSY JOB.
I'VE
HEARD A LOT ABOUT 31 DAYS
FOR AN AVERAGE
ELECTION.
THAT'S WHERE THE
UNION AND
EMPLOYER
AGREE IT'S 31 DAYS.
IF THE UNION AND
COMPANY DON'T
AGREE IT'S
OVER 31 DAYS.
I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO VOTE
AGAINST THIS
BILL.
THIS IS AN
ATTACK ON THE MIDDLE
CLASS
IN AMERICA.
WE NEED TO
PUT PEOPLE TO WORK
INSTEAD.
THANK YOU.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN'S
TIME
HAS
EXPIRED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
CONTINUES TO RESERVE.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
IS RECOGNIZED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
CALIFORNIA
IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. MILLER: I
YIELD ONE MINUTE
TO THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MISSOURI,
MR. CARNAHAN.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR ONE
MINUTE.
MR. CARNAHAN:
THANK YOU, MR.
SPEAKER, WHY AREN'T
WE TALKING
ABOUT
JOBS TODAY?
WE'RE HERE AT THE FLOOR
TO TALK
ABOUT THIS BILL
, THIS SO-CALLED
WORK
FORCE DEMOCRACY FAIRNESS
ACT.
NOT
SURPRISINGLY,
IT'S NEITHER
DEMOCRATIC
NOR FAIR.
IT IS,
IN FACT A BLATANT ATTACK
ON
WORKERS' RIGHT THE LATEST IN
A LONG LINE
OF REPUBLICAN
ASSAULTS ON
WORKERS THIS TIME
THE RIGHT WING IS
ATTACKING THE
VERY RIGHT
TO ORGANIZE.
LABOR
UNIONS HELPED CREATE THE
MIDDLE CLASS AND
BUILD THE
AMERICAN
DREAM.
THEY
HELP ESTABLISH FOR ALL
AMERICAN WORKERS
MUCH-NEEDED
PROTECTIONS AND BARGAINING
RIGHTS FOR
WAGES AND WORK FORCE
CONDITIONS.
THIS DEAL
WOULD UNDO THAT
PROGRESS.
THIS
ANTI-WORKER
BILL WOULD
ALSO
EN-- EMPOWER EMPLOYERS TO
ENGAGE
IN ANTI-UNION CAMPAIGNS
AND
WEAKEN THE ABILITY TO
PROTECT PEOPLE
AT WORK.
JUST
AS VOTERS STOOD TOGETHER
TO STOP THE REPUBLICAN
ASSAULT
ON
WORKERS, TODAY I STAND HERE
ON THE FLOOR
AGAINST YET
ANOTHER
ASSAULT ON WORKING
FAMILIES.
WHEN WILL WE
GET BEYOND ANOTHER
REPUBLICAN
SIDESHOW AND GET
BACK
TO TALKING ABOUT JOBS?
THE CHAIR: THE
JET'S TIME HAS
EXPIRED.
--
THE GENTLEMAN'S TIME
HAS
EXPYRED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA
CONTINUES TO
RESERVE.
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM
CALIFORNIA.
MR. MILLER:
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
NEW YORK, MR. CROWLEY, ONE
MINUTE.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR
ONE MINUTE.
MR. CROWLEY: THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
I RISE IN STRONG OPPOSITION
TO
THIS
SO-CALLED WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND FAIRNESS
ACT.
THE SPONSOR OF
THIS BILL
RECENTLY SAID, AND I QUOTE
IF
WE
REMOVE AN OBSTACLE STANDING
IN A WAY
OF A STRONGER,
MORE
COMPETITIVE WORK
FORCE.
I
FIND THAT PUZZLING.
THIS DEAL
WOULD MAKE THE
ORGANIZATION
PROCESS LONGER,
LESS
EFFICIENT AND MORE
LITIGIOUS.
IT WOULD
DRAG OUT LECHES SO THE
DECK IS STACKED
EVEN HIGHER
AGAINST AMERICAN
WORKERS.
BUT THE
TRUTH IS UNIONS HAVE
BEEN AT
THE FOREFRONT OF
WORKERS'
RIGHTS FOR OVER A
CENTURY IN THE
UNITED STATES.
THEY HAVE BEEN
INSTRUMENTAL IN
ACHIEVING THE
40-HOUR WORK
WEEK, SAFER
WORKPLACES AND A
GUARANTEE FOR
INJURIES SUSTAIN
ODD THE JOB.
THEY HAVE
CREATED AN ENTIRE
GENERATION
OF MIDDLE CLASS
MESHES
AN
HELPED BUILD THE MOST
PROSPEROUS
COUNTRY IN THE WORLD
TODAY.
I THINK WE
ALL AGREE THAT
UNIONS HAVE MADE
THE AMERICAN
WORK FORCE
STRONGER.
SO
HOW CAN LEGISLATION THAT
MAKES IT HARDER TO
FORM A UNION
STRENGTHEN THE AMERICAN
WORK
FORCE?
IF SOMEONE HAS
AN ANSWER I'D
LIKE TO
KNOW.
IF NOT, LET'S
GET BACK TO THE
JOB
OF CREATING JOBS FOR THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE,
STRENGTHENING
THE ECONOMY AND
CREATING MORE
JOBS FOR
THESE PEOPLE.
I URGE MEMBERS TO VOTE
NO ON
THIS BILL AND
WITH THAT, I
YIELD
BACK THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN YIELDS BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA
CONTINUES TO RESERVE.
HAS SIX MINUTES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
CALIFORNIA
HAS 3
3/4 MINUTES.
HE IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR.
MILLER: I YIELD ONE MINUTE
TO THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA, MR. ELLISON.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR ONE
MINUTE.
MR. ELLISON: I ASK
UNANIMOUS
CONSENT
TO SUBMIT
THIS LETTER
FOR THE
RECORD FROM THE
TRANSPORTATION UNION.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN'S
REQUEST IS
GRANTED UNDER
GENERAL
LEAVE.
THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. ELLISON:
MR. SPEAKER, THIS
PARTICULAR
PIECE OF LEGISLATION
THAT UNS
MINES UNIONS, MAKES IT
MORE
DIFFICULT TO ORGANIZE AND
GENERALLY
FRUSTRATES AMERICAN
WORKING
MEN AND WOMEN
TO
ORGANIZE
ON THE JOB TAKES PLACE
JUST
A FEW WEEKS BEFORE THE
REPUBLICAN MAJORITY WAS
TRYING
TO
TAKE DOWN THE CLEAN AIR ACT
IN THE
E.P.A.
WHEN YOU LOOK
AT THE AMERICAN
--
THE REPUBLICAN JOB APPROACH,
IT
SEEMS TO ME THEIR ARGUMENT
SEEMS TO BE THAT WORKERS
AND
PEOPLE WHO WANT
TO BREATHE ARE
THE PROBLEM
WITH THE AMERICAN
ECONOMY.
PEOPLE WHO
WANT TO DRINK CLEAN
WATER AND
BREATHE CLEAN AIR AND
PEOPLE WHO WANT TO HAVE SOME
RIGHTS ON THE
JOB, THEY'RE THE
REASON THE AMERICAN ECONOMY
DOESN'T WORK.
WELL THAT
HAPPENS TO BE ABOUT
99%
OF US, MR. SPEAKER.
AND I HOPE THAT
AS PEOPLE ARE
WATCHING THIS DEBATE ON
THIS
FLOOR
TODAY, THAT THEY ARE
TAKING CAREFUL
NOTE OF WHO IS
ON THE SIDE OF THE
AMERICAN
WORKER,
WHO SON THE SIDE OF
AMERICANS TRYING TO BREATHE
AND
HAVE CLEAN
AIR, AND WHAT IN THE
WORLD DOES GETTING RID
OF THE
CLEAN AIR ACT
AND GUTTING
UNIONS HAVE TO DO
WITH MAKING
AMERICAN JOBS IN THE
FACT IS,
THE REPUBLICAN MAJORITY
IS
ABANDONING
THEIR RESPONSIBILITY
TO
CREATE JOBS AND I HOPE THE
AMERICAN
WORKER IS WATCHING
TODAY.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN'S TIME
HAS
EXPIRED.
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM MINNESOTA
CONTINUES TO RESERVE.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM CALIFORNIA
IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. MILLER: THE GENTLEMAN
ONLY
HAS HIMSELF
TO CLOSE?
MR. KLINE: THAT
APPEARS TO BE
THE CASE.
MR. MILLER:
I'M THE ONLY
SPEAKER LEFT.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN HAS 2
3/4
MINUTES REMAINING.
MR. MILLER: 2 3/4.
OK
IF ANYBODY THINKS THIS IS
JUST A
TECHNICAL CHANGE, LET'S
UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAS GONE ON
SINCE
REPUBLICANS TOOK CONTROL
OF THE
HOUSE.
FIRST
EFFORT, THEY CUT $50
MILLION
OUT OF THE NLRB
ACCOUNT.
THEN THERE WAS AN AMENDMENT ON
THIS
FLOOR TO TRY AND
ZERO OUT
THE MONEY
FOR THE NLRB.
THEN THEY
PASSED A RULE THAT
SAID THAT
YOU COULD RETALIATE
AGAINST WORKERS AND
YOU COULD
MOVE
WORK AWAY FROM WORKERS,
OUTSOURCE IT,
THEY ASSIGNED THE
WORK TO OUTSOURCE
WORK TO
RETALIATE AGAINST
WORKERS.
NOW WE HAVE THE
EFFORT TO
TRY
AND TO
PREVENT ELECTIONS FROM
TAKING PLACE.
THIS IS
A SYSTEMATIC EFFORT,
JOINED
BY A NUMBER OF STATES
AND THE
REPUBLICANS IN THIS
CONGRESS TO TAKE
AWAY THE
RIGHTS OF
WORKERS AT THE
WORKPLACE IN AMERICA.
THE BASIC RIGHTS
THAT HAVE
BUILT
THE MIDDLE CLASS.
WHILE
THEY'VE CONTINUED TO
CAMPAIGN
AGAINST THE NLRB THANK
GOD THE
NLRB HAS CONNED TO
WORK.
WE SEE TODAY A
SETTLEMENT HAS
BEEN
REACHED IN THE BOEING CASE
AND YOU DON'T
GET TO RETALIATE
AGAINST
WORKERS.
THE NEW
737 WORK WILL GO TO
WASHINGTON, THE
787 WILL
CONTINUE
TO GO TO SOUTH
CAROLINA.
THE
NLRB WORKED THAT AGREEMENT
OUT BETWEEN
EMPLOYER AND
EMPLOYEE.
LET'S REMEMBER
BOEING'S ON THE
RECORD
THEY DIDN'T SUPPORT THAT
LEGISLATION.
THAT WAS PUT
THERE IN BEHALF OF
THEIR NAME.
JUST A FEW MINUTES
AGO, THE
NLRB
VOTED ON A COMPROMISE RULE
DEALING
WITH LECHES.
THAT
COMPROMISE RULE HOPEFULLY
WILL NOW BECOME
A PERMANENT
RULE
AND THAT WILL GO FORWARD.
THAT'S
WHAT THE NLR BMBING
DOES.
IT WORKS OUT
ARRANGEMENTS
BETWEEN EMPLOYERS AND
EMPLOYEES
OVER ISSUES ABOUT
HOW THE
AMERICAN WORKPLACE
WILL BE
MANAGED.
BUT IT DOES
NOT STRIP AWAY THE
BASIC
RIGHTS OF WORKERS TO
CHOOSE TO JOIN
THE UNION.
IT DOES NOT ALLOW
YOU TO
RETALIATE
AGAINST THE UNION.
IT DOES NOT ALLOW
YOU TO DELAY
ELECTIONS OR AT
A POINT WHERE
YOU BEAT THE UNION
INTO
SUBMISSION,
PEOPLE GET
DISPIRITED OR
MOVE AWAY, IT
DOESN'T ALLOW THAT.
THAT'S THE BASIC
LABOR LAW OF
THIS
COUNTRY.
SO TODAY, THE
NLRB, WORKING
WITH EMPLOYERS
AND EMPLOYEE,
HAVE
REAFFIRMED THAT PRINCIPLE.
TODAY ON THIS
HOUSE THEY
CONTINUE THE EFFORT
TO TRY TO
STRIP
WORKERS OF
THEIR RIGHTS.
THEY CONTINUE THE EFFORT
IN
LIGHT OF THE EVIDENCE THAT
THESE THINGS GET WORKED
OUT IN
THE
WORKPLACE.
YES THESE
ARE CONTENTIOUS,
THEY'RE
BIG ISSUES, BUT
WE HAVE
A
VEHICLE, THAT'S 75 YEARS OLD,
THAT
HAS WORKED WELL ON BEHALF
OF THIS
ECONOMY.
NOT ONLY
DID IT BUILD THE
MIDDLE CLASS IN THIS
COUNTRY,
IT BUILT ONE
OF THE LARGEST
ECONOMIES, BECAUSE WE HAVE
THE
MOST
PRODUCTIVE WORKERS.
THE MOST PRODUCTIVE
WORKERS IN
THE HISTORY OF THE
WORLD.
INDUSTRY
AFTER INDUSTRY AFTER
INDUSTRY.
HOWEVER YOU
MEASURE IT.
WHY AREN'T OUR
STEELWORKERS
COMPETITIVE
WITH CHINA?
BECAUSE OUR
PLANTS ARE COST
COMPETITIVE ON TONS
OF STEEL
BUT WHEN
YOU MANIPULATE THE
CURRENCY OUR PEOPLE
CAN'T WIN.
BUT
OUR WORKERS CONTINUE TO BE
THERE EVERY DAY AND THE
NLRB
WILL CONTINUE TO BE
THERE EVERY
DAY FOR
EMPLOYERS AND EMPLOYEES
TO
SETTLE THEIR DIFFERENCES.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN'S TIME
HAS
EXPIRED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
I
YIELD MYSELF AS MUCH
TIME AS
I
MAY CONSUME, THE REMAINDER OF
THINK TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN
IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: LET'S CLEAR UP
A FEW
THINGS
TODAY.
WE HEARD
IN IF -- IN THIS
DEBATE, IT'S
INTERESTING, WE
CLEARLY HAVE DIFFERENT VIEWS,
NO QUESTION ABOUT IT.
WE HAVE HEARD
REPEATEDLY THAT
THIS BILL
STRIPS WORKERS OF
THEIR RIGHTS.
SOMETIMES
MY COLLEAGUES CONFUSE
WORKERS WITH
BIG LABOR LEADERS.
THIS
BILL IN FACT PROTECTS
WORKERS'
RIGHTS.
UNION
WORKERS' RIGHTS, NONUNION
WORKERS'
RIGHTS.
THE
PR POSED REGULATIONS WHICH
ARE
APPARENTLY UNDER
MODIFICATION
AS WE SPEAK FROM
THE
NLRB
WERE IN FACT AN ATTACK
ON
WORKERS' RIGHTS.
A
DEMAND THAT MORE PERSONAL
INFORMATION BE
PROVIDED UNION
ORGANIZERS WHETHER OR NOT
THE
WORKERS
APPROVED THAT.
SHRINKING THE
AMOUNT OF TIME
THAT
WORKERS MIGHT HAVE A
DECISION, TO MAKE A DECISION
ON
ONE OF THE MOST
IMPORTANT
ASPECTS OF
THEIR LIFE TO AS
LITTLE
AS 10 DAYS.
THIS BILL
PROTECTS WORKERS'
RIGHTS,
MAKES SURE THEY HAVE
TIME TO
MAKE THIS IMPORTANT
DECISION.
WE'VE
HEARD TODAY THAT
BARGAINING
UNITS WOULD BE
GERRYMANDERED BY EMPLOYERS.
IN
FACT, THIS BILL PUTS US BACK
TO THE
STANDARD THAT HAS BEEN
IN PLACE FOR
DECADES.
TO MAKE
SURE THAT WORKPLACES
AREN'T
FRACTURED AND FRAGMENTED
AND
YOU HAVE WORKER
AGAINST
WORKER.
WORKER AGAINST EMPLOYER.
MAKING
IT HARDER FOR EMPLOYERS
TO
RUN AN EFFECTIVE BUSINESS.
MAKING
IT HARDER FOR THEM TO
HAVE
CONFIDENCE TO HIRE
AMERICANS.
WE'VE
BEEN TOLD THAT WE ARE
WASTING TIME
TODAY, THAT WE
OUGHT TO BE
HAVING A JOBS BILL,
WHICH APPARENTLY
MEANS SPENDING
MORE BORROWED MONEY.
WE'RE
ALREADY BORROWING 42
CENTS ON EVERY DOLLAR,
MR.
CHAIRMAN, THAT WE'RE
SPENDING
NOW AND YET
APPARENTLY YOU
CAN'T CREATE A
JOB IN THIS
COUNTRY UNLESS THE GOVERNMENT
DOES IT WITH
BORROWED MONEY.
WE
DISAGREE.
THINK -- WE BELIEVE THAT WE
HAVE BEEN MOVING
LEGISLATION IN
THIS HOUSE WHICH
WILL IN FACT
HELP AMERICAN JOB
CREATORS PUT
AMERICANS BACK TO
WORK.
ONE
OF THE OBSTACLES IS
CONFUSION.
IT'S
UNCERTAINTY.
IT'S WORRY
ABOUT THE
REGULATORY
CLIMATE AN WHAT'S COMING
DOWN
THE PATH.
THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED
STATES HAS SAID
THIS ECONOMY
NEEDS A JOLT,
MR. CHAIRMAN.
I DISAGREE.
IT
NEEDS CERTAINTY.
NEEDS REDICTABILITY.
EMPLOYERS,
EMPLOYEES, CONSUMERS
NEED
CONFIDENCE IN THE FUTURE.
THEY
DON'T NEED TO BE JERKED.
THE DISTINGUISHED MINORITY
WHIP
SAID THE
NLRB OUGHT TO BE FAIR
HE SAID
EMPLOYERS AND EMPLOYEES
OUGHT TO GET
A FAIR ELECTION.
I COULDN'T AGREE
MORE.
EMPLOYERS
AND EMPLOYEES OUGHT
TO HAVE A FAIR SHAKE.
THEY OUGHT TO GET A FAIR
ELECTION.
THAT'S WHAT THIS BILL DOES.
SO THE
CHOICE TODAY IS PRETTY
SIMPLE.
IF
YOU SUPPORT AN EMPLOYER'S
RIGHT TO SPEAK TO
HIS OR HER
EMPLOYEES DURING
AN ORGANIZING
CAMPAIGN, THEN
SUPPORT THE WORK
FORCE DEMOCRACY AND
FAIRNESS
ACT.
IF YOU SUPPORT A
WORKER'S RIGHT
TO MAKE AN
INFORMED DECISION IN
A UNION
ELECTION, SUPPORT
THE
WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND
FAIRNESS
ACT.
IF YOU SUPPORT
GIVING WORKERS A
SAY IN THE
PERSONAL
INFORMATION,
THE PERSONAL
MR. CHAIRMAN,
AVAILABLE TO UNION
LEADERS,
THEN
SUPPORT THE WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND FAIRNESS
ACT AND
IF
YOU SUPPORT REINING IN AN
ACTIVIST
NLRB AND REAFFIRMING
CONGRESS' RESPONSIBILITY
TO
WRITE THE
LAW, THEN SUPPORT THE
WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND
FAIRNESS
ACT.
I URGE
MY COLLEAGUES TO STAND
BY
OUR WORKERS AND THEIR
EMPLOYERS BY
SUPPORTING THE
SIMPLE, COMMONSENSE
LEGISLATION, I YIELD BACK.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN YIELDS
BACK.
ALL TIME FOR GENERAL DEBATE HAS
EXPIRED.
PURSUANT TO THE RULE THE
AMENDMENT IN THE NATURE OF
A
SUBSTITUTE PRINTED IN THE
BILL
SHALL BE
CONSIDERED AS AN
ORIGINAL BILL FOR THE
PURPOSE
OF AMENDMENT
UNDER THE
FIVE-MINUTE RULE AND SHALL
BE
CONSIDERED READ.
NO AMENDMENT TO THE COMMITTEE
AMENDMENT IN THE NATURE OF A
SUBSTITUTE SHALL BE IN ORDER
EXCEPT THOSE PRINTED IN HOUSE
REPORT
112-291.
EACH SUCH
AMENDMENT MAY BE
OFFERED ONLY IN THE ORDER
PRINTED IN THE
REPORT BY A
MEMBER
DESIGNATED IN THE REPORT,
SHALL
BE CONSIDERED READ, SHALL
BE DEBATABLE
FOR THE TIME
SPECIFIED IN
THE REPORT, EQUALLY
DIVIDED
AND CONTROLLED BY
THE
PROPONENT AND AN
OPPONENT, SHALL
NOT
BE SUBJECT TO AMENDMENT AND
SHALL NOT
BE SUBJECT FOR DEMAND
OF THE DIVISION
OF THE QUESTION.
IT IS
NOW IN ORDER TO CONSIDER
AMENDMENT NUMBER 1 PRINTED IN
HOUSE REPORT
112-291.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM NEW YORK SEEK
RECOGNITION?
MR. BISHOP: MR. SPEAKER, I HAVE
AN AMENDMENT AT THE DESK.
THE CHAIR: THE
CLERK WILL
DESIGNATE THE
AMENDMENT.
THE CLERK: AMENDMENT NUMBER 1
PRINTED IN HOUSE
REPORT 112-291
OFFERED BY MR. BERTSCH OP
OF NEW
YORK
-- BISHOP OF NEW YORK.
THE CHAIR: PURSUANT
TO HOUSE
RESOLUTION
470, THE GENTLEMAN
FROM NEW YORK, MR. BISHOP, AND A
MEMBER
OPPOSED EACH WILL
CONTROL
FIVE
MINUTES.
THE
CHAIR RECOGNIZES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM NEW YORK, MR.
BISHOP.
MR. BISHOP: THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
MR. SPEAKER.
MY AMENDMENT IS
VERY SIMPLE.
IF A PARTY
MAKES A
FRIVOLOUS OR
VEX ASHESE
FILING DURING A
PREELECTION REPRESENTATION
HEARING THE NLRB OR
AN
ADMINISTRATIVE LAW
JUDGE WILL
HAVE THE
AUTHORITY TO IMPOSE
SANCTIONS.
POTENTIAL SANCTIONS INCLUDE
REIMBURSEMENT OF ATTORNEY
FEES
AN COSTS.
FURTHER, IN THE
BOARD DETERMINES
THAT A
PARTY HAS -- IF THE BOARD
DETERMINES THAT
A PARTY HAS
FOUND THAT SUCH
A FILING IS FOR
PURPOSING
OF DELAYING AN
ELECTION, AN ELECTION
WILL BE
ORDERED TO
TAKE PLACE NOT LESS
THAN SEVEN DAYS
AFTER THE
DETERMINATION.
MY AMENDMENT IS ROOTED IN
WELL-ESTABLISHED LAW.
RULE 11 OF THE
FEDERAL RULES OF
CIVIL
PROCEDURE.
RULE 11, WHICH
SANCTIONS
FRIVOLOUS
FILINGS IN FEDERAL
COURT, IS A
LONG STANDING AND
TESTED STANDARD THAT HAS
BEEN IN
PRACTICE FOR NEARLY 70
YEARS,
BUT
IT IS CURRENTLY INAPPLICABLE
TO REPRESENTATION
PROCEEDINGS AT
THE NLRB.
WHY SHOULD
WE CONTINUE TO ALLOW
THE FILING OF
FRIVOLOUS
LITIGATION AT THE
NLRB BUT DETER
IT IN THE
COURTS?
SHORT
ANSWER -- WE SHOULDN'T.
THERE IS NO
GOOD REASON.
THIS AMENDMENT
SIMPLY HARM
ONIZES NLRB PRACTICE
WITH THE
NATIONAL
STANDARDS USED IN OUR
COURT SYSTEM.
WHILE I URGE THE ADOPTION
OF
THIS AMENDMENT, THE
UNDERLYING
BILL
BEFORE US TODAY IS NOTHING
MORE THAN ANOTHER ATTEMPT BY THE
MAJORITY TO DISTRACT THE
PUBLIC
FROM THE
MOST IMPORTANT ISSUE
FACING OUR COUNTRY, JOB
CREATION.
BECAUSE MY COLLEAGUES ON THE
OTHER SIDE OF THE
AISLE
APPARENTLY LACK ANY PLAN
TO GET
UNEMPLOYED
AMERICANS WORKING
AGAIN, THEY ARE
RELYING ON THE
FALSE
SPECTER OF
POWERFUL UNIONS
AND
BURDENSOME REGULATIONS AS
THE
BOOGEYMEN IN THE AMERICAN
LABOR MARKET.
HOWEVER, A
RECENT NATIONAL POLL
BY
THE BUREAU OF LABOR
STATISTICS
SHOWS THAT ONLY .2%
OF
EMPLOYERS CITE GOVERNMENT
REGULATIONS AND INTERFERENCE AS
THEIR REASON FOR LAYING
OFF
EMPLOYEES.
.2%.
THE MAIN REASON
CITED FOR
LAYOFFS IS LACK OF DEMAND.
WE NEED REAL
SOLUTIONS TO CREATE
AMERICAN
JOBS,
NOT PHONY
DISTRACTIONS THAT ATTEMPT TO
STEER THE
CONVERSATION TO
PROBLEMS THAT DON'T
EXIST.
WHILE
CURRENT LAW ALLOWS UNION
ELECTIONS TO PROCEED WHILE
REQUESTS FOR
FULL BOARD REVIEW
ARE
CONSIDERED,
H.R. 3094
MANDATES THAT ELECTIONS BE
DELAYED UNTIL
THE FOOD BOARD
DECIDES
WHETHER OR NOT TO GRANT
A
REQUEST FOR REVIEW
BY THE FULL
NLRB, NO
MATTER HOW FRIVE LOSS
THE ARGUMENTS.
IN DOING SO,
THIS BILL
INCENTIVIZES PARTIES
OPPOSED TO
UNIONIZATION TO FILE FRIVOLOUS
LAWSUITS TO DELAY UNION
ELECTIONS.
NOT ONLY IS THIS UNFAIR TO
HARDWORKING AMERICANS, BUT
IT
ADDS TREMENDOUS
COST TO
TAXPAYERS.
THIS
BUILT-IN INCENTIVE
FOR
DELAYING
TACTICS MAKES MY
AMENDMENT ALL THE
MORE
IMPORTANT.
IN THE PAST MANY OF MY
REPUBLICAN
COLLEAGUES HAVE
ARGUED
PASSIONATELY ABOUT THE
EVILS OF FRIVOLOUS
LAWSUITS.
THEREFORE
I AM CON FOUNDED TO
HEAR
OPPOSITION TO MY AMENDMENT
THAT
SEEKS TO DISCOURAGE
FRIVOLOUS
LITIGATION.
WHY IS
IT THAT LE LITIGATION
THAT THWARTS
THE AMBITIONS OF
WORKING
FAMILIES, NO MATTER
HOW
FRIVOLOUS OR
MISGUIDED, IS NOT
SUDDENLY OK?
DON'T CONSTRUCTION WORKERS
MATTER?
UNFORTUNATELY SUCH
FRIVOLOUS
LITIGATION IS TOO
OFTEN USED BY
UNSCRUPULOUS
EMPLOYERS TO OPPOSE
UNIONIZATION.
IN MY OWN
DISTRICT, 14 T-MOBILE
TECHNICIANS
ATTEMPTED TO
ORGANIZE IN A LOCAL
CHAPTER OF
THE COMMUNICATION
WORKERS OF
AMERICA, ONLY
TO DISCOVER THAT
THEIR EMPLOYER HAD UNDERTAKEN
SEVERAL
SUBVERSIVE MEASURES
AIMED AT
DERAILING THE PATH
TO
UNION
ORGANIZATION.
ONE
SUCH LEGAL CHALLENGE
INCLUDED A
DISPUTE OVER THE
DEFINITION OF
WHETHER OR NOT THE
C.W.A. IS
A LEGITIMATE LABOR
ORGANIZATION.
LET ME SAY THAT AGAIN.
A DISPUTE OVER
WHETHER OR NOT
THE
C.B.A. IS A -- C.W.A. IS A
LEGITIMATE LABOR ORGANIZATION.
THE C.W.A. REPRESENTS OVER
A
HALF
A MILLION AMERICAN WORKERS.
UNDER
H.R. 3094, T-MOBILE'S
FRIVOLOUS CHALLENGE
WOULD
HAVE
TO BE
COMPLETELY ADJUDICATED BY
THE NLRB
BEFORE THE UNION
ELECTION
COULD OCCUR,
GIVING
T-MOBILE THE
ABILITY TO LEGALLY
HAMMER EMPLOYEES
WITH ANTIUNION
MESSAGING FOR WEEKS,
MONTHS OR
EVEN
YEARS.
A CONSTITUENT OF MY
WROTE TO ME
REGARDING THE T-MOBILE
INCIDENT
AND I QUOTE,
IT IS ABUNDANTLY
CLEAR
TO US THAT THE COMPANY IS
ONLY ENGAGED
IN THIS EFFORT IN
ORDER TO BUY ENOUGH
TIME TO
CONTINUE
WITH AN INTIMIDATION
CAMPAIGN AS AN EFFORT
TO PREVENT
US
FROM EXERCISING OUR RIGHT TO
ORGANIZE AND
BARGAIN
COLLECTIVELY.
WE WANT TO EXERCISE OUR LEGAL
RIGHT
IN A TIMELY AND
EFFICIENT
MANNER, TO
DECIDE FOR OURSELVES
THROUGH THE ESTABLISHED
ELECTION
PROCESS WHETHER OR NOT
TO JOIN
THE
C.W.A.
THIS
PROCESS OF DELAY AND
INTIMIDATION BEING
EXERCISED IS
WRONG AND
SHOULD NOT BE ALLOWED
TO HAPPEN IN THE
FUTURE.
AFTER SEVERAL
MONTHS OF THIS
ASSAULT,
I WILL STAND
FIRM IN MY
COMMITMENT
TO GAINING A VOICE AT
WORK.
WHAT I'M ASKING
FOR IS A FAIR
CHANCE
TO VOTE.
CLOSED
QUOTE.
A FAIR CHANCE
TO VOTE.
WHAT COULD BE
MORE AMERICAN THAN
THAT?
THIS IS A FUNDAMENTAL
MATTER OF
STANDING UP
FOR THE
AMERICAN
WORKER THIS BILL IS
AN AFFRONT
TO ONE
OF OUR AMMONIUM NITRATE
MOST PRINCIPLED VALUES.
THE
ABILITY OF WORKERS TO
COLLECTIVELY BARGAIN HAS
BEEN
ONE OF THE BASIC
PATHWAYS FOR
WORKERS TO
GAIN THE PROTECTIONS
AND PAY NECESSARY
TO ACCESS THE
AMERICAN DREAM.
WE SHOULD NOT UNDERMINE THIS
SHARED PRINCIPLE AND YET
THIS IS
PRECISELY WHAT THE UNDERLYING
BILL DOES.
MY
AMENDMENT WOULD PROVIDE AT
LEAST SOME
PROTECTIONS FOR
EMPLOYEES WHO
SEEK TO ORGANIZE
THEIR
WORKPLACE.
MR. SPEAKER, I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO SUPPORT
MY
AMENDMENT AND I
RESERVE THE
BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN
RESERVES THE BALANCE OF HIS
TIME.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM SOUTH CAROLINA
SEEK RECOGNITION?
&gt;&gt; MR. CHAIRMAN, I
RISE TO CLAIM
TIME
IN
OPPOSITION.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR FIVE MINUTES.
MR. GOWDY: THANK YOU,
MR.
CHAIRMAN.
LET ME FIRST
THANK MR. BISHOP
FOR
RAISING THE IMPORTANT ISSUE
OF FRIVOLOUS
LITIGATION.
I AM
THRILLED ALMOST BEYOND
WORDS, NOT
QUITE, ALMOST BEYOND
WORDS THAT
OUR COLLEAGUES ON THE
OTHER
SIDE OF THE AISLE
HAVE
RECOGNIZED
THE IMPACT THAT
FRIVOLOUS
LITIGATION HAS ON OUR
ECONOMY.
WE VERY MUCH SUPPORT,
MR.
CHAIRMAN, A
MORE EFFECTIVE USE
OF
RULE 11.
WE HAVE
CONSISTENTLY SUPPORTED
TORT REFORM
THAT CORRECTS --
CORRECTLY
SANCTIONED FRIVOLOUS
LAWSUITS.
SO,
AGAIN, I THANK
OUR COLLEAGUE
FROM
THE OTHER SIDE OF THE AISLE
FOR BRINGING ATTENTION
ONCE
AGAIN
TO THE IMPACT FRIVOLOUS
LITIGATION
HAS ON OUR ECONOMY.
NEVERTHELESS,
MR. SPEAKER, THIS
AMENDMENT IS NOT THE RIGHT
VEHICLE FOR A NUMBER
OF
REASONS.
THE
PURPOSE OF THE UNDERLYING
BILL IS TO CORRECT THE
MISGUIDED
EFFORT OF THE NLRB
TO HAVE
QUICKY
ELECTIONS.
WHICH
MEANS THE TIME IS
COMPRESSED FOR
LITIGANTS,
ESPECIALLY
THOSE CAUGHT
OFFGUARD,
BY THE
LEGAL FILING,
TO
RESPOND.
WHAT DO
LITIGANTS AND THEIR
COUNSEL
DO WHEN THEY'RE GIVEN
AN
INADEQUATE AMOUNT
OF TIME TO
PREPARE FOR
LITIGATION?
THEY
OVERPLEAD.
OVERANSWER.
THEY THROW EVERYTHING
THEY CAN
INTO THE
ANSWER BECAUSE TO DO
OTHERWISE IS TO RISK MISSING
AN
ISSUE AND BEING
SUED FOR LEGAL
MALPRACTICE OR
WORSE YET FAILING
TO
ADEQUATELY REPRESENT YOUR
CLIENT.
SO,
IN A VERY COUNTERINTUITIVE
WAY,
THE NLRB'S RUSH TO HAVE
ELECTIONS IS
MORE LIKELY TO
RESULT
IN OVERPLEADING THAN THE
STATUS QUO
WOULD BE.
MR. SPEAKER, THIS
AMENDMENT ALSO
GIVES
INCREASED POWER TO THE
VERY
AGENCY THAT WE ARE TRYING
TO
REIN IN.
THAT, TOO,
IS COUNTERINTUITIVE.
TO
REWARD AN ACTIVIST
AGENDA-DRIVE
BRANCH ENTITY WITH
EVEN
MORE POWER TO WIELD
INCORRECTLY IS
AN INVITATION WE
ARE LOATH
TO ACCEPT.
THIS AMENDMENT
DOES NOT EVEN
PROVIDE ALL THE
SAFEGUARDS OF
RULE 11
AND I URGE MY COLLEAGUE
AND FRIEND
ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF
THE AISLE MADE REFERENCE
TO RULE
11.
IF THIS WERE
SIMPLY RULE
11, WE
MAY VERY WELL
BE STANDING UP TO
JOIN IN SUPPORT.
IT'S NOT RULE
11.
IT DOESN'T
PROVIDE NOTICE AND A
REASONABLE CHANCE TO RESPOND.
IT
DOESN'T PROVIDE AN APPEAL
PROCEDURE,
IT DENIES AN
OPPORTUNITY TO
WITHDRAW THE
FRIVOLOUS
MATTER BEFORE
SANCTIONS
ARE
IMPOSED.
EVEN CURRENT NLRB
PROVISIONS
REQUIRE
DUE NOTICE AND AN
OPPORTUNITY FOR
A HEARING AND
ALLEGATIONS
OF MISCONDUCT CASES
--
IN ALLEGATIONS OF MISCONDUCT
CASES.
THIS AMENDMENT I AM SURE, I AM
CONVINCED IS WELL
INTENDED.
TO
ROOT OUT FRIVOLOUS FILINGS
AND
PLEADINGS, BUT IT HAS TO BE
DONE IN AN
EVEN-HANDED, FAIR
MANNER.
NOT ONE CALCULATED TO SKEW
THE
BALANCE
EVEN MORE IN FAVOR OF
THOSE
SEEKING UNIONIZATION.
OTHER THAN UNION MEMBERSHIP
BEING AT A
HISTORIC LOW,
MAMPLEE, --
MR. CHAIRMAN, WHY
THE RUSH TO CHANGE THE
RULES?
IS
31 DAYS TOO LONG?
A 70% SUCCESS RATE IN
ELECTIONS NOT GOOD
ENOUGH?
I APPRECIATE
THE MOTIVE BEHIND
THE
AMENDMENT BUT I MUST OPPOSE
IT BECAUSE
OF THE MECHANISM.
AND
I WOULD ENCOURAGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO DO THE
SAME.
I
RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN
REMBS.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM NEW YORK HAS
SECONDS REMAINING --
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM NEW YORK HAS
15 SECONDS
REMAINING.
MR. BISHOP:
I WILL SAY THAT RULE
GIVES THE PERSON WHO FILES A
FRIVOLOUS
MOTION OR THE ENTITY
THAT FILES A
FRIVOLOUS MOTION 20
DAYS TO WITHDRAW
THAT FILING
WHICH
WOULD DEFEAT THE PURPOSE
OF WHAT WE'RE
TRYING TO
ACCOMPLISH HERE
WHICH IS TO SEE
TO
IT THAT WE ULTIMATELY DO GET
ELECTIONS AND I WOULD
REPEAT
WHAT THE MINORITY
WHIP SAID
WHICH IS,
I THINK A LOT OF US
WOULD FEEL
DIFFERENTLY ABOUT
THIS
UNDERLYING BILL IF THERE
WERE NOT JUST A MINIMUM
TIME FOR
WHICH THERE WAS AN
ELECTION TO
TAKE PLACE, BUT
A MAXIMUM TIME
IN WHICH THE --
IN WHICH THE
ELECTION HAS
TO TAKE
PLACE.
THIS IS ONE
MEANS OF US TO GET
THAT.
I YIELD BACK.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN'S TIME
HAS EXPIRED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM SOUTH
CAROLINA IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. GOWDY:KY INQUIRE HOW MUCH
TIME I HAVE
REMAINING?
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN
HAS 1
1/2 MINUTES
REMAINING.
MR. GOWDY: WE
NEED TO GIVE PAUSE
AND
REFLECTS ON WHY WE'RE HERE.
WE'RE NOT HERE BECAUSE
CHAIRMAN
KLINE HAD AN
IDEA OUT OF THE
BLUE.
WE'RE HERE BECAUSE AN
ACTIVIST
AGENDA-RIDDEN NLRB IS
DISSATISFIED WITH
31 DAYS TO
HAVE AN ELECTION.
THEY'RE
DISSATISFIED WITH A 70%
SUCCESS RATE, SO
WHAT MR. KLINE
HAS DONE AND
SMARTLY SO IN THIS
BILL IS TRY TO GET
US BACK TO
THE STATUS QUO
AND HOW HAVE A
LEVEL
PLAYING FIELD WHERE -- AND
HAVE A LEVEL PLAYING
FIELD WHERE
EMPLOYEES HAVE
ENOUGH
INFORMATION TO MAKE WHAT
MAY BE
ONE OF THE MOST IMPORTANT
DECISIONS OF THEIR LIFE AND
AGAIN I WILL SAY
IT TO
MY
COLLEAGUE,
RULE 11 HAS BUILT IN
PROCEDURAL
SAFEGUARDS AND WE HAD
A VERY
CIVIL, CONSTRUCTIVE, I
THOUGHT,
CONVERSATION ABOUT THIS
AMENDMENT IN
COMMITTEE AND I
COMMEND
OUR FRIEND
FOR THAT AND
I COMMEND
HIM FOR
BRINGING UP A
FRIVOLOUS
LAWSUITS AND I'M HAPPY
TO WORK WITH HIM ON HOW
TO GET
IT
DONE.
THIS VEHICLE
, WHILE WELL
INTENDED, IS NOT THE VEHICLE
TO
GET IT
DONE.
AND
WITH THAT I WOULD YIELD BACK
THE BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
SOUTH CAROLINA YIELDS BACK THE
BALANCE OF HIS TIME.
ALL TIME HAVING EXPIRED, THE
QUESTION IS ON THE AMENDMENT
OFFERED
BY THE GENTLEMAN FROM
NEW YORK.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
IN THE OPINION
OF THE CHAIR, THE
NOES HAVE
IT.
THE AMENDMENT IS NOT
AGREED
TO.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM NEW YORK.
MR. BISHOP: ON THAT I REQUEST
THE
YEAS AND NAYS.
THE CHAIR:
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 6
OF RULE 18,
FURTHER PROCEEDINGS
ON THE AMENDMENT
OFFERED BY THE
GENTLEMAN FROM NEW YORK WILL BE
POSTPONED.
IT IS NOW
IN ORDER TO CONSIDER
AMENDMENT NUMBER 2 PRINTED IN
HOUSE REPORT
112-291.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM IOWA SEEK
RECOGNITION?
MR. BOSWELL: MR. CHAIRMAN, I
HAVE AN AMENDMENT AT THE DESK.
THE CHAIR: THE CLERK
WILL
DESIGNATE THE AMENDMENT.
THE CLERK: AMENDMENT NUMBER 2
PRINTED IN HOUSE REPORT
112-291
OFFERED
BY MR. BOSWELL OF IOWA.
THE CHAIR:
PURSUANT TO HOUSE
RESOLUTION 4
70, THE GENTLEMAN
FROM
IOWA, MR. BOSWELL, AND A
MEMBER OPPOSED
EACH WILL CONTROL
FIVE
MINUTES.
THE
CHAIR NOW RECOGNIZES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
IOWA.
MR. BOSWELL: THANK YOU,
MR.
CHAIRMAN.
I RISE TO ENCOURAGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO SUPPORT MY
AMENDMENT TO THE
UNDERLYING
LEGISLATION.
I FIRST WANT TO THANK MY
COLLEAGUES, MR.
MILLER, MR. AL
ANDREWS,
FOR THEIR WORK ON
THIS
IMPORTANT ISSUE.
I'M CONCERNED THAT THIS
LEGISLATION CREATES
AN
OPPORTUNITY FOR PARTICIPATES
--
PARTIES TO
ABUSE THE
PRE-ELECTION
HEARING PROCESS TO
ENGAGE IN OPEN-ENDED
LITIGATION.
THE
MAJORITY WOULD ALLOW PARTIES
IN A HEARING
TO RAISE ANY REV
LANT AND MATERIAL ISSUES
AT ANY
TIME BEFORE THE
CLOSE OF THE
HEARING.
YET
THEY DEFINE RELEVANT
MATERIAL AS ANY OTHER
ISSUES
THAT
MAY POSSIBLY IMPACT THE
ELECTION.
PRACTICALLY THIS MEANS THAT
ANY
WORKPLACE
ISSUE, HOWEVER
FRIVOLOUS, COULD BE RAISED
AND
LITIGATED BEFORE THE
HEARING
CLOSES.
AS WE'VE SEEN
SOME SEEK TO
ENRICH THEIR
C.E.O.'S WHILE
DENYING
THE WORKERS A FAIR AND A
SAFER
WORKPLACE.
THIS AMENDMENT WOULD
ONLY APPLY
TO COMPANIES
THAT HAVE
GIVEN
BONUSES
, NOW, HEAR THIS, BONUSES
TO THE
EXECUTIVES THAT AMOUNT TO
10,000% MORE
THAN THE AVERAGE
EARNING SAL RIFF
THEIR EMPLOYEES
-- SALARIES OF THEIR
EMPLOYEES.
THOSE
EMPLOYERS WILL STATE THEIR
ISSUES AT THE ONSET OF
HEARING
AND WOULD BE PROHIBITED
FROM
ENGAGING IN
OPEN-ENDED
LITIGATION.
THIS IS A
SIMPLE PRINCIPLE.
IF YOUR AVERAGE EMPLOYEE MAKES
$50,000
AND YOU CAN AFFORD TO
PAY THE
C.E.O. A BONUS OF $5
MILLION, THEN
YOU CAN ALSO
AFFORD TO
BE PREPARED FOR THE
HEARING IN 14
DAYS AND STATE
YOUR
POSITION UP FRONT.
I'M
NOT SURE WHY WE'RE
CONSIDERING
H.R. 3094 RIGHT NOW.
IT WON'T CREATE ONE
JOB AND IT
WON'T
REDUCE OUR DEFICIT BY ONE
DOLLAR.
IT WON'T ADD
ONE JOB FOR
UNEMPLOYED CONSTRUCTION
WORKERS
TO FIX OUR HORRIBLE
BRIDGES THAT
NEED TO BE
REPAIRED.
IT WON'T HELP
ONE
MEMBER OF THE
IOWA NATIONAL GUARD THAT
RECENTLY
RETURNED FROM
AFGHANISTAN AND
IS STILL LOOKING
FOR
A JOB.
AND ALL THIS BILL
DOES IS HELP A
SMALL NUMBER OF
COMPANIES MAKE
IT
HARDER FOR THE WORKERS TO
ORGANIZE
, THE VERY LEAST WE CAN
DO
IS MAKE SURE THOSE COMPANIES
AREN'T ABUING --
ABUSING THE
PROCESS WHILE HANDING
OUT
EXECUTIVE
BONUSES THAT ARE
10,000%
MORE THAN WHAT THEIR
WORKERS EARN.
SUPPORT THIS AMENDMENT
FOR
FAIRNESS.
I
RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
IOWA RESERVES.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA RISE?
MR. KLINE: MR. CHAIRMAN,
I RISE
TO CLAIM
TIME IN OPPOSITION TO
THE AMENDMENT.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR FIVE MINUTES.
MR. KLINE:
THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
IT'S KIND
OF IRONIC SOMETIMES,
BUT THIS
OCCUPY WALL STREET
SORT OF INSPIRED
AMENDMENT IS
AN
EFFORT TO DISMANTLE UNION
ELECTION PROCESS
AND DENY
WORKERS
AN OPPORTUNITY TO MAKE
AN INFORMED DECISION.
UNDER THE
GUISE OF FIGHTING
GREED ON
WALL STREET, THIS
AMENDMENT WILL
ACTUALLY PUNISH
WORKERS, PUNISH WORKERS
IF
THEIR
COMPANY EXECUTIVES
RECEIVE BONUSES THAT ARE DEEMED
TOO BIG BY OFFICIALS IN
WASHINGTON.
MR. CHAIRMAN, WHILE MOST
OF THE
TIME
EMPLOYER AND UNION CAN
AGREE TO THE TERMS
OF THE UNION
ELECTIONS, OFTEN
A PRE-
ELECTION
HEARING IS NEEDED TO
ADDRESS
QUESTIONS
THAT ARISE.
IT
ASSURES ALL RELEVANT AND
PRE-ELECTION MATERIALS ARE
ADDRESSED BEFORE A
WORKER IS
REQUIRED
PROVIDING WORKERS TO
-- FORCING A VOTE
BEFORE THESE
ISSUES CAN GO
ADDRESSED AT THE
PRE ELECTION HEARING
WILL
SEVERELY --
PRE-ELECTION
HEARING
WILL
SEVERELY UNDERMINE
THE EMPLOYEE'S
FREE CHOICE.
IN FACT, THIS
AMENDMENT MAY
LEAD
TO NEEDLESS DELAY IN THE
ELECTION
PROCESS.
THE COURTS HAVE
OVERTURNED THE
RESULTS
OF ELECTIONS BECAUSE
IMPORTANT
ISSUES WERE NOT
PROPERLY
ADDRESSED AT THE
PRE-ELECTION
HEARING.
NO WORKER
SHOULD BE DENIED A
FAIR UNION
ELECTION PROCESS
BECAUSE
OF THE BONUSES PAID TO
COMPANY EXECUTIVES.
YET, THAT IS
PRECISELY WHAT
THIS AMENDMENT WOULD DO.
CONGRESS SHOULD NOT
BE PICKING
WINNERS
AND LOSERS HERE,
DETERMINING THAT
WORKERS
DESERVE GREATER
PROTECTIONS
THAN OTHERS.
I URGE MY
COLLEAGUES TO OPPOSE
THIS
AMENDMENT, AND
I RESERVE
THE BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM IOWA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. BOSWELL: AT THIS TIME
I'D
LIKE TO RECOGNIZE
MR. ANDREWS
FROM NEW JERSEY FOR
THE BALANCE
OF THE TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
NEW JERSEY IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. ANDREWS: I THANK
MY FRIEND
FOR YIELDING.
MY FRIEND FROM MINNESOTA, THE
CHAIRMAN OF OUR
COMMITTEE, SAYS
THAT CONGRESS SHOULDN'T BE
PICKING
WINNERS AND
LOSERS.
I THINK THE
CONGRESS HAS
ALREADY
PICKED A LOT OF WINNERS
IN THE LAST NUMBER
OF MONTHS.
THEY
PICKED THE PEOPLE THAT ARE
THE SUBJECT OF MR.
BOSWELL'S
AMENDMENT,
THOSE WHOSE BONUSES
ARE
10,000% MORE THAN THE
AVERAGE
SALARY OF THEIR
WORKERS.
THEY PICKED THEM FOR THE
LARGEST
TAX CUT IN AMERICAN
HISTORY.
THEY PICKED THE
WINNER AND SAYS
IF THAT PERSON
MANIPULATES A
HEDGE FUND
OR
A FINANCIAL
INSTITUTION THE
REGULATORS WILL
LOOK
THE OTHER
WAY AS OUR
401-K'S BECOME
201-K'S AND OUR
HOME VALUES
SHRINK.
THIS CONGRESS HAS
PICKED A SET
OF
WINNERS AND THOSE WINNERS
ARE AT THE
TOP OF AMERICAN
SOCIETY WHO GOT
93%
OF THE PAY
RAISES.
93% OF THE PAY
RAISES HAVE
GIVEN
TO THAT TOP GROUP.
MR. BOSWELL IS
TRYING TO HAVE A
SIGNIFICANT
DISINCENTIVE WHICH
SAYS, IF YOU
PAY YOURSELF
10,000% MORE THAN YOUR
AVERAGE
WORKER, MAYBE
THERE SHOULD BE A
SEPARATE SET OF
CIRCUMSTANCES
YOU HAVE TO
ABIDE BY AND LIVE
BY.
IT'S A
NOVEL IDEA AROUND
THIS
CONGRESS.
VERY NOVEL IDEA.
THAT THOSE
AT THE VERY TOP OF
AMERICAN
SOCIETY SHOULD HAVE TO
LIVE BY A SET OF
RULES THAT
PROTECTS
THE REST OF AMERICAN
SOCIETY.
FOR THAT REASON I
STRONGLY
SUPPORT MR.
BOSWELL'S
AMENDMENT.
I WOULD URGE A YES VOTE AND
YIELD BACK TO HIM.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN YIELDS
BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM IOWA
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE:
THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
I, LIKE MY
COLLEAGUES ON THE
OTHER
SIDE OF THE AISLE,
AND
AMERICANS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
CAN GET
PRETTY ANGRY WHEN SOME
OFFICIALS
, CORPORATE OFFICIALS
RECEIVE
EXTRAORDINARILY HIGH
SALARIES.
I'M NOT HERE TO
DEFEND THAT.
WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT HERE IS
WHY
WOULD YOU PUNISH THE
WORKERS
BECAUSE THE EMPLOYERS
ARE
PAYING THEMSELVES TOO MUCH
MONEY?
I DON'T THINK WE SHOULD DO
THAT,
AND THAT'S
WHAT THIS
AMENDMENT
DOES.
IT
DENIES WORKERS THE
OPPORTUNITY TO MAKE
AN INFORMED
DECISION.
WE SHOULDN'T BE PUNISHING THOSE
WORKERS BECAUSE
OF EXECUTIVES
HAVE
PAID THEMSELVES TOO MUCH
MONEY.
I RESERVE.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM IOWA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. BOSWELL: HOW MUCH TIME
IS
LEFT?
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
IOWA HAS A MINUTE AND A HALF
REMAINING.
MR. BOSWELL: A MINUTE AND A
HALF.
WELL, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU
FOR
POINTING OUT
THOSE
ASTUTE REMARKS THAT APPLY
TO
WORKERS.
MY FRIEND
FROM MINNESOTA, I
RECALL WE
BOTH
HAVE LED TROOPS
AND I AM PROUD OF
YOU FOR
HAVING DONE
THAT.
I AM PROUD
I HAD THE
OPPORTUNITY.
YOU KNOW, I SEE THESE
TOPICS --
TOP
C.E.O.'S, WHERE ARE THEIR
TROOPS?
THEIR TROOPS ARE THE
WORKERS.
THANK
HEAVENS WE HAVE THOSE
PEOPLE BEING
ENTREPRENEURS BUT
THEY HAVE ORDERS TO GET THE JOB
DONE JUST LIKE YOU AND I
HAD TO
HAVE
TROOPS TO TAKE THE
OBJECTIVE.
WHAT'S THE
DIFFERENCE?
OUR TROOPS
HAD TO BE WELL-FED,
TRAINED,
EQUIPPED, MORALE HAD
TO BE GOOD AND THEN WE
COULD
TAKE OUR
OBJECTIVE.
ANY
SERGEANT, LIEUTENANT,
COLONEL THAT CAN'T TAKE THE
OBJECTIVE
WITHOUT
TROOPS, THEN
HOW DO
THOSE WE APPRECIATE, WE
LIE ON THEM,
BUT THEY HAVE TO
HAVE
THOSE WORKERS, THEY HAVE
TO TREAT THEM FAIRLY
AND
REALIZE THEY,
TOO, WANT TO HAVE
THE AMERICAN
DREAM.
AND I'M
CONCERNED, WORRIED THAT
AMERICAN DREAM --
SURROUNDED BY
MY GRANDCHILDREN
JUST A FEW
DAYS AGO AT
THANKSGIVING, IS IT
GOING TO BE THERE FOR THEM?
WE OUGHT TO BE THINKING ABOUT
IT.
WE
DON'T PULL THE LADDER
UP.
WE LEAVE IT
DOWN.
LET'S LEAPT
EVERYBODY HAVE A
PART
OF THE AMERICAN DREAM.
AND 10,000%
AND YOU'RE WORRIED
ABOUT THAT?
COME ON, GIVE ME
A BREAK.
I URGE SUPPORT OF THIS
AMENDMENT.
I THINK IT IS
FAIR AND IT'S THE
RIGHT
THING TO
DO.
THANK YOU.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN'S TIME
HAS EXPIRED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: MAY I INQUIRE AS TO
HOW MUCH TIME I HAVE
REMAINING?
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA HAS TWO MINUTES
REMAINING.
MR. KLINE: TWO MINUTES.
THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
I,
TOO, WANT TO THANK MY
COLLEAGUE AND FRIEND
FROM IOWA
FOR HIS
SERVICE.
HE, LIKE
ME, MADE AN EARLY
MISTAKE AND
CHOSE TO FLY AND
EVEN WORSE
TO FLY HELICOPTERS.
HE JUST
PERHAPS IS BETTER AT IT
THAN SOME OF
US.
BUT THIS
AMENDMENT IS GOING THE
WRONG DIRECTION.
IT'S NOT
THE PERCENTAGE.
HOW MANY
PERCENT?
100,000%,
1,000,000,000% MORE,
I DON'T WANT
TO DEFEND THAT
EITHER.
I DON'T WANT TO
DEFEND THE
LEADER
BEFORE HIS TROOPS AND I
DON'T WANT TO DEFEND
THE LEADER
WHO THINKS HE
CAN DO IT
WITHOUT
HIS TROOPS.
BUT THIS TAKES
OUT THE RIGHTS
AND
PROTECTIONS AND THE
WORKERS.
WE
SHOULDN'T PUNISH THE
WORKERS
BECAUSE WE'RE
MAD AT THE
EXECUTIVES.
WE SHOULDN'T PUNISH THE TROOPS
BECAUSE WE'RE MAD
AT THE
COLONELS.
I AGREE WITH THE GENTLEMAN
ON
THAT,
LET'S DON'T PUNISH THE
WORKERS, LET'S
DEFEAT THIS
AMENDMENT.
I YIELD BACK.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA YIELDS BACK.
ALL TIME BEING YIELDED BACK,
THE QUESTION
IS ON THE
AMENDMENT
OFFERED BY THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
IOWA.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
IN THE OPINION OF THE CHAIR,
THE NOES HAVE IT AND THE
AMENDMENT IS NOT AGREED TO.
MR. BOSWELL: MR. CHAIRMAN.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
IOWA.
MR. BOSWELL: I REQUEST A
RECORDED VOTE.
THE CHAIR:
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 6
OF RULE 18, FURTHER PROCEEDINGS
ON THE AMENDMENT OFFERED BY THE
GENTLEMAN FROM IOWA
WILL BE
POSTPONED.
IT
IS NOW IN ORDER TO CONSIDER
AMENDMENT NUMBER 3
PRINTED IN
HOUSE REPORT 112-
291.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA SEEK
RECOGNITION?
MR. WALZ: MR. CHAIRMAN, I HAVE
AN AMENDMENT AT THE DESK.
THE CHAIR:
CLERK.
THE CLERK:
AMENDMENT NUMBER 3
PRINTED
IN HOUSE REPORT 112-291
OFFERED
BY MR. WALZ
OF
MINNESOTA.
THE CHAIR: PURSUANT
TO HOUSE
RESOLUTION
470, THE GENTLEMAN
FROM MINNESOTA, MR. WALZ, AND A
MEMBER
OPPOSED, EACH WILL
CONTROL FIVE
MINUTES.
THE
CHAIR NOW RECOGNIZES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA FOR
FIVE MINUTES.
MR. WALZ: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
I GIVE
MYSELF AS MUCH TIME AS I
MAY CONSUME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. WALZ: I OFFER AN AMENDMENT
THAT WOULD PROTECT THE
EMPLOYMENT RIGHTS OF OUR
BRAVE
SERVICE
MEMBERS.
WE'VE ALL
SEEN THIS SHOW
BEFORE, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
LET'S NOT
INSULT THE
INTELLIGENCE OF THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC.
WHEN WE HAD AN
EMPLOYEE FREE
CHOICE ACT
THE OTHER SIDE
ARGUED, WE ONLY WANT TO
PROTECT
THE SECRET
BALLOT.
NOW,
IT'S, NO, WE WANT THE
ABILITY
FOR YOU TO VOTE ON A
SECRET BALLOT
ONLY WHEN WE WANT
IT
DONE.
WE'VE SEEN IT
IN OHIO AND
WISCONSIN.
WE HAVE A
FUNDAMENTAL
DIFFERENCE ABOUT LABOR RIGHTS
AND THE ABILITY TO
COLLECTIVELY
BARGAIN.
WE ARE PROBABLY NOT GOING TO
AGREE ON THAT
BUT LET'S FIND
SOME
BIPARTISAN GROUND WHERE WE
CAN
AGREE.
MY AMENDMENT
IS VERY
STRAIGHTFORWARD.
IT SIMPLY
PREVENTS THIS PIECE
OF
LEGISLATION, H.R. 30 THE 94,
FROM
APPLYING -- H.R. 3094 FROM
APPLYING FOR
BUSINESSES WHICH
HAVE
BEEN CITED -- IT IS VERY
SIMPLE.
THESE ARE NOT
THE VAST MAJORITY
OF EMPLOYERS WHO
ARE PLAYING BY
THE
RULES.
THIS IS
THOSE THAT HAVE HAD
EGREGIOUS
VIOLATIONS,
SPECIFICALLY AGAINST VETERANS
AND THIS WILL HELP US PROTECT
THOSE.
I
WHOLEHEARTEDLY
AGREE WE HAVE
A LOT
OF GOOD, STRONG EMPLOYERS
OUT THERE
SUPPORTING OUR GUARD
RESERVE BUT LABOR LAWS ARE
STILL BEING
VEE LATED.
WE
NEED THESE LAWS.
LAST
YEAR 3,000 CASES OF
EMPLOYERS WHO
VIOLATED THE
UNIFORMED SERVICE
EMPLOYMENT
AND
RE-EMPLOYMENT RIGHTS ACT,
THE MAIN
LAW THAT PROTECTS
VETERANS.
MY AMENDMENT
PROVIDES THE MEANS
OF CONGRESS BY
REMOVING THE
ABILITY FOR
VIOLATORS
TO
PREVENT UNNECESSARY
BARRIERS TO
A
FREE AND EXPEED YUSS UNION
ELECTION
PROCESS.
KEEP
IN MIND THESE ARE THE VERY
PEOPLE
WHO FOUGHT TO PROTECT
THE
BASIC AMERICAN RIGHT TO
ORGANIZE
COLLECTIVELY FOR A
SAFE WORKPLACE.
BUT YET WHEN THEY
COME HOME
WE'RE GOING
TO THROW BARRIERS
IN THE WAY EVEN BY
COMPANIES
THAT HAVE
ALREADY VIOLATED
VETERANS'
EMPLOYMENT RIGHTS AT
A TIME WHEN
WE HAVE HIGH
UNEMPLOYMENT
AMONGST VETERANS.
THIS
IS ONE WE CAN COME
TOGETHER.
BY
THE
WAY, TWO MILLION
VETERANS ARE
IN LABOR UNIONS OF
THEIR CHOICE
NOW.
SO THIS
ISN'T A SMALL NUMBER.
THIS IS A LARGE
NUMBER.
WHY
WOULD CONGRESS HINDER THE
ABILITY FOR A VETERAN
TO CHOOSE
WHETHER OR NOT THEY
WANT
REPRESENTATION?
IT'S WHAT THEY
FOUGHT FOR.
WHILE MY COLLEAGUES
AND I CAN
DEBATE THE
ROLE OF GOVERNMENT
AND COLLECTIVE
BARGAINING, I
DON'T BELIEVE
THERE IS A
DIFFERENCE IN
WHERE WE BELIEVE
THIS SHOULD
NOT APPLY TO
VIOLATORS OF VETERANS'
EMPLOYMENT RIGHTS AND
ALLOW
THEM TO MAKE THE
CHOICE.
I RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA, MR. WALZ, RESERVES.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA, MR.
KLINE, RISE?
MR. KLINE: MR. CHAIRMAN, I RISE
-- CLAIM
TIME IN OPPOSITION TO
THE
AMENDMENT.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR FIVE MINUTES.
MR. KLINE: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
AND, OF COURSE, I ALWAYS
HATE
TO OPPOSE
SOMETHING PRESENTED
BY
MY MINNESOTA DELEGATION
COLLEAGUE, A
VETERAN HIMSELF,
BUT,
AGAIN, I THINK WE HAVE A
MISGUIDED
AMENDMENT HERE.
WE
ARE IN THE LAST AMENDMENT --
IN THE LAST
AMENDMENT WE WERE
TAKING
AN OCCUPY WALL STREET
MOMENT AND
TO EXPRESS OUR
OUTRAGE
AT THE SALARIES OR
BONUSES
OR COMPENSATION FOR
EXECUTIVES AND WE WERE
GOING TO
PUNISH
WORKERS BECAUSE OF OUR
OUTRAGE.
UNFORTUNATELY WE'RE SORT OF
DOING THE SAME
THING HERE.
IF YOU'RE A
VETERAN AND YOUR
EMPLOYER HAS
HARMED ANY NUMBER
OF YOUR
RIGHTS UNDER
FEDERAL
LABOR
LAW, THEY HAVE BROKEN THE
LAW AND
ACTION OUGHT TO BE
TAKEN AGAINST THEM.
BUT NOW WITH THIS
AMENDMENT
THIS
WOULD GIVE THE -- THIS
ACTIVIST, NLRB,
HAVING EXCUSED
THE FREE CHOICE
OF YOUR
CO-WORKERS IN
A UNION ELECTION.
I DON'T THINK WE
WANT TO
DO
THAT.
WE
WANT
TO SUPPORT THE RIGHTS
OF
ALL WORKERS.
WE
WANT TO -- AS THE
DISTINGUISHED MINORITY
WHIP
SAID -- EMPLOYERS
AND EMPLOYEES
OUGHT TO
GET A FAIR
ELECTION.
WE WANT
A FAIR ELECTION FOR
EMPLOYERS AND
EMPLOYEES, FOR
WORKERS, WHETHER THEY ARE
VETERANS OR NOT
VETERANS.
I, HAVING SPENT
SOMETIME IN
UNIFORM
MYSELF, HAVE A SPECIAL
PLACE FOR
VETERANS.
I WANT
TO MAKE SURE THEY GET
EVERYTHING, EVERYTHING
THAT'S
COMING TO
THEM.
WE OWE THEM
SO MUCH, BUT THIS
AMENDMENT UNFORTUNATELY
WOULD
END UP
PUNISHING THEM AND THEIR
CO-WORKERS
AND I THINK
MISGUIDED EFFORT
TO HELP THEM.
WE
SHOULDN'T DO THAT.
LET'S SUPPORT THE
UNDERLYING
LEGISLATION
AND OPPOSE THIS
AMENDMENT.
I RESERVE.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA, MR. KLINE,
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA,
MR. WALZ, IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. WALZ: THANK YOU.
I RESPECT THE CHAIRMAN AND
THE
GENTLEMAN'S OPINION ON THIS.
BUT I WANT TO BE VERY
CLEAR.
THE ONLY PEOPLE
THIS APPLIES TO
IS
VIOLATORS OF VETERANS'
WORKPLACE
EMPLOYMENT.
THESE
ARE VETERANS RETURNING
HOME WHO
CHOOSE TO HAVE UNION
REPRESENTATION, WHO HAVE FOUGHT
FOR THAT RIGHT IN
UNIFORM AND
ARE NOW
BEING TOLD -- THE NLRB
SAID THIS
IS NO PROBLEM BEING
ABLE TO PUT
IN.
IT'S AT
NO COST TO THE TAXPAYER
TO BE ABLE TO DO
THIS, AND THE
THING THAT
I HEAR COMING UP
IN
THE DISCUSSION TODAY WAS
WE
NEED TO HAVE
MORE TIME TO
EXPLAIN IT
TO THEM.
I HAVE TREMENDOUS
FAITH IN THE
ABILITY OF OUR
FOLKS WHO
SERVED
IN
SPLIT-SECOND LIFE AND DEATH
DECISIONS OVERSEAS
SERVING IN
COMBAT
TO BE ABLE TO AFTER A
FEW DAYS MAKE
A DECISION WITH
THE
INFORMATION THEY'RE GIVEN
WHETHER THEY WANT
REPRESENTATION OR NOT, NOT
BEING DRUG OUT
IN LITIGATION
FOR TWO
YEARS SO
THEY CAN
PROTECT THEIR
RIGHTS AGAINST
EMPLOYERS PREVIOUSLY CITED IN
THE ONE
YEAR.
THESE ARE
NOT THE GOOD ACTORS.
THESE
ARE THE BAD ACTORS.
I DON'T WANT LIKE THE
UNDERLYING BILL.
I'M TRYING TO MAKE IT
BETTER.
WHY ARE
WE PROTECTING THE 1% OF
BAD
ACTORS IN THIS AT THE
EXPENSE OF A VETERAN
WHO HAS
THE RIGHT TO
ORGANIZE?
WITH
THAT I RESERVE THE BALANCE
OF MY TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA, MR. WALZ,
RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA,
MR. KLINE, IS RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
AGAIN, MAY I
INQUIRE AS TO HOW
MUCH TIME REMAINS ON
EITHER
SIDE?
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA, MR. KLINE, HAS THREE
MINUTES REMAINING.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA,
MR. WALZ, HAS 1
1/2 MINUTES
REMAINING.
MR. KLINE: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
I THINK THERE'S SOME
CONFUSION
HERE.
THE
OTHER GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA SAYS THAT THESE
ARE,
TALK ABOUT
VETERANS WHO HAVE
CHOSEN TO HAVE A UNION.
THE
POINT IS, WE DON'T KNOW IF
THEY'VE CHOAST CHOSE EVER
TO
HAVE A UNION
-- IF THEY'VE
CHOSEN TO HAVE
A UNION.
WE
DON'T KNOW THAT.
THAT'S WHAT
THE ELECTION IS
FOR.
AND
THEY DESERVE THE TIME AND
THE
OPPORTUNITY TO ASK
QUESTIONS, GET ANSWERS,
HEAR
FROM
ALL SIDES AND MAKE AN
INFORMED DECISION.
AND
WHAT THE UNDERLYING BILL
DOES IS
SAYS, YOU GET AT LEAST
35 DAYS
AND I WOULD REMIND MY
COLLEAGUES
THAT THE CURRENT
AVERAGE
TIME IS 31 DAYS AND THE
MEDIAN
TIME IS 38 DAYS.
BUT WE
THINK A MONTH, FIVE
WEEKS,
OUGHT TO BE TIME FOR
WORKERS TO BE
ABLE TO RECEIVE
THE INFORMATION, ASK
THE
QUESTIONS,
CHALLENGE INFORMATION
FROM THE
EMPLOYER AND FROM THE
UNION ORGANIZER
AND THEN MAKE AN
INFORMED DECISION.
AND WHILE
IT IS TRUE CERTAINLY
SOMETIMES IN COMBAT THAT
YOU
HAVE TO MAKE
SPLIT-SECOND
DECISIONS TO
SAVE YOUR LIFE OR
THE
LIVES OF -- LIVES OF
COLLEAGUES OR TO ACHIEVE
THE
MISSION, YOU SHOULDN'T BE
REQUIRED TO DO
THAT HERE IN
MAKING THIS DECISION
FOR YOU AND
YOUR
FAMILY.
YOU OUGHT TO HAVE TIME
TO DO
IT.
AND BECAUSE AN
EMPLOYER HAS
MISBEHAVED, IN THE EXAMPLE
OF
THIS AMENDMENT
, THE EMPLOYER
SHOULD BE PUNISHED
FOR THAT IF
HE'S BROKEN
LAW BUT THE
EMPLOYEES SHOULD NOT BE
DEPRIVED
OF THE OPPORTUNITY TO MAKE
AN
INFORMED DECISION AND THAT'S
WHAT THIS AMENDMENT
WOULD DO,
SO,
AGAIN, RELUCTANTLY I OPPOSE
THIS AMENDMENT AND SUPPORT
THE
UNDERLYING BILL
AND I RESERVE.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA, MR. KLINE, RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA,
MR.
WALZ, IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. WALZ:
THANK YOU.
I EXPRESS MY
DISAPPOINTMENT WITH
THE GENTLEMAN.
I DO RESPECT HIS
SERVICE AND WE
HAVE
A FOND ATTACHMENT TO OUR
VETERANS
IN GETTING THIS RIGHT.
LET ME DO SOMETHING THAT
DOESN'T
HAPPEN DOWN HERE
VERY MUCH.
TO SHOW YOU
HOW SMALL THIS IS.
I'LL
READ YOU THE
ENTIRE
AMENDMENT.
THE DESIGNATED
AUTHORITY
REFERRED TO IN
SUBPARAGRAPH B
ARE EMPLOYERS THAT HAVE BEEN
FOUND LIABLE
FOR LABOR LAW
VIOLATIONS AGAINST VETERANS OF
THE ARMED FORCES DURING THE
ONE-YEAR PERIOD PROCEEDING THE
FILING OF PETITION
UNDER THIS
SUBSECTION.
SUCH
PARTIES HAY NOT ENGAGE IN
THE TACTIC
OF RAISING NEW ISSUES
OR PETITIONS DURING
A
PRE-ELECTION HEARING THAT WERE
NOT
RAISED PRIOR TO THE
COMMENCEMENT OF THE HEARING.
NO MATTER HOW
YOU FEEL ABOUT THE
UNDERLYING BILL,
IF WE REALLY
WANT TO MAKE
THIS BETTER AND TRY
AND REACH ACROSS
TOGETHER, MAYBE
THIS IS ONE AREA WE COULD
DO IT.
I WOULD URGE
MY COLLEAGUES ON
BOTH
SIDES OF THE AISLE, DO
WHAT'S RIGHT,
PICK OFF THESE BAD
EMPLOYERS SO
THEY CAN'T ENGAGE
IN THESE
TACTICS AGAINST
VETERANS.
LET'S GET OUR FOLKS BACK TO WORK
AND AGREE TO DISAGREE
ON THE
FUNDAMENTAL UNDERLYING BILL
ON
LABOR.
THIS ONE WE SHOULDN'T.
AND
I YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF
MY TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA YIELDS BACK.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA,
MR. KLINE, IS
RECOGNIZED.
MR. KLINE: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
THANK YOU
FOR KEEPING TRACK
OF
THE MINNESOTANS HERE,
TOO,
AS
WELL.
I'M SORRY BUT AGAIN
WE JUST HAVE
A FUNDAMENTAL
DIFFERENCE HERE.
IF AN EMPLOYER
IS LIABLE, HAS
MADE MISTAKES, HAS
BROKEN THE
LAW, THEY SHOULD BE PUNISHED
UNDER THE
LAW.
WHICH EVER LAW
THEY HAVE
VIOLATED
, IN VIOLATING THE
RIGHTS OF
EMPLOYEES, VETERANS OR
NOT.
BUT
THIS AMENDMENT IS AN ATTEMPT
TO
DISMANTLE, DISMANTLE A
SUCCESSFUL UNION ELECTION
PROCESS
THAT IS FAIR TO VETERANS
AND
NONVETERANS, TO EMPLOYEES
AND TO EMPLOYERS
.
THIS AMENDMENT
IN AN ATTEMPT TO
PUNISH EMPLOYERS WHO HAVE
MISBEHAVED, WHO OUGHT
TO BE
PUNISHED UNDER
THE LAW, UNDER
ANOTHER LAW,
IS SIMPLY GOING TO
DENY THE RIGHTS
OF WORKERS TO
HAVE THE
OPPORTUNITY TO MAKE AN
INFORMED
DECISION AND SO I
OPPOSE
THIS AMENDMENT AND
SUPPORT THE
UNDERLYING
LEGISLATION AND YIELD BACK.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA, MR. KLINE,
YIELDS
BACK.
ALL TIME HAVING
EXPIRED, THE
QUESTION IS ON THE AMENDMENT
OFFERED BY THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA, MR.
WALZ.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
IN THE OPINION OF THE
CHAIR, THE
NOES
HAVE IT, AND THE AMENDMENT
IS NOT
AGREED TO.
MR. WALZ: MR. CHAIRMAN, I ASK
FOR A RECORDED
VOTE.
THE CHAIR: PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 6
OF RULE 18, FURTHER PROCEEDINGS
OFFERED BY THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA, MR. WALZ, WILL BE
POSTPONED.
IT IS NOW
IN ORDER TO CONSIDER
AMENDMENT NUMBER 4 PRINTED IN
HOUSE REPORT
112-291.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM TEXAS SEEK
RECOGNITION?
THE CLERK
WILL DESIGNATE THE
AMENDMENT.
THE CLERK: AMENDMENT NUMBER 4
PRINTED
IN HOUSE REPORT
112-291
OFFERED
BY MS. JACKSON LEE OF
TEXAS.
THE CHAIR: PURSUANT TO HOUSE
RESOLUTION
470,
THE GENTLEWOMAN
FROM TEXAS,
MS. JACKSON LEE, AND
A MEMBER
OPPOSED EACH WILL
CONTROL
FIVE
MINUTES.
THE CHAIR NOW
RECOGNIZES THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM TEXAS
.
MS. JACKSON LEE: I THANK THE
CHAIRMAN VERY MUCH
AND MY
QUESTION
TO MY COLLEAGUES IS
WHETHER
WORKERS COME AS
REPUBLICANS
OR DEMOCRATS OR DO
THEY COME SIMPLY
AS AMERICANS
OPERATING UNDER
A CONSTITUTIONAL
PROVISION?
THAT
WE ALL
CELEBRATE.
AND THAT IS THE
FIRST
AMENDMENT.
THE FIRST
AMENDMENT CLEARLY
ALLOWS
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE TO
PETITION
, TO HAVE FREEDOM OF
EXPRESSION
AND BY ESSENCE
FREEDOM TO
ASSEMBLE.
WE ALSO RECOGNIZE
THAT IN THE
COURSE OF POWER
THERE IS A
WORKER AND
THERE IS THE EMPLOYER
, THE
EMPLOYER IN MANY INSTANCES
INTIMIDATES.
AND SO
THE NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS BOARD
RECOGNIZED THE
UNEVENNESS OF POWER
WITH THOSE
WHO, WHETHER THEY ARE RETURNING
TROOPS
OR VETERANS, WHETHER OR
NOT THEY'RE SINGLE
MOTHERS,
WORKING FAMILIES WHO WANT
TO
BETTER THEIR
LIFE, THEY
UNDERSTAND THAT THERE
NEEDS TO
BE
A FAIRNESS IN ORDER FOR THIS
LITTLE SMALL BOOK, THE
CONSTITUTION, TO
ACTUALLY
OPERATE.
SO MY AMENDMENT IS
VERY SIMPLE.
MY AMENDMENT
ATTEMPTS TO MAKE AN
EVEN
PLAYING FIELD AND IT TAKES
AWAY THE POWER OF THE
UNDERLYING
LEGISLATION
WHICH IS TO LIMIT
HOW LONG
THE ELECTION MAY GO ON
AND IN FACT
DELAY THE ELECTION,
IF
YOU
WILL.
AND
SO THIS AMENDMENT STRIKES
THE PROVISION
THAT KEELS --
DEALS
WITH THE TIME FRAME FOR
WHICH THE ELECTION
CAN GO ON AND
THE
EMPLOYER CAN INTERFERE WITH
THAT ELECTION.
DELAY GIVES
UNSCRUPULOUS
EMPLOYERS MORE
TIME TO USE THE
TIME FRAME TO
DELAY THE
ELECTIONS.
IT'S A SIMPLE PREMISE
THAT YOU
WIN OR
LOSE ELECTIONS, BUT IF
YOU ALLOW EMPLOYERS TO USE
THE
HAND
OF INTIMIDATION AND TO STOP
THE
ELECTION, YOU TAKE AWAY SOME
OF THE
PRIVILEGES OF BEING AN
AMERICAN.
NOW, I FRANKLY BELIEVE
THAT IN
THIS TIME
THAT WE'RE ON THE
FLOOR WE REALLY
SHOULD BE
DEBATING THE
EXTENSION OF THE
UNEMPLOYMENT
BENEFITS.
I BELIEVE THAT WE
SHOULD BE
DISCUSSING THE PASSAGE
OF THE
AMERICAN
JOBS ACT.
WE'RE
NOT DOING THAT.
WE'RE HERE
TO LIMIT THE RIGHTS
OF
AMERICANS AND I'D ASK MY
COLLEAGUE TO
SUPPORT THE
AMENDMENT
THAT STOPS EMPLOYERS
FROM
DELAYING THE RIGHTS OF
AMERICANS BY PARTICIPATING
IN
DELAYING LITIGATION
, RISING
THEIR POWER,
LIMITING THE POWER
OF THE
WORKER.
I HOPE
MY COLLEAGUES WILL JOIN
ME
IN SUPPORTING
MY AMENDMENT.
I
RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLELADY
RESERVES.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM SOUTH CAROLINA
RISE?
MR. GOWDY: MR. CHAIRMAN, I RISE
IN -- TO
CLAIM TIME IN
OPPOSITION.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR FIVE MINUTES.
MR. GOWDY: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
THIS AMENDMENT WOULD
STRIKE
PROVISIONS OF THE WORK
FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND FAIRNESS
ACT THAT
ENSURE
EMPLOYERS HAVE AT LEAST
14 DAYS
, THAT'S NOT A
MISSTATEMENT, 14 DAYS
TO FIND
LEGAL COUNSEL
AND PREPARE THEIR
CASE FOR THE
PRE-ELECTION
HEARING.
ADDITIONALLY IT WOULD STRIKE THE
PROVISIONS
THAT ENSURE EMPLOYERS
HAVE
35 DAYS TO EDUCATE THEIR
WORKERS
AND EMPLOYEES HAVE 35
DAYS
TO DETERMINE WHETHER THEY
WISH
TO JOIN A UNION.
AND,
MR. CHAIRMAN, INFORMATION
IS POWER AND I
FRANKLY DON'T
UNDERSTAND THE
ANTAGONISM TOWARD
INFORMATION
.
I
DON'T UNDERSTAND THE
ANTAGONISM
TOWARDS EMPLOYERS.
WE GIVE
GARDEN VARIETY,
COMMON
CRIMINAL
SHOPLIFTERS 180
DAYS TO
FIND
A LAWYER.
DAYS FOR A SHOPLIFTER TO
FIND A
LAWYER BEWE CAN'T GIVE
EMPLOYERS
TWO WEEKS?
IS TWO
WEEKS REALLY TOO MUCH TO
ASK?
TO FIND
A LAWYER?
AND THERE HAVE BEEN
UNIONS, MR.
CHAIRMAN, THAT HAVE
ALREADY
ENDORSED
THIS PRESIDENT AND HIS
RE-ELECTION BID.
ALREADY
360-SOMETHING-DAYS OUT
WAS THE FIRST
ONE I NOTED.
SO THEY NEED
365 DAYS TO PREPARE
FOR AN
ELECTION BUT WE CAN'T
GIVE EMPLOYERS
35 DAYS?
YOU C
AN CHECK OUT A LIBRARY BOOK
FOR
LONGER THAN YOU WANT TO GIVE
EMPLOYERS THE
ABILITY TO PREPARE
FOR AN ELECTION
?
THIS IS AN
IMPORTANT DECISION,
NOT
ONLY IN THE
LIVES OF THE
EMPLOYEES BUT THE
EMPLOYERS.
MANY OF WHOM
ARE SMALL BUSINESS
OWNERS.
AND
THEY'VE GOT TO NEGOTIATE THE
LEGAL
LABYRINTH THAT IS OUR
FEDERAL
LABOR LAW AND YOU'RE
GOING TO GIVE THEM
35 DAYS AND
TO GET A LAWYER.
MR. CHAIRMAN, THIS AMENDMENT
WILL RESTRICT
EMPLOYERS' FREE
SPEECH AND
UNDERMINE WORKERS'
FREE
CHOICE.
INFORMATION
IS POWER.
SOMETIMES THAT
TAKES TIME.
I DON'T THINK
35 DAYS UNDER
ANYONE'S
CALCULUS IS TOO MUCH
TIME TO PREPARE
FOR AN ELECTION.
AND IF WE
CAN GIVE A SHOPLIFTER
OR
A SPEEDER OR A DRUNK DRIVER
180 DAYS TO GO HIRE A LAWYER,
SURELY THE GOODNESS
WE CAN GIVE
A SMALL BUSINESS
JOB CREATOR A
COUPLE OF WEEKS
AND WITH THAT I
WOULD
RESERVE THE BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
SOUTH CAROLINA RESERVES.
THE GENTLEWOMAN FROM TEXAS IS
RECOGNIZED.
MS. JACKSON LEE: VERY BRIEFLY,
LISTENING TO MY GOOD FRIEND
FROM
SOUTH CAROLINA, IT'S TIME TO
TAKE OUT THE WHITE
HANKIE AND
BEGIN TO
CRY FOR THE EMPLOYERS
AGAINST THESE
DEADLY WORKERS.
SOME OF
THEM VETERANS AND SINGLE
PARENTS.
HEAR ME
VERY CLEARLY.
THERE ARE
35 DAYS FOR
THE FILING
OF A PETITION BUT
THERE IS NO
LIMIT TO IT THE
AMOUNT OF TIME
-- TO THE
AMOUNT OF
TIME AN
EMPLOYER
CAN DELAY THE ELECTION
THROUGH
LITIGATION.
IF THAT
ISN'T AN IMBALANCE
AGAINST THE
VULNERABLE WORKER,
THE WORKER
THAT IS BEHIND A
CASHIER, THE
WORKER WHO IS
MANUFACTURING
MADE IT IN AMERICA
D, A TRINKET OF SOME
KIND, THE
TEXTILE WORKER,
A RETURNING
SOLDIER FROM
THE BATTLEFIELD,
THEN
WHAT IS?
GOD BLESS THE
EMPLOYER WITH
THEIR
CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS, I
APPLAUD
THEM.
BUT WHAT THIS
BILL IS DOING AND
WHAT
THIS SECTION IS DOING IS
TAKING A SPEAR
AND GOING ON AND
ON AND
ON FOR DILATORY
LITIGATION TACTICS,
TO DISALLOW
THE ORGANIZING
THAT IS PROTECTED
UNDER THE CONSTITUTION AND
THE
DUE PROCESS
UNDER THE FIFTH
AMENDMENT.
GO AHEAD,
EMPLOYERS, GET YOUR
LAWYERS, MOVE ON.
BUT THE QUESTION
IS, HOW LONG?
IS
-- HOW LONG IS TOO LONG?
I RESERVE MY TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLELADY FROM
TEXAS RESERVES.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM TICK IS
RECOGNIZED.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM SOUTH
CAROLINA HAS 2 1/2 MINUTES
REMAINING.
MR. GOWDY: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
MY FIRST JOB WAS DELIVERING
NEWSPAPERS.
THE JOB AFTER THAT WAS BAGGING
GROCERIES AT A
LOCAL GROCERY
STORE AND
THE JOB AFTER THAT WAS
WORKING IN A
TOBACCO WAREHOUSE.
I DON'T RECALL EVER
BEING HIRED
BY AN EMPLOYEE
.
I
DON'T UNDERSTAND THE
ANTAGONISM TOWARD
EMPLOYERS.
I
DON'T UNDERSTAND THE
ANTAGONISM
TOWARDS PEOPLE WHO
ARE
WILLING
TO INVEST THEIR
FORTUNE AND HAVE
THE UNMITIGATED
TEMERITY TO
WANT TO BE
SUCCESSFUL AND HIRE OTHER
PEOPLE.
I
DON'T UNDERSTAND
THE
ANTAGONISM
TOWARDS JOB CREATORS.
AND,
MR. CHAIRMAN, I WILL SAY IT
AGAIN.
IF
WE CAN GIVE
180 DAYS TO
SOMEONE
WHO SHOPLIFTS FROM A
STORE,
TO GO FIND A LAWYER, BUT
WE CAN'T
GIVE 14 DAYS TO THE
SMALL BUSINESS OWNER
WHO WANTS
TO
DEFEND AGAINST A SUIT,
NEGOTIATING THE LEGAL LABYRINTH
THAT MANY OF THE
LAWYERS IN THIS
BODY DON'T UNDERSTAND
, PRESENT
COMPANY INCLUDED,
THERE ARE
EXPERTS IN LABOR LAW AND
UNLESS
YOU HAVE
COUNSEL HIRED,
CORPORATE COUNSEL, YOU'RE GOING
TO HAVE TO GO
FIND A
LAWYER,
EDUCATE THEM ON YOUR
ISSUES AND
MR. KLINE
GIVES THEM A WHOPPING
TWO
WEEKS.
14 DAYS
IS EMINENTLY REASONABLE
AND
35 DAYS FOR SOMETHING AS
POTENTIALLY
TRANSFORMATIVE AS AN
ELECTION
IS NOT TOO MUCH TO ASK
FOR AND
THERE IS NOTHING IN THE
CONSTITUTION OF THE UNITED
STATES THAT SAYS OTHERWISE.
AND WITH THAT I WOULD
RESERVE
THE BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
SOUTH CAROLINA RESERVES.
THE GENTLELADY FROM TEXAS IS
RECOGNIZED.
MS. JACKSON LEE: WHAT I SAY TO
MY GOOD FRIEND
FROM SOUTH
CAROLINA, I HAVE THE
GREATEST
RESPECT FOR
EMPLOYERS.
I'D LIKE
THE GENTLEMAN TO JOIN
ME
IN PASSING THE AMERICAN
JOBS
ACT TO
GIVE THEM PAYROLL TAX
RELIEF, TO
GIVE THEM TAX CREDITS
FOR
HIRING NEW EMPLOYEES.
BUT YOU HAVE
TO ASK THE QUESTION
AFTER THIS BILL'S
IMPLEMENTATION, WILL WORKERS
VIEW THEIR WORKPLACE MORE
FAVORABLY?
WILL THEIR WAGES MATCH THE
GROWTH RATE OF THE COMPANY AND
ECONOMY?
WILL WORKERS FEEL
LIKE AMERICAN
EMPLOYERS SUPPORTED
BY
GOVERNMENT PROVIDE
MEANINGFUL
SAFETY
FOR COMMUNITY SURVIVAL?
THIS LEGISLATION
FRANKLY
UNDERMINES THE AMERICAN WORKERS.
CAN WE ALL GET
ALONG?
CAN WE FIND
A WAY TO ADDRESS THE
CONCERNS
OF MAKING SURE THAT
WE'RE FAIR
TO THE EMPLOYER BUT
NOT HAVE DELAY
AFTER DELAY AFTER
DELAY
TO DENY SOMEONE THEIR
CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS OF
ORGANIZING, FREEDOM
OF
EXPRESSION?
I THINK WE CAN.
THE
ELIMINATION OF THE
PROVISIONS -- PROVISIONS THAT I
HAVE
SPOKEN TO IS A DILATORY
UPPERHAND OF
EMPLOYERS TO GET
THE BETTER HAND
OF OUR
EMPLOYEES.
I RESERVE MY TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLELADY FROM
TEXAS RESERVES.
THE GENTLELADY FROM TEXAS HAS
SECONDS
REMAINING.
THE GENTLEMAN FROM SOUTH
CAROLINA IS RECOGNIZED, HE HAS
45 SECONDS
REMAINING.
MR. GOWDY: THANK YOU,
MR.
CHAIRMAN.
I WOULD INVITE MY FRIENDS ON THE
OTHER SIDE OF THE AISLE TO JOIN
US IN
ADDRESSING WHAT I HEAR
FROM EVERY SMALL BUSINESS
OWNER
BACK IN SOUTH CAROLINA, WHICH
IS
FIX
THE REGULATORY APPARATUS,
FIX THE TAX
STRUCTURE, FIX THE
LITIGATION STRUCTURE,
QUIT
SPENDING MONEY
YOU DON'T HAVE.
MR. CHAIRMAN, THE PRESIDENT,
WHO
WAS STANDING NOT THREE
FEET IN
FRONT
OF YOU, SAID, WE SHOULD
HAVE NO
MORE REGULATION THAN IS
NECESSARY FOR
THE HEALTH, SAFETY
AND SECURITY
OF THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
THAT'S
NOT A REPUBLICAN THAT
SAID
THAT, THAT'S THE
PRESIDENT
OF THE
UNITED STATES.
SO I WOULD ASK THE
NLRB, WHAT
PART OF HEALTH, SAFETY
AND
SECURITY ARE YOU
TRYING TO FIX
WITH
QUICKY ELECTIONS, PLACING
POSTERS IN THE
WORKPLACE AND
OTHER
REGULATIONS THAT DO
NOTHING
EXCEPT PUNISH JOB
CREATORS?
AND
WITH THAT I WOULD
RESERVE
THE BALANCE OF MY TIME.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN'S TIME
HAS EXPIRED.
THE GENTLELADY FROM TEXAS IS
RECOGNIZED FOR 15
SECONDS.
MS. JACKSON LEE: IN MY
HAND I
HAVE
H.R. 3094 AND IN THIS HAND
I HAVE THE CONSTITUTION.
I DON'T KNOW WHO YOU
WOULD STAND
WITH.
SUPPORT MY AMENDMENT, SUPPORT
THE CONSTITUTION, PROVIDE
WORKERS THE OPPORTUNITY
FOR
FREEDOM AND
THE RIGHT TO
ORGANIZE.
I ASK MY COLLEAGUES
TO SUPPORT
AND JOIN ME
WITH THE JACKSON LEE
AMENDMENT.
WITH THAT I YIELD BACK.
THE CHAIR:
THE QUESTION IS ON
THE AMENDMENT OFFERED
BY THE
GENTLELADY FROM TEXAS.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
IN THE OPINION OF THE CHAIR,
THE NOES HAVE IT.
THE AMENDMENT IS NOT AGREED
TO.
THE GENTLELADY FROM
TEXAS.
MS. JACKSON LEE: I
ASK FOR THE
YEAS AND NAYS.
THE CHAIR: PURSUANT TO CLAUSE 6
OF RULE 18,
FURTHER PROCEEDINGS
ON THE AMENDMENT OFFERED BY BY
THE GENTLELADY FROM TEXAS WILL
BE POSTPONED.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLELADY FROM WISCONSIN SEEK
RECOGNITION?
MS. MOORE:
I HAVE A MOTION AT
THE
DESK.
THE CLERK: MS.
MOORE OF
WISCONSIN MOVES
THAT THE
COMMITTEE DO
NOW RISE AND
REPORT THE
BILL TO THE HOUSE
WITH THE RECOMMENDATION
THAT
THE
ENACTING CLAUSE BE
STRICKEN.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLELADY FROM
WISCONSIN IS RECOGNIZED FOR
FIVE MINUTES IN SUPPORT OF
HER
MOTION.
MS. MOORE: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIR.
I RISE TO MAKE THIS MOTION
TODAY BECAUSE
I AM OPPOSED TO
THE
UNDERLYING
BILL.
THE
SO-CALLED WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND
FAIRNESS ACT.
MR. CHAIR,
I HOPE THAT ALL MY
COLLEAGUES
HAVE GOTTEN THEIR
TICKETS FOR
THIS SHOW BECAUSE
ONCE AGAIN
MY REPUBLICAN
COLLEAGUES HAVE TURNED
THESE
HALLOWED
HALLS OF CONGRESS INTO
A PLACE
WHERE POLITICAL THEATER
OR BETTER
YET A CIRCUS AS THE
JOKE IS
ON WORKING CLASS
AMERICA.
TODAY'S
SO-CALLED WORK FORCE
DEMOCRACY AND FAIRNESS ACT
IS
ANOTHER SCENE IN THIS
UNFOLDING
PLOT
TO UNDERMINE AMERICAN
WORKERS.
IT
WOULD BE
COMEDY IF IT
WEREN'T SUCH A
TRAGEDY FOR THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE.
EVERY DAY THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
ARE
FORCED TO PLAY
THE PART OF
THE CLOWN
.
THEY WATCH
REPUBLICANS PUT ON
THIS PERFORMANCE
CLAIMING TO
WANT
TO PROTECT AMERICAN JOBS
AND
WORKERS WHILE BEHIND THE
SCENES THEY
WORK TO DISMANTLE
THE
RIGHTS OF THE AMERICAN
WORKER.
AND LIKE THE CLOWN,
THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE
MUST LEARN TO
LAUGH WITH
TEARS IN THEIR EYES.
TODAY'S
INSTALLMENT OF TRAGIC
THEATER STARS
A BILL WHICH HAS
BEEN MORE APPROPRIATELY
RENAMED
BY
MY DEMOCRATIC COLLEAGUES AS
THE ELECTION
PREVENTION ACT,
THIS BILL
WILL PERMIT EMPLOYERS
TO DELAY
INDEFINITELY A UNION
ELECTION BY
MANDATING DELAYS IN
THE UNION ELECTION
PROCESS AND
FAILING TO
PLACE
LIMITS ON HOW
LONG AN ELECTION CAN BE
DELAYED.
THESE DELAYS WOULD
ALLOW MORE
INTIMIDATION AND
HARASSMENT OF
EMPLOYEES, INCLUDING
HIRING
UNION-BUSTING
COMPANIES.
THIS BILL
PERVERTS THE NOTION
OF EMPLOYEE
FREE CHOICE IN THE
FACE OF THE
POWER OF AN
EMPLOYER
TO INDEFINITELY
POSTPONE
AN ELECTION.
IN WISCONSIN,
MR. CHAIR, WE
HAVE SEEN THIS
SONG AND DANCE
BEFORE.
UNDER THE GUISE OF
DEFICIT
REDUCTION, GOVERNOR
WALKER
UNDERMINED
WORKERS' RIGHTS,
RAMMED THROUGH
LEGISLATION THAT
CUT STATE EMPLOYEE
BENEFITS AND
STRIPS
UNIONS OF THEIR
COLLECTIVE
BARGAINING RIGHTS.
OHIO, TOO,
HAS SEEN THIS
HORRIFIC CURTAIN CALL
WITH THE
GOVERNOR AND
THE PASSAGE OF
S.B. 5.
BUT
WHAT GOVERNOR WALKER AND
CASEY IS
NOT PREPARED FOR IS
THE SECOND ACT
OF THIS DRAMA.
WHEN
THE CURTAIN OPENED ON
NOVEMBER 8
IN OHIO, THEY
FLOCKED TO THE
POLLS WITH A
RESOUNDING
VOICE AND REPEALED
S.B.
5.
IT CONTINUES IN MY
STATE OF
WISCONSIN WHEREIN IN
JUST TWO
WEEKS
WE HAVE GARNERED 300,000
SIGNATURES POISED TO
RECALL
GOVERNOR SCOTT
WALKER.
MR. CHAIR, THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE
WILL
NOT BE UPSTAGED BY THIS
ANTI-UNION,
ANTI-WORKER AND
ANTI-FAMILY PLAY.
OUR NATION'S
MIDDLE CLASS IS
DEMANDING TO
BARGAIN FOR MORE
OF THE WEALTH THAT THEY
CREATED.
MR.
CHAIR, THIS CLEAR
ATTACK ON
WORKERS'
RIGHTS
DEPARTS
FROM
DEMOCRACY IN THE WORKPLACE.
IT'S TIME TO PULL
THE CURTAIN
AND PULL
THE
HOOK OUT ON THIS
CIRCUS ACT AND
BRING UP REAL
JOBS.
I YIELD
TO MY COLLEAGUE,
THE
LADY FROM
OHIO, BETTY SUTTON.
MS. SUTTON: I THANK THE
GENTLEWOMAN FOR YIELDING
AND I
THANK HER FOR
THE MOTION.
MR. SPEAKER, WHAT'S IT
GOING TO
TAKE TO
GET THIS BODY TO FOCUS
ON PRIORITY ONE WHICH
IS
GETTING
AMERICA BACK TO WORK?
WHY, MR. SPEAKER,
ARE WE HERE
YET
AGAIN DEBATING AN
ANTI-WORKER BILL WHEN
WE SHOULD
BE
WORKING TOGETHER TO HELP
FOSTER
JOBS?
INSTEAD OF
TRYING TO DISEMPOWER
WORKERS
AND FURTHER WEAKEN THE
MIDDLE
CLASS, WHY AREN'T WE
TRYING TO CREATE OPPORTUNITIES
FOR THEM AND
THEIR FAMILIES?
EVERY DAY
THAT THE FOCUS IS ON
ATTACKING
WORKERS INSTEAD OF
GENERATING JOB
OPPORTUNITIES IS
ONE
DAY LONGER
WE'RE
MEYERED AT
UNACCEPTABLE RATE
OF
UNEMPLOYMENT.
IT'S ANOTHER DAY THAT AMERICANS
WILL
STRUGGLE.
HERE WE ARE
DEBATING THIS
EXTREME AND
LOPSIDED BILL TO
GIVE BIG CORPORATIONS
THE UPPER
HAND
OVER WORKING FAMILIES, A
BILL THAT DOES NOTHING
TO
BOLSTER
OUR RECOVERY BUT DOES A
LOT
TO STACK THE DECK AGAINST
AMERICAN
WORKERS.
WE HAVE
SEEN THIS FIGHT BEFORE
AS
THE GENTLEWOMAN HAS POINTED
OUT IN OTHER
PLACES AND THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE ARE VOICING
THEIR ON
SESSION TO THESE
FUNDAMENTAL ATTACKS
AGAINST
WORKERS.
IN MY STATE OF OHIO
WE SAW A
GOVERNOR TRY TO
SILENCE OUR
FIREFIGHTERS,
TEACHERS, OUR
POLICE OFFICERS, OUR
NURSES AND
OTHER
PEOPLE WHO SERVE OHIO.
INSTEAD OF FOCUSING ON
JOBS,
THE GOVERNOR AND
HIS ALLIES
PUSHED
THE BILL THROUGH AND
UNLEVELED THE PLAYING FIELD
FOR
WORKING
FAMILIES.
IT
WASN'T RIGHT THERE AND IT'S
NOT RIGHT
HERE AND THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE
--
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLELADY'S
TIME HAS EXPIRED.
MS. SUTTON: DEFEAT THIS
BILL.
THE CHAIR:
FOR WHAT PURPOSE
DOES
THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA
RISE?
MR. KLINE: I
RISE TO CLAIM TIME
IN OPPOSITION
TO THIS MOTION.
THE CHAIR:
THE GENTLEMAN IS
RECOGNIZED FOR FIVE MINUTES.
MR. KLINE: THANK YOU, MR.
CHAIRMAN.
THIS CLEARLY
-- IN
FACT, THE
LANGUAGE OF THE MOTION IS
DESIGNED TO KILL
THE BILL.
I UNDERSTAND THE GENTLELADY
DOESN'T LIKE
THE BILL.
BUT THE
CHARACTERIZATION OF IT
IS INCORRECT.
WE HEARD
TODAY ON THIS FLOOR
SOME DISTINGUISHED
MEMBERS OF
THE OTHER
PARTY THAT THE NLRB
OUGHT TO BE FAIR
, THAT
EMPLOYERS AND EMPLOYEES
OUGHT
TO GET
A FAIR ELECTION.
WE AGREE
WITH THAT.
WE HAVE
HEARD TODAY THAT THE
MAJORITY
PARTY HAS DONE NOTHING
TO IMPROVE THE
ECONOMY AND HELP
JOB CREATORS CREATE
JOBS.
CLEARLY WE
DISAGREE.
MEMBER
AFTER MEMBER HAS STOOD
UP
HERE AND SAID
WE HAVE A
PLAN, WE'VE BEEN
ADVANCING
LEGISLATION,
WE CONTINUE TO
ADVANCE
LEGISLATION, WE HAVE
OVER 20 BILLS
PASSED BY THIS
HOUSE
SITTING OVER IN THE
SENATE
WAITING
FOR MAJORITY
LEADER REID TO TAKE
THEM UP.
JOBS THAT WILL CLEAR
THE WAY
FOR JOB
CREATORS, THE PRIVATE
SECTOR,
TO PUT AMERICANS BACK
TO WORK.
CLEARLY
THERE IS A BLIZZARD OF
REGULATIONS
THAT IS DESCENDING
ON
THE WORKPLACE.
THE SPEAKER GOT
A LETTER BACK
FROM THE ADMINISTRATION A FEW
WEEKS AGO
THAT SAID THERE WERE
SOME 219
REGULATIONS IN THE
PIPELINE EACH OF WHICH
WOULD
HAVE AN
IMPACT ON THE ECONOMY
OVER
$100 MILLION AND I THINK
SEVEN WOULD
HAVE AN IMPACT OVER
$1
BILLION.
REGULATIONS COMING
FROM
EVERY
DIRECTION.
AND MY COLLEAGUES POINTED
OUT
THAT EVEN THE
PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES SAID WE SHOULDN'T
BE HAVING
MORE
REGULATIONS THAT
DON'T
DIRECTLY AFFECT THE
SAFETY AND
SECURITY OF THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE OR
WORDS CLOSE
TO
THAT EFFECT.
THE GENTLELADY,
MY FRIEND FROM
WISCONSIN, SAID THERE WAS
AN
UNFOLDING
PLOT.
WELL
, I AGREE THERE DOES SEEM
TO BE AN
UNFOLDING PLOT THAT'S
COMING
FROM THE ADMINISTRATION
THROUGH THE
NLRB TO ADVANCE THE
SPECIAL
INTEREST OF BIG LABOR
BOSSES
.
WE DON'T
THINK THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S NOT
GIVING EMPLOYERS AND
EMPLOYEES A FAIR
ELECTION.
THAT'S
ADVANCING THE SPECIAL
INTEREST OF BIG
UNION BOSSES.
IT'S
NOT PROTECTING THE RIGHTS
OF WORKERS,
WHETHER THEY'RE IN
THE UNION
OR NOT.
-- WHETHER
THEY'RE IN A UNION
OR NOT.
EMPLOYEES AND EMPLOYERS SHOULD
GET
A FAIR ELECTION.
THE
NLRB SHOULD
NOT BE SLANTING
IT,
HANDING IT TO BIG LABOR
BOSSES.
SO THIS
IS AN EFFORT TO KILL
THE BILL.
I BELIEVE IT'S A GOOD
BILL.
IT RESTORES
PRACTICES THAT HAVE
BEEN
IN PLACE, PROVIDING
FAIR
ELECTIONS
FOR DECADES.
I WOULD
ENCOURAGE MY COLLEAGUES
TO
SUPPORT THE
UNDERLYING
LEGISLATION
AND VOTE AGAINST
THIS MOTION TO
KILL THE BILL
AND I YIELD BACK.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA YIELDS BACK.
THE QUESTION
IS ON THE
PREFERENTIAL MOTION.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
THE NOES HAVE
IT AND THE
PREFERENTIAL MOTION IS NOT
ADOPTED.
MS. MOORE: MR.
CHAIR, I WOULD
NOTE
THERE IS NO QUORUM AND I
REQUEST A ROLL CALL.
THE CHAIR: THE CHAIR
WILL COUNT
FOR A QUORUM.
MS. MOORE:
I'M NOT ASKING FOR A
QUORUM
CALL.
I'M ASKING FOR
A ROLL CALL.
THE CHAIR: THE GENTLEWOMAN
WITHDRAWS
ARE POINT OF ORDER
FOR A QUORUM?
MS. MOORE:
YES.
THE CHAIR: THE CHAIR
WILL COUNT
FOR A
RECORDED VOTE.
A SUFFICIENT NUMBER HAVING
ARISEN, A RECORDED VOTE IS
ORDERED.
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE.
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE
6-G OF RULE
18, THIS WILL BE
FOLLOWED BY
TWO-MINUTE
VOTES ON THE
FOLLOWING AMENDMENT,
AMENDMENT
NUMBER 1 BY
MR. BISHOP OF
NEW
YORK, AMENDMENT NUMBER
2 BY MR.
BOSWELL OF IOWA,
AMENDMENT
NUMBER
3 BY MR. WALZ OF
MINNESOTA AND AMENDMENT NUMBER
4 BY
MS. JACKSON LEE OF TEXAS.
THIS IS A
15-MINUTE VOTE AND
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC., IN COOPERATION
WITH THE UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
ANY USE OF THE CLOSED-CAPTIONED
COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS
EXPRESSLY PROHIBITED BY THE
U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE CHAIR:
ON THIS VOTE THE
YEAS ARE 176.
AND THE NAYS ARE
241.
THE MOTION
IS NOT ADOPTED.
THE UNFINISHED BUSINESS
IS THE
REQUEST FOR A
RECORDED VOTE ON
AMENDMENT NUMBER
1 PRINTED IN
HOUSE REPORT 112-
291 BY THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
NEW YORK, MR.
BISHOP, ON WHICH FURTHER
PROCEEDINGS WERE POSTPONED
AND
ON WHICH THE NOES
PREVAILED BY
VOICE VOTE.
THE CLERK WILL REDESIGNATE THE
AMENDMENT.
THE CLERK: AMENDMENT NUMBER 1
PRINTED IN
HOUSE REPORT 112-291
OFFERED BY MR.
BISHOP OF NEW
YORK.
THE CHAIR: A
RECORDED VOTE HAS
BEEN
REQUESTED.
THOSE IN SUPPORT OF THE REQUEST
FOR A RECORDED VOTE WILL RISE
AND BE COUNTED
.
A SUFFICIENT NUMBER HAVING
ARISEN, A RECORDED VOTE IS
ORDERED.
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE.
THIS
WILL BE A TWO-MINUTE VOTE.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC., IN COOPERATION
WITH THE UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
ANY USE OF THE CLOSED-CAPTIONED
COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS
EXPRESSLY PROHIBITED BY THE
U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE CHAIR: ON THIS
VOTE, THE
YEAS ARE
187 AND THE NAYS ARE
228 AND THE
AMENDMENT IS NOT
ADOPTED.
THE
UNFINISHED BUSINESS IS
REQUEST FOR A RECORDED
VOTE ON
AMENDMENT NUMBER 2,
PRINTED IN
HOUSE REPORT
112-291 BY THE
GENTLEMAN FROM IOWA ON
WHICH
FURTHER PROCEEDINGS
WERE POST
POPED AND THE
NOES PREVAILED BY
VOICE VOTE.
THE CLERK: AMENDMENT NUMBER
PRINTED IN
HOUSE REPORT 112-291
OFFERED BY MR.
BOSWELL OF IOWA.
THE CHAIR: A
RECORDED VOTE HAS
BEEN
REQUESTED.
THOSE IN
SUPPORT OF A
RECORDED
VOTE WILL
RISE AND
BE COUNTED.
A SUFFICIENT NUMBER HAVING
ARISEN, A RECORDED VOTE IS
ORDERED.
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE. THIS IS A
TWO-MINUTE VOTE.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
INC., IN COOPERATION WITH THE
UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
ANY USE OF THE CLOSED-CAPTIONED
COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS EXPRESSLY
PROHIBITED BY THE U.S. HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE CHAIR: THE YEAS
ARE 181 --
THE CHAIR: ON THIS VOTE, THE
YEAS ARE
181, THE NAYS ARE 239,
THE AMENDMENT IS
NOT ADOPTED.
THE
UNFINISHED BUSINESS IS THE
REQUEST FOR A
RECORDED VOTE ON
AMENDMENT NUMBER 3,
PRINTED IN
HOUSE REPORT
112-291 BY THE
GENTLEMAN FROM
MINNESOTA, MR.
WALZ, ON
WHICH FURTHER
PROCEEDINGS WERE
POSTPONED AND
THE
NOES PREVAILED.
THE CLERK:
AMENDMENT NUMBER 3
PRINTED
IN HOUSE REPORT NUMBER
112-291,
OFFERED BY
MR. WALZ OF
MINNESOTA.
THE CHAIR: A RECORDED VOTE
HAS
BEEN REQUESTED.
THOSE IN SUPPORT
OF THE REQUEST
FOR A RECORDED VOTE
WILL RISE
AND BE
COUNTED.
A SUFFICIENT NUMBER HAVING
ARISEN, A RECORDED VOTE IS
ORDERED.
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE. THIS IS A
TWO-MINUTE VOTE.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
INC., IN COOPERATION WITH THE
UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
ANY USE OF THE CLOSED-CAPTIONED
COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS EXPRESSLY
PROHIBITED BY THE U.S. HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE CHAIR: THE
YEAS ARE 200 AND
THE
NAYS ARE
221 AND THE
AMENDMENT IS NOT
ADOPTED.
THE
UNFINISHED BUSINESS IS
REQUEST FOR A RECORDED
VOTE ON
AMENDMENT NUMBER
4,
PRINTED IN
HOUSE REPORT
112-2 1 ON WHICH
FURTHER PROCEEDINGS
WERE
POSTPONED
AND THE NOES PREVAILED
BY VOICE
VOTE.
THE CLERK WILL
DESIGNATE THE
AMENDMENT.
THE CLERK: AMENDMENT NUMBER 4
PRINTED IN HOUSE
REPORT 112-291
OFFERED BY
MS. JACKSON LEE OF
TEXAS.
THE CHAIR: A RECORDED VOTE
HAS
BEEN REQUESTED.
THOSE IN SUPPORT
OF THE REQUEST
FOR A
RECORDED VOTE WILL RISE
AND BE
COUNTED.
A SUFFICIENT NUMBER HAVING
ARISEN, A RECORDED VOTE IS
ORDERED.
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE. THIS IS A
TWO-MINUTE VOTE.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
INC., IN COOPERATION WITH THE
UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
ANY USE OF THE CLOSED-CAPTIONED
COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS EXPRESSLY
PROHIBITED BY THE U.S. HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE CHAIR:
ON THIS VOTE THE
YEAS ARE
188, THE
NAYS ARE 236.
THE AMENDMENT IS NOT
ADOPTED.
THE
QUESTION IS ON THE
COMMITTEE AMENDMENT
IN THE
NATURE OF A
SUBSTITUTE.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
THE AYES HAVE IT.
THE AMENDMENT
IS ADOPTED.
ACCORDINGLY, UNDER
THE RULE THE
COMMITTEE RISES.
THE CHAIR: THE
--
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR OF THE WHOLE
HOUSE ON THE
STATE OF THE UNION
REPORTS THAT
THE
COMMITTEE HAS HAD THE BILL
H.R.
AND PURSUANT TO HOUSE
RESOLUTION
470 ADOPTED AN
AMENDMENT
IN THE COMMITTEE OF
THE WHOLE.
THE QUESTION IS ON THE
COMMITTEE
AMENDMENT IN THE
NATURE OF
A SUBSTITUTE.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
THE AYES HAVE IT.
THE AMENDMENT IS
AGREED TO.
THE
QUESTION IS ON ENGROSSMENT
AND THIRD READING
OF THE BILL.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
THE AYES HAVE IT.
THIRD READING.
THE CLERK: A BILL
TO AMEND THE
NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS ACT
WITH RESPECT TO REPRESENTATION
HEARINGS AND
THE TIME OF --
TIMING OF
ELECTIONS OF LABOR
ORGANIZATIONS UNDER
THAT ACT.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
HOUSE WILL BE IN ORDER.
THE HOUSE WILL BE IN ORDER.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLELADY FROM OHIO RISE?
MS. SUTTON: I HAVE A MOTION
TO
RECOMMIT AT THE
DESK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: IS
THE
GENTLELADY OPPOSED
TO THE BILL?
MS. SUTTON:
I AM IN THE CURRENT
FORM.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY QUALIFIES.
THE CLERK:
MIZZ SUTTON OF OHIO
MOVES TO RECOMMIT THE BILL
H.R.
TO THE COMMITTEE ON
EDUCATION AND THE WORK FORCE
WITH
INSTRUCTIONS TO
REPORT THE
SAME
TO THE HOUSE FORTHWITH
WITH THE
FOLLOWING AMENDMENT.
AT THE END OF THE BILL
INSERT
THE
FOLLOWING -- SECTION 3,
ADDITIONAL PROVISIONS TO
ENSURE
A LEVEL
PLAYING FIELD FOR
EMPLOYEES --
TO DISCLOSURE
OUTSOURCING.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
HOUSE WILL PLEASE COME
TO
ORDER.
THE CLERK
MAY CONTINUE.
THE CLERK: SECTION
9 OF THE
NATIONAL
LABOR RELATIONS ACT,
U.S.C. 59 INSERT AT THE END
OF THE SUBSECTION --
OF
SUBSECTION
C-1 THE FOLLOWING
NEW
SUBPARAGRAPH.
C, LEVEL
PLAYING FIELD FOR
EMPLOYEES AND
CORPORATE
DIRECTORS.
ONCE
AN ELECTION BY AN EMPLOYEE
IS
DIRECTED BY THE
BOARD,
NOTHING IN
THIS SUBSECTION
SHALL
REQUIRE A LONGER DELAY
FOR EMPLOYEES
TO VOTE FOR A
BARGAINING
REPRESENTATIVE THAN
IS
REQUIRED FOR THE BOARD OF
DIRECTORS TO
VOTE FOR A CHIEF
EXECUTIVE OFFICER UNDER
THE
INCORPORATION
LAWS OF THE STATE
WHERE THE EMPLOYER IS
LOCATED.
D,
FREE AND FAIR ELECTIONS AND
EQUAL
ACCESS TO VOTERS.
UPON THE FILING OF
A PETITION
FOR AN
ELECTION, THE BOARD
SHALL ENSURE
AN EQUAL
OPPORTUNITY
FOR EACH PARTY TO
ACCESS AND INFORM VOTERS
PRIOR
TO ELECTION
INCLUDING BY
PROHIBITING
CAMPAIGN MEETINGS
FOR WHICH EMPLOYEE
ATTENDANCE
IS
MANDATORY OR EMPLOYEE TIME
IS PAID UNLESS BOTH
PARTIES
MUTUALLY AGREE TO
WAIVE SUCH
PROHIBITION.
E,
PROHIBITION ON CORPORATIONS
THAT OUTSOURCE
JOBS.
NOTWITHSTANDING
SUBPARAGRAPH B,
AN
EMPLOYER THAT OUTSOURCE JOBS
TO A FOREIGN
COUNTRY OR
ANNOUNCE
PLANS TO OUTSOURCE
JOBS TO A
FOREIGN COUNTRY
DURING THE
ONE-YEAR PERIOD
PRECEDING THE
FILING OF
PETITION
UNDER THE SUBSECTION
MAY NOT
ENGAGE OF RAISING NEW
ISSUES OR
POSITIONS UNDER A
PRE-ELECTION
HEARING THAT WERE
NOT RAISED PRIOR TO THE
COMMENCEMENT OF THE
HEARING.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
HOUSE WILL BE IN ORDER.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA RISE?
MR. KLINE: MR. SPEAKER, I
RESERVE ALL
POINTS OF ORDER
AGAINST THE
MOTION.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
A
POINT OF ORDER IS
RESERVED.
THE GENTLELADY FROM OHIO IS
RECOGNIZED FOR FIVE
MINUTES.
MS. SUTTON:
MR. SPEAKER
,
I'M
OPPOSED TO
THIS BILL, BUT LET
ME BEGIN BY
SAYING THAT THIS
FINAL
AMENDMENT, IF PASSED, IF
ADOPTED IT
WILL NOT KILL THE
BILL
OR SEND IT BACK TO
COMMITTEE.
INSTEAD,
THE BILL, AS AMENDED,
WILL IMMEDIATELY
BE VOTED
UPON
FOR
FINAL PASSAGE.
SO WE MAY
STRONGLY DISAGREE ON
THE BILL IN
QUESTION, BUT
SURELY
NO ONE IN THIS CHAMBER
CAN
DISAGREE THAT IN THESE HARD
TIMES
WORKING FAMILIES IN THIS
COUNTRY DESERVE
A FAIR SHAKE.
UNFORTUNATELY, THE
UNDERLYING
BILL, AS
WRITTEN, IS
FUNDAMENTALLY
UNFAIR.
MR. SPEAKER,
A FEW WEEKS AGO IN
MY
HOME STATE OF OHIO VOTERS IN
AN
EXERCISE OF DIRECT DEMOCRACY
VOTED TO
OVERWHELMINGLY REPEAL
THE
INFAMOUS SENATE BILL 5
WHICH WAS A
FUNDAMENTALLY
UNFAIR
AND EXTREME ATTACK ON
WORKERS.
IN A
RESOUNDING VICTORY FOR
MIDDLE-CLASS
OHIOANS --
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
HOUSE WILL COME TO ORDER.
THE GENTLELADY FROM OHIO
MAY
CONTINUE.
MS. SUTTON: IN A RESOUNDING
VICTORY FOR THE
MIDDLE-CLASS
OHIOANS, MANY
DEMOCRATS AND
REPUBLICANS
ALIKE,
WENT TO THE
POLLS AND
REJECTED THE
UNION-BUSTING EFFORT
THAT WOULD
HAVE UNFAIRLY
STACKED THE DECK
AGAINST THEM.
AT A TIME WHEN
PUBLIC OFFICIALS
ACROSS EVERY LEVEL OF
GOVERNMENT SHOULD BE
FOCUSED ON
GETTING AMERICANS
BACK TO WORK,
THE UNDERLYING
BILL BEFORE US
TODAY, LIKE OHIO'S
RECENTLY
REPEALED
SENATE BILL 5, WOULD
UNFAIRLY STACK
THE DECK AGAINST
OUR
WORKERS AND AMERICAN JOBS.
BUT THE GOOD
NEWS, MR. SPEAKER,
IS THAT IT
DOESN'T HAVE TO BE
THAT
WAY.
RIGHT
HERE RIGHT NOW WE,
DEMOCRATS AND
REPUBLICANS
TOGETHER,
LIKE SO MANY
VOTERS
IN OHIO JOIN
TOGETHER, WE CAN
STAND UP FOR FAIRNESS
AND THE
MIDDLE CLASS
AND PASS THIS
AMENDMENT.
OUR AMENDMENT WOULD IMPROVE THE
BILL
IN THREE VERY IMPORTANT
WAYS.
FIRST, IT WOULD LEVEL THE
PLAYING FIELD
BETWEEN EMPLOYEES
AND CORPORATE
BOARDS.
IT'S
ONLY FAIR WHEN WORKERS
CHOOSE
WHETHER TO ORGANIZE A
UNION, THEY'RE
CHOOSING WHO
THEIR
REPRESENTATIVE WILL BE IN
THE
WORKPLACE.
WHEN
A BOARD OF DIRECTORS TAKES
A VOTE ON
WHETHER TO HIRE A
C.E.O.,
THEY'RE CHOOSING
MANAGEMENT'S
REPRESENTATIVE IN
THE
WORKPLACE.
AND I DOUBT
THAT PROPONENTS OF
THIS
BILL WOULD EVER THINK OF
LEAVING
A CORPORATION VOICELESS
OR
FLOW OBSTACLES IN THE WAY OF
A CORPORATE
BOARD OF DIRECTOR'S
ABILITY TO CHOOSE THEIR
NEXT
C.E.O. AND YET THAT'S
EXACTLY
WHAT THIS
BILL BEFORE US DOES
TO WORKERS.
IT'S NOT
RIGHT.
WORKERS
SHOULDN'T HAVE TO WAIT
ANY
LONGER THAN A
CORPORATE
BOARD OF
DIRECTORS.
AND
SO THIS AMENDMENT LEVELS
THINGS OUT BY SAYING THAT
NOTHING
IN THIS BILL WILL
IMPOSE ANY
LONGER WAITING
PERIOD
FOR WORKERS TO VOTE FOR
A UNION
THAN ANY STATE LAW
IMPOSES ON A BOARD
OF DIRECTORS
VOTING
ON A C.E.O.
SECOND, THIS AMENDMENT
WILL
MAKE SURE THAT ELECTIONS
PROCEED
LEGITIMATELY AND
FAIRLY.
EVERYONE CAN AGREE THAT WORKERS
DESERVE TO BE FULLY
INFORMED.
SO THIS AMENDMENT
REQUIRES THAT
WHEN
A PETITION FOR AN
ELECTION
IS
FILED, THE BOARD MUST ENSURE
AN
EQUAL OPPORTUNITY FOR
WORKERS TO HEAR
FROM ALL SIDES.
UNDER
CURRENT LAW, MR. SPEAKER,
ONLY ONE
PARTY, THE EMPLOYER,
CAN ENGAGE
IN WHAT IS CALLED
CAPTIVE
AUDIENCE MEETINGS.
ONLY ONE
PARTY CAN FORCE THE
VOTERS
TO ATTEND CAMPAIGN
SPEECHES,
RALLIES AND
MEETINGS
OR BE
FIRED.
UNDER THIS
MOTION, UNDER THIS
AMENDMENT, THE
PARTIES WOULD
AGREE TO EQUAL
ACCESS TO
VOTERS.
IT'S
ONLY FAIR.
NO MORE
CAPTIVE AUDIENCE
MEETINGS
UNLESS THE PARTIES
AGREE, UNLESS THERE'S
FAIR AND
EQUAL
ACCESS TO VOTERS SO THAT
ALL SIDES MAY BE
HEARD SO THAT
WORKERS CAN JUDGE
FOR
THEMSELVES AND
MAKE A FULLY
INFORMED CHOICE WHEN IT
COMES
TIME TO
VOTE.
AND
FINALLY AND IMPORTANTLY,
THIS AMENDMENT
DISCOURAGES JOB
OUTSOURCING.
WITH
9% UNEMPLOYMENT IN THE
COUNTRY
AND OUR ECONOMY BARELY
GROWING, THE LAST THING WE
WANT
TO DO IS
REWARD COMPANIES WHO
SHIP JOBS
OVERSEAS.
THE
UNDERLYING BILL PROVIDES
EMPLOYERS
WITH THE NASTY WEAPON
FOR TACTICAL DELAY.
IT ALLOWS EMPLOYERS
TO DRAG OUT
PRE-ELECTION
HEARINGS
INDEFINITELY, PREVENTING
AN
ELECTION FROM EVER
HAPPENING.
EMPLOYERS CAN
RAISE ANY ISSUE
AT A TIME PRIOR
TO THE END OF
THE
HEARING.
EVEN
ISSUES THAT HAVE NOTHING
TO DO WITH THE
CONDUCT OF THE
ELECTION OR
THE QUESTION OF
WHETHER THERE
SHOULD BE AN
ELECTION
AT
ALL.
OUTSOURCERS SHOULD
NOT HAVE THE
BENEFIT OF
A TACTICAL DELAY TO
HELP SHIP JOBS
OVERSEAS.
WE SHOULD
NOT ALLOW IT.
SO THIS
AMENDMENT SAYS IF YOU
HAVE OUTSOURCED
JOBS OR
ANNOUNCE PLANS TO
OUTSOURCE
JOBS IN THE PAST
YEAR, YOU
DON'T
GET THAT PRIVILEGE.
YOU HAVE TO
DO WHAT EVERY PARTY
TO
A FEDERAL
CASE MUST DO --
STATE YOUR
CLAIMS AT THE
BEGINNING OF THE
HEARING.
WE
SHOULDN'T EXTEND PRIVILEGES
TO
OUTSOURCERS.
I
URGE A VOTE YES ON THIS FINAL
AMENDMENT TO THE
BILL.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY'S TIME HAS EXPIRED.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MINNESOTA RISE?
MR. KLINE: MR. SPEAKER,
I
WITHDRAW
MY POINT OF ORDER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN WITHDRAWS.
DOES THE GENTLEMAN
RISE IN
OPPOSITION?
MR. KLINE: I RISE
IN OPPOSITION
TO THE MOTION TO RECOMMIT AND
RECLAIM THE TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR
FIVE MINUTES.
MR. KLINE: THANK YOU, MR.
SPEAKER.
I DO
RISE TO THIS MOTION TO
RECOMMIT.
THIS IS SIMILAR TO
AMENDMENTS
WE'VE SEEN EARLIER
TODAY.
WE HAD SORT
OF AN AMENDMENT
TRYING TO
CAPITALIZE ON THE
OCCUPY
WALL STREET MOVEMENT AND
TIE -- LIMIT
WORKERS' RIGHTS
BECAUSE OF
BEHAVIOR OF
EXECUTIVES.
THIS MOTION ATTEMPTS TO
REWRITE
EXISTING
RULES REGARDING UNION
ACCESS TO EMPLOYER
PROPERTY.
THE
CURRENT SYSTEM, MR.
SPEAKER, THE
POINT IS THE
CURRENT SYSTEM HAS BEEN
PROVIDING
FAIR ELECTIONS AS THE
DISTINGUISHED
MINORITY WHIP
SAID FOR
EMPLOYERS AND
EMPLOYEES.
THE NLRB'S JOB IS
TO SEE THAT
EMPLOYERS AND EMPLOYEES
HAVE
FAIR UNION
ORGANIZING
ELECTIONS.
AT A TIME WHEN
MILLIONS OF
AMERICANS ARE
SEARCHING FOR
WORK, THE
DEMOCRATS HAVE
INTRODUCED YET ANOTHER
PROPOSAL
THAT WILL
MAKE IT MORE
DIFFICULT
FOR JOB
CREATORS,
EMPLOYERS TO PUT AMERICANS BACK
TO WORK.
RATHER THAN
PROMOTING A
BALANCED ELECTION
PROCESS, THIS
MOTION TO RECOMMIT WILL
FURTHER
TILT
THE PLAYING FIELD IN FAVOR
OF
BIG LABOR BOSSES.
IT'S TIME
FOR THE DEMOCRATS
HERE TO STOP STANDING
IN THE
WAY OF THE NATION'S JOB
CREATORS AND
WORK ON
COMMONSENSE SOLUTIONS THAT
WILL
ALLOW JOB CREATORS
TO PUT
AMERICANS BACK
TO WORK.
THE
UNDERLYING BILL, MR.
SPEAKER, THE
UNDERLYING BILL
PROTECTS
EMPLOYERS' FREE SPEECH
AND
EMPLOYEES OPPORTUNITY
TO
MAKE AN
INFORMED
DECISION.
THIS
MOTION TO RECOMMIT UNDOES
THAT.
WE NEED TO
DEFEAT THIS MOTION
TO RECOMMIT FOR WHAT IT IS,
SUPPORT THE
UNDERLYING
LEGISLATION.
LET'S
VOTE THIS -- VOTE
NO ON
THIS
MOTION.
I YIELD
BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN
YIELDS BACK.
WITHOUT OBJECTION,
THE PREVIOUS
QUESTION IS
ORDERED.
THE QUESTION
IS ON THE
MOTION
TO RECOMMIT.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
THE NOES HAVE
IT AND THE MOTION
FAILS.
MS. SUTTON:
MR. SPEAKER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLELADY FROM OHIO.
MS. SUTTON: ON BEHALF OF THE
99%, I ASK FOR A ROLL CALL
VOTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: A
RECORDED VOTE IS REQUESTED.
THOSE FAVORING A RECORDED VOTE
WILL
RISE.
A SUFFICIENT NUMBER HAVING
ARISEN, A RECORDED VOTE IS
ORDERED.
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE.
PURSUANT TO CLAUSE
8 AND CLAUSE
9 OF
RULE 20, THIS IS A
15-MINUTE
VOTE ON THE MOTION TO
RECOMMIT WILL BE FOLLOWED BY
FIVE-MINUTE
VOTES ON PASSAGE OF
THE
BILL IF ORDERED,
ORDERING
THE PREVIOUS
QUESTION ON HOUSE
RESOLUTION
477 AND ADOPTION
OF
HOUSE RESOLUTION 477
IF
ORDERED.
THIS WILL BE A 15-MINUTE VOTE
AND
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR
VOTES BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC., IN COOPERATION
WITH THE UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
ANY USE OF THE CLOSED-CAPTIONED
COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS
EXPRESSLY PROHIBITED BY THE
U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
MOTION IS
NOT
ADOPTED . THE AYES
HAVE
IT.
&gt;&gt; I ASK
FOR THE YEAS AND NAYS.
RECORDED VOTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: A
RECORDED VOTE IS
REQUESTED.
THOSE FAVORING A
RECORDED VOTE
WILL RISE.
A SUFFICIENT NUMBER HAVING
ARISEN, A RECORDED VOTE IS
ORDERED.
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE. THIS IS A
FIVE-MINUTE VOTE.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
INC., IN COOPERATION WITH THE
UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
ANY USE OF THE CLOSED-CAPTIONED
COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS EXPRESSLY
PROHIBITED BY THE U.S. HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: ON THIS
VOTE THE YEAS ARE 235, THE
NAYS
ARE
188, THE BILL IS
PASSED AND
WITHOUT OBJECTION A MOTION TO
RECONSIDER IS LAID
UPON THE
TABLE.
THE
UNFINISHED BUSINESS IS THE
VOTE ON REORDERING THE
PREVIOUS
QUESTION
ON HOUSE RESOLUTION 477
ON
WHICH THE YEAS AND NAYS ARE
ORDERED.
THE CLERK WILL
REPORT THE TITLE
OF THE RESOLUTION.
THE CLERK: HOUSE CALENDAR
NUMBER
894, HOUSE RESOLUTION
477,
RESOLUTION
PROVIDING FOR
CONSIDERATION OF THE
BILL H.R.
3463, TO REDUCE FEDERAL
SPENDING
AND THE
DEFICIT BY TERMINATING
TAXPAYER
FINANCIALING OF
PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION
CAMPAIGNS
AND
PARTY CONVENTIONS AND BY
TERMINATING THE ELECTION
ASSISTANCE COMMISSION,
PROVIDING
FOR
CONSIDERATION OF THE BILL,
H.R.
527, TO AMEND CHAPTER 6 OF
TITLE
5, UNITED STATES CODE,
COMMONLY
KNOWN AS
THE REGULATORY
FLEXIBILITY ACT
, TO ENSURE
COMPLETE ANALYSIS OF
POTENTIAL
IMPACTS
ON SMALL ENTITIES OF
RULE AND
FOR OTHER PURPOSES.
AND
PROVIDING FOR CONSIDERATION
OF THE BILL
H.R. 3010, TO REFORM
THE
PROCESS BY WHICH FEDERAL
AGENCIES ANALYZE
AND FORMULATE
NEW
REGULATIONS AND GUIDANCE
DOCUMENTS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
QUESTION IS ON ORDERING THE
PREVIOUS QUESTION.
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE.
THIS WILL BE A
FIVE-MINUTE VOTE.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
INC., IN COOPERATION WITH THE
UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
ANY USE OF THE CLOSED-CAPTIONED
COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS EXPRESSLY
PROHIBITED BY THE U.S. HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
ON THIS
VOTE THE YEAS ARE
239, THE
NAYS
ARE
184, THE PREVIOUS QUESTION
IS
ORDERED.
THE QUESTION
IS ON ADOPTION OF
THE
RESOLUTION.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
IN THE OPINION OF THE CHAIR,
THE
AYES
HAVE IT.
&gt;&gt;
MR. SPEAKER.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
THE
GENTLEMAN FROM MASSACHUSETTS.
&gt;&gt; ON THAT I ASK FOR A
RECORDED
VOTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: A --
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: A
RECORDED VOTE IS REQUESTED.
ALL THOSE IN FAVOR OF TAKING
THIS VOTE BY THE YEAS AND NAYS
WILL RISE AND REMAIN STANDING
UNTIL COUNTED.
A SUFFICIENT NUMBER HAVING
ARISEN, A RECORDED VOTE IS
ORDERED.
MEMBERS WILL RECORD THEIR VOTES
BY ELECTRONIC DEVICE.
THIS WILL BE A FIVE-MINUTE VOTE.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
INC., IN COOPERATION WITH THE
UNITED STATES HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
ANY USE OF THE CLOSED-CAPTIONED
COVERAGE OF THE HOUSE
PROCEEDINGS FOR POLITICAL OR
COMMERCIAL PURPOSES IS EXPRESSLY
PROHIBITED BY THE U.S. HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.]
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: ON
THIS VOTE, THE
YEAS ARE 239,
THE
NAYS ARE 178, THE
RESOLUTION IS
ADOPTED.
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE MOTION
TO RECONSIDER IS
LAID ON THE
TABLE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
HOUSE WILL BE IN ORDER.
WOULD THE
MEMBERS PLEASE TAKE
THEIR CONVERSATIONS
OFF THE
FLOOR.
THE
CHAIR IS PREPARED TO
ENTERTAIN
ONE-MINUTE REQUESTS.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM
ILLINOIS SEEK
RECOGNITION?
&gt;&gt;
TO ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE
AND REVISE AND EXTEND MY
REMARKS.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLEWOMAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR
ONE MINUTE.
&gt;&gt; MR. SPEAKER,
I RISE TODAY TO
CONGRATULATE
THE BENNETT
ACADEMY
GIRL'S VOLLEYBALL TEAM
FROM
LYLE, ILLINOIS, FOR
WINNING THE STATE
CHAMPIONSHIP
ON NOVEMBER 12.
MRS. BIGGERT: THE
TEAM FINISHED
WITH
A PHENOMENAL RECORD OF 39
WINS
AND THREE LOSSES.
THIS
ACCOMPLISHMENT MARKS THE
FIRST
STATE CHAMPIONSHIP FOR AN
ALL
GIRLS' TEAM AT BENNETT
ACADEMY.
EACH
TEAM MEMBER
SHOULD BE
CONGRATULATED FOR THEIR
HARD
WORK,
INCLUDING SENIOR MEGAN
WHO HAD
THREE KILLS AND 13
POINTS
IN THE FINAL GAME.
HER
SISTER, SOPHOMORE MAGGIE,
FOLLOWED HER LEAD
WITH 16
KILLS
AND SENIOR
JENNA WHO WAS NAMED
M.V.P. ROUNDED OUT
THE TEAM
WITH 10.
MR. SPEAKER, OUR COMMUNITY
IS
VERY PROUD OF
THESE
ACCOMPLISHED
YOUNG WOMEN, AT
LEAST SEVEN OF WHOM
ALREADY
HAVE MADE
PLANS TO PLAY
VOLLEYBALL
AT DIVISION I
UNIVERSITIES.
ONCE AGAIN,
I'D LIKE TO
CONGRATULATE THE
BENNETT
ACADEMY
RED WINGS ON THEIR WIN
AND WISH
THEM CONTINUED SUCCESS
IN ALL
THEIR FUTURE ENDEAVORS.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM
CALIFORNIA
SEEK
RECOGNITION?
&gt;&gt; I REQUEST UNANIMOUS
CONSENT
TO ADDRESS
THE HOUSE FOR ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLEWOMAN IS RECOGNIZED FOR
ONE MINUTE.
&gt;&gt; THANK YOU, MR. SPEAKER.
MR. SPEAKER, EVERY NINE
MINUTES
AND 30 SECONDS SOMEONE
IS
INFECTED WITH H.I.V. IN THE
UNITED STATES.
TODAY,
34 MILLION PEOPLE
WORLDWIDE LIVE WITH
H.I.V. AND
OF
THOSE INFECTED, 60% DO NOT
KNOW THEY ARE
POSITIVE.
MS. BASS:
THESE STAGGERING
FACTS
DEMAND WE STRENGTHEN OUR
EFFORTS TO
PREVENT THE SPREAD
OF THIS
LIFE-THREATENING
DISEASE.
TOMORROW, DECEMBER 1,
WE WILL
RK NICE WORLD
AIDS DAY.
WORLD
AIDS DAY IS AN
OPPORTUNITY
TO TAKE ACTION
AND
INVIGORATE THE
GLOBAL MOVEMENT
TO
ULTIMATELY HALT THE SPREAD
OF
H.I.V.
EMPHASIZING THE
IMPORTANCE OF
ENDING THIS
THREE-DECADE FIGHT
THIS
YEAR'S
WORLD AIDS DAY
THEME
IS GETTING TO ZERO.
ZERO
NEW INFECTIONS, ZERO
DISCRIMINATION, ZERO
AIDS-RELATED
DEATHS.
IN
OBSERVANCE, STARTING AT
MIDNIGHT, I
WILL HOLD A 24-HOUR
TWEET
BLAST WHERE EVERY HOUR I
WILL
TWEET FACTS ABOUT
H.I.V.-AIDS AND
WAYS EVERYONE
CAN GET
INVOLVED TO END THIS
DISEASE.
I INVITE YOU ALL TO
JOIN ME IN
THIS CONVERSATION
ON TWITTER AT
REPKARENBASS.
I YIELD BACK THE
BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM LOUISIANA SEEK
RECOGNITION?
&gt;&gt; I ASK
UNANIMOUS CONSENT TO
ADDRESS THE HOUSE FOR
ONE
MINUTE.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLEMAN FROM LOUISIANA IS
RECOGNIZED FOR ONE MINUTE.
&gt;&gt; MR. SPEAKER,
AS THE -- MR.
FLEMING: AS THE PRICE
OF CRUDE
OIL MOVES PAST
$100 A BARREL,
IT IS ANOTHER
REMINDER OF THE
HIGH
COST OF OUR DEPENDENCE ON
FOREIGN
COUNTRIES, KILLS JOBS
AND RAISES
ENERGY COSTS.
EVERY
TIME THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT
IMPOSES A MORATORIUM
OR
NEW
REGULATIONS AS IT DID ON
DRILLING IN THE GULF
AND NOW
THE KEYSTONE
PIPELINE, IT HURTS
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
DESPITE
60 YEARS OF A SPOTLESS
SAFETY
RECORD, EXCELLENT STATE
REGULATION AND
MONITORING,
APPROVAL FOR
SAFETY BY THE
E.P.A. IN
CREATION OF
INEXPENSIVE
ENERGY SOURCES,
FRACKING FOR OIL
AND NATURAL
GAS IS UNDER
ATTACK BY THE
DEPARTMENT OF THE
INTERIOR.
WHAT IS THE
EXPECTED OUTCOME?
LOOK
AT WHAT THE ADMINISTRATION
HAS DONE TO
COAL OFFSHORE
DRILLING, NOT TO MENTION WE
HAVEN'T
BUILT A NEW NUCLEAR
ENERGY PLANT
FOR DECADES DUE TO
OVERREGULATION.
HYDROFRACKING OF OIL AND
NATURAL GAS
WILL INEVITABLY BE
PUSHED INTO RED
TAPE, HIGHER
COST OF
PRODUCTION AND
LOWER
YIELD,
AGAIN, HURTING AMERICA
THROUGH HIGH
ENERGY
COSTS AND
FEWER JOBS.
I YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
FOR
WHAT PURPOSE
DOES THE GENTLEMAN
FROM PENNSYLVANIA SEEK
RECOGNITION?
&gt;&gt; MR. SPEAKER, I REQUEST
UNANIMOUS CONSENT
TO ADDRESS
THE
HOUSE FOR ONE MINUTE AND
REVISE AND EXTEND.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLEMAN FROM PENNSYLVANIA IS
RECOGNIZED FOR ONE
MINUTE.
MR. THOMPSON: THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
THE
HARDSHIP OF ALL THOSE
INVOLVED
IN THE RECENT TRAGIC
DEVELOPMENTS OF PENN
STATE
UNIVERSITY IS HEAVY
ON OUR
HEARTS
AS THIS COMMUNITY MOVES
FORWARD AND THESE
INDIVIDUALS
AND THEIR
FAMILIES
CONTINUE TO
COPE WITH
THE HORRIFIC
ADVERSITY AND PAIN.
DESPITE THE TRAGIC
EVENTS, RISE
TODAY FOR A
DIFFERENT REASON,
SOMETHING MY COMMUNITY, THE
PENN STATE
COMMUNITY, CAN BE
MOST PROUD
OF.
THE CHRONICLE
OF HIGHER
EDUCATION
REPORTED THAT PENN
STATE
LEADS THE
NATION IN
OUTGOING
FACULTY FULBRIGHT
GRANTS FOR THE
2011-2012
ACADEMIC YEAR.
THEY HAVE RECEIVED
16 GRANTS,
14 OF WHICH
WERE AWARDED AT THE
UNIVERSITY
PARK CAMPUS AT STATE
COLLEGE.
THE COMPETITIVE
BASED FOR
STUDENTSERING
TEACHERS, AND
OTHER
PROFESSIONALS IS THE U.S.
GOVERNMENT'S
PREMIER
INTERNATIONAL
EXCHANGE
PROGRAM.
THESE
VIMS WILL EXPAND OUR
NATION'S EDUCATIONAL
ENDEAVORS
BY
STRENGTHENING PARTNERSHIPS
AROUND THE
WORLD.
THESE
SUCCESS STORIES SERVE AS
AN ENCOURAGING
EXAMPLE THAT
EVERY INDIVIDUAL CAN
ACHIEVE
POTENTIAL THROUGH HARD
WORK AND
DEDICATION.
THESE
TALENTED INDIVIDUALS HAVE
MUCH TO BE PROUD OF.
CONGRATULATIONS TO EACH
RECIPIENT ON THIS
ESEEMED --
ESTEEMED AWARD.
THANK YOU, MR. SPEAKER, AND I
YIELD BACK.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: FOR
WHAT PURPOSE DOES
THE GENTLEMAN
FROM PENNSYLVANIA SEEK
RECOGNITION?
&gt;&gt; REQUEST TO ADDRESS THE HOUSE
FOR
ONE MINUTE
AND REVISE AND
EXTEND.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
GENTLEMAN FROM PENNSYLVANIA IS
RECOGNIZED FOR ONE
MINUTE.
&gt;&gt; THANK YOU,
MR. SPEAKER.
I RISE
TODAY TO COMMEND
THE
COMBINED
EFFORTS OF GOVERNMENT
AT ALL
LEVELS,
LAW ENFORCEMENT
PERSONNEL, NONPROFIT
GROUPS,
LOCAL
BUSINESSES AND COMMUNITY
VOLUNTEERS AS PART
OF THE THIRD
NATIONWIDE
DRUG TAKE BACK DAY
ON OCTOBER
29.
MY HOME OF BUCKS
COUNTY HAS
EMERGED AS
A LEADER IN THE
PRIOR TAKE BACK
EVENTS SO IT
CAME AS NO
SURPRISE THAT
DESPITE
THE
UNUSUAL FALL STORM,
WE LED
PENNSYLVANIA IN
COLLECTING TWO TONS OF
UNWANTED
PRESCRIPTION
DRUGS.
MR. FITZPATRICK:
DUE
TO THE
EFFORTS OF OF ALL
INVOLVED,
THESE DRUGS
HAVE BEEN REMOVED
FROM THE
MUSTN'T AND NO LONGER
POSE A THREAT TO PEOPLE
OR THE
ENVIRONMENT.
I APPLAUD THE
GOVERNMENT IN
KEEPING THE DRUGS
OFF THIS
ESTREETS
AND OUT OF THE HANDS
OF THOSE WHO MAY
SEEK TO ABUSE
THEM AND ENCOURAGE
CONTINUED
EFFORTS.
I YIELD BACK THE BALANCE OF
MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
CHAIR LAYS BEFORE
THE HOUSE
THE
FOLLOWING PERSONAL REQUEST.
THE CLERK: LEAF OF
ABSENCE
REQUESTED FOR MR. DREIER
OF
CALIFORNIA FOR
TUESDAY,
NOVEMBER
29, AND FOR TODAY.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE:
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE REQUEST
IS GRANTED.
UNDER THE SPEAKER'S ANNOUNCED
POLICY OF JANUARY 5, 2011,
THE
GENTLEWOMAN FROM NORTH CAROLINA,
MRS. ELLMERS, IS RECOGNIZED
FOR
MINUTES AS THE DESIGNEE OF
THE
MAJORITY LEADER.
MRS. ELLMERS: THANK YOU,
MR.
SPEAKER.
I'M HERE TONIGHT WITH MY
COLLEAGUES TO DISCUSS THE
IMPORTANCE OF SMALL BUSINESS IN
AMERICA.
BEFORE I GET STARTED I WOULD
LIKE TO ASK UNANIMOUS CONSENT
THAT ALL MEMBERS HAVE FIVE
LEGISLATIVE DAYS TO REVISE AND
EXTEND THEIR REMARKS AND INSERT
EXTRANEOUS MATERIALS ON THE
TOPIC OF THIS SPECIAL ORDER.
AGAIN,
MR. SPEAKER, WE'RE HERE
TALKING
ABOUT SMALL BUSINESS
.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: EXCUSE
ME, WITHOUT OBJECTION, SO
ORDERED.
MRS. ELLMERS: THANK YOU.
SMALL BUSINESS ARE OUR JOB
CREATORS IN
AMERICA.
AND WE
HERE IN CONGRESS MUST DO
EVERYTHING
THAT WE CAN TO HELP
THEM
TO BE DOING EXACTLY THAT
AND
CREATING JOBS IN OUR
COUNTRY.
WE'RE HERE TO
TALK ABOUT THESE
ISSUES,
WE'RE HERE TO TALK ABOUT
THE BURDENS THAT
ARE ON SMALL
BUSINESS,
THAT REMAIN IN TACT,
THAT WE CAN
HELP WITH.
WE
MUST DO EVERYTHING WE CAN
BECAUSE RIGHT NOW
OUR SMALL
BUSINESS
HANDS ARE TIED, THEY
ARE TELLING US OVER
AND OVER
AGAIN
THAT REGULATIONS AND THE
THREAT
OF TAXATION AND
UNCERTAINTY CONTINUE
TO HOLD
THEM BACK
FROM CREATING JOBS,
INNOVATING AND
INVESTING IN
THEIR OWN
COMPANIES.
WITH THAT
I WOULD LIKE TO ALLOW
MY
COLLEAGUE FROM WASHINGTON
TO
SPEAK.
BEAUT BEAUT THANK YOU
--
MS. HERRERA BEUTLER: THANK YOU.
I THANK THE GENTLELADY
FOR
ALLOWING
ME THE TIME TO JOIN HER
HERE TODAY,
TO TALK ABOUT WHAT
THIS GOVERNMENT
CAN AND SHOULD
BE DOING TO
HELP THE PRIVATE
SECTOR GROW
JOBS.
PERIOD.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE ABOUT.
WE WANT TO HELP
SMALL
BUSINESSES
GROW
JOBS.
THERE'S A STATISTIC MOST OF US
ARE FAMILIAR WITH,
CLOSE TO 2/3
OF
EVERY NEW JOB, OF ALL NEW
JOBS COME FROM SMALL
BUSINESSES.
THEY ARE TRULY
THE BACKBONE OF
OUR ECONOMY.
SO WHAT IF THIS GOVERNMENT
STARTED BY
SAYING, WHAT CAN WE
DO TO
HELP YOU,
NOT HURT YOU OR
IMPEDE
YOUR SUCCESS?
AND THAT'S WHAT
THIS CONGRESS IS
GOING TO BE DOING THIS
WEEK, AS
WE CONSIDER
THE REGULATORY
FLEXIBILITY ACT,
H.R. 527, IT'S
A BILL THAT
STRENGTHENS EXISTING
LAW.
IT
SIMPLY SAYS
IF A FEDERAL RULE
IS
KILLING JOBS, IF A FEDERAL
AGENCY IS THEN
REQUIRED TO FIND
A
RULE THAT'S LESS BURDENSOME.
IT'S
PRETTY CUT AND DRY.
SOMETHING WE SHOULD BE DOING
ALREADY, BUT
WE ACTUALLY HAVE TO
PASS A BILL TO
REQUIRE IT.
YOU
KNOW, WHEN THE FEDERAL
AGENCIES HERE IN
WASHINGTON,
D.C., ISSUE ONE
RULE AFTER
ANOTHER, SMALL
BUSINESSES
PAY
THE PRICE AND OUR
ECONOMY LOSES
JOBS.
FOR INSTANCE, TAKE
MY NECK OF
THE WOODS
IN SOUTHWEST
WASHINGTON.
A BUSINESS MANUFACTURER.
WHEN I VISIT THIS BUSINESS I SEE
A THRIVING
FACILITY WITH
PEOPLE
AT WORK.
THEY'RE
ASSEMBLING PRODUCTS THAT
HELP
OUR ECONOMY
GROW.
BUT
THE VACUUM PUMPS DON'T HAVE
A HUGE
TEAM OF LAWYERS AND
BUSINESS
ACCOUNTANTS AND -- TO
HANDLE THE
REGULATORY DETAILS,
THEY
ACTUALLY NEED REGULATORY
SPECIALISTS TO NAVIGATE
THE MAZE
OF FEDERAL
RULES.
THEY DON'T HAVE THE
MONEY.
BUT YOU
KNOW, THEY JUST MIGHT
NEED IT.
I ACTUALLY BROUGHT
THE REASON
WHY I THINK THEY
MIGHT
NEED
THAT.
MR. SPEAKER,
THIS IS PRETTY
HEAVY.
THIS IS
ACTUALLY THE LIST OF
FEDERAL RULES
AND REGULATIONS
JUST FOR HALF
OF
NOVEMBER.
THIS DOESN'T EVEN
REPRESENT THE
ENTIRE MONTH.
THESE BOOKS I
HAVE RIGHT HERE
REPRESENT ABOUT TWO
WEEKS WORTH
OF
FEDERAL REGULATIONS AND RULES
THAT
BUSINESSES HAVE TO
NAVIGATE.
LET ME SHOW
YOU IF I MAY, JUST
THE RULES FROM THE LAST THREE
DAYS.
MONDAY, TUESDAY AND WEDNESDAY.
RIGHT HERE.
YOU KNOW, PART
OF THE REASON
WE'RE HERE TODAY
IS TO
ILLUSTRATE THE NEED
TO MAKE IT
SIMPLER AND
EASIER FOR SMALL
BUSINESSES
TO NAVIGATE THIS
FEDERAL MAZE.
I
MEAN, THIS IS
RIDICULOUS.
THIS IS MONDAY
, THIS IS TUESDAY
AND
THIS IS WEDNESDAY.
THREE
DAYS WORTH OF RULES THAT
VACUUM
PUMPS IN SOUTHWEST
WASHINGTON IS
GOING TO HELP --
NEED HELP NAVIGATING.
WHICH IS WHY
WE'RE PASSING A
BILL THAT
SAYS, IF
THESE RULES
-- PUTS
THE PROOF OF THE BURDEN
BACK ON THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT.
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT NEEDS TO
FIND A BETTER WAY
TO PUT FORWARD
ITS
REGULATIONS.
ANOTHER
RULE THAT'S REALLY
IMPORTANT,
IT'S WORKING ITS
WAY
THROUGH THE ENVIRONMENTAL
PROTECTION AGENCY
AND THROUGH
THE COURTS,
IT'S CALLED THE
FOREST
ROADS RULE.
IT'S
ALSO VERY IMPACTFUL TO
SOUTHWEST WASHINGTON.
IT'S CRIPPLING
IN THAT IT
OVERTURNS 35
YEARS OF
ENVIRONMENTAL POLICY
AND WOULD
REQUIRE A
FEDERAL PERMIT ON
EVERY SINGLE
FOREST ROAD.
IN ESSENCE
YOU HAVE TO GET
THE
SAME
FEDERAL PERMIT FOR A ROAD
THROUGH YOUR
PRIVATELY OWNED
FOREST LAND
, THAT WOULD YOU HAVE
TO GET FOR
FACTORIES AND
INDUSTRIAL
SITES.
THAT'S NOT NECESSARY
.
LET'S CONSIDER THE
IMPACTS ON
PUBLIC LAND.
ACCORDING TO THE U.S.
FOREST
SERVICE
IT WOULD REQUIRE THAT
AGENCY ALONE
10 YEARS TO ATTAIN
THE 400,000
PERMITS NECESSARY
FOR THE
ROADS ON PUBLIC
LANDS.
WHAT WOULD
THAT DO TO RICK, WHO
OWNS A
SMALL TREE FARM IN CLARK
COUNTY, WASHINGTON?
HE'S NOT THE U.S. FOREST
SERVICE, HE DOESN'T HAVE
UNLIMITED LAWYERS AND
RESOURCES.
HE HAS TO DO
THIS ON HIS OWN.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE
HERE TONIGHT
TO DO.
IS TO MAKE IT
EASIER ON THESE
SMALL BUSINESS
OWNERS TO OPERATE
IN OUR REGIONS AND GROW
OUR
ECONOMY.
SO WITH
THAT I THANK THE
GENTLELADY FOR THE TIME
TO TALK
ABOUT MY SUPPORT
FOR THE
REGULATORY
FLEXIBILITY ACT, FOR
WHAT WE'RE DOING
TO HELP GROW
JOBS AND SMALL BUSINESSES.
I YIELD BACK.
MRS. ELLMERS: THANK YOU.
AND I'LL
JUST ECHO MY
COLLEAGUE'S REMARKS BY
SAYING
THAT
ACCORDING TO THE NFIB
COMPLIANCE WITH THE
ENVIRONMENTAL
REGULATIONS COST
SMALL
BUSINESSES FOUR
TIMES MORE
THAN LARGER
FIRMS.
LARGER
FIRMS DO HAVE THE ABILITY
AND
EMPLOYEES IN PLACE TO DEAL
WITH THESE
ISSUES.
OUR
SMALL BUSINESSES SIMPLY
CANNOT AFFORD
TO DO BUSINESS
THAT WAY.
AND WITH THAT
I WOULD LIKE TO
ALLOW
MY COLLEAGUE FROM
CALIFORNIA TO COME
FORWARD, MR.
DUNHAM.
-- MR.
DENHAM.
MR. DENHAM: THANK YOU
FOR YOUR
LEADERSHIP ON THIS
ISSUE.
WE CAN'T
AFFORD ANY MORE OF THE
OVERREGULATION
.
REGULATORY
BURDENS FROM NEW
RULES JUST THIS YEAR
ALONE HAVE
COST
AMERICAN TAXPAYERS $93.2
BILLION
.
AND ONE
SFUDDY FOUND THAT EACH
MILLION
DOLLARS INCREASE IN THE
FEDERAL REGULATORY
BUDGET COSTS
JOBS.
OVERREGULATION
COSTS US JOBS
AROUND THE
NATION.
AND LET ME
JUST SPEAK FROM MY
OWN PERSPECTIVE.
12 YEARS AGO I STARTED
DENHAM
PLASTICS.
SOMETHING THAT MY
WIFE AND I
BORROWED AN
INCREDIBLE AMOUNT OF
MONEY TO
START A VISION THAT WE
HAD
, SUPPORTING THE AGRICULTURE
INDUSTRY WITH A
PLASTICS
COMPANY.
YOU KNOW, IT HAS
BEEN A TOUGH
ROAD TO HOE AS
A SMALL BUSINESS
OWNER.
CERTAINLY COMES AT GREAT
RISK TO
OUR FAMILY.
BUT IT WAS A VISION
THAT WE HAD,
THAT
WE BELIEVED THAT WITHOUT
GOVERNMENT
INTERVENTION WE CAN
SUCCEED IN NOT ONLY CREATING NEW
CUSTOMERS BUT NEW
JOBS.
BUT
ONE REGULATION WOULD HAVE
PUT US OUT
OF BUSINESS.
THE
GOVERNMENT-RUN HEALTH CARE,
JUST THE
1099 PROVISION ALONE,
BY
HAVING TO REPORT ALL OF OUR
CUSTOMERS, BY
HAVING TO REPORT
ALL OF OUR
SUPPLIERS, WOULD HAVE
PUT OUR
SMALL BUSINESS UNDER.
FROM AN
AGRICULTURE PERSPECTIVE,
I'M A FARMER IN THE
CENTRAL
VALLEY AND, YOU
KNOW, THE E.P.A.
CAME DOWN WITH
NEW DUST CONTROL
REGULATIONS.
NOW, WE FARM, WE DRIVE
TRACTORS,
WE TILL OUR
LAND, AND WE'RE
GOING
TO HAVE DUST.
I
MEAN, JUST BY THE SHEER MOTION
OF A
TRACTOR DRIVING THROUGH A
FIELD OR A
PLOW PUTTING THROUGH
THE
DIRT, IT'S SOMETHING WE'VE
DONE FOR THE HISTORY
OF OUR
NATION,
CREATES DUST.
ARE YOU GOING TO PUT
US OUT OF
BUSINESS BECAUSE OF
IT?
WE GROW
ALMONDS.
YOU CAN'T SPRAY THE
TREES FULL
OF
WATER BEFORE YOU SHAKE THE
TREES AND HARVEST THE
ALMONDS.
YOU'RE GOING
TO HAVE DUST.
SO, I'VE
BEEN A CO-AUTHOR OF A
BILL
THAT GETS RID OF THIS
BURDENSOME REGULATION, SOMETHING
THAT WOULD SHUT DOWN OUR
AGRICULTURE INDUSTRY, NOT ONLY
IN THE
CENTRAL VALLEY OF
CALIFORNIA,
BUT ACROSS THE
NATION.
WE'RE FARMERS, WE ARE GOING
TO
HAVE DUST.
SOME OF MY
FELLOW FARMERS AND
RANCHERS ARE ALSO
AWARE THAT THE
E.P.A. ALSO
WANTED TO EXPAND ITS
REGULATION OF MANURE
AS A THREAT
OF
GREENHOUSE GAS.
I MEAN, SOME OF THESE
THINGS ARE
SO
LUDICROUS THAT THEY JUST COST
US
MILLIONS OF JOBS AND THE
THREAT ALONE CAUSES
FARMERS TO
SAY, DO WE
REALLY WANT TO BE IN
THIS BUSINESS?
DO OUR KIDS REALLY WANT TO
TAKE
OVER THE FAMILY FARM
?
WE'VE GOT TO
STOP THIS
OVERREGULATION BECAUSE IT
DOES
COST US
JOBS.
WE'VE
GOT TO STOP ELIMINATING
JOBS BEFORE
WE CAN GO OUT AND
CREATE MORE JOBS.
WE HAVE TO HAVE
CERTAINTY IN THE
MARKETPLACE.
AND WHETHER YOU'RE A FARMER OR
SMALL BUSINESS OWNER,
THE
REGULATIONS
EFFECT US IN SUCH A
WAY THAT AS A SMALL
BUSINESS
OWNER I COULDN'T GO OUT THERE
AND HIRE A LOBBYIST
TO GO
THROUGH
THE 90,000 PAGES OF NEW
REGULATIONS THIS
YEAR ALONE.
WE HAVE TO
STOP THE REGULATIONS
THAT
ARE KILLING BUSINESSES
THROUGHOUT THE NATION AND
H.R.
527 IS ONE WAY
TO DO THAT.
WE
NEED FLEXIBILITY, MOST OF ALL
NEED CERTAINTY.
WE'VE
GOT TO BE ABLE TO PLAN OUR
BUSINESS, NOT FOR
A MONTH, NOT
FOR TWO MONTHS,
NOT FOR ONE
YEAR,
BUT WHEN YOU'RE IN
BUSINESS, WHEN YOU'RE OUT
THERE
BORROWING
CAPITAL, WHEN YOU'RE
PUTTING YOUR HOME INTO
A SECOND
MORTGAGE
BECAUSE YOU WANT TO DO
THE AMERICAN DREAM AND
CREATE A
BUSINESS, WANT TO GO OUT AND
HIRE NEW
PEOPLE, YOU HAVE TO
HAVE
SOME CERTAINTY.
I CAN'T GO TO MY WIFE
AND SAY,
LET'S TAKE A SECOND
OUT ON
OUR
HOME AND MAYBE WE MIGHT
MAKE IT
NEXT YEAR.
REGULATIONS, WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN.
WE NEED TO BE ABLE
TO PLAN FOR
FIVE YEARS,
10 YEARS, NEED
TO BE
ABLE TO PLAN ON
PUTTING OUR KIDS
THROUGH
COLLEGE.
NEED TO, BEFORE I
GO OUT AND
HIRE A NEW
EMPLOYEE, I NEED TO
HAVE A
COMMITMENT NOT
ONLY TO
THAT EMPLOYEE THAT
WE'RE GOING
TO HAVE
ONGOING EMPLOYMENT, BUT
I'VE GOT A
COMMITMENT TO THAT
EMPLOYEE'S ENTIRE FAMILY
THAT
DEPENDS ON US
FOR THAT NEW JOB.
SO
THE REGULATIONS THAT ARE
KILLING OUR
BUSINESSES ACROSS
THE NATION HAVE TO
END.
WE
NEED FLEXIBILITY.
WE NEED CERTAINTY AS
A BUSINESS.
WE NEED IT TO CREATE
JOBS IN
THIS GREAT
NATION.
THANK YOU AND I
YIELD BACK.
MRS. ELLMERS: THANK YOU
TO
MY
COLLEAGUE.
THAT IS JUST YOUR PE
SPECTACULARIVE ALONE AS
A SMALL
BUSINESS OWNER AND
A FARMER, YOU
KNOW, REALLY
GIVES US THAT
STRONG
IDEA OF WHAT WE'RE REALLY
FACING.
MANY OF US HERE IN
WASHINGTON
NOW ARE AND HAVE
BEEN SMALL
BUSINESS OWNERS
AND WE
UNDERSTAND THE
BURDENS THAT WE
ARE HAVING
TO UNDERTAKE AND THE
REST OF AMERICA IS
DEALING WITH.
IN FACT, MR. SPEAKER,
I'M GOING
TO JUST TALK
A LITTLE BIT ABOUT
SOME STATISTICS
AND POLL DATA.
ACCORDING
TO A RECENT GALLUP
POLL, SMALL BUSINESS
OWNERS IN
THE UNITED STATES SAY COMPLYING
WITH
GOVERNMENT REGULATIONS IS
THE MOST
IMPORTANT PROBLEM
FACING
THEM TODAY.
FOLLOWED
BY CONSUMER CONFIDENCE
IN THE ECONOMY
AND LACK OF
CONSUMER
DEMAND.
SMALL
BUSINESS FIRMS BEAR
REGULATORY COST OF
$10,585 PER
EMPLOYEE.
JUST TO DEAL WITH
THE
REGULATIONS.
WHICH IS
36% HIGHER, THERE
AGAIN, THAN LARGER
BUSINESSES.
FOR SMALL
BUSINESS, SMALL
BUSINESS IS
WHAT
DRIVES OUR
ECONOMY AND YET
IT IS WHAT IS
CONTINUOUSLY
TARGETED AND WE
MUST
ACT ON IT WITH THE BILL
THAT WE WILL
PASS TOMORROW, H.R.
527.
I SPOKE
A LITTLE BIT ABOUT THE
EXCESSIVE COSTS OF
DEALING WITH
ENVIRONMENTAL
REGULATIONS.
ACCORDING TO
THE SMALL BUSINESS
ADMINISTRATION,
REGULATIONS COST
THE AMERICAN ECONOMY
$1.7
TRILLION
ANNUALLY.
THAT IS
AN ENORMOUS COST AND YOU
CAN SEE BY
OUR UNEMPLOYMENT RATE
WHY WE CONTINUE
IN THIS.
UNTIL WE
ARE ABLE TO CUT THE
EXCESSIVE
OVERBEARING
REGULATIONS THAT ARE FACING OUR
BUSINESSES,
WE WILL NOT TURN
THIS ECONOMY AROUND.
THAT IS
WHY WE MUST ACT NOW,
THAT IS WHY THE MANY
BILLS THAT
WE HAVE
PASSED OVER TO THE
SENATE
WE REPEATEDLY ASK FOR A
VOTE.
SO
THAT WE CAN GET
STARTED.
WE
COULD DO THIS TOMORROW IF
THESE BILLS WERE
VOTED ON.
ONE LAST
BIT OF INFORMATION
BEFORE I
INTRODUCE MY NEXT
COLLEAGUE
OF THE
ADMINISTRATION'S NEW
REGULATIONS, NEW
REGULATIONS.
200 ARE
EXPECTING TO COST OVER
$100 MILLION
EACH.
SEVEN OF THOSE
NEW REGULATIONS
WILL
COST THE ECONOMY MORE THAN
$1
BILLION EACH.
WE
CANNOT CONTINUE ON THIS PATH.
WITH THAT
I'D LIKE TO CALL ON MY
COLLEAGUE FROM --
I WAS GOING TO
SAY
CHICAGO, FROM ILLINOIS, MR.
SCHILLING.
MR. SCHILLING:
THANK YOU,
CONGRESSWOMAN ELLMERS, FOR THE
INTRODUCTION.
AND JUST FOR
INVITING ME TO
PARTICIPATE TODAY.
THE BEST THING ABOUT
HAVING THE
OPPORTUNITY TO
REPRESENT THE
RESIDENTS OF ILLINOIS'S
17TH
DISTRICT IS JUST
LISTENING TO
THEIR CONCERNS
AND TAKING THOSE
CONCERNS BACK HERE TO
WASHINGTON, D.C.
AS I TRAVEL
THROUGHOUT THE
DISTRICT, THE AREA, I
LISTEN AND
I'M ALSO
ASKED, YOU KNOW, WHAT
WORRIES ME.
I WORRY ABOUT
UNEMPLOYMENT AND
ABOUT THE UNCERTAINTY FACING OUR
FAMILIES IN OUR
DISTRICT.
I'M
WORRIED THAT MORE IS NOT
BEING
DONE TO CREATE AN
ENVIRONMENT OF
CERTAINTY THAT
PROMOTES
LONG-TERM GROWTH IN OUR
JOB
SECTOR.
GOVERNMENT
DOES NOT CREATE JOBS.
WE NEED TO BE
CLEAR ABOUT THAT.
GOVERNMENT
CREATES AN
ENVIRONMENT
FOR JOB CREATION BY
THE PRIVATE
SECTOR.
FOLKS SIMPLY
WILL NOT BE PUT
BACK
TO WORK IF GOVERNMENT
CONTINUES
VILLENIZING OUR JOB
CREATORS AND
ENACTING POLICIES
THAT KEEP
WORKERS ON THE
UNEMPLOYMENT LINE
AND DRIVE US
DEEPER
INTO DEBT.
AS A
SMALL BUSINESS OWNER
MYSELF, I UNDERSTAND HOW THIS
HINDERS THE ABILITY
TO CREATE
JOBS
.
BACK IN AUGUST
I INVITED LOCAL
BUSINESS OWNERS
THROUGHOUT OUR
AREA
TO PARTICIPATE IN A
BUSINESS ROUND TABLE
WHERE WE
DISCUSSED WHAT
GOVERNMENT CAN DO
TO EMPOWER THE
PRIVATE SECTOR,
SPUR JOB CREATION AND
GROW OUR
ECONOMY.
THESE BUSINESS OWNERS
ARE THE
PEOPLE WE ARE
ASKING TO LEAD US
INTO
ECONOMIC RECOVERY AND TO
PUT
AMERICANS BACK TO WORK.
I WAS
PLEASED TO SEE FOLKS FROM
ALL
SORTS OF
INDUSTRIES TO
PRESENT GREAT IDEAS AND
THOUGHT
OPS
ISSUES THAT ARE CAUSING
THEM TO STRUGGLE IN THIS
ECONOMY.
THEY SHARED
WITH ME THAT HIGH
ENERGY COSTS,
RISING TAXES,
MIXED
MESSAGES FROM WASHINGTON,
D.C., AND
THE UNCERTAINTY FROM
THE ILLINOIS STATE GOVERNMENT
ARE STIFLING THE
CREATION OF
THE ENVIRONMENT
OF ECONOMIC
SUCCESS.
NOW,
THERE ARE MORE THAN 27
MILLION SMALL BUSINESSES
THROUGHOUT THE UNITED STATES OF
AMERICA.
THEY ARE THE LIFEBLOOD OF
OUR
NATION'S ECONOMY.
AMERICA'S SMALL
BUSINESSES
CREATE SEVEN
OUT OF EVERY 10
NEW
JOBS AND
EMPLOY OVER HALF
THE
COUNTRY'S PRIVATE SECTOR
WORK
FORCE.
WE OUGHT
TO BE MAKING IT EASY
FOR THESE
FOLKS TO GROW AND
HIRE
NEW
WORKERS, NOT VILLE
ANIZING
THEM OR -- NOT
VILLAINIZING
THEM OR BURDENING
THEM
WITH
NEW TAX CODES.
WE
NEED TO TEAR DOWN
ROADBLOCKS, GET GOVERNMENT
OUT
OF
THE WAY AND LAY THE
GROUNDWORK FOR
REAL, PRIVATE
SECTOR JOB
CREATION.
PHIL NELSON, PRESIDENT
OF THE
ILLINOIS
FARM BUREAU
ASSOCIATION,
TESTIFIED
BEFORE
THE SMALL BUSINESS
COMMITTEE.
TO QUOTE
HIM, HE SAID, WHAT
KEEPS ME LYING
AWAKE AT NIGHT
IS THE POTENTIAL FOR
MORE
REGULATORY
CREEP.
IT'S AS
IF WE GO TO BED ONE
NIGHT WITH ONE
SET OF
REGULATIONS AND WAKE
UP THE
NEXT MORNING WITH A
NEW SET.
EVERY MOMENT
WE SPEND FIGHTING
AND THEN WORKING TO COMPLY
WITH
THE
NEEDLESS, DUPLICATIVE
SERVICE
REGULATIONS TAKES AWAY
FROM WHAT WE DO
BEST, PRODUCING
FOOD.
MY
COLLEAGUES AND I IN THE
HOUSE HAVE BEEN
FOCUSED ON
JOBS
SINCE DAY ONE.
PASSING MORE THAN
20 JOBS BILLS
TO GIVE SMALL
BUSINESSES THE
CERTAINTY
THEY NEED TO GROW,
INCREASE
THE DOMESTIC
PRODUCTION
OF
OIL AND GET
AMERICANS BACK
TO WORK.
UNFORTUNATELY, THESE
BILLS
REMAIN STUCK IN THE SENATE
BUT
WE CANNOT DO
IT ALONE.
THE
PRESIDENT AND THE SENATE
DEMOCRATS MUST JOIN US.
THIS WEEK WE'LL
BE VOTING ON H
R.
527, THE REGULATORY
FLEXIBILITY
IMPROVEMENT ACT.
THIS IS
YET ANOTHER
PRO-JOBS
BILL,
ONE THAT ADDRESSES THE
PROBLEM
OF BURDENSOME, RECKLESS
REGULATION THAT BURDEN
BUSINESSES AND STUNT JOB
GROWTH.
THE
REGULATORY FLEXIBILITY
IMPROVEMENT
ACT PROVIDES
URGENTLY
NEEDED HELP TO SMALL
BUSINESSES
FACING AN ONSLAUGHT
OF FEDERAL
REGULATIONS.
WHEN CONSIDERING
REGULATIONS,
AGENCIES
FREQUENTLY FAIL TO
CONSIDER
ALTERNATIVE WAYS TO
ACHIEVE
REGULATORY GOALS
WITHOUT IMPOSING
UNNECESSARY
BURDENS ON
AMERICAN JOB
CREATORS.
THIS
BILL INCREASES THE
ABILITY
OF
SMALL BUSINESSES TO PROVIDE
INPUT TO
AGENCIES AS THEY
CONSIDER
GOVERNMENT REGULATIONS
AND
GIVES THE SMALL BUSINESS
ADMINISTRATION NEW AUTHORITY TO
ENSURE FLEXIBILITY
IN TAKING
REGULATORY ACTION
AGAINST SMALL
BUSINESS.
IT
TAKES PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
REGULATORY REVIEW
EXECUTIVE
ORDER
ONE STEP FURTHER, GIVING
THE SMALL BUSINESS
ADMINISTRATION THE ABILITY TO
ENSURE
NEW REGULATIONS ARE IN
COMPLIANCE WITH THE LAW
WHILE
VERIFYING THAT SMALL BUSINESSES
WILL BE ABLE TO COMPLY WITHOUT
HURTING THEIR ABILITY TO
CREATE
JOBS.
BUSINESS OWNERS NEED THE
CERTAINTY THAT THE
GOVERNMENT
WILL GET OUT
OF THE
WAY SO THAT
THEY CAN
DO WHAT THEY DO BEST
AND GROW THEIR
BUSINESSES AND
CREATE
JOBS.
AND THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE NEED
REAL, BIPARTISAN
SOLUTIONS TO
OUR
JOBS CRISIS.
LET'S PUT POLITICS
AND
PARTISANSHIP
ASIDE AND HELP THE
PRIVATE
SECTOR CREATE JOBS THAT
AMERICANS THROUGHOUT THE
COUNTRY SO
DESPERATELY NEED.
THE TIME
HAS COME TO EMPOWER
SMALL BUSINESSES
TO REDUCE
GOVERNMENT
BARRIERS BY HELPING
OUR
SMALL BUSINESSES.
TO FIX
THE TAX CODE, TO HELP
OUR JOB
CREATORS AND TO BOOST
COMPETITIVENESS
FOR AMERICAN
MANUFACTURERS,
ENCOURAGE
ENTREPRENEURSHIP AND
GROWTH,
MAXIMIZE AMERICAN ENERGY
PRODUCTION, PAY
DOWN AMERICA'S
UNSUSTAINABLE DEBT BURDEN AND
START LIVING WITHIN
OUR MEANS.
WITH
THAT, I YIELD BACK.
MRS. ELLMERS: THANK YOU
TO MY
COLLEAGUE FOR THAT IMPORTANT
INFORMATION.
AGAIN, AS A SMALL BUSINESS
OWNER, THIS INFORMATION
IS
VITAL TO THE
SOLUTIONS THAT WE
ARE COMING UP WITH HERE
IN
WASHINGTON.
WE'RE NOT JUST
MEMBERS OF
CONGRESS WHO DON'T HAVE
THE
EXPERIENCE OUT
THERE, WE AREN'T
LISTENING
TO JUST THE USUAL
WASHINGTON
BUREAUCRATS, WE ARE
ACTUALLY SMALL BUSINESS
OWNERS
WHO DEAL WITH
THESE
REAL-LIFE
EXPERIENCES
AND UNDERSTAND WHAT
WORKS AND WHAT
DOESN'T.
AND
THIS SIMPLY IS NOT WORKING.
MR. SPEAKER,
IN MY DISTRICT,
WHERE THE
UNEMPLOYMENT RATE
HOVERS AT
ABOUT
10.3%, I AM
HEARING
NUMEROUS STORIES,
HIGHLIGHTING HOW SMALL
BUSINESSES ARE
HANGING ON BY A
THREAD AND I
SAY THAT IN
QUOTES,
HANGING ON BY A THREAD
IS WHAT
I HEAR.
OVERREGULATION IS
KILLING US,
IS ANOTHER
QUOTE I HEAR OVER
AND OVER AND
OVER AGAIN.
THEY FEEL THAT THEY ARE
BEING
PUNISHED BY
WASHINGTON.
THEY -- YEARS
AGO,
THEY FELT
THAT
THEIR COMPETITORS WERE THE
ONES
THAT THEY WERE WORKING
AGAINST IN
TRYING TO COMPETE --
AND TRYING TO COMPETE
WITH FOR
A
BETTER PRODUCT.
NOW
THEY FEEL THEY ARE WORKING
AGAINST THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
AND THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
IS
WORKING AGAINST THEM.
THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT HAS
BECOME THEIR ENEMY.
ONE OF
THE LOCAL SMALL
BUSINESSES
IN MY DISTRICT IS
KIVITZ INCORPORATED
OWNED AND
OPERATED BY
WONDERFUL PEOPLE,
AND I MET
THEM WHEN I WAS
RUNNING
FOR OFFICE.
WHY?
BECAUSE I
NEEDED TO GO IN, THEY
CALLED FOR A
MEETING WITH ME
BECAUSE THEY
WERE SO CONCERNED
WITH
WHERE OUR COUNTRY WAS
GOING AND
WHAT WAS HAPPENING TO
THEIR
BUSINESS.
THEY WERE NOT
PEOPLE WHO HAD
BEEN POLITICALLY
ACTIVE, THEY
WERE NOT PEOPLE
WHO HAD EVER
SAT DOWN
WITH A MEMBER OF
CONGRESS OR A
WANT-TO-BE MEMBER
OF
CONGRESS BUT THEY FELT
TRAPPED
AND CONTINUE TO FEEL
TRAPPED BY THE GOVERNMENT
REGULATIONS
AND ALL OF THE
UNCERTAINTY,
INCLUDING THE
PRESIDENT'S HEALTH CARE
BILL.
WHICH
THEY KNOW WILL HARM THEM
GREATLY.
KIVITZ
INCORPORATED IS THE
LARGEST FAMILY
OWNED AND
OPERATED
CHURCH PEW
MANUFACTURER AND PEW
REFINISHER
IN THE UNITED STATES.
IN ADDITION THEY BUILD
AND
REFURBISH OTHER
CHURCH
FURNITURE AND
FIXTURES SUCH AS
STEEPLES AND
STAINED GLASS
WINDOWS AND PROVIDE A
FULL
RANGE OF
SERVICES FROM DELIVERY
TO INSTALLATION.
THIS IS A
JEWEL IN MY DISTRICT
SYSTEM OF MANY ARE SENDING
THESE
JOBS OVER TO CHINA AND
YET THE
KIVITZ HAVE MAINTAINED
THEIR BUSINESS,
THEIR BUSINESS
WAS
STARTED BY GERALD'S FATHER,
I BELIEVE BACK IN THE
1950'S.
THEY HAVE SPENT THEIR
LIVES AND
DEDICATED
THEIR LIVES TO THEIR
BUSINESS AND THEY ARE
FEELING
THAT IT IS BEING
PULLED
OUT
FROM UNDERNEATH THEM.
MR.
KIVITZ' COMPANY HAD 160
EMPLOYEES IN 2005.
AND THEY ARE
NOW DOWN TO 52.
FROM
160 TO 52.
THEIR
VOLUME OF BUSINESS IS
DOWN
60%.
THEIR BUSINESS
HAS NOT MADE A
PROFIT IN THE LAST
THREE YEARS.
THAT IS SIGNIFICANT.
THEY HAVE
NOT INCREASED THE
PRICES ON
THEIR PRODUCTS,
EITHER, SINCE 2005.
THIS HAS BEEN DUE
TO THE FEAR
OF
LOSING MORE BUSINESS, EVEN
THOUGH THEIR
COSTS, THEIR
COSTS
FOR PRODUCTS,
HAVE
ESCALATED
BUT THEY HAVE
TRIED TO MAINTAIN
THEIR BUSINESS
BY KEEPING THEIR
PRICES AT THE
SAME LEVEL.
AT ONE
POINT, THEY WERE
AVERAGING ONE CHURCH
, CHURCH
FURNITURE FOR
ONE CHURCH EVERY
DAY
AND ARE NOW
DOWN TO
APPROXIMATELY
TWO PER WEEK.
MR. SPEAKER, HOW ARE THEY
GOING
TO BE ABLE
TO KEEP THEIR DOORS
OPEN AND
KEEP THOSE 52
REMAINING
EMPLOYEES WORKING?
CHURCHES DEPEND
ON CHARITABLE
GIVING AND THEY ARE
HAVING A
HARD TIME
FINDING A WAY TO MEET
THEIR OPERATING BUDGET
WHICH
LEAVES ANY KIND
OF FUTURE
PLANNING
COMPLETELY OUT OF THE
REALM OF POSSIBILITY.
I SPOKE
A MOMENT AGO ABOUT THE
HEALTH CARE
LAW, THE
UNCERTAINTY
IT'S
CREATING FOR
SMALL
BUSINESSES.
OWNERS MAKE
IT HARDER FOR US TO
DETERMINE, AN THIS IS
COMING
STRAIGHT FROM MR.
KIVITZ, IT IS
MAKING IT
HARDER FOR US TO
DETERMINE WHAT OUR
COSTS ARE AT
A TIME
WHEN WE ARE STRUGGLING
TO MEET THE
MOST BASIC COSTS OF
RUNNING OUR BUSINESS.
AS
HE PUTS IT, WE ARE JUST
TRYING TO MAINTAIN
AND PRAYING
FOR
THE GOVERNMENT TO STOP
ATTEMPTING TO
REGULATE SMALL
BUSINESSES AND GET
OUT OF THE
WAY.
THAT IS
ANOTHER QUOTE I HEAR
OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
GET OUT OF
THE WAY.
THAT'S
SOME OF THE GLOOM AND
DOOM THAT
MY BUSINESS OWNERS IN
MY DISTRICT ARE FACED
WITH.
AS YOU HEARD TONIGHT FROM
SOME
OF MY
COLLEAGUES, THERE IS A
LIGHT AT THE END
OF THE TUNNEL.
MR.
SCHILLING FROM ILLINOIS
SHOWED YOU THE
CARD, THE NUMBER
OF
BILLS, AGAIN, THAT WE HAVE
PASSED IN THE HOUSE,
WITH
BIPARTISAN SUPPORT
, TO CREATE
JOBS.
WE KEEP HEARING
HOW AMERICA
WANTS
JOBS.
WE KEEP
HEARING ABOUT THE 99.
THE
99% IS SITTING ON THE FLOOR
OF
THE MAJORITY LEADER IN THE
SENATE.
BECAUSE IF THOSE
BILLS WERE
PASSED
AND SENT TO THE
PRESIDENT TO BE
SIGNED INTO
LAW, WE COULD
HAVE JOBS CREATED
IN THIS COUNTRY.
WE NEED
TO DECREASE THE
UNEMPLOYMENT RATE.
WE CAN TALK ABOUT
CUTTING
SPENDING
ALL DAY LONG AND WE
ARE ALL
ABOUT THAT, BUT UNTIL
WE GET
PEOPLE BACK TO WORK,
WE'RE NOT
GOING TO TURN THIS
ECONOMY AROUND.
AGAIN, THERE IS A LIGHT
AT THE
END OF THE
TUNNEL AND YOU'VE
HEARD US SPEAK
TONIGHT ABOUT
H.R.
527, WHICH WE'LL BE VOTING
ON TOMORROW.
WE SIMPLY
CANNOT CONTINUE THE
ONE-SIZE-FITS-ALL REGULATIONS
PRODUCED BY
THIS ADMINISTRATION
WHICH HINDER OUR
SMALL
BUSINESSES.
THIS
BILL WILL HELP ALLEVIATE
NEEDLESS
BURDENS, ECONOMIC
RECOVERY
BEGINS WITH OUR SMALL
BUSINESSES.
BUT THIS
WILL NOT HAPPEN UNLESS
WE REIN
IN THE MASS OF
REGULATIONS COMING FROM
RIGHT
HERE IN WASHINGTON.
THE
REGULATORY FLEXIBILITY ACT
OF
1980, AS AMENDED BY THE
SMALL
BUSINESS REGULATORY
ENFORCEMENT
FAIRNESS ACT,
REQUIRES
FEDERAL AGENCIES TO
ASSESS
THE ECONOMIC IMPACT OF
THEIR
REGULATIONS ON SMALL
BUSINESSES.
IMAGINE THAT.
IMAGINE
HAVING TO RUN
AN
ECONOMIC
IMPACT STUDY TO FIND
OUT HOW MUCH
DAMAGE THEY WILL
BE
DOING TO SMALL BUSINESSES IF
THESE
REGULATIONS ARE PUT IN
PLACE.
IF THE IMPACT
IS SIGNIFICANT,
THEY MUST CONSIDER
ALTERNATIVES
THAT ARE LESS
BURDENSOME,
HOWEVER
, THE AGENCIES HAVE USED
LOOPHOLES TO GET AROUND THIS
STATUTE AND THAT
IS WHY IT IS
SO IMPORTANT
THAT WE PAY --
THAT WE PASS
H.R. 527, THE
REGULATORY FLEXIBILITY
IMPROVEMENT
ACT OF 2011.
WHICH WOULD
REMOVE THE
LOOPHOLES
AND STRENGTHEN THE
FLEXIBILITY ACT.
BY
INCREASING THE POWER OF THE
OFFICE OF THE
CHIEF COUNCIL FOR
ADVOCACY,
TO ENFORCE THE
R.F.A.,
ENSURING COMPLETE
ANALYSIS
OF POTENTIAL IMPACTS
ON SMALL BUSINESSES.
AND FORCING
AGENCIES TO PERFORM
BETTER
PERIODIC REVIEW OF
RULES.
REGULATIONS
OFTEN IMPOSE
UNNECESSARY
BURDENS ON SMALL
BUSINESSES.
YOU'VE HEARD THAT OVER
AND OVER
AND
OVER AGAIN TONIGHT.
THAT IMPEDE
THEIR ABILITY TO
CREATE JOBS.
AGENCIES
FREQUENTLY FAIL TO
CONSIDER
APPROPRIATE
ALTERNATIVES
THAT ALLOW
AGENCIES
TO ACHIEVE THEIR
REGULATORY
OBJECTIVES WITHOUT
IMPOSING BURDENS ON
AMERICA'S
JOB
CREATORS.
OUR
SMALL BUSINESS OWNERS.
THE
REGULATORY FLEXIBILITY
IMPROVEMENTS
ACT, H R. 527,
PROVIDES
-- H.R. 527
MUCH NEEDED HELP TO BUSINESSES
FACING
AN ONSLAUGHT OF FEDERAL
REGULATIONS.
IT HAS BEEN 15 YEARS SINCE
CONGRESS
LAST UPDATED THE
REGULAR
WILLER TO FLEXIBILITY
ACT
OF 1980.
DURING THAT TIME,
WE HAVE SEEN
THAT THERE ARE WEAKNESSES
IN
THE REGULATORY
PROCESS THAT
FEDERAL
AGENCIES HAVE EXPLOITED
AT THE
DETERMINANT OF SMALL
BUSINESS AND
JOB CREATORS.
THIS BILL
ENSURES FEDERAL
AGENCIES CAN NO
LONGER IGNORE
THE R.F.A.
JOB
CREATORS ARE THE KEY TO
ECONOMIC
RECOVERY.
AND THE
SMALL BUSINESSES ARE
AMERICA'S JOB
CREATORS.
OVERREGULATION
REQUIRES THE
DIVERSION OF
SCARCE CAPITAL
FROM JOB
CREATION TO CREATE
REGULATORY COMPLIANCE.
I SAID EARLIER,
MR. SPEAKER,
NORTH CAROLINA'S UNEMPLOYMENT
RATE IS NOW
10.4%.
THIS IS NOT
A STATISTIC, THIS
IS A CATASTROPHE.
MR. CHAIRMAN,
MR. SPEAKER,
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
THIS
OPPORTUNITY
TONIGHT AND I YIELD
TO MY COLLEAGUE.
MR. KING:
I THANK THE
GENTLELADY FOR
YIELDING
AND
ESPECIALLY THANK HER FOR
LEADING THIS SPECIAL
ORDER HOUR
HERE
TONIGHT TO DISCUSS THE
BURDEN
ON REGULATION -- BURDEN
OF
REGULATION ON BUSINESS IN
THIS
COUNTRY, PARTICULARLY
SMALL
BUSINESS.
FROM MY
STANDPOINT, MY
BACKGROUND,
I STARTED A
BUSINESS
IN 1975.
.
I REMEMBER THE
FEARS AND
I
KNEW I
COULD
DO THE WORK AND
TURN A
CASH
FLOW BUT I DIDN'T
KNOW I COULD
COMPLY WITH ALL THE
GOVERNMENT
REGULATIONS
AND
LITTLE DID
I KNOW
HOW MUCH I WAS
STEPPING
INTO.
AND
WHEN YOU BEGIN TO ENTER INTO
A
BUSINESS, YOU STEP INTO THE
UNKNOWN AND
I WOULD FIND OUT
ABOUT A
GOVERNMENT AGENT AFTER A
GOVERNMENT
AGENT.
THEY WOULD SHOW
UP AND I WOULD
TALK TO
SOMEBODY
ELSE IN MY
BUSINESS AND
SAID DID YOU MEET
WITH
THAT REGULATION, WHAT ABOUT
THE
E.P.A. SIDE
OF THIS?
DO YOU KNOW YOU HAVE
TO
POST A
SIGN THAT
YOU ARE AN EQUAL
OPPORTUNITY EMPLOYER AND BY
THE
WAY, THAT
HAS
TO BE IN MULTIPLE
LANGUAGES AND
IN CASE SOMEONE
WHO
HOSE UP THAT DOESN'T
SPEAK
THAT LANGUAGE AND
ON AND ON IT
WENT.
AND
THERE WAS
COMPLIANCE
WITH
FEDERAL AND
STATE REGULATIONS.
AND SO
AS
THE YEARS WENT BY, I
GOT BETTER
ABOUT
IT AND I FOUND
OUT MORE
TO COMPLY WITH AND I
GOT
GREATER FRUSTRATION IN ME
BECAUSE OF
THIS BURDEN OF FILING
REPORTS
AND MEETING DEADLINES
AND MAKING
SURE THEY HAD ALL THE
PAPERWORK
AND ALL THE PAPERWORK
THAT I WAS
FILLING OUT
WAS GOING
OUT IN A
STORAGE
DUNGEON, NEVER
TO BE SEEN
AGAIN,
UNLESS THERE
WAS
A REGULATION OR ENFORCEMENT
REGULATION
AND I WAS CONFIDENT
THEY WOULD
DIG IT
UP.
WHAT GOOD
DID IT DO AND WHAT
GOOD DID
THAT REGULATION DO IF
IT WAS
GOING TO GO OFF INTO
STORAGE THAT
GOD FORBID WE HAD
AN ACCIDENT AND
OS HMP A WANTED
TO MAKE SURE I
HAD MY
REGULATIONS IN
PLACE.
AND I
MADE
A COMMENT HERE IN THE
JUDICIARY COMMITTEE A
MONTH OR
SO
AGO THAT OF ALL THESE
REGULATIONS THAT WE HAVE
TO
COMPLY WITH,
IF YOU LOOK ACROSS
AMERICA, THERE ARE GOOD
COMPANIES IN THIS
COUNTRY.
AND
OF THE THOUSANDS OF
COMPANIES
IN
AMERICA,
HUNDREDS
OF
MILLIONS OF COMPANIES IN
AMERICA ALL
TOGETHER, THEY
ADVERTISE
EVERYTHING UNDER THE
SUN.
THEY HAVE
BANNERS ON
THEIR WEB
SITE
AND TELL YOU THEY ARE THE
BEST OR
FIRST AND THEY WILL
ADVERTISE THEIR
QUALITY,
THEIR
PERSONNEL, ADVERTISE THE
EFFICIENCY,
THE
COST.
IT WILL
GO
ON AND ON AND ON.
NOT
ONE SINGLE COMPANY THAT HAS
A
LITTLE
BANNER ON THEIR WEB
SITE THAT SAYS WE
ARE IN
COMPLIANCE WITH ALL
FEDERAL
REGULATIONS.
NOT
ONE SINGLE COMPANY TAKES
THAT
POSITION.
IF THEY EVER
ADVERTISED THEY
WOULD BE IN
COMPLIANCE, THERE
WOULD BE
A
FEDERAL BUREAUCRAT
THAT
REPRESENTED AN AGENCY, 682
FEDERAL
AGENCIES AND THERE ARE
SUBDEMENTS AND
DIVISIONS, 682 OF
THEM AND
THIS COUNT
IS FIVE
YEARS
OLD, THAT CAN LEVY
SANCTION ACTIONS
AGAINST
AMERICAN
BUSINESSES.
AND THE NUMBER
ONE FEAR I HAD
WAS, CAN
I COMPLY WITH THESE
REGULATIONS AND CAN
I IDENTIFY
WITH THEM, WHAT DO
I DO
ABOUT
THE
CONFLICTING REGULATIONS IF
YOU MEET
ONE,
THE OTHER
REGULATION IS
CONFLICTING.
TODAY, NOT
A SINGLE COMPANY IN
AMERICA
SAYS THEY ARE IN
COMPLIANCE AND IF
THEY
DO, WE
SHOULD GIVE
THEM THE AWARD FOR
THAT
BECAUSE THEY
WOULD BE
SURROUNDED BY
BUREAUCRATS,
FEDERAL
REGULATORS TO MAKE
SURE
THEY
ARE IN COMPLIANCE AND THEY
HAVE TO JUSTIFY THEIR
JOB.
WOY
PREDICT ANY
COMPANY THAT
WOULD ANNOUNCE THEY
ARE IN
COMPLIANCE OF ALL
FELLED
REGULAR
LAYINGS
WOULDN'T SURVIVE 18
MONTHS BEFORE
THEY WENT INTO
BANKRUPTCY
BECAUSE
THEY WOULD BE
TIED
DOWN AND THEY COULDN'T
PRODUCE THOSE
GOODS AND
SERVICES.
THERE IS A
TRADEOFF AND DOESN'T
MEAN WE
SHOULDN'T HAVE WISE
REGULATIONS.
BUT THEY NEED TO
KEEP IT IN MIND
THE
REGULATORY BURDEN OF THOSE
RULES, BUT
WHAT IT DOES TO SLOW
DOWN
PRODUCTION.
NOW, I HAVE
SAID, GOODS AND
SERVICES
THAT HAVE A MARKETABLE
VALUE, THAT MEANS,
IF
YOU RUN A
COMPANY, YOU WANT
TO
GO TO WORK
EVERY
DAY,
WHAT DO WE DO?
PRODUCE
A PRODUCT.
MANUFACTURE AND
ADVERTISE A
WIDTH AND
IF
YOU PUT 100 PEOPLE
OUT THERE AND
DOESN'T TAKE BUT
ONE PERSON TO
RUN THE MAIL AND
PAYROLL,
YOU
ARE
IN GOOD SHAPE.
ONE OF THOSE
PEOPLE DOING THAT.
99%
PRODUCING THAT PRODUCT,
NUMBER
ONE
GRADE AWIDGET.
AS SOON
AS A BUREAUCRAT COMES
ALONG AND
SAYS YOU HAVE TO HAVE
SOMEONE
DOCUMENTING THE WATER
COMING
IN,
ELECTRICITY COMING
IN, THE SEWAGE
GOING OUT, YOU
HAVE
TO
HAVE SAFETY INSPECTORS
AND INSPECT
MEETINGS AND YOU
LINE
EVERYONE UP AND TELLING
THEM WHAT THEY
NEED TO DO WHICH
IS
SAFE, NOT A BAD IDEA.
BUT THE GOVERNMENT
PUTS MORE ON
YOUR
OVERHEAD AND SHUT DOWN YOUR
PRODUCTION OF THAT PLANT
FOR THE
ENTIRE
PERIOD OF TIME THAT THEY
HAVE
PRESCRIBED.
AND THE
OTHER REGULATIONS,
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT SAYING,
LET'S
SAY, YOU HAVE
TO PAY THE
GOVERNMENT
SCALE.
DAVIS-BACON WAGE
THAT
MEANS UNION-IMPOSED SCALE
AND IT
MIGHT
CHANGE THE WAGES IN
THE
PAST.
I HAVE SEEN
THEM DOUBLE OR CUT
IN
HALF.
YOU GO
INTO A DIFFERENT DIVISION
AND
A WHOLE DIFFERENT WAGE
SCALE.
AND DIFFERENT FROM THE
GUY
THAT
IS RUNNING THE
MACHINE
THAT IS
BEING
AGREESED AND I HAVE TO
KEEP
TRACK ON ALL OF THAT, WHICH
MEANS, IS
CONSUMESING THE
EFFICIENCY
ON THE PROJECT.
MAKES IT DIFFICULT
--
IS OUR
TIME
NEARLY UP?
I WOULD YIELD
THEN?
MRS. ELLMERS:
I
JUST WANT TO
TAKE THE
OPPORTUNITY TO SAY
IN
CLOSING THAT AS
A SMALL BUSINESS
OWNER
WITH
MY HUSBAND BACK IN
NORTH
CAROLINA WITH OUR SURGICAL
PRACTICE THAT
WE HAVE FACED
EXACTLY WHAT MY
COLLEAGUE IS
TALKING
ABOUT, THESE EXCESSIVE
REGULATIONS THAT HAVE
CONTINUED
THROUGH THE
YEARS.
WE
ARE AT A POINT NOW WHERE WE
ARE SEEING
OUR FELLOW COLLEAGUES
BACK HOME
WITH MEDICAL PRACTICES
CLOSING THEIR
DOORS, BEING
BOUGHT OUT BY
HOSPITALS, BECAUSE
THEY JUST
CANNOT
AND KNOW THEY
WILL NOT BE
ABLE TO ADHERE TO
THE
MANDATES COMING FORWARD WITH
HEALTH CARE BILL AND ALL OF
THE
UNCERTAINTY WITH THE D OMP C
FIX,
S.G.R., ALL OF THOSE
WONDERFUL
THINGS.
MR.
SPEAKER, WE MUST ACT NOW.
WE
CAN TURN THIS ECONOMY AROUND
BY
ACTING
ON THESE REGULATIONS,
BYPASSING
THESE REGULATORY
DECREASES FOR
OUR BUSINESSES SO
THERE AGAIN OUR
JOB CREATORS CAN
DO WHAT THEY
DO BEST,
RE-INVESTING IN THIS
COUNTRY AND
BEING THE
JOB
CREAILTORS THAT
THEY
ARE.
AND WITH
THAT,
I YIELD BACK.
MR. KING: I
THANK THE GENTLELADY
FROM NORTH
CAROLINA.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: UNDER
THE SPEAKER'S
ANNOUNCED POLICY
OF JANUARY
5, 2011, THE CHAIR
RECOGNIZES THE GENTLEMAN FROM
IOWA, FOR 30
MINUTES.
MR. KING: I APPRECIATE
THAT
RECOGNITION
AND
APPRECIATE THE
INPUT THAT
HAS
COME
FROM THE
OTHERS ON THE FLOOR TALKING
ABOUT
REGULATION AND I CAME DOWN
TO CHANGE THE
SUBJECT.
AND
TAKE IT OVER TO THIS,
THAT
AS I
EMERGED INTO THE
CONSTRUCTION BUSINESS
THAT
IDENTIFIED, I
FOUND MYSELF DOING
SEMINARS WITH OTHER
PEOPLE OF
THE SAME
PROFESSION AROUND THE
FIVE-STATE AREA IN
THE
UPPER
MIDWEST WITH
OUR TRADE
ASSOCIATION
AND THOSE FIVE-STATE
AREA AS I
TRAVELED
AROUND AND
HELD THOSE
SEMINARS, BEGAN TO
ASK THE
QUESTIONS OF
SELF-EMPLOYED PEOPLE, MOST
OF
THEM STARTED
THE BUSINESSES
THEMSELVES AND WERE
EMPLOYERS,
DOING THIS IN
THE
KIND
OF WAY
THAT WE
NEED
TO ENCOURAGE
AMERICANS TO DO,
I BEGAN TO ASK
THEM, HOW MANY
AGENCIES REGULATE
YOUR
TRADE?
AND AS I
ASKED
THAT
QUESTION,
THERE
MIGHT BE 60 TO 70
CONTRACTORS IN A ROOM AND WE
WOULD BEGIN TO
WRITE DOWN THE
NAMES OF THOSE AGENCIES
AND SOME
OF THOSE
WERE DIVISIONS WITHIN
THE
AGENCIES.
START WITH THE
I.R.S. AND E.P.A.
AND GO
ON
AND ON AND ON AND
OSHA,
MINING REGULATORS AND
CONTINUES ON, BUT
WE CAME TO
THIS
NUMBER
OF OUR LITTLE NARROW
TRADE GROUP,
43 DIFFERENT
AGENCIES THAT
REGULATE US.
WE
NEEDED TO KNOW THE
REGULATIONS FROM
43 DIFFERENT
AGENCIES AND
NEEDED TO BE ABLE
TO
ANTICIPATE
HOW THEY WOULD
INTERPRET
THOSE
REGULATIONS AND
ENFORCE THEM
AND CALCULATE
WHEN
THEY
CONTRADICTED ONE ANOTHER,
ONE
AGENCY SHOWING UP VERSUS
ANOTHER.
AND
IF
THEY
HAD CONFLICTING
REGULATIONS, YOU RAN
YOUR
OPERATION TO TRY
TO COMPLY WITH
THE
ONE WHO IS TRYING TO SHOW UP
AND REGULATE THE
OTHER.
THAT GOES
ON
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
FLR
FLOORS AND FLOORS OF LAWYERS
WHOSE
JOB IT IS TO KEEP THOSE
COMPANIES FROM
AVOIDING THE
CONFLICT THAT
COMES FROM FEDERAL
REGULATIONS AND OUR
STATE
REGULATIONS THAT ARE
PART
OF
THAT AS
WELL.
IT IS A
GREAT FRUSTRATION TO
ENTER INTO A
BUSINESS WANTING TO
PROVIDE THAT GOOD OR
SERVICE
AND
DO IT
WITH A MARKETABLE
COMPETITIVE WAY
AND CONTROL YOUR
DESTINY
AND
RAISE YOUR FAMILY
AND FIND OUT THAT
A LOT OF YOUR
LIFE
IS REALLY TIED UP IN MEET
INK WITH
GOVERNMENT REGULATIONS
AND
CONTROL THE DESTINY OF 300
MILLION
AMERICANS WHO NEVER
SIGNED THE
FRONT OF
A PAY CHECK
AND HAVE NO
IDEA WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO MAYBE
NOT HAVE ANY CAPITAL
AND BUILD A
LITTLE BIT WITH
SWEAT EQUITY AND
ROLL
IT AND
INVEST
IT AND FIND ENOUGH MARGIN
AND CUSTOMERS THAT
YOU
ARE
COMPELLED
TO
HIRE A PERSON TO
HELP
YOU.
YOU
MULTIPLY THAT AGAIN AND TAKE
SOME MORE
SWEAT AND EQUITY AND
DOUBLE UP
THE EQUITY AND HAVE
ANOTHER
EMPLOYEE AND ANOTHER AND
WHILE THAT'S
GOING ON,
YOU ARE
BUILDINGS A
CAPITAL BASE THAT
BRIDGES YOU
THROUGH THE HARD
TIMES.
AND
THE AT TODAY ESPECIALLY ON
THIS SIDE OF THE
AISLE, THERE
ARE
ATTITUDES.
I WOULD SAY
TO YOU THOSE FOLKS
HERE IN THIS
CONGRESS AND
MOST
OF THEM
ON THE LIBERAL SIDE OF
THIS
AISLE
BELIEVE THAT
EMPLOYERS ARE
VICTIMIZER AND
EMPLOYEES HAVE A
CERTAIN VIRTUE
TO
THEM.
WE HAVE
GOOD AND
EVIL IN ALL OF
US.
THE PEOPLE WHO
RISK
THEIR
CAPITAL AND PUT
EVERYTHING THEY
HAVE ON THE
LINE
AND STAND TO
LOSE IT ALL
IF IT DOESN'T WORK,
THEY
AREN'T
TAKING ADVANTAGE OF
THE EMPLOYEES BUT
GIVING
EMPLOYEES A
JOB.
AND
REPUBLICANS, WE SAY JOBS,
JOBS,
JOBS.
WELL, YES, WE WANT THOSE
I DON'T BELIEVE GOVERNMENT
WANTS
THE
JOBS.
WE NEED
TO GET GOVERNMENT OUT OF
THE WAY SO
THAT INVESTORS CAN
SEE AN
OPPORTUNITY FOR
PROFIT
AND IF
THEY
SEE THAT OPPORTUNITY
FOR
P
ROFIT, THEY WILL INVEST
THEIR
CAPITAL OR
THEIR SWEAT AND
THEY WILL
PRODUCE THE KIND OF
JOBS
OUT THERE THAT WILL SUSTAIN
PEOPLE IN A MARKET
ECONOMY.
THAT'S WHAT NEEDS
TO HAPPEN
BECAUSE FIRST
, YOU CAN'T PAY
PAYROLL VERY LONG
IF YOU DON'T
HAVE
PROFIT, WHICH MEANS YOU
WON'T HAVE JOBS
UNLESS PEOPLE
MAKE
MONEY.
WHAT
DO YOU
DO?
YOU PUNISH PEOPLE
MAKING
MONEY
AND ON
THIS
SIDE OF THE AISLE,
WE DON'T
WANT
TO PUNISH THOSE
PEOPLE WHO
ARE
SEEKING A PROFIT
BECAUSE WE WANT
JOBS.
WE SHOULD
ALL
SAY, WE WANT TO
SEE PROFIT
IN THESE COMPANIES SO
THAT PROFIT
GETS
RE-INVESTED AND
MORE PEOPLE HAVE
AN
OPPORTUNITY
TO GO
TO
WORK AND RECEIVE A PAY
CHECK AND PERHAPS
A
PAY RAZOR
BENEFITS
PACKAGE AND MAYBE IF
THE PROFIT IS
GREAT, THEY WILL
SPIN OFF OF THERE AND
THE
PEOPLE
GOING TO WORK
FOR THE BOSS END
UP IN COMPETITION
AGAINST THE
BOSS.
THAT IS ANOTHER THING THAT
IS
THE AMERICAN
WAY.
THESE THINGS
NEED TO HAPPEN OVER
AND
OVER AGAIN MILLIONS OF
TIMES.
IF IT
DOESN'T
HAPPEN, WE GO DOWN
INTO A
SOCIAL DEMOCRACY -- HARD
FOR ME TO
SAY OF THOSE WORDS.
WE
MOVED IN THAT DIRECTION
DRAMATICALLY.
THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES DOESN'T BELIEVE
IN THESE
THINGS THAT I DESCRIBED
THAT I
THINK ARE
GOOD.
HE HAS
ADVOCATED THIS AND
SPENDING TRILLIONS
OF
DOLLARS
AND
BORROWING IT AND THEY
BELIEVE
THAT
U.S. TREASURY BILLS
ARE THE
SAFEST PLACE TO PUT YOUR
MONEY,
BECAUSE
THE OTHER
CURRENCY HAS
GOTTEN UNSTABLE.
THE EURO
IS IN A VERY, I WILL
SAY AN
UNBALANCED CONDITION
RIGHT
NOW.
THEY HAVE SPENT
MONEY IN THE
EUROPEAN
ECONOMY, IN THE
UNION, MONEY THEY
DIDN'T
HAVE.
THEY HAVE
BUILT A GOVERNMENT
BUREAUCRACY MUCH
HEAVIER, I HAVE
TWICE BEEN TO
GREECE THIS YEAR
AND HAVE THEIR
HEADS IN THE SAND
IN MY
OPINION.
THEY BELIEVE THAT
THEY ARE
THE
FIRST OF
A MULTIPLE DOMINOES AND
2% OF THE
G.D.P. AND IF THE
G.D.P. OF THE EUROPEAN
UNION
AND
IF THEY
ARE NOT
BAILED OUT BY
THE
E.U.
AND THAT MEANS -- YES,
LOAN
GUARANTEES, BUT GETS DOWN
TO DEBT
FORGIVENESS AND IF THEY
DEFAULT,
THEN THEY WILL MOVE
AWAY FROM THE
EURO, THE CURRENCY
AND
PRINT THEIR MONEY BACK IN
GREECE A
SECOND
TIME OR AGAIN.
AND IF THAT
HAPPENS, THEY THINK
THE EURO
BECOMES LESS
STABLE AND
IF THE
GREEKS AREN'T INVOLVED IN
IT
SOMEHOW AND IF THEY AREN'T
HELD UP,
PROPPED UP, THEY WILL
FOLLOW
THE DOMINOE AND THEIR
DOMINOE WILL CLIP
ITALY,
PORTUGAL,
BELGIUM, SPAIN, NAME
YOUR
COUNTRY.
IT MAY OR
MAY NOT BE TRUE.
IT'S HARD TO
LOOK AT GREECE AND
ARGUE IF THEY
ARE A DOMINOE AND
IF THEY
FALL, THEY WILL HIT ONE
OF
THOSE UNSTABLE COUNTRIES AND
WILL START
THIS CASCADING EFFECT
THROUGH THEDOM KNOWS OF
THOSE
UNSTABLE
COUNTRIES.
MIGHT NOT
BE TRUE.
.
COULD BE
THEY HAVE A FIREWALL
BUILT ARN
IT AND IF THEY FALL,
THEY FALL AND
THEY HAVE TO
BUILD
THEIR COUNTRY BACK UP
AGAIN.
I HOPE THIS DOESN'T HAPPEN IN
GREECE.
I HOPE THAT THERE'S
A STABLE
ECONOMIC ENVIRONMENT THAT
GROWS
OUT OF EUROPE.
WE'RE TIED TO
THEM FINANCIALLY
WITH HUNDREDS OF
BILLIONS OF
DOLLARS
INVESTED IN THE
EUROPEAN
BANKS.
IF
THEY SHOULD FAIL IT HURTS US
BADLY.
WE'RE
ALSO
HIGHLY LEVERAGED IN
THIS
CUPRY AND THE
COMPARISON
OF US
TO GREECE IS ONE THAT IS
CONSIDERABLY
DISTURBING.
THERE
IS A GOOD SIDE TO A
POTENTIAL
GREECE DEFAULT, A
GREEK
DEFAULT, THAT WOULD BE
THAT IT WOULD
GIVE THIS
CONGRESS A
LESSON FOR WHAT
AMERICA NEEDS TO
DO TO AVOID A
SIMILAR
CALAMITY.
I'D LIKE TO
SEE US STEER OUR
WAY OUT OF THIS
BUT WE'RE HERE
HAVING
A DEBATE IN
THIS
CONGRESS ABOUTMY
NUREBA IN
PROPORTION
TO THE SCOPE OF THE
PROBLEM
WE ARE IN.
WE
CAME INTO THIS CONGRESS,
THIS
NEW CONGRESS, WITH NEW
SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER, WE HAVE
AN OPPORTUNITY
WITH 7 NEW
FRESHMAN REPUBLICANS
WHO CAME
HERE,
MOST PLEDGED NOT TO RAISE
THE DEBT
CEILING, MOST PLEDGED
TO BRING US BACK
TO FISCAL
RESPONSIBILITY, FISCAL
ACCOUNTABILITY.
THEY ALL BELIEVE THAT TO THIS
DAY.
I DON'T THINK THEY'VE LOST
THEIR
BELIEFS.
BUT ALONG
THE WAY, THERE WERE
A
LOT OF BIG
DECISIONS THAT
NEEDED TO BE
MADE WITHOUT TIME
TO
ANALYZE.
SO
WHAT HAPPENED?
I SAID
THE FIRST THING WE
NEEDED TO DO WAS
REPEAL
OBAMACARE
RESM PEEL OBAMACARE,
REPEAL
OBAMACARE.
I
CAN'T SAY IT ENOUGH.
WE
NEED TO
REPEAL OBAMACARE IF
WE'RE
GOING TO HAVE A COUNTRY
THAT FUNCTIONS
AGAIN.
IT DRIVES
US SO DEEPLY IN DEBT
THAT
JUST REMOVING A COUPLE OF
COMPONENTS
OF OBAMACARE,
ACCORDING TO
DENNY
REHBERG,
CHAIR OF
THE HEALTH AND HUMAN
RESOURCES
COMMITTEE, IT WOULD
CUT OUR SPENDING BY
$1.379
TRILLION.
IT WOULD HAVE
SOLVED THE WHOLE
PROBLEM OF THE SUPER
COMMITTEE,
THAT
$1.379 TRILLION CUT, BY
ENING THE
EXPANSION INTO
MEDICAID,
THE ADMINISTRATION
ADMITTED THEY COULDN'T
SU
SUSTAIN THAT
COMPONENT.
ONE OTHER COMPONENT IN THE
OBAMACARE, THE INDIVIDUAL
PREMIUM SUBSIDY FOR THOSE
WHO
ARE COMPELLED TO BUY
INSURANCE
UNDER
OBAMACARE.
THOSE
COMPONENTS TOTALED $1.379
TRILLION.
WE STRIKE THOSE
OUT, SHUT OFF
FUNDING TO
THAT AND SAVE THAT
$1.379
TRILLION, THAT WOULD
MORE THAN HANDLE THE
$1.2
TRILLION THAT
WERE DIRECTED IN
THE DEBT CEILING
DEAL.
MR. SPEAKER, THIS WENT THIS
WAY.
WE HAD
A CHANCE COMING INTO
THIS NEW CONGRESS
THIS 112TH
CONGRESS TO DRAW BRIGHT
LINES
AND
TO ENSURE FISCAL
RESPONSIBILITY AND
ACTUALLY FIX
THE REAL
SCOPE
OF THIS PROBLEM
AND STEP
NUMBER ONE WAS REPEAL
OBAMACARE.
WE PASSED THAT OUT OF
THIS
HOUSE,
H.R. 2.
SEND IT
OVER TO HARRY REID
WHERE HE
SET IT UP FOR FAILURE
AND THEY SHOT
IT DOWN.
EVERY
REPUBLICAN IN THE HOUSE
AND EVERY REPUBLICAN
IN THE
SENATE HAS
VOTED TO REPEAL
OBAMACARE.
CONGRATULATIONS,
THANK YOU ALL
FOR DOING
THAT.
WE DIDN'T GET IT
DONE BUT WE
GOT IT
VOTED ON AND IT'S ON THE
CONSCIENCE
OF THE PEOPLE THAT
VOTED
NO THAT THAT MONSTROSITY
OF
A REGULATION CHURNS ITS WAY
THROUGH, CONSUMING
$105.5
BILLION
IN AUTOMATIC
APPROPRIATIONS THAT
WERE
WRITTEN,
DECEPTIVELY, INTO
OBAMACARE
IN AN UNS PREDENED
TACTIC.
YES, THE TACTIC HAD BEEN USED
BEFORE BUT THE
SCOPE HAD NEVER
BEEN
USED BEFORE.
SO
THAT'S IN THERE.
IT'S AROUND
$26 BILLION IN THE
FIRST TWO
YEARS
OF OBAMACARE,
THIS YEAR, NEXT
YEAR, $26
BILLION, BEING
CHURNED AWAY.
IF WE
HAD REACHED AN IMPASSE ON
THE
NEGOTIATIONS WITH THE
CONTINUING RESOLUTION, THE
C.R.
THAT
HIT AT MIDNIGHT ON MARCH
4,
IF THAT HAD RESULTED IN A
SHOWDOWN THAT
WOULD HAVE BEEN
THE PRESIDENT
CAUSING A
SHUTDOWN, THAT
MIGHT HAVE SEEN
THE
LIGHTS GO OFF IN FEDERAL
OFFICES ALL
ACROSS THE LAND,
MR. SPEAKER.
BUT
YOU COULD HAVE GIVEN
THROUGH THE FEDERAL BUILDINGS
IN THIS CITY, AROUND THE
FEDERAL BUILDINGS IN
THIS CITY
AND AROUND THE
FEDERAL
BUILDINGS
ACROSS AMERICA AND
WHERE LIKES WERE
ON IN THAT
EVENTUALITY, THEY WOULD BE
ON
BECAUSE THE
MONEY THAT FUNDS
OBAMACARE GOES
ON ANYWAY.
IT'S
AUTOMATIC.
THEY CALL IT
MANNER TO
SPENDING.
AND WE
TRIED TO SHUT THAT OFF
AS
WELL.
AND WE DID
SEND THE AMENDMENT
LANGUAGE OUT OF
THIS HOUSE THAT
SHUT OFF ALL
FUNDING TO
OBAMACARE AND IT WENT TO THE
SENATE BUT IT WAS
ATTACHED TO
THE BILL THAT WENT
WITH THE
C.R.
AS AN APPENDAGE SO THAT
THEY COULD SEPARATE IT OUT
AN
VOTE IT DOWN
IN THE SENATE AND
THAT'S
WHAT HARRY REID
DID IN
THE SENATE ALSO, MR. SPEAKER.
SO
HERE WE ARE.
WITH A
CONGRESS THAT BEGAN ON
THE
RIGHT FOOT, WITH
AN
OPPORTUNITY TO FORCE A
SHOWDOWN
WITH
THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES AND MAKE
HIM
DEFEND
OBAMACARE.
WE COULD HAVE
LEGITIMATELY
FUNDED ALL OF THE
FUNCTIONS OF
GOVERNMENT, OR I SHOULD
SAY, WE
COULD HAVE RESPONSIBLY
FUNDED
ALL THE LEGITIMATE FUNCTIONS
OF
GOVERNMENT, WOULD BE A
BETTER
WAY TO
PHRASE THAT, MR.
SPEAKER, AND
SHUT OFF ALL
FUNDING TO
OBAMACARE.
THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED
STATES THEN
WAS
PREDICTED TO
VETO A BILL LIKE
THAT.
HAD HE DOPE
THAT HE WOULD HAVE
HAD TO
EXPLAIN
TO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE THAT
HIS SIGNATURE
PIECE
OF
LEGISLATION, OBAMACARE,
MEANS
MORE TO HIM THAN ALL OF
THE
LEGITIMATE FUNCTIONS OF
GOVERNMENT COMBINED.
THAT WOULD HAVE
BEEN THE
SHOWDOWN.
IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN THE
I BELIEVE THAT WE WOULD HAVE
PREVAILED ON THAT
SHOWDOWN AND
I THINK
THE PRESIDENT WOULD
HAVE HAD TO ACCEPT THE
FUNDS
THAT WE
PUT ON HIS DESK IN THE
C.R.
APPROPRIATIONS BILL, MINUS
ANY
FUNDING THAT GO INTO
OBAMACARE,
CUTTING OFF THE
AUTOMATIC
FUNDING TO OBAMACARE.
COULD HAVE,
WOULD HAVE, SHOULD
HAVE
DONE THAT MR. SPEAKER.
WE MOVE PAST
THAT POINT.
THE C.R. WAS
GOING TO BE $100
BILLION IN
CUTS, OUT DIDN'T
BECOME
THAT.
THAT NUMBER WENT
LOW ENOUGH,
IT'S NOT
SOMETHING ANYBODY
REVISITS, THEN WE WERE
GOING TO
DO Y
E -- YEOMAN'S WORK
TO
BALANCE THE
BUDGET.
IT WAS DONE BY
REPRESENTATIVE
PAUL OF
-- REPRESENTATIVE RYAN
OF WISCONSIN THAT
BUDGET DIDN'T
BALANCE FOR
26 YEARS,
THAT WAS
ALL WE COULD
GET OUT OF THIS
CONGRESS, IT'S HARD
TO CRAFT A
BUDGET
THAT COMES THAT CLOSE HE
DID
A LOT OF HARD
WORK, LAID
OUT SOME GOOD
PARAMETERS WE
NEED TO
PICK UP AND DEAL WITH
BUT
THE BUDGET RESOLUTION ON
THE FLOOR OF THE HOUSE
WITH WAS
A
PROMISE FROM OURSELVES, TO
OURSELVES TO HOLD THE
SPENDING
DOWN AND THIS
ALLOCATION
WAS AGREED TO BY
THIS CONGRESS, BY
THE MAJORITY
OF THE
HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES, EXCUSE ME, AND
THE SENATE HASN'T
PASSED A
BUDGET
IN SO LONG I DON'T
REMEMBER
WHEN.
SO MR. SPEAKER, THAT
BUDGET WAS
PASSED, BALANCING IN
26 YEARS,
SPENDING TOO MUCH
MONEY,
LEAVING US WITH
$23 TRILLION IN
NATIONAL DEBT 10
YEARS DOWN THE
ROAD AND
IT WAS A GREAT STEP IN
THE
RIGHT DIRECTION.
NOT AS STRONG AS
I WANTED IT TO
BE, NOT AS
STRONG AS THE R.S.C.
BUDGET, BUT THE ONE THAT
COULD
PASS,
COULD CONSTRAIN OUR
SPENDING,
I VOTED FOR BOTH, THE
R.S.C.
BUDGET THAT BALANCED IN
ABOUT NINE
YEAR, AND THE RYAN
BUDGET WHICH
BALANCED IN 26
YEARS,
LEFT US WITH $23
TRILLION IN NATIONAL
DEBT 10
YEARS DOWN THE
ROAD, THAT
DOESN'T
SOUND VERY APPETIZING
TO THE AMERICAN PUBLIC, THOSE
FACTS,
MR. SPEAKER, BUT, THOSE
FACTS
DIDN'T HOLD THE PROMISE
FROM
OURSELVES TO OURSELVES,
WENT KIND
OF OUT THE WINDOW
WHEN THE DEBT
CEILING AGREEMENT
WAS
PRESENTED TO THE FLOOR OF
THIS CONGRESS AND
ULTIMATELY
PASSED.
IN THAT WAS
THE SUPER
COMMITTEE, IN THAT
WAS A
PROMISE
TO VOTE ON A BALANCED
BUDGET AMENDMENT
AND IN THAT
WAS THE
THREAT THAT IF THE
SUPER COMMITTEE
DIDN'T PRODUCE
A
PRODUCT THAT COULD PASS THE
CONGRESS, BE SIGNED
BY THE
PRESIDENT,
THEN THERE WOULD BE
THE SE QUEST RAGE, I DON'T KNOW
WHERE THE LANGUAGE
OF THAT CAME
FROM, BUT
THE SEQUESTRATION IS
THE AUTOMATIC
CUTS WE'RE
LOOKING AT
NOW.
I KNEW WHEN
THE DEBT CEILING
DEAL WAS PUT
ON PAPER THAT WE
HAD
TO GO THROUGH A NUMBER OF
THINGS.
ONE
WAS WE HAD TO HAVE
A DEBATE
ABOUT HOW WE WERE
GOING
TO
DEFINE A BALANCED BUDGET
AMENDMENT.
WE HAD
THAT DEBATE.
I THINK
I WON THE DEBATE AND
LOST THE
DECISION BUT
NONETHELESS, THE CLEAN
VERSION
OF THE
BALANCED BUDGET
AMENDMENT
WAS BROUGHT TO THE
FLOOR, I
DIDN'T CALL IT A CLEAN
VERSION.
I THINK WE NEEDED TO HAVE THE
PLANSED BUDGET
AMENDMENT THAT
PASSED THE JUDICIARY
COMMITTEE.
WE
SHOULD HAVE LET THE
COMMITTEE WORK
ITS WELL, THE
JUDICIARY COMMITTEE
MARKED UP A
BALANCED
BUDGET AMENDMENT THAT
HAD A CAP AT
18% OF G.D.P. ON
SPENDING
AND HAD A SUPER
MAJORITY TO RAISE
TACKS.
IT HAD EXEMPTIONS FOR
A
DECLARED WAR OR
CASE OF A
SERIOUS NATIONAL EMERGENCY
AND
OTHER PROVISIONS.
IT WAS
A GOOD CONSTITUTIONAL
AMENDMENT THAT WE COULD LIVE
WITH THAT WOULD
STRENGTHEN THIS
COUNTRY OVER THE
LONG-TERM.
WE
DIDN'T HAVE A VOTE ON THAT
WE HAD THE
ONE THAT SAID THOU
SHALL HAVE A
BALANCED BUDGET
AND
ALLOWS FOR A TAX INCREASE
TO BALANCE THAT
BUDGET.
OF COURSE YOU
GET TO
A CERTAIN
POINT WITH
TAX INCREASES AND
SEE A
DECLINE ECONOMICALLY AND
I THINK WE'RE PAST THAT
POINT.
THAT WAS ANOTHER
STRUGGLE.
NOW WE'RE
FACED WITH THE
SEQUESTRATION, I'M
THANKFUL THE
SUPER COMMITTEE
DIDN'T SEND US
A PACKAGE THAT COULDN'T
PASS
THE HOUSE OR
SENATE.
I
NEVER BELIEVED THEY CAN.
THEY
CONCLUDED THEY COULDN'T
REACH AN
AGREEMENT.
THERE WAS
AN IMPASSE,
REPUBLICANS SAID WE'RE NOT
GOING TO RAISE TAXES AND
DEMOCRATS SAID, WE
AREN'T GOING
TO DO
IT IF YOU DON'T RAISE
TAXES.
THEY WANT TO PUNISH
THE PEOPLE
THAT ARE PRODUCE, THE PEOPLE --
THEY WOULD INCREASE
THE
TAXES,
YOU GUYS
OVER THERE, YOU WOULD
INCREASE THE
TAXES ON THE
PEOPLE
THAT ARE PAYING THE MOST
TAXES, YOU'D INCREASE
THE TAXES
ON THE
PEOPLE PAYING THE
HIGHEST PERCENTAGE.
YOU WOULD ARGUE
IT'S
PROGRESSIVE.
AND YOU'RE NEVER
GOING TO BE
SATISFIED.
I
KNOW YOU WON'T BE
SATISFIED.
IF I COULD TELL
YOU TODAY AND
TOMORROW
IS THE FIRST DAY OF
DECEMBER, THAT I HAVE
A MAGIC
WAND AND
I PROMISE YOU ALL THAT
WE'RE GOING TO
GIVE YOU WHAT
YOU WANT, YOU'VE
GOT ALL THE
MONTH OF DECEMBER
TO PUT YOUR
WISH LIST
TOGETHER
AND WHEN THE
BALL DROPS
IN TIMES SQUARE IN
NEW YORK, NEW YEAR'S EVE AT
MIDNIGHT AND
THE NEW YEAR GIPS,
HERE WOULD BE THE
DEAL, GIVE ME
THE LIST OF ALL THE THINGS
YOU
WANT TO DO,
TO TAKE AWAY THE
LIBERTY AND
FREEDOM OF THE
AMERICAN
PEOPLE, TAKE AWAY THE
WEALTH AND CAPITAL THAT'S
BEEN
SO
JUSTLY EARNED BY PEOPLE IN
THIS COUNTRY
AND REDISTRIBUTE
THE WEALTH
AND THE IDEAL KARL
MARKS OR ANY OTHER
LEFTISTS
THAT
YOU WORSHIP, GRANT ALL THE
WISHES
YOU HAVE, REORDER
SOCIETY
ACCORDING TO ALL YOUR
DREAMS AND
LET YOU HAVE 30 DAYS
TO PUT THE LIST
TOGETHER, AND
AT MIDNIGHT
WHEN THE BALL DROPS
AT TIMES
SQUARE, STROKE THE
MAGIC
WAND, GIVE YOU YOUR
ENTIRE
WISH LIST.
IF I HAD
THAT POWER AND IF THIS
HAPPENED IN
THIS FASHION, I
WILL
THEY WILL YOU YOU GUYS
WOULD WORK
HARD.
YOUR LIGHTS ARE ON AT
NIGH.
YOU'RE WELL
FUNDED AND SMART
PEOPLE.
WRONG ON YOUR
PHILOSOPHY.
BUT
YOU WOULD PUT TOGETHER A
LIST.
IT WOULD BE A LONG LIST.
IT
WOULDN'T BE
WITHOUT SOME
INTERNAL
FIGHTS AND BARNEY
FRANK WILL
STILL BE THERE AFTER
ALL,
SO THERE WOULD BE INTERNAL
FIGHTS.
IN THE END, GRANTED YOUR WISH
AT
MIDNIGHT AT THE NEW
YEAR BUT
THE DEAL WOULD BE THAT
YOU HAD
TO
THEN STOP COMPLAINING THE
REST OF YOUR LIFE,
YOU'D HAVE
TO LIVE UNDER
THE
RULES YOU HAD
WRITTEN, THAT YOU
SPENT 30 DAYS
AND
ALL YOUR CAREER WISHING AND
DREAMING AN LEVERAGING
FOR IN
THIS
CONGRESS, GIVE YOU
EVERYTHING YOU ASKED FOR ON
THE
NEW YEAR BUT
YOU'D HAVE TO BE
QUIET AN LIVE UNDER
THOSE
RULES.
I CAN TELL YOU
WHAT HAPPENED.
YOU'D STAY
UP ALL
NIGHT LONG ON
NEW YEAR'S NIGHT THINKING,
WHAT
DID WE FORGET?
HOW DID HE CHEAT
US?
WE FORGOT
TO LEAVE THIS IN, WE
NEED TO CHANGE THE
RULES AND
WE'RE
GOING TO WANT MORE AND
MORE AND MORE.
BECAUSE FIRST OF ALL YOU DON'T
WANT
TO ADMIT TO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE WHAT YOU REALLY
WANT TO
DO,
YOU'RE ANTI-CAPITALIST,
ANTI-AMERICAN
LIBERTY,
ANTI-FREE ENTERPRISE, THERE ARE
A NUMBER OF
PILLARS OF AMERICAN
EXCEPTIONALISM YOU JUST PLAIN
OPPOSE.
AND HERE WE ARE,
HARDWORKING
AMERICAN PEOPLE,
WHY DO WE HAVE
ALL
THIS CAPITAL?
IT NEVER
WAS A ZERO
SUM GAME.
IT NEVER
WAS.
IF
YOU LOOK BACK, WHERE WAS IT
WHEN THE
SAVE MAN FIRST WENT
OUT THERE AND
BROUGHT A PELT
BACK AND
TURNED
IT INTO A
BLANKET.
THERE WAS A LITTLE
BIT OF
WEALTH THAT HAVE
CREATED OUT OF
THE LABOR THAT'S THERE.
WHEN THEY WERE
SCAVENGERS AND
FORAGERS,
THEY STILL MADE TOOLS
AND ALONG THE WAY,
SOMEBODY
ELSE COULD
MAKE A TOOL A LITTLE
BETTER A LITTLE
MORE EFFICIENT
AND
SOMEONE ELSE COULD RAISE
ATE LL
GARDEN, TRADE SOME
VEGETABLES FOR ARROW
HEADS,
WHATEVER IT
MIGHT BE.
SOMEONE ELSE COULD TAN A
HIDE
BETTER THAN THE
PERSON WHO HUNT
NERD
PELT SYSTEM OF THEY TRADED
LABOR.
IN THE MIDDLE OF ALL
OF THAT,
THEY
ACQUIRED THINGS.
THEY SAIDING
LET'S DO TWO PELTS
YOU KEEP ONE, I'LL
KEEP THE
ORE.
NOW
THERE ARE TWO
BLANKETS
WHERE THERE HAD ONLY BEEN ONE
BEFORE AND ON
AND ON THEY
WENTING
BUILDING CAPITAL
BECAUSE WE HAD
FREE ENTERPRISE
CAPTLIFFLE, WE
LET PEOPLE
INVEST
THEIR SWEAT AND TURNED
IT INTO
EQUITY AND EVENTUALLY
THEY
INVENTED THE WHEEL AND
ALONG CAME
THE INDUSTRIAL
REVOLUTION
WHERE WE BUILT
THINGS AND
PUT THEM ON
SHIPS
AND TRADED AROUND
THE WORLD AN
WE
FOUND THAT THERE WERE
RESOURCES THAT WERE
DEVELOPED
IN OTHER COUNTRIES
MORE
EFFICIENTLY
THAN WE COULD HERE.
ADAM SMITH WROTE
IN &quot;WEALTH OF
NATIONS&quot; HABIT HOW THEY HAD
THE
WOOL INDUSTRY
GOING ON UP IN
ENGLAND,
SCOTLAND AND IRELAND
AND THEY
SHOULD BE THE ONE
THERE IS SHEARING
SHEEP AND
TURNING THAT INTO CLOTHING
AND
PUT THE WOOL
PRODUCTS THAT THEY
DID SO
WELL ON SHIPS AND
SAIL
THEM
DOWN TO PORTUGAL WHERE
THEY WERE A
LOT BETTER AT
RAISING
GRAPES AND TURNING IT
INTO
WINE, BRING BACK A LOAD OF
WINE AND
BOTH COUNTRIES WERE
BETTER OFF.
.
WHENEVER THERE ARE
TWO
PEOPLE THAT TRADE A
DOLLAR AND A
BUSINESS
TRANSACTION, MAYBE
TWO,
THREE,
FOUR, FIVE, SIX PEOPLE,
THESE BUSINESS DEALS
ARE SET UP
BECAUSE EACH
PARTY BENEFITS.
DOESN'T NEED
TO BE A LOSER AND
WHEN I HIRE
SOMEBODY
SO GO TO
WORK FOR
ME AND I PAY THEM A
WAGE, THEY
GET
SOMETHING
IN
RETURN.
THEY WANT
THE
CHALLENGE
AND
WANT
TO
CONTRIBUTE AND WE REACH THIS
AGREEMENT.
IT IS
A CRACK TALL AGREEMENT
BETWEEN TWO
-- CONTRACTUAL
AGREEMENT
BETWEEN TWO
ADULTS.
GOLD GOT
MINED BETWEEN THE IN
CRMP ARCH S
AND THEY CUT OUT THE
COST OF
LABOR AND SAID THEY CUT
OUT
THE COST OF LABOR AND ONCE
THEY
REMOVED A SIGNIFICANT COST
OF THE LABOR OF
PRODUCING THE
GOLD FROM
THEM, THEY DUMPED INTO
THE
MARKETS OF EUROPE AND THE
PRICE
WEPT DOWN.
SUPPLY AND
DEMAND AND COST WENT
TOGETHER.
AND
OVER
THE CENTURIES WE BUILT
SHIPS AND WE
BUILT BUILDINGS AND
HIGHWAY
S AND
BRIDGES AND WE
CREATED CASH
AND
CURRENCY TO
TRADE THESE
--
TO TRADE OUR
LABOR BACK AND
FORTH WITH A
COMMODITY THAT WOULD BE WILLING
TO EXCHANGE.
THAT'S
MONEY.
AND
THEN THE CAPITALISTS BUILT
IN THIS
WORLD
TRILLIONS AND
YET CLASS ENVIA
SETS
IN.
AND I HEAR
SOME
OF YOU SAY THE
PEOPLE WHO
WANT TO WORK SHOULD
WORK
AND HAVE A JOB AND PEOPLE
ARE
ABLE TO, THE PEOPLE WHO ARE
ABLE TO WORK
NEED TO SUSTAIN
THEMSELVES AND NEED
TO
CONTRIBUTE TO
THE GROSS DOMESTIC
PRODUCT IN THIS
COUNTRY AND
PATRIOTIC THING TO
DO.
AND AMERICA
HAS CREATED THAT
SOMEHOW THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
IS GOING
TO GUARANTEE A
STANDARD
OF
LIVING.
MR. SPEAKER, I
KNOW YOU ARE
GOING TO
BE ASTONISHED BUT 72
MEANS-TESTED
PROGRAMS.
THERE ISN'T
A SINGLE AMERICAN
CAN
NAME THEM FROM MEMORY.
AND
IF THEY CAN'T DESCRIBE THEM,
THEY CAN'T
UNDERSTAND HOW THEY
FUNCTION
INDIVIDUALLY LET ALONE
HOW
72 DIFFERENT WELFARE
PROGRAMS CAN
INTERACT AND
FUNCTION TO
PROVIDE AN INCENTIVE
TO DO THE RIGHT
THING.
MAYBE GET AN
EDUCATION AND
DEVELOP
JOB SKILLS.
WILLIAM
BENNETT TOLD US, HE SAID
HE
CONSIDERED 75% OF THE
NATION'S
PATHOLOGY.
GET
MARRIED, STAY MARRIED, GET A
JOB,
STAY A JOB.
IF
HE
IS
RIGHT ON THAT'S CORRECT
THE OTHER
IS SUBSTANCE ABUSE AND
GET TO
99% IF PEOPLE GET
MARRIED, STAY
MARRIED, GET A
JOB, KEEP A
JOB AND NOT ABUSE
ALCOHOL
AND REJECT ILLEGAL DRUGS
AND
WOULD SETTLE DOMESTIC
SCAUBLES.
AND OUR
CULTURE IS
EXPANDING
THE
DEPENDENCY
CLASS IN AMERICA.
IT GOES ON
AND OVER AND OVER
AGAIN.
YOU DO THAT
BECAUSE
SOME OF YOU
BELIEVE, MAYBE ALL
OF
YOU
BELIEVE THAT
IT IS A HUMANE
THING TO
DO IS TAKE THE SWEAT OF
ONE PERSON
AND
HAND
IT OVER TO
ONE PERSON
WHO
WON'T SWEAT AND
DO IT
BECAUSE IT EXPANDS YOUR
POLITICAL BASE AND
CATER
TO THE
PEOPLE
THAT YOU ARE PROMISING
SOMEBODY
ELSE'S LABOR TO.
WE ARE
GETTING WEAKER.
WE
REACHED THE POINT NOW WHERE
THE
300 MILLION AMERICANS THAT
WE HAVE, WE TALK
ABOUT HOW MUCH
UNEMPLOYMENT WE HAVE.
MILLION.
YOU LOOK
AT THE WEEKLY NUMBERS
OF THE
NEW SIGN-UPS AND THAT
RANGES DOWN TO
400,000 OR SO AND
WE
THINK THERE IS 400,000
SIGN-UPS TO
UNEMPLOYMENT.
AND THEY
EXPIRE AND NO LONGER
ELIGIBLE AND
DOWN TO 14 MILLION
UNEMPLOYED OR A LITTLE
MORE.
THAT'S NOT
THE
NUMBER WE SHOULD
BE MOST CONCERNED
ABOUT.
IT
IS A NUMBER, WE SHOULD ADD
THE
14 MILLION THAT MEET THE
DEFINITION FOR
UNEMPLOYMENT TO
THE NUMBER
OF
AMERICANS THAT ARE
WORKING AGE THAT ARE NOT IN
THE
WORK FORCE.
DEPARTMENT OF LABOR HAS IT
IN THEIR
WEB SITE AND YOU WILL
SEE
DIFFERENT AGE GROUPS.
STARTS AT AGE
16, 16-19, NINE
MILLION
AMERICANS OF
THAT
WORKING AGE THAT
AREN'T IN THE
WORK FORCE.
THEY
MAY BE IN
SCHOOL.
I
STARTED BEFORE THAT AGE OF 16.
AND THEN
YOU GO FROM 20 UP TO
25,
ANOTHER CHUNK.
AMERICANS OF
WORKING AGE NOT IN
THE WORK FORCE.
WHEN I
CAME
TO THIS CONGRESS
WERE
69 MILLION.
THEN IT
BECAME 80 MILLION AND
2.5 MONTHS
AGO, THE NUMBER FOR
THE FIRST
TIME
IN THIS
COUNTRY,
THE NUMBER
OF
AMERICANS OF
WORKING AGE
NOT IN THE WORK
FORCE NOW
HAS EXCEEDED 100
MILLION
AMERICANS, 100 MILLION
AMERICANS.
AND WHILE THAT'S
GOING ON, NOW
WE HAVE WHAT IS
OUR NUMBER, 11
OR 12
MILLION ILLEGALS IN
AMERICA
CAN
.
BUT
INDICATES
WE KNOW THIS SEVEN
OUT OF EVERY
12 ILLEGALS HERE IN
THIS
COUNTRY WORK, THAT IS LOWER
THAN THE
NUMBER
OF AMERICANS
WORKING.
AND
SEVEN OUT OF 12 THAT ARE
THERE
ARE PART OF -- AROUND
EIGHT
MILLION, SEVEN TO EIGHT
MILLION,
DOCUMENTED, STUDY
ANALYZED CONSENSUS
NUMBERS THAT
ARE
WORKING.
IF THEY
ALL WOKE UP TOMORROW
MORNING,
THAT
CREATES EIGHT
MILLION NEW
JOBS.
IF THEY WEREN'T
COMING INTO THIS
COUNTRY
ILLEGALLY, THEY COULD DO
SOMETHING
PRODUCTIVE
RATHER THAN
SOMETHING THAT IS
NOT
CONTRIBUTING
ECONOMICALLY.
EIGHT MILLION JOBS
THERE.
BUT THERE ARE MANY
OTHER
JOBS
OUT THERE THAT WILL
START A
BUSINESS,
ASK FOR A JOB AND
COMPETE AND EVERYONE
OFFERS 100
MILLION
AMERICANS THAT AREN'T
WORKING THAT PUTS
IN ONE HOUR
CONTRIBUTES TO
THE GROSS
DOMESTIC PRODUCT
OF THE UNITED
STATES OF
AMERICA.
PEOPLE WHO AREN'T
PRODUCING ARE
NOT CONTRIBUTING
UNLESS THEY
HAVE INVESTMENTS
AND THEN I WILL
GIVE THEM
CREDIT.
100 MILLION,
THINK IF YOU WERE
ON A
BOAT OR A SHIP AND 300
PEOPLE ON
THAT BOAT OR SHIP AND
SOME
PULLING THE OARS, SOME
COOKING,
CLEANING
AND
HOUSEKEEPING AND
TAKING
CARE OF
THE CAPTAIN AND
HAD 100 PEOPLE
SAID I'M
GOING TO SIT HERE AND
SAY,
BRING ME MY FOOD.
I PUT THE
PEOPLE ON THE OA RMP S
AND WE
WILL SAIL A LOT SMOOTHER
AND FEEL
BETTER
ABOUT OURSELVES.
THIS DIGNITY OF
WORK IS THERE
FOR EVERY MAN
AND WORK THAT
TAKES THAT
JOB
ON.
LET'S STEP UP
AND TAKE THE
FREEDOM WE HAVE LEFT
AND GRASP
MORE OF
THAT
LIBERTY AND FREEDOM
AND PUT
SOME OF
THESE 100
MILLION
PEOPLE
TO WORK SO THEY
CAN CONTINUE TO
THEIR GROSS
DOMESTIC
PRODUCT.
WE WILL BE
STRONGER ECONOMICALLY
AND HAVE MORE
PRUDENT PEOPLE
CONTRIBUTING AND GET
TO
A
BALANCED BUDGET AND
START TO PAY
DOWN THE
NATIONAL
DEBT AND
RESPECT THE RULE OF
LAW.
MR. SPEAKER,
I WOULD GO ON FOR
ANOTHER HALF
HOUR, ARTICULATING
THE OTHER
PILLARS, BUT I
RECOGNIZE THERE IS A
LIMIT TO
MY
TIME AND
I
APPRECIATE YOUR
ATTENTION AND I YIELD
BACK
THE
BALANCE OF MY
TIME.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
GENTLEMAN YIELDS BACK THE
BALANCE OF HIS TIME.
DOES THE GENTLEMAN HAVE
A
MOTION?
MR. KING: I MOVE
THE
HOUSE
DO
NOW ADJOURN.
THE SPEAKER PRO TEMPORE: THE
QUESTION IS ON THE MOTION
TO
ADJOURN.
THOSE IN FAVOR SAY AYE.
THOSE OPPOSED, NO.
THE AYES HAVE IT.
THE MOTION IS
ADOPTED.
ACCORDING
TO
THE HOUSE STANDS
ADJOURNED UNTIL 10:00
A.M.
TOMORROW FOR
MORNING
HOUR
DEBATE.